<chapter book="2 Kings" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">In the twentieth year and seventh year to Jeroboam king of Israel, reigned Azariah son of Amaziah king of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The son of sixteen years was he in his reigning, and fifty and two years he reigned in Jerusalem. And his mother’s name Jecholiah, from Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he will do the straight in the eyes of Jehovah, according to all which Amaziah his father did.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But the heights were not turned away: the people yet sacrificing and burning incense upon the heights.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jehovah will strike the king, and he will be leprous until the day of his death, and he will dwell in a house of infirmity. And Jotham the king’s son over the house, judging the people of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the rest of the words of Azariah, and all that he did, are they not written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Judah?</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Azariah will lie down with his fathers and they will bury him with his fathers in the city of David; and Jotham his son will reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And in the thirtieth year and eighth year to Azariah king of Judah, reigned Zechariah son of Jeroboam over Israel in Shomeron six months.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he will do evil in the eyes of Jehovah, as did his fathers: he turned not away from the sins of Jeroboam son of Nebat, who caused Israel to sin.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Shallum son of Jabesh will conspire against him, and strike him before the people, and kill him, and reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the rest of the words of Zechariah, behold them written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="12">This the word of Jehovah which he spake to Jehu, saying, The fourth sons shall sit to thee upon the throne of Israel, and it will be so.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Shallum son of Jabesh reigned in the thirtieth year and ninth year to Uzziah king of Judah; and he will reign a month of days in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Menahem son of Gadi from Tirzah, will go up, and will come to Shomeron and strike Shallum son of Jabesh, in Shomeron, and kill him, and reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the rest of the words of Shallum, and his conspiracy which he conspired, behold them written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then Menahem will strike Tiphsah and all which was in her, and her bounds from Tirzah: for it was not opened, and he will strike; all those being pregnant in it he clave asunder.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In the thirtieth year and ninth year to Azariah king of Judah, reigned Menahem son of Gadi, over Israel, ten years in Shomeron.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he will do evil in the eyes of Jehovah: he turned not away from the sins of Jeroboam son of Nebat, who caused Israel to sin, all his days.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Pul, king of Assyria came upon the land; and Menahem will give to Pul a thousand talents of silver, for his hands to be with him to strengthen the kingdom in his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Menahem will bring forth the silver upon Israel, upon all the mighty of strength, to give to the king of Assyria fifty shekels of silver to one man. And the king of Assyria turned back and stood not there in the land.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the rest of the words of Menahem and all which he did, are they not written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Israel?</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Menahem will lie down with his fathers; and Pekahiah his son will reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="23">In the year the fiftieth year to Azariah king of Judah, reigned Pekahiah son of Menahem over Israel in Shomeron, two years.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he will do evil in the eyes of Jehovah: he turned not away from the sins of Jeroboam son of Nebat who caused Israel to sin.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Pekah son of Remaliah, his third, will conspire against him, and will strike him in Shomeron, in the fortress of the king’s house, with Argob and Arieh, and with him fifty men from the sons of the Gileadites: and he will kill him, and reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And the rest of the words of Pekahiah and all which he did, behold them written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="27">In the fiftieth year and second year to Azariah king of Judah, reigned Pekah son of Remaliah over Israel in Shomeron, twenty years.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he will do evil in the eyes of Jehovah: he turned not away from the sins of Jeroboam son of Nebat who caused Israel to sin.</verse>
  <verse number="29">In the days of Pekah king of Israel, came Tiglath-Pileser, king of Assyria, and he will take Ijon, and Abel of the house of oppression, and Janoah, and Kadesh and Hazer, and Gilead, and Galilee, all the land of Naphtali, and he will carry them captive to Assyria.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Hoshea son of Elah will conspire a conspiracy against Pekah son of Remaliah, and he will smite him and kill him, and reign in his stead, in the twentieth year to Jotham son of Uzziah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And the rest of the words of Pekah and all that he did, behold them written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="32">In the second year to Pekah son of Remaliah, king of Israel, reigned Jotham son of Uzziah king of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The son of twenty and five years was he in his reigning, and sixteen years he reigned in Jerusalem. And his mothers name Jerusha, daughter of Zadok.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And he will do the straight in the eyes of Jehovah: he did according to all which Ahaziah his father did.</verse>
  <verse number="35">But the heights were not removed: the people yet sacrificing and burning incense upon the heights. He built the gate of the house of Jehovah the Most High.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the rest of the words of Jotham and all which he did, are they not written upon the book of the words of the days to the kings of Judah?</verse>
  <verse number="37">In those days Jehovah began to send against Judah, Rezin, king of Aram, and Pekah son of Remaliah.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Jotham will lie down with his fathers, and he will be buried with his fathers in the city of David his father: and Ahaz his son will reign in his stead.</verse>
</chapter>