<chapter book="Mark" number="15" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And immediately, in the morning, the chief priests having made a consultation, with the elders, and scribes, and the whole sanhedrim, having bound Jesus, did lead away, and delivered him to Pilate;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and Pilate questioned him, ‘Art thou the king of the Jews?’ and he answering said to him, ‘Thou dost say it.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the chief priests were accusing him of many things, but he answered nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Pilate again questioned him, saying, ‘Thou dost not answer anything! lo, how many things they do testify against thee!’</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Jesus did no more answer anything, so that Pilate wondered.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And at every feast he was releasing to them one prisoner, whomsoever they were asking;</verse>
  <verse number="7">and there was one named Barabbas, bound with those making insurrection with him, who had in the insurrection committed murder.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the multitude having cried out, began to ask for themselves as he was always doing to them,</verse>
  <verse number="9">and Pilate answered them, saying, ‘Will ye that I shall release to you the king of the Jews?’</verse>
  <verse number="10">for he knew that because of envy the chief priests had delivered him up;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and the chief priests did move the multitude, that he might rather release Barabbas to them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Pilate answering, again said to them, ‘What, then, will ye that I shall do to him whom ye call king of the Jews?’</verse>
  <verse number="13">and they again cried out, ‘Crucify him.’</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Pilate said to them, ‘Why—what evil did he?’ and they cried out the more vehemently, ‘Crucify him;’</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Pilate, wishing to content the multitude, released to them Barabbas, and delivered up Jesus—having scourged him—that he might be crucified.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the soldiers led him away into the hall, which is Praetorium, and call together the whole band,</verse>
  <verse number="17">and clothe him with purple, and having plaited a crown of thorns, they put it on him,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and began to salute him, ‘Hail, King of the Jews.’</verse>
  <verse number="19">And they were smiting him on the head with a reed, and were spitting on him, and having bent the knee, were bowing to him,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and when they had mocked him, they took the purple from off him, and clothed him in his own garments, and they led him forth, that they may crucify him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they impress a certain one passing by—Simon, a Cyrenian, coming from the field, the father of Alexander and Rufus—that he may bear his cross,</verse>
  <verse number="22">and they bring him to the place Golgotha, which is, being interpreted, ‘Place of a skull;’</verse>
  <verse number="23">and they were giving him to drink wine mingled with myrrh, and he did not receive.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And having crucified him, they were dividing his garments, casting a lot upon them, what each may take;</verse>
  <verse number="25">and it was the third hour, and they crucified him;</verse>
  <verse number="26">and the inscription of his accusation was written above—‘The King of the Jews.’</verse>
  <verse number="27">And with him they crucify two robbers, one on the right hand, and one on his left,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and the Writing was fulfilled that is saying, ‘And with lawless ones he was numbered.’</verse>
  <verse number="29">And those passing by were speaking evil of him, shaking their heads, and saying, ‘Ah, the thrower down of the sanctuary, and in three days the builder!</verse>
  <verse number="30">save thyself, and come down from the cross!’</verse>
  <verse number="31">And in like manner also the chief priests, mocking with one another, with the scribes, said, ‘Others he saved; himself he is not able to save.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The Christ! the king of Israel—let him come down now from the cross, that we may see and believe;’ and those crucified with him were reproaching him.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And the sixth hour having come, darkness came over the whole land till the ninth hour,</verse>
  <verse number="34">and at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a great voice, saying, ‘Eloi, Eloi, lamma sabachthani?’ which is, being interpreted, ‘My God, my God, why didst Thou forsake me?’</verse>
  <verse number="35">And certain of those standing by, having heard, said, ‘Lo, Elijah he doth call;’</verse>
  <verse number="36">and one having run, and having filled a spunge with vinegar, having put it also on a reed, was giving him to drink, saying, ‘Let alone, let us see if Elijah doth come to take him down.’</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Jesus having uttered a loud cry, yielded the spirit,</verse>
  <verse number="38">and the veil of the sanctuary was rent in two, from top to bottom,</verse>
  <verse number="39">and the centurion who was standing over-against him, having seen that, having so cried out, he yielded the spirit, said, ‘Truly this man was Son of God.’</verse>
  <verse number="40">And there were also women afar off beholding, among whom was also Mary the Magdalene, and Mary of James the less, and of Joses, and Salome,</verse>
  <verse number="41">(who also, when he was in Galilee, were following him, and were ministering to him,) and many other women who came up with him to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And now evening having come, seeing it was the preparation, that is, the fore-sabbath,</verse>
  <verse number="43">Joseph of Arimathea, an honourable counsellor, who also himself was waiting for the reign of God, came, boldly entered in unto Pilate, and asked the body of Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And Pilate wondered if he were already dead, and having called near the centurion, did question him if he were long dead,</verse>
  <verse number="45">and having known it from the centurion, he granted the body to Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And he, having brought fine linen, and having taken him down, wrapped him in the linen, and laid him in a sepulchre that had been hewn out of a rock, and he rolled a stone unto the door of the sepulchre,</verse>
  <verse number="47">and Mary the Magdalene, and Mary of Joses, were beholding where he is laid.</verse>
</chapter>