<chapter book="Numbers" number="23" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Balaam said to Balak, “Build me here seven altars, and prepare me here seven bulls and seven rams.”</verse>
  <verse number="2">Balak did as Balaam had spoken; and Balak and Balaam offered on every altar a bull and a ram.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Balaam said to Balak, “Stand by your burnt offering, and I will go: perhaps Yahweh will come to meet me; and whatever he shows me I will tell you.” He went to a bare height.</verse>
  <verse number="4">God met Balaam: and he said to him, “I have prepared the seven altars, and I have offered up a bull and a ram on every altar.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">Yahweh put a word in Balaam’s mouth, and said, “Return to Balak, and thus you shall speak.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">He returned to him, and behold, he was standing by his burnt offering, he, and all the princes of Moab.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He took up his parable, and said, “From Aram has Balak brought me, the king of Moab from the mountains of the East. Come, curse Jacob for me. Come, defy Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">How shall I curse whom God has not cursed? How shall I defy whom Yahweh has not defied?</verse>
  <verse number="9">For from the top of the rocks I see him. From the hills I see him. Behold, it is a people that dwells alone, and shall not be reckoned among the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Who can count the dust of Jacob, or number the fourth part of Israel? Let me die the death of the righteous! Let my last end be like his!”</verse>
  <verse number="11">Balak said to Balaam, “What have you done to me? I took you to curse my enemies, and behold, you have blessed them altogether.”</verse>
  <verse number="12">He answered and said, “Must I not take heed to speak that which Yahweh puts in my mouth?”</verse>
  <verse number="13">Balak said to him, “Please come with me to another place, where you may see them; you shall see but the utmost part of them, and shall not see them all: and curse me them from there.”</verse>
  <verse number="14">He took him into the field of Zophim, to the top of Pisgah, and built seven altars, and offered up a bull and a ram on every altar.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He said to Balak, “Stand here by your burnt offering, while I meet over there.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">Yahweh met Balaam, and put a word in his mouth, and said, “Return to Balak, and say this.”</verse>
  <verse number="17">He came to him, and behold, he was standing by his burnt offering, and the princes of Moab with him. Balak said to him, “What has Yahweh spoken?”</verse>
  <verse number="18">He took up his parable, and said, “Rise up, Balak, and hear! Listen to me, you son of Zippor.</verse>
  <verse number="19">God is not a man, that he should lie, nor the son of man, that he should repent. Has he said, and will he not do it? Or has he spoken, and will he not make it good?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Behold, I have received a command to bless. He has blessed, and I can’t reverse it.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He has not seen iniquity in Jacob. Neither has he seen perverseness in Israel. Yahweh his God is with him. The shout of a king is among them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">God brings them out of Egypt. He has as it were the strength of the wild ox.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Surely there is no enchantment with Jacob; Neither is there any divination with Israel. Now it shall be said of Jacob and of Israel, What has God done!</verse>
  <verse number="24">Behold, the people rises up as a lioness, As a lion he lifts himself up. He shall not lie down until he eat of the prey, and drinks the blood of the slain.”</verse>
  <verse number="25">Balak said to Balaam, “Neither curse them at all, nor bless them at all.”</verse>
  <verse number="26">But Balaam answered Balak, “Didn’t I tell you, saying, ‘All that Yahweh speaks, that I must do?’”</verse>
  <verse number="27">Balak said to Balaam, “Come now, I will take you to another place; perhaps it will please God that you may curse me them from there.”</verse>
  <verse number="28">Balak took Balaam to the top of Peor, that looks down on the desert.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Balaam said to Balak, “Build me here seven altars, and prepare me here seven bulls and seven rams.”</verse>
  <verse number="30">Balak did as Balaam had said, and offered up a bull and a ram on every altar.</verse>
</chapter>