<chapter book="Isaiah" number="8" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the LORD said to me, “Take a large scroll and write on it with an ordinary stylus: Maher-shalal-hash-baz.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I will appoint for Myself trustworthy witnesses—Uriah the priest and Zechariah son of Jeberekiah.”</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I had relations with the prophetess, and she conceived and gave birth to a son. The LORD said to me, “Name him Maher-shalal-hash-baz.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For before the boy knows how to cry ‘Father’ or ‘Mother,’ the wealth of Damascus and the plunder of Samaria will be carried off by the king of Assyria.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the LORD spoke to me further:</verse>
  <verse number="6">“Because this people has rejected the gently flowing waters of Shiloah and rejoiced in Rezin and the son of Remaliah,</verse>
  <verse number="7">the Lord will surely bring against them the mighty floodwaters of the Euphrates—the king of Assyria and all his pomp. It will overflow its channels and overrun its banks.</verse>
  <verse number="8">It will pour into Judah, swirling and sweeping over it, reaching up to the neck; its spreading streams will cover your entire land, O Immanuel!</verse>
  <verse number="9">Huddle together, O peoples, and be shattered; pay attention, all you distant lands; prepare for battle, and be shattered; prepare for battle, and be shattered!</verse>
  <verse number="10">Devise a plan, but it will be thwarted; state a proposal, but it will not happen. For God is with us.”</verse>
  <verse number="11">For this is what the LORD has spoken to me with a strong hand, instructing me not to walk in the way of this people:</verse>
  <verse number="12">“Do not call conspiracy everything these people regard as conspiracy. Do not fear what they fear; do not live in dread.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The LORD of Hosts is the One you shall regard as holy. Only He should be feared; only He should be dreaded.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And He will be a sanctuary—but to both houses of Israel a stone of stumbling and a rock of offense, to the dwellers of Jerusalem a trap and a snare.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Many will stumble over these; they will fall and be broken; they will be ensnared and captured.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">Bind up the testimony and seal the law among my disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I will wait for the LORD, who is hiding His face from the house of Jacob. I will put my trust in Him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Here am I, and the children the LORD has given me as signs and symbols in Israel from the LORD of Hosts, who dwells on Mount Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="19">When men tell you to consult mediums and spiritists who whisper and mutter, shouldn’t a people consult their God instead? Why consult the dead on behalf of the living?</verse>
  <verse number="20">To the law and to the testimony! If they do not speak according to this word, they have no light of dawn.</verse>
  <verse number="21">They will roam the land, dejected and hungry. When they are famished, they will become enraged; and looking upward, they will curse their king and their God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then they will look to the earth and see only distress and darkness and the gloom of anguish. And they will be driven into utter darkness.</verse>
</chapter>