<chapter book="2 John" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The elder to the chosen mistress in truth; (and not I only, but also all and to her children, whom I love they having known the truth;)</verse>
  <verse number="2">For the truth remaining in us, and shall be with us forever.</verse>
  <verse number="3">There shall be with you grace, mercy, peace, from God the Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of the Father, in truth, and love.</verse>
  <verse number="4">I was greatly rejoiced that I found of thy children walking about in the truth, as we received a command from the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And now I entreat thee, mistress, not as writing a new command, but what we had from the beginning, that we should love one another.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And this is love, that we walk about according to his commands. This is the command, That as ye heard from the beginning, ye should walk in it.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For many cheats come into the world, they not acknowledging Jesus Christ coming in the flesh. This is the cheat and antichrist.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Look to yourselves, lest we should destroy what things we have wrought, but we should receive a full reward.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Every one passing by, and not remaining in the teaching of Christ, has not God. He remaining in the teaching of Christ, the same also has the Father and the Son.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If there come any to you, and bring not this teaching, receive ye him not into the household, and to rejoice tell him not:</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he telling him to rejoice, partakes of his evil works.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Having many things to write to you, I was not willing by paper and ink: but I hope to come to you, and to speak mouth to month, that our joy might be filled up.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The children of thy chosen sister greet thee. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>