<chapter book="Romans" number="12" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I BESEECH you therefore, brethren, by the mercy of God, that you present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, pleasing unto God, your reasonable service.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And be not conformed to this world; but be reformed in the newness of your mind, that you may prove what is the good, and the acceptable, and the perfect will of God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For I say, by the grace that is given me, to all that are among you, not to be more wise than it behoveth to be wise, but to be wise unto sobriety, and according as God hath divided to every one the measure of faith.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For as in one body we have many members, but all the members have not the same office:</verse>
  <verse number="5">So we being many, are one body in Christ, and every one members one of another.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And having different gifts, according to the grace that is given us, either prophecy, to be used according to the rule of faith;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Or ministry, in ministering; or he that teacheth, in doctrine;</verse>
  <verse number="8">He that exhorteth, in exhorting; he that giveth, with simplicity; he that ruleth, with carefulness; he that sheweth mercy, with cheerfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Let love be without dissimulation. Hating that which is evil, cleaving to that which is good.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Loving one another with the charity of brotherhood, with honour preventing one another.</verse>
  <verse number="11">In carefulness not slothful. In spirit fervent. Serving the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Rejoicing in hope. Patient in tribulation. Instant in prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Communicating to the necessities of the saints. Pursuing hospitality.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Bless them that persecute you: bless, and curse not.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Rejoice with them that rejoice; weep with them that weep.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Being of one mind one towards another. Not minding high things, but consenting to the humble. Be not wise in your own conceits.</verse>
  <verse number="17">To no man rendering evil for evil. Providing good things, not only in the sight of God, but also in the sight of all men.</verse>
  <verse number="18">If it be possible, as much as is in you, have peace with all men.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Revenge not yourselves, my dearly beloved; but give place unto wrath, for it is written: Revenge is mine, I will repay, saith the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But if thy enemy be hungry, give him to eat; if he thirst, give him to drink. For, doing this, thou shalt heap coals of fire upon his head.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Be not overcome by evil, but overcome evil by good.</verse>
</chapter>