<chapter book="Philippians" number="2" translation="Webster Bible Translation" translationID="wbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">If there is therefore any consolation in Christ, if any comfort of love, if any fellowship of the Spirit, if any bowels and mercies,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Fulfill ye my joy, that ye be like-minded, having the same love, being of one accord, of one mind.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let nothing be done through strife or vain glory; but in lowliness of mind let each esteem other better than themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Look not every man on his own things, but every man also on the things of others.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ Jesus:</verse>
  <verse number="6">Who, being in the form of God, thought it not robbery to be equal with God:</verse>
  <verse number="7">But made himself of no reputation, and took upon him the form of a servant, and was made in the likeness of men:</verse>
  <verse number="8">And being found in fashion as a man, he humbled himself, and became obedient to death, even the death of the cross.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Wherefore God also hath highly exalted him, and given him a name which is above every name:</verse>
  <verse number="10">That at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, of things in heaven, and things on earth, and things under the earth;</verse>
  <verse number="11">And that every tongue should confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wherefore, my beloved, as ye have always obeyed, not as in my presence only, but now much more in my absence, work out your own salvation with fear and trembling.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For it is God who worketh in you both to will and to do of his good pleasure.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Do all things without murmurings and disputings:</verse>
  <verse number="15">That ye may be blameless and harmless, the sons of God, without rebuke, in the midst of a crooked and perverse nation, among whom ye shine as lights in the world;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Holding forth the word of life; that I may rejoice in the day of Christ, that I have not run in vain, neither labored in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And if I am even offered upon the sacrifice and service of your faith, I joy, and rejoice with you all.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the same cause also do ye joy, and rejoice with me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But I trust in the Lord Jesus to send Timothy shortly to you, that I also may be of good comfort, when I know your state.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I have no man like-minded, who will naturally care for your state.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For all seek their own, not the things of Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But ye know the proof of him, that as a son with the father, he hath served with me in the gospel.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Him therefore I hope to send presently, so soon as I shall see how it will go with me.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But I trust in the Lord that I also myself shall come shortly.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Yet I supposed it necessary to send to you Epaphroditus, my brother, and companion in labor, and fellow-soldier, but your messenger, and he that ministered to my wants.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For he longed after you all, and was full of heaviness, because ye had heard that he was sick.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For indeed he was sick nigh to death: but God had mercy on him; and not on him only, but on me also, lest I should have sorrow upon sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I sent him therefore the more speedily, that, when ye see him again, ye may rejoice, and that I may be the less sorrowful.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Receive him therefore in the Lord with all gladness; and hold such in reputation:</verse>
  <verse number="30">Because for the work of Christ he was nigh to death, not regarding his life, to supply the want of your service towards me.</verse>
</chapter>