<chapter book="Philippians" number="4" translation="Webster Bible Translation" translationID="wbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Therefore, my brethren dearly beloved and longed for, my joy and crown, so stand fast in the Lord, my dearly beloved.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I beseech Euodias, and beseech Syntyche, that they be of the same mind in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I entreat thee also, true yoke-fellow, help those women who labored with me in the gospel, with Clement also, and with other my fellow-laborers, whose names are in the book of life.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Rejoice in the Lord always: and again I say, Rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Let your moderation be known to all men. The Lord is at hand.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Be anxious for nothing; but in every thing by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the peace of God, which passeth all understanding, will keep your hearts and minds through Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Finally, brethren, whatever things are true, whatever things are honest, whatever things are just, whatever things are pure, whatever things are lovely, whatever things are of good report; if there is any virtue, and if there is any praise, think on these things.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Those things, which ye have both learned, and received, and heard, and seen in me, do: and the God of peace will be with you.</verse>
  <verse number="10">But I rejoiced in the Lord greatly, that now at the last your care of me hath flourished again; wherein ye were also careful, but ye lacked opportunity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Not that I speak in respect of want: for I have learned, in whatever state I am, with that to be content.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I know both how to be abased, and I know how to abound: every where and in all things I am instructed both to be full and to be hungry, both to abound and to suffer need.</verse>
  <verse number="13">I can do all things through Christ who strengtheneth me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Notwithstanding ye have done well, that ye did communicate with my affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Now, ye Philippians, know also, that in the beginning of the gospel, when I departed from Macedonia, no church communicated with me as concerning giving and receiving, but ye only.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For even in Thessalonica ye sent once and again to my necessity.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Not because I desire a gift: but I desire fruit that may abound to your account.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But I have all, and abound: I am full, having received from Epaphroditus the things which were sent from you, an odor of a sweet smell, a sacrifice acceptable, well-pleasing to God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But my God will supply all your need according to his riches in glory by Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Now to God and our Father be glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Salute every saint in Christ Jesus. The brethren who are with me greet you.</verse>
  <verse number="22">All the saints salute you, chiefly they that are of Cesar’s household.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you all. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>