<chapter book="John" number="5" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After this there was a Festival of the Jews, and Jesus went up to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Now there is in Jerusalem near the Sheep Gate a pool, called in Hebrew ‘Bethesda.’ It has five arcades.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In these there used to lie a great number of sick persons, and of people who were blind or lame or paralyzed.</verse>
  <verse number="4"></verse>
  <verse number="5">And there was one man there who had been an invalid for thirty-eight years.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Jesus saw him lying there, and knowing that he had been a long time in that condition, He asked him, “Do you wish to have health and strength?”</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Sir,” replied the sufferer, “I have no one to put me into the pool when the water is moved; but while I am coming some one else steps down before me.”</verse>
  <verse number="8">“Rise,” said Jesus, “take up your mat and walk.”</verse>
  <verse number="9">Instantly the man was restored to perfect health, and he took up his mat and began to walk.</verse>
  <verse number="10">That day was a Sabbath. So the Jews said to the man who had been cured, “It is the Sabbath: you must not carry your mat.”</verse>
  <verse number="11">“He who cured me,” he replied, “said to me, ‘Take up your mat and walk.’”</verse>
  <verse number="12">“Who is it,” they asked, “that said to you, ‘Take up your mat and walk’?”</verse>
  <verse number="13">But the man who had been cured did not know who it was; for Jesus had passed out unnoticed, there being a crowd in the place.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Afterwards Jesus found him in the Temple and said to him, “You are now restored to health. Do not sin any more, or a worse thing may befall you.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">The man went and told the Jews that it was Jesus who had restored him to health;</verse>
  <verse number="16">and on this account the Jews began to persecute Jesus—because He did these things on the Sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His reply to their accusation was, “My Father works unceasingly, and so do I.”</verse>
  <verse number="18">On this account then the Jews were all the more eager to put Him to death—because He not only broke the Sabbath, but also spoke of God as being in a special sense His Father, thus putting Himself on a level with God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">“In most solemn truth I tell you,” replied Jesus, “that the Son can do nothing of Himself—He can only do what He sees the Father doing; for whatever He does, that the Son does in like manner.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For the Father loves the Son and reveals to Him all that He Himself is doing. And greater deeds than these will He reveal to Him, in order that you may wonder.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For just as the Father awakens the dead and gives them life, so the Son also gives life to whom He wills.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The Father indeed does not judge any one, but He has entrusted all judgement to the Son,</verse>
  <verse number="23">that all may honour the Son even as they honour the Father. The man who withholds honour from the Son withholds honour from the Father who sent Him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">“In most solemn truth I tell you that he who listens to my teaching and believes Him who sent me, has the Life of the Ages, and does not come under judgement, but has passed over out of death into Life.</verse>
  <verse number="25">“In most solemn truth I tell you that a time is coming—nay, has already come—when the dead will hear the voice of the Son of God, and those who hear it will live.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For just as the Father has life in Himself, so He has also given to the Son to have life in Himself.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And He has conferred on Him authority to act as Judge, because He is the Son of Man.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Wonder not at this. For a time is coming when all who are in the graves will hear His voice and will come forth—</verse>
  <verse number="29">they who have done what is right to the resurrection of Life, and they whose actions have been evil to the resurrection of judgement.</verse>
  <verse number="30">“I can of my own self do nothing. As I am bidden, so I judge; and mine is a just judgement, because it is not my own will that guides me, but the will of Him who sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="31">“If I give testimony concerning myself, my testimony cannot be accepted.</verse>
  <verse number="32">There is Another who gives testimony concerning me, and I know that the testimony is true which He offers concerning me.</verse>
  <verse number="33">“You sent to John, and he both was and still is a witness to the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="34">But the testimony on my behalf which I accept is not from man; though I say all this in order that you may be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He was the lamp that burned and shone, and for a time you were willing to be gladdened by his light.</verse>
  <verse number="36">“But the testimony which I have is weightier than that of John; for the work the Father has assigned to me for me to bring it to completion—the very work which I am doing—affords testimony concerning me that the Father has sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And the Father who sent me, *He* has given testimony concerning me. None of you have ever either heard His voice or seen what He is like.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Nor have you His word dwelling within you, for you refuse to believe Him whom *He* has sent.</verse>
  <verse number="39">“You search the Scriptures, because you suppose that in them you will find the Life of the Ages; and it is those Scriptures that yield testimony concerning me;</verse>
  <verse number="40">and yet you are unwilling to come to me that you may have Life.</verse>
  <verse number="41">“I do not accept glory from man,</verse>
  <verse number="42">but I know you well, and I know that in your hearts you do not really love God.</verse>
  <verse number="43">I have come as my Father’s representative, and you do not receive me. If some one else comes representing only himself, him you will receive.</verse>
  <verse number="44">How is it possible for you to believe, while you receive glory from one another and have no desire for the glory that comes from the only God?</verse>
  <verse number="45">“Do not suppose that I will accuse you to the Father. There is one who accuses you, namely Moses, on whom your hope rests.</verse>
  <verse number="46">For if you believe Moses, you would believe me; for he wrote about me.</verse>
  <verse number="47">But if you disbelieve his writings, how are you to believe my words?”</verse>
</chapter>