<chapter book="Proverbs" number="10" translation="King James Bible" translationID="kjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The proverbs of Solomon. A wise son maketh a glad father: but a foolish son [is] the heaviness of his mother.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Treasures of wickedness profit nothing: but righteousness delivereth from death.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The LORD will not suffer the soul of the righteous to famish: but he casteth away the substance of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He becometh poor that dealeth [with] a slack hand: but the hand of the diligent maketh rich.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He that gathereth in summer [is] a wise son: [but] he that sleepeth in harvest [is] a son that causeth shame.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Blessings [are] upon the head of the just: but violence covereth the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The memory of the just [is] blessed: but the name of the wicked shall rot.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The wise in heart will receive commandments: but a prating fool shall fall.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He that walketh uprightly walketh surely: but he that perverteth his ways shall be known.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He that winketh with the eye causeth sorrow: but a prating fool shall fall.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The mouth of a righteous [man is] a well of life: but violence covereth the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Hatred stirreth up strifes: but love covereth all sins.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In the lips of him that hath understanding wisdom is found: but a rod [is] for the back of him that is void of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Wise [men] lay up knowledge: but the mouth of the foolish [is] near destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The rich man’s wealth [is] his strong city: the destruction of the poor [is] their poverty.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The labour of the righteous [tendeth] to life: the fruit of the wicked to sin.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He [is in] the way of life that keepeth instruction: but he that refuseth reproof erreth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He that hideth hatred [with] lying lips, and he that uttereth a slander, [is] a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="19">In the multitude of words there wanteth not sin: but he that refraineth his lips [is] wise.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The tongue of the just [is as] choice silver: the heart of the wicked [is] little worth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The lips of the righteous feed many: but fools die for want of wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The blessing of the LORD, it maketh rich, and he addeth no sorrow with it.</verse>
  <verse number="23">[It is] as sport to a fool to do mischief: but a man of understanding hath wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The fear of the wicked, it shall come upon him: but the desire of the righteous shall be granted.</verse>
  <verse number="25">As the whirlwind passeth, so [is] the wicked no [more]: but the righteous [is] an everlasting foundation.</verse>
  <verse number="26">As vinegar to the teeth, and as smoke to the eyes, so [is] the sluggard to them that send him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The fear of the LORD prolongeth days: but the years of the wicked shall be shortened.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The hope of the righteous [shall be] gladness: but the expectation of the wicked shall perish.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The way of the LORD [is] strength to the upright: but destruction [shall be] to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The righteous shall never be removed: but the wicked shall not inhabit the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The mouth of the just bringeth forth wisdom: but the froward tongue shall be cut out.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The lips of the righteous know what is acceptable: but the mouth of the wicked [speaketh] frowardness.</verse>
</chapter>