<chapter book="Luke" number="13" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And certain were present in that time announcing to him of the Galileans, whose blood Pilate mingled with their sacrifices.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Jesus having answered, said to them, Think ye that these Galileans were sinful above all the Galileans, because they have suffered such things?</verse>
  <verse number="3">No, I say to you: but except ye should change the mind, ye shall all likewise perish.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Or those eighteen, upon whom the tower in Siloam fell, and killed them, think ye that these were debtors above all men dwelling in Jerusalem?</verse>
  <verse number="5">No, I say: but except ye repent, ye shall all likewise perish.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And he spake this parable: A certain had a fig tree planted in his vineyard; and he came seeking fruit on it, and found not.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And he said to the vine-dresser, Behold, three years I am come seeking fruit on this fig tree, and find not: cut it off; wherefore also does it leave the earth unemployed?</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he having answered says to him, Lord, let it go also this year, till I shall dig round it, and cast dung:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whereas also it might bear fruit: and if not, afterwards thou shalt cut it off.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And he was teaching in one of the assemblies in the sabbaths.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And, behold, there was a woman having a spirit of weakness eighteen years, and was bent together, and not able wholly to lift up the head.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And having seen her, Jesus called to, and said to her, Woman, thou hast been loosed from thy weakness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he put his hands on her: and immediately she was set upright, and honoured God.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the ruler of the assembly having answered, feeling pain because Jesus cured on the sabbath, said to the crowd, Six days there are in which they ought to work; in those therefore, coming, be ye cured, and not the day of the sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Then answered the Lord and said, Hypocrite, does not each of you on the sabbath loose his ox or ass from the stall, and leading away, give to drink?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And this being a daughter of Abraham, whom Satan has bound, behold, eighteen years, ought she not to be loosed from this bond the day of the sabbath</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he saying these things, all opposed to him were ashamed: and the crowd rejoiced for all the glorious things done by him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he said, To what is the kingdom of God like? and to what shall I liken it?</verse>
  <verse number="19">It is like a kernel of mustard, which a man having taken, cast into his garden; and it grew, and became into a great tree; and the fowls of heaven encamped in its young shoots.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And again he said, To what shall I liken the kingdom of God?</verse>
  <verse number="21">It is like leaven, which a woman having taken, hid in three measures of wheaten flour, until the whole was leavened.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he went through cities and towns, teaching, and making his passage to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And a certain said to him, Lord, if few saved? And he said to them,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Strive earnestly to enter through the narrow gate: for many, I say to you, shall seek to enter in, and shall not be able.</verse>
  <verse number="25">From the time when the master of the house should rise up, and shut the door, and ye begin to stand without, and knock at the door, saying, Lord, Lord, open to us: and having answered, he will say to you, I know not whence ye are:</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then will ye begin to say, We ate and drank before thee, and thou didst teach in our streets.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he will say, I say to you, I know you not whence ye are; depart from me, all ye workmen of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Weeping shall be there and gnashing of teeth, when ye see Abraham, and Isaac, and Jacob, and all the prophets, in the kingdom of God, and you cast without.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And they shall come from the risings, and the settings, and from north, and south, and they shall recline in the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And, behold, there are last which shall be first, and there are first which shall be last.</verse>
  <verse number="31">In the same day certain Pharisees came near, saying to him, Come out, and go from thence: for Herod wishes to kill thee.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And he said to them, Having gone, say to that fox, Behold, I cast out demons, and complete cures to day and to morrow, and the third day I am completed.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But I must go to day and to morrow and the following: for it is not possible for a prophet to perish out of Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Jerusalem, Jerusalem, killing the prophets, and striking with stones those having been sent to her; how often I wished to gather thy children together, which manner a hen her young brood under the wings, and ye would not!</verse>
  <verse number="35">Behold, your house is left to you a desert: and truly I say to you, That ye should not see me, until it should come when ye say, Praised he coming in the name of the Lord.</verse>
</chapter>