<chapter book="Luke" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And all publicans and sinful were drawing near him to hear him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the Pharisees and scribes murmured, saying, That this receives the sinful, and eats together with them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he spake this parable to them, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="4">What man of you, having one hundred sheep, and having lost one of them, leaves not the ninety-nine in the desert, and goes for the one lost, till he find it.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And having found, he puts upon his shoulders, rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And having come into the house, he calls together friends and neighbors, saying to them, Rejoice with me: for I have found my lost sheep.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I say to you, that so shall joy be in heaven over one sinful repenting, more than over ninety-nine just, which have no need of repentance.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Or what woman having ten drachmas, if she lose one drachma, lights not a lamp, and sweeps the house, and seeks diligently till she should find?</verse>
  <verse number="9">And having found, she calls together female friends and neighbors, saying, Rejoice with me; for I found the drachma which I lost.</verse>
  <verse number="10">So, I say to you, joy is in heaven before the messengers of God for one sinful changing the mind.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he said, A certain man had two sons:</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the younger of them said to the father, Father, give me the portion of property falling. And he divided to them the property.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And not many days after, having gathered all things, the younger son went abroad into a far off country, and there disposed his property, living in a profligate manner.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And having spent all things, a powerful famine was in that country; and he began to be in want.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And having gone, he was joined to one of the citizens of that country; and he sent him into the fields to feed swine.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he eagerly desired to fill his belly with the fruits of the horntree which the swine ate: and none gave to him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And having come to himself, he said, Many hired of my father abound in loaves, and I am perishing with hunger!</verse>
  <verse number="18">Having risen, I will go to my father, and say to him, Father, I have sinned against heaven, and before thee,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And I am no more worthy to be called thy son: make me as one of thy hired.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And having risen, he came to his father. And yet being far off, his father saw him, and felt compassion, and having run, fell upon his neck, and kissed him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the son said to him, Father, I sinned against heaven, and before thee, and I am no more worthy to be called thy son.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the father said to his servants, Bring out the first robe, and clothe him; and give a ring for his hand, and shoes for the feet:</verse>
  <verse number="23">And having brought the fatted calf, sacrifice, and eating, let us be gladdened.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For this my son was dead, and has returned to life; and he was lost, and found. And they began to be gladdened.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And his elder son was in the field: and coming, as he drew near the house, he heard a concert of music, and dances.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And having called one of his servants, he inquired what these may be.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he said to him, That thy brother has come, and thy father has sacrificed the fatted calf; because he received him in good health.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he was angry and would not go in; then his father having come out, besought him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And he having answered said to the father, Behold, so many years I serve thee, and never at any time passed by thy command: and never hast thou given me a kid, that I might be gladdened with my friends.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And when this thy son, devouring thy property with harlots, came, thou hast sacrificed for him the fattened calf.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And he said to him, Child, thou art always with me, and all mine are thine.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And to be gladdened, and to rejoice, was fitting: for this thy brother was dead, and has returned to life; and he was lost, and found.</verse>
</chapter>