<chapter book="Luke" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it was in those days an order came out from Caesar Angustus, for the whole habitable globe to be enrolled.</verse>
  <verse number="2">(This enrolling was first, Cyrenius being leader of Syria.)</verse>
  <verse number="3">And all went to be enrolled, each in his own city.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Joseph also went up from Galilee, out of the city of Nazareth, into Judea, to the city of David, which is called Bethlehem; (for he was of the house and family of David:)</verse>
  <verse number="5">To be enrolled with Mary his betrothed wife, being pregnant.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And it was in their being there, the days were completed for her to bring forth.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And she brought forth her firstborn son, and swathed him, and put him in a manger; for there was no place for them in the inn.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And shepherds were in the country, sleeping in the fields, and watching over their flock the watches of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And, behold, a messenger of the Lord stood before them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them: and they fear a great fear.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the messenger said to them, Fear not: for, behold, I announce you good news, great joy, which shall be to all people.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For this day a Saviour was born to you, who is Christ the Lord, in the city of David.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And this the sign to you; ye shall find the babe swathed, lying in a manger.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And suddenly was there a multitude with the messenger of the heavenly army praising God, and saying,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Glory to God in the highest ones, and upon earth peace, benevolence in men.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And it was when the messenger departed from them into heaven, and the men, the shepherds, said to one another, Let us pass through now to Bethlehem, and see this word done, which the Lord made known to us.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And having hastened, they came and found both Mary, and Joseph, and the babe lying in a manger.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And having seen, they made known concerning the word spoken to them about the child.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And all having heard wondered at the things spoken to them by the shepherds.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Mary kept together all these sayings, reflecting in her heart.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the shepherds returned, honouring and praising God for all which they heard and saw, as was spoken to them.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And when eight days were completed for circumcising the child and his name was called JESUS, called by the messenger before he was conceived in the womb.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And when the days of her cleansing were completed, according to the law of Moses, they brought him to Jerusalem to present to the Lord;</verse>
  <verse number="23">(As has been written in the law of the Lord, That every male opening the womb shall be called holy to the Lord;)</verse>
  <verse number="24">And to give a sacrifice according to that said in the law of the Lord, A pair of turtle-doves, or two of the young of pigeons.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And, behold, a man was in Jerusalem, the name to him Simeon; and this man just and cautious, waiting the consolation of Israel: and the Holy Spirit was upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And it was intimated to him by the Holy Spirit, not to see death, before he should see the Christ of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he came in the Spirit to the temple: and in the parents bringing in the child Jesus, for them to do according to the custom of the law for him,</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he took him into his arms, and praised God, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="29">Now Lord, thou wilt loose thy servant, according to thy word, in peace:</verse>
  <verse number="30">For mine eyes have seen thy salvation,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Which thou hast prepared before the face of all peoples:</verse>
  <verse number="32">A light for the revelation of the nations, and the glory of thy people Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Joseph and his mother were wondering at the things spoken of him.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Simeon praised them, and said to Mary his mother, Behold, he is laid for the fall and rising up of many in Israel; and for a sign spoken against;</verse>
  <verse number="35">(And also a spear shall pass through the soul of thyself,) so that the reasonings from many hearts might be revealed.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Anna was a prophetess, daughter of Phanuel, of the tribe of Aser: she advanced in many days, having lived with a husband seven years from her virginity;</verse>
  <verse number="37">And she a widow of about eighty-four years, who departed not from the temple, with fastings and supplications serving night and day.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And she having stood at that hour, confessed to the Lord, and spake concerning him to all awaiting redemption in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And when they finished all things according to the law of the Lord, they returned into Galilee to their city, Nazareth.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the child grew, and was strengthened in spirit, being filled with wisdom: and the grace of God was upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And his parents went every year to Jerusalem to the festival of the passover.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And when he was of twelve years, they having gone up to Jerusalem according to the custom of the festival:</verse>
  <verse number="43">And having completed the days, in their returning the child Jesus remained in Jerusalem; and Joseph and his mother knew not.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And they, having supposed him to be in the caravan, came the way of a day, and sought him among kinsmen and among acquaintances.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And not having found him, they returned to Jerusalem, seeking him.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And it was after three days they found him in the temple, sitting in the midst of teachers, and hearing them, and inquiring of them.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And all hearing him were affected in mind at his understanding and answers.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And having seen him, they were struck with awe: and his mother said to him, Child, why didst thou so to us? behold, thy father and I, grieving, have sought thee.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And he said to them, For what have ye sought me? knew ye not that among the things of my Father I must be?</verse>
  <verse number="50">And they understood not the word which he spake to them.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And he went down with them, and came to Nazareth, and was placed under them: and his mother kept all these words in her heart.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And Jesus advanced in wisdom and age, and in grace with God and man.</verse>
</chapter>