<chapter book="Luke" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And in one of the sabbaths, in the depth of the dawn of day, they came to the tomb, bringing spices which they had prepared, and certain with them.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And they found the stone rolled away from the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And coming in, they found not the body of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And it was in their being perplexed for this, and, behold, two men stood by them in shining garments:</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they having, been afraid, and bending the face to the earth, they said to them, Why seek ye the living with the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He is not here, but has risen: remember how he spake to you being yet in Galilee,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Saying, That the Son of man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men, and be crucified, and be raised up the third day.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they remembered his words,</verse>
  <verse number="9">And having returned from the tomb, they announced these things to the eleven, and to all the rest.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they were Mary Magdalene, and Joanna, and Mary of James, and the rest with them, who said these things to the sent.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And their words appeared before them as idle talk, and they believed them not.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Peter having risen, ran to the tomb; and having stooped, saw the linen bandages lying alone, and he departed, wondering in himself at what was done.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And, behold, two of them were going in the same day to a town being about sixty stadia from Jerusalem, the name of which Emmaus.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they were conversing with one another concerning all things having happened.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And it was in their conversing and seeking out together, and Jesus himself, having drawn near, went with them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And their eyes were holden not to know him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he said to them, What words these which, walking about, ye discuss with one another, and are of gloomy aspect?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And one having answered, to whom the name Cleopas, said to him, Sojournest thou alone in Jerusalem, and knowest not the things done in it in these days?</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Jesus said to them, What things? And they said to him, The things concerning Jesus the Nazarite, who was a man, a prophet, powerful in work and words before God and all the people:</verse>
  <verse number="20">And how the chief priests and our rulers delivered him to the judgment of death, and crucified him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And we hoped that this is he about to redeem Israel: but also with all these things, to day it brings the third day from which these things were.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And also certain women of ours moved us out of place, having been early at the tomb;</verse>
  <verse number="23">And not finding his body, they came, saying also to have seen a vision of messengers, who say he is living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And certain of them with us departed to the tomb, and found so as the women said: and him they saw not.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he said to them, O ye unwise, and slow in heart to believe in all things which the prophets spake:</verse>
  <verse number="26">Must not Christ suffer these things, and enter into his glory?</verse>
  <verse number="27">And having begun from Moses and from all the prophets, he explained clearly to them in all the writings concerning himself.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they drew near to the town where they were going: and he laid claim to go still further.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And they constrained him, saying, Remain with us: for it is near eve, and the day has declined. And he went in to remain with them.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And it was in his reclining at table with them, having taken bread, he praised, and having broken, bestowed upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And their eyes were opened, and they knew him; and he was removed from their view.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they said to one another, Was not our heart burning in us, as he spake to us in the way, and as he opened the writings to us.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And having risen the same hour, they returned to Jerusalem, and found the eleven gathered together, and those with them.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Saying, That truly the Lord was risen, and was seen to Simon.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And they recounted the things in the way, and how he was known to them in the breaking of bread.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And they speaking these things, Jesus himself stood in the midst of them, and he says to them, Peace to you.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And they, struck with awe and being afraid, thought to see a spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And he said to them, Why have ye been troubled? and wherefore do reflections come up in your hearts?</verse>
  <verse number="39">See my hands and my feet, for I am he; feel, and see: for a spirit has not flesh and bones, as ye see me having.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And having said this, he showed them hands and feet.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And yet they not believing from joy, and wondering, he said to them, Have ye any food here?</verse>
  <verse number="42">And they bestowed upon him part of a broiled fish, and of an honey comb.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And having taken, he ate before them.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And he said to them, These the words which I spake to you, being yet with you, for all things must be completed, written in the law of Moses, and in the prophets, and in the Psalms, concerning me.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then opened he their understanding, to understand the writings,</verse>
  <verse number="46">And he said to them, That so has it been written, and so was it necessary for Christ to suffer, and to rise from the dead the third day:</verse>
  <verse number="47">And repentance and remission of sins to be proclaimed in his name to all nations, having begun from Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And ye are witnesses of these things.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And, behold, I send the solemn promise of my Father upon you: and do ye sit in the city of Jerusalem, till ye be clothed with power from on high.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And he led them without, even to Bethany, and having lifted up his hands, he praised them.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And it was in his praising them, he was separated from them, and carried into heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And they having worshipped him, returned to Jerusalem with great joy.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And they were always in the temple, praising and extolling God. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>