<chapter book="Hosea" number="12" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Ephraim feedeth on wind, and pursueth after the east wind: all day long he multiplieth lies and desolation; and they make a covenant with Assyria, and oil is carried into Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Jehovah hath also a controversy with Judah, and he will punish Jacob according to his ways; according to his doings will he recompense him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He took his brother by the heel in the womb, and in his strength he wrestled with God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Yea, he wrestled with the Angel, and prevailed; he wept, and made supplication unto him: he found him in Bethel, and there he spoke with us,</verse>
  <verse number="5">—even Jehovah, the God of hosts,—Jehovah is his memorial.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And thou, return unto thy God: keep loving-kindness and judgment, and wait on thy God continually.</verse>
  <verse number="7">[He is] a merchant, balances of deceit are in his hand; he loveth to oppress.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Ephraim saith, Nevertheless I am become rich, I have found me out substance; in all my labours they shall find none iniquity in me that were sin.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But I [that am] Jehovah thy God from the land of Egypt will again make thee to dwell in tents, as in the days of the solemn feast.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And I have spoken to the prophets, and I have multiplied visions, and by means of the prophets have I used similitudes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If Gilead is iniquity, surely they are but vanity: they sacrifice bullocks in Gilgal; yea, their altars are as heaps in the furrows of the fields.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Jacob fled into the country of Syria, and Israel served for a wife, and for a wife he kept [sheep].</verse>
  <verse number="13">And by a prophet Jehovah brought Israel out of Egypt, and by a prophet was he preserved.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Ephraim provoked [him] to anger most bitterly; and his Lord shall leave his blood upon him, and recompense unto him his reproach.</verse>
</chapter>