<chapter book="Joshua" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the lot shall be to the tribe of the sons of Judah according to their families, to the bound of Edom, the desert of Zin south from the south extremity.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the south bound shall be to them from the extremity of the salt sea from the tongue turning south.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And it went out to the south to the ascent of Akrabbim, and it passed over Zin and went up from the south to Kadesh-Barnea, and passed by Hezron and went up to Adar and encompassed Karkaa.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And it passed through Azmon, and it went out to the torrent of Egypt; and the going forth of the bound was to the sea: this shall be to you the south bound.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the east bound, the salt sea, unto the end of Jordan: and the bound to the north side, from the tongue of the sea from the extremity of Jordan:</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the bound went up to the house of Hoglah, and passed over from the north of the house of Arabah; and the bound went up to the stone of Bohan, son of Reuben:</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the bound went up to Debir from the valley of Achor, and north turned to Gilgal which is before the going up of Adummim, which is from the south of the torrent: and the bound passed over to the water of the fountain of the Sun, and its going forth to the fountain of Rogel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the bound went up to the valley of the son of Hinnom to the shoulder of the Jebusite from the south; this is Jerusalem: and the bound went up to the head of the mountain which is upon the face of the valley of Hinnom to the sea, which is in the end of the valley of Rephaim to the north:</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the bound extended from the head of the mountain to the fountain of water of Nephtoah, and it went out to the city of mount Ephron; and the bound extended to Baalah; this is Kirjath-Jearim:</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the bound encompassed from Baalah to the sea to mount Seir, and passed over to the shoulder of Jearim from the north (this is Chesalon) and it went down to the House of the Sun, and passed over to Timnah:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the bound went forth to the shoulder of Ekron north: and the bound extended to Shicron, and passed over to mount Baalah and went forth to Jabneel; and the goings out of the bound were to the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the bound of the sea, the great sea: and this bound the bound of the sons of Judah round about according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And to Caleb son of Jephunneh he gave a portion in the midst of the sons of Judah, according to the mouth of Jehovah to Joshua, the city of Arba the father of Anak, this is Hebron.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Caleb drove from thence the three sons of Anak, Sheshai, and Ahiman and Talmai, children of Anak.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he will go up from thence to the inhabitants of Debir: and the name of Debir before, the City of the Book.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Caleb will say, Who will smite the City of the Book and take it, and I gave to him Achsah my daughter for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Othniel, son of Kenaz will take it, the brother of Caleb, and he will give to him Achsah his daughter for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And it will be in her going forth she will stimulate him to ask from her father a field: and she will descend from the ass, and Caleb will say to her, What to thee?</verse>
  <verse number="19">And she will say, Thou wilt give to me a blessing; for a south land thou gavest me, and give to me springs of water: and he will give to her the springs above and the springs beneath.</verse>
  <verse number="20">This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Judah according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the cities from the extremity to the tribe of the sons of Judah, to the bound of Edom in the south, will be Kabzeel and Eder, and Jagur,</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Kinah and Dinonah and Adadah,</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Kedesh and Hazor and Ithnan,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Ziph and Telem and Bealoth,</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Hazor, Hadattah, and the city of Hezron (this is Hazor),</verse>
  <verse number="26">Amam and Shema and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Hazor-Gaddah, and Heshmon and the House of Escape,</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Hazor-Shual and the Well of the Oath, and Bizjothjah,</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Baalah and Iim and Azem,</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Eltolad and Chesil and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Ziklag and Madmannah, and Sansannah,</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Lebaoth and Shilhim and Ain and Rimmon: all the cities twenty and nine and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="33">In the plain Eshtaol and Zoreah, and Ashnah,</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Zanoah and En-Gannim, Tappuah and Enam.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Jarmuth and Adullam, Socoh, and Azekah,</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Sharaim, and Adithaim, and Gederah, and Gederothaim; fourteen cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="37">Zenan, and Hadashah, and Migdal-Gad,</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Dilean, and Mizpeh, and Joktheel,</verse>
  <verse number="39">Lachish and Bozkath and Eglon,</verse>
  <verse number="40">And Cabbon and Lahmam and Kithlish,</verse>
  <verse number="41">And Gederoth, the House of Dagon, and Naamath and Makedah; sixteen cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="42">Libnah and Ether and Ashen,</verse>
  <verse number="43">And Jiphtah, and Ashnah, and Nezib,</verse>
  <verse number="44">And Keilah, and Achzib and Mareshah; nine cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="45">Ekron and her daughters and her enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="46">From Ekron and the sea, all which was upon the hand of Ashdod, and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="47">Ashdod, her daughters and her enclosures: Gaza, her daughters and her enclosures, even to the torrent of Egypt, and the great sea and the bound:</verse>
  <verse number="48">And in the mountain Shamir, and Jattir, and Socoh,</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Dannah, and Kirjath-Sannah (this is Debir),</verse>
  <verse number="50">And Anab and Eshtemoh and Anim,</verse>
  <verse number="51">And Goshen and Holon and Giloh; eleven cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="52">Arab, and Dumah and Eshean,</verse>
  <verse number="53">And Janum, and the House of Tappuah, and Aphekah,</verse>
  <verse number="54">And Humtah, and the Fourth City (this is Hebron), and Zior; nine cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="55">Maon, Carmel, and Ziph and Juttah</verse>
  <verse number="56">And Jezreel and Jokdeam, and Zanoah,</verse>
  <verse number="57">Cain, Gibeah, and Timnah; ten cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="58">Halhnl, the House of Zur, and Gedor,</verse>
  <verse number="59">And Maarath and the House of Anoth, and Eltekon; six cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="60">The city of Baal, (this the City of Forests) and Rabbah; two cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="61">In the desert, the House of Arabah, Middin, and Secacah,</verse>
  <verse number="62">And Nibshan, and the City of Salt, and the Fountain of Engedi; six cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="63">And the Jebusites dwelling in Jerusalem, the sons of Judah will not be able to drive them out: and the Jebusites dwelt with the sons of Judah in Jerusalem even to this day.</verse>
</chapter>