<chapter book="Joshua" number="19" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the second lot came forth to Simeon, to the tribe of the sons of Simeon, according to their families: and their inheritance will be in the midst of the inheritance of the sons of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And there will be to them in their inheritance the Well of the Oath, and the oath, and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Hazor-Shual, and Balah, and Azem,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Eltolad, and Bethul, and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Ziklag, and the House of Chariots, and Hazor-Susah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Beth-Lehaoth, and Sharuhen; thirteen cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="7">The Fountain, the Pomegranate, and Ether, and Ashan; four cities and their enclosures:</verse>
  <verse number="8">And all the enclosures which surrounded these cities, even to Baalath-Beor, Ramath of the south. This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Simeon according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Out of the portion of the sons of Judah was the inheritance of the sons of Simeon: for the portion of the sons of Judah was great above theirs: and the sons of Simeon will inherit in the midst of their inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the third lot will come up to the sons of Zebulon, according to their families: and the bound of their inheritance will be even to Sarid:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And their bound went up to the sea and Maralah, and struck upon Dabbasheth, and struck into the torrent which is upon the face of Jokneam,</verse>
  <verse number="12">And turned back from Sarid, east from the rising of the sun, upon the bound of Chisloth-Tabor, and went forth to Daberath, and went up to Japhia,</verse>
  <verse number="13">And from thence it passed over east from the sunrising to Gittah-Hepher, Ittah-Kazin, the Pomegranate, marked out of the Earthquake;</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the bound encompassed it from the north of Hanathon: and its outgoings were the valley of Jiphthahel:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Kattah and Nahallal, and Shimron, and Idalah, and the House of Bread; twelve cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This the inheritance of the sons of Zebulon according to their families, these cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="17">To Issachar came forth the fourth lot, to the sons of Issachar according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And their bound will be Jezreel and Chesulloth, and Shunem,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Hapharaim, and Shihon and Anaharoth,</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Babbith and Kishion and Abez.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Remeth and the Fountain of Gardens, and the Sharp Fountain, and the House of Dispersion.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the bound struck upon Tabor, and Shahazimah, and the House of the Sun; and the outgoings of their bounds were Jordan: sixteen cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Issachar according to their families, the cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the fifth lot came out to the tribe of the sons of Asher according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And their bound will be Helkath and Hali, and Beten and Achsaph,</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Alammelech and Amad and Mishael; and it struck upon Carmel of the sea, and upon Shihor-Libnah;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And turned back upon the rising of the sun to the House of Grain, and struck upon Zebulon and upon the valley of Jiphthahel north of the House of the Plain, and Neiel, and went forth to Cabul from the left.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Ebron and Rehob and Hammon and Kanah, even to great Zidon;</verse>
  <verse number="29">And the bound turned back to Ramah and even to the city of the fortress of Tyre; and the bound turned back to Hosah: and its outgoings were the sea from the region of Achzib.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Ummah and Aphek, and Rehob: twenty and two cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="31">This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Asher according to their families, these cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="32">To the sons of Naphtali came forth the sixth lot, to the sons of Naphtali according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And their bound will be from Heleph, from Allon to Zaanannim, and Adami, Nekeb and Jabneel and Lakum; and its outgoings Jordan.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the bound turned back to the sea of Aznoth-Tabor, and came forth from thence to Hukkok, and struck upon Zebulon from the south, and struck upon Asher from the sea, and upon Judah at Jordan from the rising of the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the cities of fortification, Ziddim, Zur and Hammath, Rakkath and Cinneroth,</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Adamah, and Ramah, and Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Kadesh and Edrei and the Fountain of Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Iron, and Migdol-El, Horem, and the Mouse of Affliction, and the House of the Sun; nineteen cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="39">This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Naphtali according to their families, the cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="40">To the tribe of the sons of Dan according to their families came forth the seventh lot.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And the bound of their inheritance will be Zorah and Eshtaol, and the city of the Sun,</verse>
  <verse number="42">And Shaalabbin and Ajalon and Jethlah,</verse>
  <verse number="43">And Ailon and Timnath and Ekron,</verse>
  <verse number="44">Eltekah and Gibbethon and Baalath,</verse>
  <verse number="45">And Jehud and the Sons of Lightning, and the Press of the Pomegranate,</verse>
  <verse number="46">The Water of Paleness, and Rakkon, with the bound in front of Joppa.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And the bound of the sons of Dan went out from them: and the sons of Dan will go up and fight with Leshem, and they will take it and smite it with the mouth of the sword, and will possess it and dwell in it; and they will call Leshem, Dan, according to the name of Dan their father.</verse>
  <verse number="48">This the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Dan according to their families, these cities and their enclosures.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And they will finish to inherit the land according to their bounds: and the sons of Israel will give an inheritance to Joshua son of Nun, in the midst of them:</verse>
  <verse number="50">At the month of Jehovah they gave to him the city which he asked, Timnath-Serah in mount Ephraim; and he will build the city and dwell in it.</verse>
  <verse number="51">These the inheritances which Eleazar the priest, and Joshua the son of Nun, and the heads of the fathers to the tribes of the sons of Israel, caused to inherit by lot in Shiloh before Jehovah, at the door of the tent of appointment And they will finish dividing the land.</verse>
</chapter>