<chapter book="Zephaniah" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wo! to the wonderful and oppressing city being redeemed.</verse>
  <verse number="2">She heard not to the voice: she received not instruction; she trusted not in Jehovah; she drew not near to her God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Her chiefs in the midst of her are roaring lions; her judges evening wolves; they laid not up for the morning.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Her prophets vain-glorious men of treacheries: her priests defiled the holy place, they violated the law.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Jehovah is just in her midst; he will not do iniquity: in morning by morning he will give his judgment to the light, he as not wanting; and the evil will not know shame.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I cut off the nations: their pinnacles were desolate: I laid waste their streets from none passing by; their cities were destroyed from not a man, from not an inhabitant.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I said, Surely thou wilt fear me, thou wilt receive instruction; and her dwelling shall not be cut off, all that I reviewed over her but they rose early, they corrupted all their doings.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For this, wait for me, says Jehovah, to the day of my rising up for a testimony: for my judgment is to assemble the nations for my gathering the kingdoms to pour upon them my wrath, all the burning of mine anger: for in the fire of my jealousy all the earth shall be devoured.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For then I will turn to the peoples a purified lip, for all to call upon the name of Jehovah, to serve him with one shoulder.</verse>
  <verse number="10">From beyond to the rivers of Cush incense, the daughter of my dispersed shall bring my gifts.</verse>
  <verse number="11">In that day shalt thou not be ashamed for all thy doing which thou didst transgress against me: for then will I remove from the midst of thee those exulting in thy pride, and thou shalt no more add to be elevated in my holy mountain.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I left in the midst of thee a humble and weak people, and they trusted in the name of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The remnant of Israel shall not do iniquity, and they shall not speak falsehood: and in their mouth shall not be found a tongue of deceit: for they shall feed and lie down, and none terrifying.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Shout for joy, O daughter of Zion; cry with a loud voice, O Israel; rejoice and exult with all the heart, O daughter of Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Jehovah removed thy judgments, be turned away thine enemy: the king of Israel, Jehovah in the midst of thee: thou shalt no more see evil.</verse>
  <verse number="16">In that day he will say to Jerusalem, Thou shalt not fear: O Zion, thy hands shall not be slack.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Jehovah thy God is in the midst of thee: the strong one will save, he will rejoice over thee with joy; he will be silent in his love, he will exult over thee with rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I will assemble those grieved for the appointment, who were from thee, the lifting up upon it a reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold me doing all for sake of thee in that time: and I saved her halting, and her being driven out I will gather; and I set them for a praise and for a name in every land of their shame.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In that time I will bring you, and in the time of my gathering you: for I will give you for a name and for a praise among all peoples of the earth, in my turning your captivity before your eyes, said Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>