<chapter book="Romans" number="14" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Him that is weak in the faith receive you, but not to doubtful disputations.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For one believes that he may eat all things: another, who is weak, eats herbs.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let not him that eats despise him that eats not; and let not him which eats not judge him that eats: for God has received him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who are you that judge another man’s servant? to his own master he stands or falls. Yes, he shall be held up: for God is able to make him stand.</verse>
  <verse number="5">One man esteems one day above another: another esteems every day alike. Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He that regards the day, regards it to the Lord; and he that regards not the day, to the Lord he does not regard it. He that eats, eats to the Lord, for he gives God thanks; and he that eats not, to the Lord he eats not, and gives God thanks.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For none of us lives to himself, and no man dies to himself.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For whether we live, we live to the Lord; and whether we die, we die to the Lord: whether we live therefore, or die, we are the Lord’s.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For to this end Christ both died, and rose, and revived, that he might be Lord both of the dead and living.</verse>
  <verse number="10">But why do you judge your brother? or why do you set at nothing your brother? for we shall all stand before the judgment seat of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For it is written, As I live, said the Lord, every knee shall bow to me, and every tongue shall confess to God.</verse>
  <verse number="12">So then every one of us shall give account of himself to God.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Let us not therefore judge one another any more: but judge this rather, that no man put a stumbling block or an occasion to fall in his brother’s way.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I know, and am persuaded by the Lord Jesus, that there is nothing unclean of itself: but to him that esteems any thing to be unclean, to him it is unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But if your brother be grieved with your meat, now walk you not charitably. Destroy not him with your meat, for whom Christ died.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Let not then your good be evil spoken of:</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the kingdom of God is not meat and drink; but righteousness, and peace, and joy in the Holy Ghost.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For he that in these things serves Christ is acceptable to God, and approved of men.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Let us therefore follow after the things which make for peace, and things with which one may edify another.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For meat destroy not the work of God. All things indeed are pure; but it is evil for that man who eats with offense.</verse>
  <verse number="21">It is good neither to eat flesh, nor to drink wine, nor any thing whereby your brother stumbles, or is offended, or is made weak.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Have you faith? have it to yourself before God. Happy is he that comdemns not himself in that thing which he allows.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he that doubts is damned if he eat, because he eats not of faith: for whatever is not of faith is sin.</verse>
</chapter>