<chapter book="Lamentations" number="5" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Remember, O Lord, what is come upon us: consider and behold our reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Our inheritance is turned to aliens: our houses to strangers.</verse>
  <verse number="3">We are become orphans without a father: our mothers are as widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">We have drunk our water for money: we have bought our wood.</verse>
  <verse number="5">We were dragged by the necks, we were weary and no rest was given us.</verse>
  <verse number="6">We have given our hand to Egypt, and to the Assyrians, that we might be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Our fathers have sinned, and are not: and we have borne their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Servants have ruled over us: there was none to redeem us out of their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">We fetched our bread at the peril of our lives, because of the sword in the desert.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Our skin was burnt as an oven, by reason of the violence of the famine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They oppressed the women in Sion, and the virgins in the cities of Juda.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The princes were hanged up by their hand: they did not respect the persons of the ancient.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They abused the young men indecently: and the children fell under the wood.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The ancients have ceased from the gates: the young men from the choir of the singers.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The joy of our heart is ceased, our dancing is turned into mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The crown is fallen from our head woe to us, because we have sinned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore is our heart sorrowful, therefore are our eyes become dim,</verse>
  <verse number="18">For mount Sion, because it is destroyed, foxes have walked upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But thou, O Lord, shalt remain for ever, thy throne from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why wilt thou forget us for ever? why wilt thou forsake us for a long time?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Convert us, O Lord, to thee, and we shall be converted: renew our days, as from the beginning.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But thou hast utterly rejected us, thou art exceedingly angry against us.</verse>
</chapter>