<chapter book="1 Timothy" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">An elder shouldest thou not reprove, but beseech as a father; the younger as brethren;</verse>
  <verse number="2">The elder women as mothers; the younger as sisters, in all purity.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Honour widows, truly widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And if any widow have children or descendants, let them learn first to be pious to their own house, and to return recompenses to their progenitors: for this is good and acceptable before God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And she truly a widow, and forsaken, has hoped in God, and remains in supplications and prayers night and day.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And she living luxuriously is dead, living.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And these things proclaim, that they might be irreprehensible.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And if any for his own, and chiefly for his own household provide not, he has denied the faith, and is worse than the unbelieving.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Let not a widow be chosen less than sixty years, having been wife of one man,</verse>
  <verse number="10">Testified of in good works; if she have brought up children, if she lodged strangers, if she washed the feet of the holy, if she relieved the pressed, if she followed every good work.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the younger widows reject: for when they conduct themselves arrogantly against Christ, they wish to marry:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Having judgment, for they put away the first faith.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And at the same time also they learn to be idle, going round about the houses; and not only idle, but also indulging in idle talk, and occupied with unnecessary things, speaking things not becoming.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I wish therefore the younger to marry, to bear children, to rule the house, to give no occasion to him opposing for reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For already have some turned aside after Satan.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If any man or woman faithful have widows, let them relieve them, and let not the church be loaded; that it may relieve the truly widows.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let the elders having presided well be deemed worthy of double honour, chiefly they being wearied in word and doctrine.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the writing says, Thou shalt not muzzle the ox grinding. And, The laborer worthy of his hire.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Against an elder receive not an accusation from without, except from two or three witnesses.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Them having sinned rebuke before all, that the rest also have fear.</verse>
  <verse number="21">I call to witness before God, and the Lord Jesus Christ, and the chosen angels, that thou watch these things without preference, doing nothing by bending.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Put hands swiftly upon none, nor participate in others’ sins: keep thyself pure.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Drink no longer water, but use a little wine for thy stomach and thy frequent weaknesses.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Some men’s sins are manifest, going before to judgment; and also to some they follow in the train.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Likewise also the good works of some are manifest; and having these otherwise, it cannot be hid.</verse>
</chapter>