<chapter book="Job" number="21" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear, I beseech you, my words, and do penance.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Suffer me, and I will speak, and after, if you please, laugh at my words.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Is my debate against man, that I should not have just reason to be troubled?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Hearken to me and be astonished, and lay your finger on your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">As for me, when I remember, I am afraid, and trembling taketh hold on my flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Why then do the wicked live, are they advanced, and strengthened with riches?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Their seed continueth before them, a multitude of kinsmen, and of children’s children in their sight.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Their houses are secure and peaceable, and the rod of God is not upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Their cattle have conceived, and failed not: their cow has calved, and is not deprived of her fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Their little ones go out like a flock, and their children dance and play.</verse>
  <verse number="12">They take the timbrel, and the harp, and rejoice at the sound of the organ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They spend their days in wealth, and in a moment they go down to hell.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who have said to God: Depart from us, we desire not the knowledge of thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Who is the Almighty, that we should serve him? and what doth it profit us if we pray to him?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Yet because their good things are not in their hand, may the counsel of the wicked be far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">How often shall the lamp of the wicked be put out, and a deluge come upon them, and he shall distribute the sorrows of his wrath?</verse>
  <verse number="18">They shall be as chaff before the face of the wind, and as ashes which the whirlwind scattereth.</verse>
  <verse number="19">God shall lay up the sorrow of the father for his children: and when he shall repay, then shall he know.</verse>
  <verse number="20">His eyes shall see his own destruction, and he shall drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For what is it to him what befalleth his house after him: and if the number of his months be diminished by one half?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Shall any one teach God knowledge, who judgeth those that are high?</verse>
  <verse number="23">One man dieth strong, and hale, rich and happy.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His bowels are full of fat, and his bones are moistened with marrow.</verse>
  <verse number="25">But another dieth in bitterness of soul without any riches:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And yet they shall sleep together in the dust, and worms shall cover them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Surely I know your thoughts, and your unjust judgments against me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For you say: Where is the house of the prince ? and where are the dwelling places of the wicked?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Ask any one of them that go by the way, and you shall perceive that he knoweth these same things.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Because the wicked man is reserved to the day of destruction, and he shall be brought to the day of wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Who shall reprove his way to his face? and who shall repay him what he hath done?</verse>
  <verse number="32">He shall be brought to the graves, and shall watch in the heap of the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He hath been acceptable to the gravel of Cocytus, and he shall draw every man after him, and there are innumerable before him.</verse>
  <verse number="34">How then do ye comfort me in vain, whereas your answer is shewn to be repugnant to truth ?</verse>
</chapter>