<chapter book="Job" number="30" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But now the younger in time scorn me, whose fathers I would not have set with the dogs of my flock:</verse>
  <verse number="2">The strength of whose hands was to me as nothing, and they were thought unworthy of life itself.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Barren with want and hunger, who gnawed in the wilderness, disfigured with calamity and misery.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they ate grass, and barks of trees, and the root of junipers was their food.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who snatched up these things out of the valleys, and when they had found any of them, they ran to them with a cry.</verse>
  <verse number="6">They dwelt in the desert places of torrents, and in caves of earth, or upon the gravel.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They pleased themselves among these kind of things, and counted it delightful to be under the briers.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The children of foolish and base men, and not appearing at all upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Now I am turned into their song, and am become their byword.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They abhor me, and flee far from me, and are not afraid to spit in my face.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he hath opened his quiver, and hath afflicted me, and hath put a bridle into my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="12">At the right hand of my rising, my calamities forthwith arose: they have overthrown my feet, and have overwhelmed me with their paths as with waves.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They have destroyed my ways, they have lain in wait against me, and they have prevailed, and there was none to help.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They have rushed in upon me, as when a wall is broken, and a gate opened, and have rolled themselves down to my miseries.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I am brought to nothing: as a wind thou hast taken away my desire: and my prosperity hath passed away like a cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And now my soul fadeth within myself, and the days of affliction possess me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In the night my bone is pierced with sorrows: and they that feed upon me, do not sleep.</verse>
  <verse number="18">With the multitude of them my garment is consumed, and they have girded me about, as with the collar of my coat.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I am compared to dirt, and am likened to embers and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I cry to thee, and thou hearest me not: I stand up, and thou dost not regard me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Thou art changed to be cruel toward me, and in the hardness of thy hand thou art against me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Thou hast lifted me up, and set me as it were upon the wind, and thou hast mightily dashed me.</verse>
  <verse number="23">I know that thou wilt deliver me to death, where a house is appointed for every one that liveth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But yet thou stretchest not forth thy hand to their consumption: and if they shall fall down thou wilt save.</verse>
  <verse number="25">I wept heretofore for him that was afflicted, and my soul had compassion on the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I expected good things, and evils are come upon me: I waited for light, and darkness broke out.</verse>
  <verse number="27">My inner parts have boiled without any rest, the days of affliction have prevented me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I went mourning without indignation; I rose up, and cried in the crowd.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I was the brother of dragons, and companion of ostriches.</verse>
  <verse number="30">My skin is become black upon me, and my bones are dried up with heat.</verse>
  <verse number="31">My harp is turned to mourning, and my organ into the voice of those that weep.</verse>
</chapter>