<chapter book="Job" number="38" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the Lord answered Job out of a whirlwind, and said :</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who is this that wrappeth up sentences in unskillful words?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Gird up thy loins like a man : I will ask thee, and answer thou me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where wast thou when I laid up the foundations of the earth ? tell me if thou hast understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who hath laid the measures thereof, if thou knowest? or who hath stretched the line upon it?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Upon what are its bases grounded? or who laid the corner stone thereof,</verse>
  <verse number="7">When the morning stars praised me together, and all the sons of God made a joyful melody?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Who shut up the sea with doors, when it broke forth as issuing out of the womb :</verse>
  <verse number="9">when I made a cloud the garment thereof, and wrapped it in a mist as in swaddling bands?</verse>
  <verse number="10">I set my bounds around it, and made it bars and doors :</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I said : Hitherto thou shalt come, and shalt go no further, and here thou shalt break thy swelling waves.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Didst thou since thy birth command the morning, and shew the dawning of the day its place?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And didst thou hold the extremities of the earth shaking them, and hast thou shaken the ungodly out of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">The seal shall be restored as clay, and shall stand as a garment :</verse>
  <verse number="15">From the wicked their light shall be taken away, and the high arm shall be broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Hast thou entered into the depths of the sea, and walked in the lowest parts of the deep?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Have the gates of death been opened to thee, and hast thou seen the darksome doors?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Hast thou considered the breadth of the earth? tell me, if thou knowest all things?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Where is the way where light dwelleth, and where is the place of darkness :</verse>
  <verse number="20">That thou mayst bring every thing to its own bounds, and understand the paths of the house thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Didst thou know then that thou shouldst be born ? and didst thou know the number of thy days?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Hast thou entered into the storehouses of the snow, or has thou beheld the treasures of the hail :</verse>
  <verse number="23">Which I have prepared for the time of the enemy, against the day of battle and war?</verse>
  <verse number="24">By what way is the light spread, and heat divided upon the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who gave a course to violent showers, or a way for noisy thunder :</verse>
  <verse number="26">That it should rain on the earth without man in the wilderness, where no mortal dwelleth :</verse>
  <verse number="27">That it should fill the desert and desolate land, and should bring forth green grass?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Who is the father of rain ? or who begot the drops of dew?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Out of whose womb came the ice; and the frost from heaven who hath gendered it?</verse>
  <verse number="30">The waters are hardened like a stone, and the surface of the deep is congealed.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Shalt thou be able to join together the shining stars the Pleiades, or canst thou stop the turning about of Arcturus?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Canst thou bring forth the day star in its time, and make the evening star to rise upon the children of the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Dost thou know the order of heaven, and canst thou set down the reason thereof on the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Canst thou lift up thy voice to the clouds, that an abundance of waters may cover thee?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Canst thou send lightnings, and will they go, and will they return and say to thee : Here we are?</verse>
  <verse number="36">Who hath put wisdom in the heart of man? or who gave the cock understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who can declare the order of the heavens, or who can make the harmony of heaven to sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="38">When was the dust poured on the earth, and the clods fastened together?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Wilt thou take the prey for the lioness, and satisfy the appetite of her whelps,</verse>
  <verse number="40">When they couch in the dens and lie in wait in holes?</verse>
  <verse number="41">Who provideth food for the raven, when her young ones cry to God, wandering about, because they have no meat?</verse>
</chapter>