<chapter book="Job" number="7" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The life of man upon earth is a warfare, and his days are like the days of a hireling.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As a servant longeth for the shade, as the hireling looketh for the end of his work;</verse>
  <verse number="3">So I also have had empty months, and have numbered to myself wearisome nights.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If I lie down to sleep, I shall say: When shall arise? and again I shall look for the evening, and shall be filled with sorrows even till darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="5">My flesh is clothed with rottenness and the filth of dust, my skin is withered and drawn together.</verse>
  <verse number="6">My days have passed more swiftly than the web is cut by the weaver, and are consumed without any hope.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Remember that my life is but wind, and my eyes shall not return to see good things.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Nor shall the sight of man behold me: thy eyes are upon me, and I shall be no more.</verse>
  <verse number="9">As a cloud is consumed, and passeth away: so he that shall go down to hell shall not come up.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Nor shall he return my more into his house, neither shall his place know him any more.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wherefore I will not spare my month, I will speak in the affliction of my spirit: I will talk with the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Am I a sea, or a whale, that thou hast enclosed me in a prison?</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I say: My bed shall comfort me, and I shall be relieved speaking with myself on my couch:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thou wilt frighten me with dreams and terrify me with visions.</verse>
  <verse number="15">So that my soul rather chooseth hanging, and my bones death.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I have done with hope, I shall now live no longer: spare me, for my days are nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="17">What is a man that thou shouldst magnify him? or why dost thou set thy heart upon him?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Thou visitest him early in the morning, and thou provest him suddenly.</verse>
  <verse number="19">How long wilt thou not spare me, nor suffer me to swallow down my spittle?</verse>
  <verse number="20">I have sinned: what shall I do to thee, O keeper of men? why hast thou set me opposite to thee, and I am become burdensome to myself?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Why dost thou not remove my sin, and why dost thou not take away my iniquity? Behold now I shall sleep in the dust: and if thou seek me in the morning, I shall not be.</verse>
</chapter>