<chapter book="Job" number="8" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The Baldad the Suhite answered, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long wilt thou speak these things, and how long shall the words of thy mouth be like a strong wind?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Doth God pervert judgment, or doth the Almighty overthrow that which is just?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Although thy children have sinned against him, and he hath left them in the hand of their iniquity:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Yet if thou wilt arise early to God, and wilt beseech the Almighty:</verse>
  <verse number="6">If thou wilt walk clean and upright, he will presently awake onto thee, and will make the dwelling of thy justice peaceable:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Insomuch, that if thy former things were small, thy latter things would be multiplied exceedingly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For inquire of the former generation, and search diligently into the memory of the fathers:</verse>
  <verse number="9">(For we are but of yesterday, and are ignorant that our days upon earth are but a shadow:)</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they shall teach thee: they shall speak to thee, and utter words out of their hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Can the rush be green without moisture? or a sedge-bush grow without water?</verse>
  <verse number="12">When it is yet in flower, and is not plucked up with the hand, it withereth before all herbs.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Even so are the ways of all that forget God, and the hope of the hypocrite shall perish:</verse>
  <verse number="14">His folly shall not please him, and his trust shall be like the spider’s web.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He shall lean upon his house, and it shall not stand: he shall prop it up, and it shall not rise:</verse>
  <verse number="16">He seemeth to have moisture before the sun cometh, and at his rising his blossom shall shoot forth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His roots shall be thick upon a heap of stones, and among the stones he shall abide.</verse>
  <verse number="18">If one swallow him up out of his place, he shall deny him, and shall say: I know thee not.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For this is the joy of his way, that others may spring again out of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="20">God will not cast away the simple, nor reach out his hand to the evildoer:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Until thy mouth be filled with laughter, and thy lips with rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="22">They that hate thee, shall be clothed with confusion: and the dwelling of the wicked shall not stand.</verse>
</chapter>