<chapter book="1 Peter" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Having put aside, then, all evil, and all guile, and hypocrisies, and envyings, and all evil speakings,</verse>
  <verse number="2">as new-born babes the word’s pure milk desire ye, that in it ye may grow,</verse>
  <verse number="3">if so be ye did taste that the Lord is gracious,</verse>
  <verse number="4">to whom coming—a living stone—by men, indeed, having been disapproved of, but with God choice, precious,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and ye yourselves, as living stones, are built up, a spiritual house, a holy priesthood, to offer up spiritual sacrifices acceptable to God through Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Wherefore, also, it is contained in the Writing: ‘Lo, I lay in Zion a chief corner-stone, choice, precious, and he who is believing on him may not be put to shame;’</verse>
  <verse number="7">to you, then, who are believing is the preciousness; and to the unbelieving, a stone that the builders disapproved of, this one did become for the head of a corner,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and a stone of stumbling and a rock of offence—who are stumbling at the word, being unbelieving,—to which also they were set;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and ye are a choice race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people acquired, that the excellences ye may shew forth of Him who out of darkness did call you to His wondrous light;</verse>
  <verse number="10">who were once not a people, and are now the people of God; who had not found kindness, and now have found kindness.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Beloved, I call upon you, as strangers and sojourners, to keep from the fleshly desires, that war against the soul,</verse>
  <verse number="12">having your behaviour among the nations right, that in that which they speak against you as evil-doers, of the good works having beheld, they may glorify God in a day of inspection.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Be subject, then, to every human creation, because of the Lord, whether to a king, as the highest,</verse>
  <verse number="14">whether to governors, as to those sent through him, for punishment, indeed, of evil-doers, and a praise of those doing good;</verse>
  <verse number="15">because, so is the will of God, doing good, to put to silence the ignorance of the foolish men;</verse>
  <verse number="16">as free, and not having the freedom as the cloak of the evil, but as servants of God;</verse>
  <verse number="17">to all give ye honour; the brotherhood love ye; God fear ye; the king honour ye.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The domestics! be subjecting yourselves in all fear to the masters, not only to the good and gentle, but also to the cross;</verse>
  <verse number="19">for this is gracious, if because of conscience toward God any one doth endure sorrows, suffering unrighteously;</verse>
  <verse number="20">for what renown is it, if sinning and being buffeted, ye do endure it? but if, doing good and suffering for it, ye do endure, this is gracious with God,</verse>
  <verse number="21">for to this ye were called, because Christ also did suffer for you, leaving to you an example, that ye may follow his steps,</verse>
  <verse number="22">who did not commit sin, nor was guile found in his mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="23">who being reviled—was not reviling again, suffering—was not threatening, and was committing himself to Him who is judging righteously,</verse>
  <verse number="24">who our sins himself did bear in his body, upon the tree, that to the sins having died, to the righteousness we may live; by whose stripes ye were healed,</verse>
  <verse number="25">for ye were as sheep going astray, but ye turned back now to the shepherd and overseer of your souls.</verse>
</chapter>