<chapter book="Exodus" number="25" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Speak to the children of Israel, that they bring me an offering: of every man that gives it willingly with his heart you shall take my offering.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And this is the offering which you shall take of them; gold, and silver, and brass,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine linen, and goats’ hair,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And rams’ skins dyed red, and badgers’ skins, and shittim wood,</verse>
  <verse number="6">Oil for the light, spices for anointing oil, and for sweet incense,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Onyx stones, and stones to be set in the ephod, and in the breastplate.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And let them make me a sanctuary; that I may dwell among them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">According to all that I show you, after the pattern of the tabernacle, and the pattern of all the instruments thereof, even so shall you make it.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they shall make an ark of shittim wood: two cubits and a half shall be the length thereof, and a cubit and a half the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a half the height thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And you shall overlay it with pure gold, within and without shall you overlay it, and shall make on it a crown of gold round about.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And you shall cast four rings of gold for it, and put them in the four corners thereof; and two rings shall be in the one side of it, and two rings in the other side of it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And you shall make staves of shittim wood, and overlay them with gold.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And you shall put the staves into the rings by the sides of the ark, that the ark may be borne with them.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The staves shall be in the rings of the ark: they shall not be taken from it.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And you shall put into the ark the testimony which I shall give you.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And you shall make a mercy seat of pure gold: two cubits and a half shall be the length thereof, and a cubit and a half the breadth thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And you shall make two cherubim of gold, of beaten work shall you make them, in the two ends of the mercy seat.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And make one cherub on the one end, and the other cherub on the other end: even of the mercy seat shall you make the cherubim on the two ends thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the cherubim shall stretch forth their wings on high, covering the mercy seat with their wings, and their faces shall look one to another; toward the mercy seat shall the faces of the cherubim be.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And you shall put the mercy seat above on the ark; and in the ark you shall put the testimony that I shall give you.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And there I will meet with you, and I will commune with you from above the mercy seat, from between the two cherubim which are on the ark of the testimony, of all things which I will give you in commandment to the children of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="23">You shall also make a table of shittim wood: two cubits shall be the length thereof, and a cubit the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a half the height thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And you shall overlay it with pure gold, and make thereto a crown of gold round about.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And you shall make to it a border of an hand breadth round about, and you shall make a golden crown to the border thereof round about.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And you shall make for it four rings of gold, and put the rings in the four corners that are on the four feet thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Over against the border shall the rings be for places of the staves to bear the table.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And you shall make the staves of shittim wood, and overlay them with gold, that the table may be borne with them.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And you shall make the dishes thereof, and spoons thereof, and covers thereof, and bowls thereof, to cover with: of pure gold shall you make them.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And you shall set on the table show bread before me always.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And you shall make a candlestick of pure gold: of beaten work shall the candlestick be made: his shaft, and his branches, his bowls, his knops, and his flowers, shall be of the same.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And six branches shall come out of the sides of it; three branches of the candlestick out of the one side, and three branches of the candlestick out of the other side:</verse>
  <verse number="33">Three bowls made like to almonds, with a bud and a flower in one branch; and three bowls made like almonds in the other branch, with a bud and a flower: so in the six branches that come out of the candlestick.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And in the candlesticks shall be four bowls made like to almonds, with their knops and their flowers.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And there shall be a bud under two branches of the same, and a bud under two branches of the same, and a bud under two branches of the same, according to the six branches that proceed out of the candlestick.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Their knops and their branches shall be of the same: all it shall be one beaten work of pure gold.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And you shall make the seven lamps thereof: and they shall light the lamps thereof, that they may give light over against it.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And the tongs thereof, and the firepans thereof, shall be of pure gold.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Of a talent of pure gold shall he make it, with all these vessels.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And look that you make them after their pattern, which was showed you in the mount.</verse>
</chapter>