<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="11" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And all Israel will gather together to David to Hebron, saying, Behold, we thy bone and thy flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Also yesterday also the third day, also in Saul being king thou wert bringing forth and bringing in Israel: and Jehovah thy God will say to thee, Thou shalt feed my people Israel, and thou shalt be leader over my people Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And all the old men of Israel will come to the king to Hebron; and David will cut out to them a covenant in Hebron before Jehovah; and they will anoint David for king over Israel according to the word of Jehovah by the hand of Samuel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And David will go, and all Israel to Jerusalem; this is Jebus; and there the Jebusites dwelling in the land.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they dwelling in Jebus will say to David, Thou shalt not come in hither. And David will take the castle of Zion, this the city of David.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And David will say, Every one striking the Jebusites the first shall be for head and for chief. And Joab son of Zeruiah, will go up at first, and he will be for head.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And David dwelt in the castle; for this they called to it the city of David.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he will build the city from round about from Millo, and even round about: and Joab will revive the remainder of the city.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And David will go, going and growing great: and Jehovah of armies with him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And these the heads, strong ones, which were to David, strengthening themselves with him in his kingdom, with all Israel, to cause him to reign according to the word of Jehovah upon Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And these the number of strong ones which were to David; Jashobeam, son of Hachmoni, head of the thirty; he lifted up his spear against three hundred wounding at one time.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And after him Eleazar, son of Dodo, the Ahohite, he among the three strong ones.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He was with David in Pasdammim, and the rovers were gathered together there to war, and there will be a portion of the field filled with barley; and the people fled from before the rovers.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they will set themselves in the midst of the portion, and they will deliver it and will strike the rovers; and Jehovah will save a great salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the three from the thirty heads will go down upon the rock to David to the cave of Adullam; and the camp of the rovers encamped in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And David then in the castle, and a garrison of the rovers then in the house of bread.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And David will long, and say, Who will give me to drink from the water from the well of the house of bread, which is in the gate?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the three will break forth into the camp of the rovers, and draw waters from the well of the house of bread which is in the gate, and they will lift up and bring to David: and David would not drink them, and he will pour them forth to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he will say, Far be it to me from my God from doing this: shall I drink the blood of these men with their souls? for with their souls they brought them. And he would not drink them. These did the three strong ones.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Abishai, brother of Joab, he was head of the three: and he lifted up his spear against three hundred; he wounded, and to a name among the three.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Of the three, above the two he was honored; and will be to them for chief: and even to the three he came not.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Benaiah son of Jehoida, son of a man of power, great of deeds, from Kabzeel, he struck two lions of god of Moab: and he went down and struck the lion in the midst of the pit in the day of snow.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he struck the man, the Egyptian, a man of measure, five by the cubit; and in the hand of the Egyptian a spear as the beam of those weaving; and he went down to him with a rod, and he will take by force the spear from the hand of the Egyptian, and he will kill him with his spear.</verse>
  <verse number="24">These did Benaiah son of Jehoida; and to him a name among the three strong ones.</verse>
  <verse number="25">From the thirty, behold, he was honored, and to three he came not: and David will set him over his audience.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And the strong ones of the forces, Asahel, brother of Joab, Elhanan son of Dodo from the house of bread,</verse>
  <verse number="27">Shammoth the Harorite, Helez the Pelonite,</verse>
  <verse number="28">Ira son of Ikkesh the Tekoite, Abiezer the Anathothite,</verse>
  <verse number="29">Sibbecai the Hushathite, Ilai the Ahohite,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Maharai the Netophathite, Heled son of Baanah the Netophathite,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Ithai son of Ribai from Gibeah, the sons of Benjamin, Benaiah the Pirathonite,</verse>
  <verse number="32">Hurai from the torrents of Gaash, Abiel the Arbathite,</verse>
  <verse number="33">Azmaveth the Baharumite, Eliaba the Shaalbonite,</verse>
  <verse number="34">The sons of Hashem the Gizonite, Jonathan son of Shage the Harorite,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Ahiam son of Sacar the Harorite, Eliphal son of Ur,</verse>
  <verse number="36">Hepher the Mecherathite, Ahijah the Pelonite,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Hezro the Carmelite, Naarai son of Ezbai,</verse>
  <verse number="38">Joel, brother of Nathan, Mibhar son of Haggeri,</verse>
  <verse number="39">Zelek the Ammonite, Nahami the Berothite, lifting up the utensils of Joab son of Zeruiah,</verse>
  <verse number="40">Ira the Ithrite, Gareb the Ithrite,</verse>
  <verse number="41">Uriah the Hittite, Zabad son of Athlai,</verse>
  <verse number="42">Adina son of Shiza the Reubenite, head to the Reubenites, and with him thirty,</verse>
  <verse number="43">Hanan son of Maachah, and Josaphat the Mithnite,</verse>
  <verse number="44">Uzziah the Ashterathite, Shama and Jehiel, the sons of Hothan the Aroerite,</verse>
  <verse number="45">Jediael the son of Shimri, and Joha his brother the Tizite,</verse>
  <verse number="46">Eliel the Mahavite, and Jeribai and Joshaviah, sons of Elnaam, and Ithmah the Moabite,</verse>
  <verse number="47">Eliel and Obed and Jasiel, the Mesobaite.</verse>
</chapter>