<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And to the sons of Aaron their divisions. The sons of Aaron: Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Nadab will die, and Abihu, before their father; and sons were not to them: and Eleazar and Ithamar will be priests.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And David will separate them, and Zadok from the sons of Eleazar, and Ahimelech from the sons, of Ithamar, for their reviewing in their service.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the sons of Eleazar will be found many for heads, mighty ones above the sons of Ithamar; and they will be divided: to the sons of Eleazar, heads to the house of the fathers, sixteen; and to the sons of Ithamar, to the house of their fathers, eight.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they will be divided by lots, these with these, for the chiefs of the holy place, and the chiefs of God, were from the sons of Eleazar, and among the sons of Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Shemaiah, son of Nathaniel the scribe, son of the Levites, will write them before the king, and the chiefs, and Zadok the priest, and Ahimelech son of Abiathar, and the heads of the fathers to the priests and to the Levites: one house of a father taken for Eleazar, and taking, he took for Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the first lot will go forth to Jehoiarib, to Jedaiah the second,</verse>
  <verse number="8">To Harim the third, to Seorim the fourth,</verse>
  <verse number="9">To Malchijah the fifth, to Mijamin the sixth,</verse>
  <verse number="10">To Hakkoz the seventh, to Abijah the eighth,</verse>
  <verse number="11">To Joshua the ninth, to Shecaniah the tenth,</verse>
  <verse number="12">To Eliashib the eleventh, to Jakim the twelfth,</verse>
  <verse number="13">To Huppah the thirteenth, to Jeshebeab the fourteenth,</verse>
  <verse number="14">To Bilgah the fifteenth, to Immer the sixteenth,</verse>
  <verse number="15">To Hezir the seventeenth, to Aphses the eighteenth,</verse>
  <verse number="16">To Pethahiah, the nineteenth, to Jehezekel, the twentieth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">To Jachin, the one and twentieth, to Gamul the two and twentieth,</verse>
  <verse number="18">To Delaiah, the three and twentieth, to Maaziah, the four and twentieth.</verse>
  <verse number="19">These their reviewing for their service to come into the house of Jehovah according to their judgment, by the hand of Aaron their father, as Jehovah God of Israel commanded him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And to the sons of Levi remaining: To the sons of Amram: Shubael: to the sons of Shubael, Jehdeiah.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To Rehabiah: to the sons of Rehabiah: the head, Isshiah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">To the Izharites: Shelornoth: to the sons of Shelomoth: Jahath.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the sons of Jeriah: Amariah the second, Jahaziel the third, Jekameam the fourth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The sons of Uzziel: Micah: to the sons of Micah: Shamir.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The brother of Micah, Isshiah: to the sons of Isshiah: Zechariah.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sons of Merari: Mahli, and Mushi: the sons of Jaaziah: his son.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sons of Merari, to Jaaziah: his son and Shoham and Zaccur and Ibri.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And to Mahli, Eleazar; and no sons to him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">To Kish: the sons of Kish, Jerahmeel.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the sons of Mushi: Mahli and Eder and Jerimoth. These the sons of the Levites to the house of their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they will also cast lots near their brethren the sons of Aaron before David the king and Zadok, and Ahimelech, and the heads of the fathers to the priests and to the Levites, the fathers the head near his brethren the small.</verse>
</chapter>