<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="29" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And David the king will say to all the convocation, Solomon my son, God chose in him alone, is a youth and tender, and the work great; for the fortress not for man but for Jehovah God.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And with all my power I prepared for the house of my God, gold for gold, and silver for silver, and brass for brass, and iron for iron, woods for woods, and stones of onyx, and the fillings up, and stones of paint and of variegation, and every precious stone, and stones of white marble for multitude.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And yet in my delighting in the house of my God, there is to me property of gold and silver I gave to the house of my God, to above from all I prepared for the holy house,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Three thousand talents of gold from gold of Ophir, and seven thousand talents of purified silver, to spread over the walls of the houses:</verse>
  <verse number="5">To gold for gold, and to silver for silver, and for all the work by the hand of artificers And who being willing for the filling up of his hand this day to Jehovah?</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the chiefs of the fathers will show themselves willing, and the chiefs of the tribes of Israel, and the chiefs of thousands and of hundreds, and for the chiefs of the king’s work,</verse>
  <verse number="7">And will give for the service of the house of God, gold five thousand talents and ten thousand darics, and silver ten thousand talents, and brass a myriad and eight thousand talents, and iron a hundred thousand talents.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And with whom stones being found they gave to the treasure of the house of Jehovah by the hand of Jehiel the Gershonite.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the people will rejoice for their showing themselves willing, for with the whole heart they showed themselves willing to Jehovah: and also David the king rejoiced with great gladness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And David will praise Jehovah before the eyes of all the convocation: and David will say, Praised be thou, O Jehovah God of Israel our father, from forever and even to forever.</verse>
  <verse number="11">To thee, O Jehovah, the greatness and the strength, and the glory and the confidence, and the majesty: for all in the heavens and in the earth to thee, O Jehovah, the kingdom and being lifted up to all for head.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And riches and honor from before thee, and thou ruling over all, and in thy hand power and strength, and in thy hand to magnify and to strengthen to all.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And now, our God, we confess to thee, and praise to the name of thy glory.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And because who am I? and who my people, that we shall retain power to show ourselves willing according to this? for from thee all things, and from thy hand they gave to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For we are strangers before thee, and sojourners, as all our fathers: as a shadow our days upon the earth, and no expectation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">O Jehovah our God, all this multitude that we prepared to build to thee a house for thy holy name, it is from thy hand, and to thee the whole.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I knew, my God, that thou triest the heart, and from uprightness thou wilt delight. I in the uprightness of my heart gave willingly all these: and now thy people were found here; I saw with gladness to show themselves willing to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">O Jehovah the God of Abraham, Isaak, and Israel, our fathers, watch this forever to the formation of the thoughts of the heart of thy people, and prepare for their heart to thee:</verse>
  <verse number="19">And to Solomon my son wilt thou give a whole heart to watch thy commands, thy testimonies, and thy laws, and to do the whole, and to build the fortress which I prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And David will say to all the convocation, Praise ye now Jehovah your God. And all the convocation will praise to Jehovah the God of their fathers, and they will bow down and worship to God and the king.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they will sacrifice sacrifices to Jehovah, and they will bring up burnt-offerings to Jehovah for the morrow of that day, a thousand bullocks, a thousand rams, a thousand lambs, and their libations, and sacrifices for abundance for all Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="22">And they will eat and drink before Jehovah in that day with great gladness. And they will make the second time for Solomon son of David to be king, and they will anoint him to Jehovah for leader, and to Zadok for priest.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Solomon will sit upon the throne of Jehovah for king instead of David his father, and he will prosper; and all Israel will hear to him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And all the chiefs and the strong ones, and also all the sons of king David gave the hand under Solomon the king.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Jehovah will magnify Solomon to above before the eyes of all Israel, and he will give upon him the majesty of the kingdom which was not upon any king before him over Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And David son of Jesse reigned over all Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the days which he reigned over Israel were forty years; in Hebron he reigned seven years, and in Jerusalem he reigned thirty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he will die in a good old age, full of days, riches, and honor: and Solomon his son will reign in his stead.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And the first and the last words of David the king, behold them written upon the words of Samuel the seer, and upon the words of Nathan the prophet, and upon the words of Gad the seer,</verse>
  <verse number="30">With all his kingdom and his strength, and the times which passed over upon him and upon Israel, and upon all the kingdoms of the lands.</verse>
</chapter>