<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the sons of Reuben the first-born of Israel, (for he the firstborn; and in his defiling his father’s bed, the birth-right was given to the sons of Joseph the son of Israel; and not to be enrolled for the birthright.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For Judah was strong over his brethren, and for a leader from him; and the birthright to Joseph:)</verse>
  <verse number="3">The sons of Reuben, the first-born of Israel, Hanoch, and Pallu, Hezron and Carmi.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The sons of Joel: Shemaiah his son, Gog his son, Shimei his son,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Micah his son) Reaiah his son, Baal his son,</verse>
  <verse number="6">Beerah his son, whom Tilgath-Pileser king of Assur carried into exile: he the prince to the Reubenites.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And his brethren according to their families, (in the enrolling to their generations) the chief Jeiel and Zechariah,</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Bela son of Azaz, son of Shema son of Joel, he will dwell in Aroer, and even to Nebo, and Baal-Meon:</verse>
  <verse number="9">And to the sunrising he dwelt even to the coming from the desert from the river Phrath: for their cattle were multiplied in the land of Gilead.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And in the days of Saul they made war with the Hagarites, and they will fall by their hand: and they dwelt in their tents upon all the face from the sunrising to Gilead.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the sons of Gad dwelt before them in the land of Bashan and Salcah:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Joel the head, and Shapham the second, and Jaanai and Shaphat in Bashan.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And their brethren to the house of their fathers, Michael and Meshullam, and Sheba, and Jorai, and Jachan, and Zia, and Eber; seven.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Those the sons of Abihail son of Huri, son of Jaroah, son of Gilead, son of Michael, son of Jeshishai, son of Jahdo, son of Buz;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Ahi son of Abdiel, son of Guni, the head to the house of their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they dwelt in Gilead in Bashan, and in her daughters, and in all the areas of Sharon, upon their goings forth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">All these were enrolled in the days of Jotham king of Judah, and in the days of Jeroboam king of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The sons of Reuben and the Gadites, and half the tribe of Manasseh from the sons of strength, men lifting up shield and sword, and bending the bow, and accustomed to war; forty and four thousand and seven hundred and sixty going forth to war.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And they will make war with the Hagarites, and Jetur and Nephish, and Nodab.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And they will be helped against them, and the Hagarites will be given into their hand, and all with them: for they cried to God in the war, and he was entreated for them, for they trusted in him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they will take captive their cattle; their camels fifty thousand, and sheep two hundred and fifty thousand, and asses two thousand, and the soul of man, a hundred thousand.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For many fell down wounded, for the war was from God. And they dwelt in their stead even to the exile.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the sons of half the tribe of Manasseh dwelt in the land: from Bashan even to Baal-Hermon and Senir and mount Hermon they multiplied.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And these the heads of the house of their fathers: and Epher and Ishi, and Eliel, and Azriel, and Jeremiah, and Hodaviah, and Jandiel; mighty men of strength, men of names, heads to the house of their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And they will transgress against the God of their fathers, and they will commit fornication after the gods of the peoples of the land, which God destroyed from before them.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And the God of Israel will rouse up the spirit of Pul, king of Assur and the spirit of Tilgath-Pileser, king of Assur; and he will carry them into exile to the Reubenites and to the Gadites, and to half the tribe of Manasseh; and he will bring them to Halah, and Habor, and Hara, and the river Gozan, even to this day.</verse>
</chapter>