<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="6" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the sons of Levi: Gershon, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the sons of Kohath: Amram, Izhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the sons of Amram: Aaron and Moses and Miriam. And the sons of Aaron: Nadab, and Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Eleazar begat Phinehas, Phinehas begat Abishua,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Abishua begat Bukki, and Bukki begat Uzzi,</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Uzzi begat Zerahiah, and Zerahiah begat Meraioth,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Meraioth begat Amariah, and Amariah begat Ahitub,</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Ahitub begat Zadok, and Zadok begat Ahimaaz,</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Ahimaaz begat Azariah, and Azariah begat Johanan,</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Johanan begat Azariah, he who was the priest in the house that Solomon built in Jerusalem:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Azariah will beget Amariah, and Amariah begat Ahitub,</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Ahitub begat Zadok, and Zadok begat Shallum,</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Shallum begat Hilkiab, and Hilkiah begat Azariah,</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Azariah begat Seraiah, and Seraiah begat Jehozadek,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Jehozadek went away in Jehovah’s carrying away into exile Judah and Jerusalem by the hand of Nebuchadnezzar.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The sons of Levi: Gershom, hath and Merari.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And these the names of the sons of Gershom: Libni and Shimei.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the sons of Kohath, Amram and Izhar, and Hebron and Uzziel.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The sons of Merari: Mahli and Mushi. And these the families of the Levites according to their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="20">To Gershom: Libni his son, Jahath his son, Zimmah his son,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Joah his son, Iddo his son, Zerah his son, Jeaterai his son.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The sons of Kohath: Aminadab his son, Korah his son, Assir his son,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Elkanah his son, and Ebiasaph his son, and Assir his son,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Tahath his son, Uriel his son, Uzziah his son, and Saul his son.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the sons of Elkanah: Amasai, and Ahimoth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Elkanah, the sons of Elkanah Zophai his son and Nahath his son.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Eliab his son, Jeroham his son, Elkanah his son.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the sons of Samuel: the first-born, Vashni and Abiah.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The sons of Merari: Mahli, Libni his son, Shimei his son, Uzza his son,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Shimea his son, Haggish his son, Asaiah his son.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And these whom David set up over the hands of song of the house of Jehovah from the resting of the ark.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they will be serving before the dwelling of the tent of appointment in song even till Solomon built the house of Jehovah in Jerusalem: and they will stand according to their judgment over their service.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And these standing and their sons. From the sons of the Kohathites: Heman singing, son of Joel, son of Samuel,</verse>
  <verse number="34">Son of Elkanah, son of Jeroham, son of Eliel, son of Toah,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Son of Zuph, son of Elkanah, son of Mahath, son of Amasai,</verse>
  <verse number="36">Son of Elkanah, son of Joel, son of Azariah, son of Zephaniah,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Son of Tahath, son of Assir, son of Ebiasaph, son of Korah,</verse>
  <verse number="38">Son of Izhar, son of Kohath, son of Levi, son of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And his brother Asaph standing at his right hand, Asaph the son of Berachiah the son of Shimea,</verse>
  <verse number="40">The son of Michael, the son of Baaseiah, the son of Malchiah,</verse>
  <verse number="41">The son of Ethni, the son of Zerah, the son of Adaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="42">The son of Ethan, son of Zimmah, son of Shimei,</verse>
  <verse number="43">Son of Jahath, son of Gershom, son of Levi.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And the sons of Merari their brethren at the left: Ethan son of Kishi, son of Abdi, son of Malluch,</verse>
  <verse number="45">Son of Hashabiah, son of Amaziah, son of Hilkiah,</verse>
  <verse number="46">Son of Amzi, son of Bath, son of Shamer,</verse>
  <verse number="47">Son of Mahli, son of Mushi, son of Merari, son of Levi.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And their brethren the Levites being given to all the service of the dwelling of the house of God.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Aaron and his sons burning incense upon the altar of the burnt-offering, and upon the altar of incense for all the work of the holy of holies, and to expiate for Israel according to all that Moses the servant of God commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And these the sons of Aaron: Eleazar his son, Phinehas his son, Abishua his son,</verse>
  <verse number="51">Bukki his son, Uzzi his son, Zerahiah his son,</verse>
  <verse number="52">Moraioth his son, Amariah his son, Ahitub his son,</verse>
  <verse number="53">Zadok his son, Ahimaaz his son.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And these their dwellings for their walls in their bound to the sons of Aaron to the families to the Kohathites: for to them was the lot.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And they will give to them Hebron in the land of Judah, and its areas round about it.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And the field of the city and its enclosures they gave to Caleb son of Jephunneh,</verse>
  <verse number="57">And to the sons of Aaron they gave the cities of refuge, Hebron and Libnah and her areas, and Jattir and Eshtemoa, and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="58">And Hilen and her areas, and Debir and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="59">And Ashan and her areas, and the house of the sun and her areas:</verse>
  <verse number="60">And from the tribe of Benjamin: Geba and her areas, and Alemeth and her areas, and Anathoth and her areas. All their cities thirteen cities in their families.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And to the sons of Kohath being left from the family of the tribe from the half tribe, the half of Manasseh, by lot, ten cities.</verse>
  <verse number="62">And to the sons of Gershom for their families from the tribe of Issachar, and from the tribe of Asher, and from the tribe of Naphtali, and from the tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities.</verse>
  <verse number="63">To the sons of Merari for their families from the tribe of Reuben, and from the tribe of Gad, and from the tribe of Zebulon, by lot, twelve cities.</verse>
  <verse number="64">And the sons of Israel will give to the Levites cities and their areas.</verse>
  <verse number="65">And they will give by lot from the tribe of the sons of Judah, and from the tribe of the sons of Simeon, and from the tribe of the sons of Benjamin, these cities which they called them by names.</verse>
  <verse number="66">And from the families of the sons of Kohath and there will be cities of their bound from the tribe of the sons of Ephraim.</verse>
  <verse number="67">And they will give to them the cities of refuge, Shechem and her areas in mount Ephraim and Gezer and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="68">And Jokmeam and her areas, and the house of the hollow and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="69">And Ajalon and her areas, and Gath-Rimmon and her areas.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And from the half tribe of Manasseh: Aner and her areas, and Bileam and her areas for the families remaining to the sons of Kohath.</verse>
  <verse number="71">To the sons of Gershom from the families of half the tribe of Manasseh, Golan in Bashan and her areas and Ashtaroth and her areas:</verse>
  <verse number="72">And from the tribe of Issachar: Kadesh and her areas, Daberah and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="73">And Ramoth and her areas, and Anem and her areas:</verse>
  <verse number="74">And from the tribe of Asher: Mashal and her areas, and Abdon and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="75">And Hukok and her areas, and Rehob and her areas;</verse>
  <verse number="76">And from the tribe of Naphtali: Kadesh in Galilee and her areas, and Hammon and her areas, and Kirjathaim and her areas.</verse>
  <verse number="77">To the sons of Merari remaining from the tribe of Zebulon Rimmon and her areas, Tabor and her areas:</verse>
  <verse number="78">And from beyond Jordan of Jericho to the sunrising of Jordan, from the tribe of Reuben, Bezer in the desert and her areas, and Jahzah and her areas,</verse>
  <verse number="79">And Kedemoth and her areas, and Mephaath and her areas.</verse>
  <verse number="80">And from the tribe of Gad: Ramoth in Gilead and her areas, and Mahanaim and her areas.</verse>
  <verse number="81">And Heshbon and her areas, and Jazer and her areas.</verse>
</chapter>