<chapter book="Nahum" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The hammer came up upon thy face: press upon the fortress, look about the way, strengthen the loins, make the power strong greatly.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For Jehovah turned back the pride of Jacob as the pride of Israel: for they emptying emptied them out, they corrupted their vine-shoots.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The shield of the strong ones being red, the men of strength being clothed in scarlet: with fire of irons the chariots in the day of his preparing, and the cypresses were made to tremble.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The chariots shall be mad in the streets, they shall run up and down in the broad places: their appearance as flames; as lightnings shall they run.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He shall make mention of his chiefs: they shall be weak in their goings; they shall hasten to her wall, and the covering was prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The gates of the rivers were opened, and the temple melted away.</verse>
  <verse number="7">It was fixed, she was led away captive, she went up and her maids being led as the voice of doves smiting upon their heart.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Nineveh it is as a pool of water from the days, and they fleeing, stood: they stood, and none looking back.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They plundered silver, they plundered gold: and no end to her splendid equipage; glory from all the vessels of desire.</verse>
  <verse number="10">She was emptied, and being emptied, and being made empty: and the heart melted, and a wavering of the knees, and trembling in all loins, and the face of them all gathered a glow.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Where is the dwelling of the lions and that pasture for the young lions where the lion went, the lioness there, the lion’s whelp, and none terrifying?</verse>
  <verse number="12">The lion tore in pieces the sufficiency of his whelps, and strangling for his lionesses; and his holes shall be filled with the prey, and his dens with that torn in pieces.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Behold me against thee, says Jehovah of armies; and I burnt her chariot in the smoke, and the sword shall devour thy young lions, and I cut of thy prey from the land, and the voice of her messengers shall no more be heard.</verse>
</chapter>