<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="1" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, called to be an apostle of Jesus Christ through the will of God, and Sosthenes our brother,</verse>
  <verse number="2">unto the church of God which is at Corinth, even them that are sanctified in Christ Jesus, called to be saints, with all that call upon the name of our Lord Jesus Christ in every place, their Lord and ours:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="4">I thank my God always concerning you, for the grace of God which was given you in Christ Jesus;</verse>
  <verse number="5">that in everything ye were enriched in him, in all utterance and all knowledge;</verse>
  <verse number="6">even as the testimony of Christ was confirmed in you:</verse>
  <verse number="7">so that ye come behind in no gift; waiting for the revelation of our Lord Jesus Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="8">who shall also confirm you unto the end, that ye be unreproveable in the day of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="9">God is faithful, through whom ye were called into the fellowship of his Son Jesus Christ our Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now I beseech you, brethren, through the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that ye all speak the same thing, and that there be no divisions among you; but that ye be perfected together in the same mind and in the same judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For it hath been signified unto me concerning you, my brethren, by them which are of the household of Chloe, that there are contentions among you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now this I mean, that each one of you saith, I am of Paul; and I of Apollos; and I of Cephas; and I of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Is Christ divided? was Paul crucified for you? or were ye baptized into the name of Paul?</verse>
  <verse number="14">I thank God that I baptized none of you, save Crispus and Gaius;</verse>
  <verse number="15">lest any man should say that ye were baptized into my name.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And I baptized also the household of Stephanas: besides, I know not whether I baptized any other.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For Christ sent me not to baptize, but to preach the gospel: not in wisdom of words, lest the cross of Christ should be made void.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the word of the cross is to them that are perishing foolishness; but unto us which are being saved it is the power of God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For it is written, I will destroy the wisdom of the wise, And the prudence of the prudent will I reject.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Where is the wise? where is the scribe? where is the disputer of this world? hath not God made foolish the wisdom of the world?</verse>
  <verse number="21">For seeing that in the wisdom of God the world through its wisdom knew not God, it was God’s good pleasure through the foolishness of the preaching to save them that believe.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Seeing that Jews ask for signs, and Greeks seek after wisdom:</verse>
  <verse number="23">but we preach Christ crucified, unto Jews a stumblingblock, and unto Gentiles foolishness;</verse>
  <verse number="24">but unto them that are called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God, and the wisdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Because the foolishness of God is wiser than men; and the weakness of God is stronger than men.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For behold your calling, brethren, how that not many wise after the flesh, not many mighty, not many noble, are called:</verse>
  <verse number="27">but God chose the foolish things of the world, that he might put to shame them that are wise; and God chose the weak things of the world, that he might put to shame the things that are strong;</verse>
  <verse number="28">and the base things of the world, and the things that are despised, did God choose, yea and the things that are not, that he might bring to nought the things that are:</verse>
  <verse number="29">that no flesh should glory before God.</verse>
  <verse number="30">But of him are ye in Christ Jesus, who was made unto us wisdom from God, and righteousness and sanctification, and redemption:</verse>
  <verse number="31">that, according as it is written, He that glorieth, let him glory in the Lord.</verse>
</chapter>