<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="8" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now concerning things sacrificed to idols: We know that we all have knowledge. Knowledge puffeth up, but love edifieth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">If any man thinketh that he knoweth anything, he knoweth not yet as he ought to know;</verse>
  <verse number="3">but if any man loveth God, the same is known of him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Concerning therefore the eating of things sacrificed to idols, we know that no idol is anything in the world, and that there is no God but one.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For though there be that are called gods, whether in heaven or on earth; as there are gods many, and lords many;</verse>
  <verse number="6">yet to us there is one God, the Father, of whom are all things, and we unto him; and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things, and we through him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Howbeit in all men there is not that knowledge: but some, being used until now to the idol, eat as of a thing sacrificed to an idol; and their conscience being weak is defiled.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But meat will not commend us to God: neither, if we eat not, are we the worse; nor, if we eat, are we the better.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But take heed lest by any means this liberty of yours become a stumblingblock to the weak.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For if a man see thee which hast knowledge sitting at meat in an idol’s temple, will not his conscience, if he is weak, be emboldened to eat things sacrificed to idols?</verse>
  <verse number="11">For through thy knowledge he that is weak perisheth, the brother for whose sake Christ died.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And thus, sinning against the brethren, and wounding their conscience when it is weak, ye sin against Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore, if meat maketh my brother to stumble, I will eat no flesh for evermore, that I make not my brother to stumble.</verse>
</chapter>