<chapter book="Galatians" number="5" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Stand firm, and do not be willing to be again held by the yoke of servitude.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Behold, I, Paul, say to you, that if you have been circumcised, Christ will be of no benefit to you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For I again testify, about every man circumcising himself, that he is obligated to act according to the entire law.</verse>
  <verse number="4">You are being emptied of Christ, you who are being justified by the law. You have fallen from grace.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For in spirit, by faith, we await the hope of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For in Christ Jesus, neither circumcision nor uncircumcision prevails over anything, but only faith which works through charity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">You have run well. So what has impeded you, that you would not obey the truth?</verse>
  <verse number="8">This kind of influence is not from him who is calling you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A little leaven corrupts the whole mass.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I have confidence in you, in the Lord, that you will accept nothing of the kind. However, he who disturbs you shall bear the judgment, whomever he may be.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And as for me, brothers, if I still preach circumcision, why am I still suffering persecution? For then the scandal of the Cross would be made empty.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I wish that those who disturb you would be torn away.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For you, brothers, have been called to liberty. Only you must not make liberty into an occasion for the flesh, but instead, serve one another through the charity of the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the entire law is fulfilled by one word: “You shall love your neighbor as yourself.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">But if you bite and devour one another, be careful that you are not consumed by one another!</verse>
  <verse number="16">So then, I say: Walk in the spirit, and you will not fulfill the desires of the flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the flesh desires against the spirit, and the spirit against the flesh. And since these are against one another, you may not do whatever you want.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But if you are led by the Spirit, you are not under the law.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Now the works of the flesh are manifest; they are: fornication, lust, homosexuality, self-indulgence,</verse>
  <verse number="20">the serving of idols, drug use, hostility, contentiousness, jealousy, wrath, quarrels, dissensions, divisions,</verse>
  <verse number="21">envy, murder, inebriation, carousing, and similar things. About these things, I continue to preach to you, as I have preached to you: that those who act in this way shall not obtain the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But the fruit of the Spirit is charity, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, forbearance,</verse>
  <verse number="23">meekness, faith, modesty, abstinence, chastity. There is no law against such things.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For those who are Christ’s have crucified their flesh, along with its vices and desires.</verse>
  <verse number="25">If we live by the Spirit, we should also walk by the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Let us not become desirous of empty glory, provoking one another, envying one another.</verse>
</chapter>