<chapter book="Proverbs" number="13" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A WISE son heareth his father’s instruction: but a scorner heareth not rebuke.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A man shall eat good by the fruit of his mouth: but the soul of the treacherous shall eat violence.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He that guardeth his mouth keepeth his life: but he that openeth wide his lips shall have destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The soul of the sluggard desireth, and hath nothing: but the soul of the diligent shall be made fat.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A righteous man hateth lying: but a wicked man is loathsome, and cometh to shame.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Righteousness guardeth him that is upright in the way: but wickedness overthroweth the sinner.</verse>
  <verse number="7">There is that maketh himself rich, yet hath nothing: there is that maketh himself poor, yet hath great wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The ransom of a man’s life is his riches: but the poor heareth no threatening.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The light of the righteous rejoiceth: but the lamp of the wicked shall be put out.</verse>
  <verse number="10">By pride cometh only contention: but with the well advised is wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wealth gotten by vanity shall be diminished: but he that gathereth by labour shall have increase.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Hope deferred maketh the heart sick: but when the desire cometh, it is a tree of life.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso despiseth the word bringeth destruction on himself: but he that feareth the commandment shall be rewarded.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The law of the wise is a fountain of life, to depart from the snares of death.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Good understanding giveth favour: but the way of the treacherous is rugged.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Every prudent man worketh with knowledge: but a fool spreadeth out folly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A wicked messenger falleth into evil: but a faithful ambassador is health.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Poverty and shame shall be to him that refuseth correction: but he that regardeth reproof shall be honoured.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The desire accomplished is sweet to the soul: but it is an abomination to fools to depart from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Walk with wise men, and thou shalt be wise: but the companion of fools shall smart for it.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Evil pursueth sinners: but the righteous shall be recompensed with good.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A good man leaveth an inheritance to his children’s children; and the wealth of the sinner is laid up for the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Much food is in the tillage of the poor: but there is that is destroyed by reason of injustice.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He that spareth his rod hateth his son: but he that loveth him chasteneth him betimes.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The righteous eateth to the satisfying of his soul: but the belly of the wicked shall want.</verse>
</chapter>