<chapter book="Proverbs" number="16" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The preparations of the heart belong to man: but the answer of the tongue is from the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="2">All the ways of a man are clean in his own eyes: but the LORD weigheth the spirits.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Commit thy works unto the LORD, and thy thoughts shall be established.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The LORD hath made every thing for its own end: yea, even the wicked for the day of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Every one that is proud in heart is an abomination to the LORD: though hand join in hand, he shall not be unpunished.</verse>
  <verse number="6">By mercy and truth iniquity is purged: and by the fear of the LORD men depart from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="7">When a man’s ways please the LORD, he maketh even his enemies to be at peace with him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Better is a little with righteousness than great revenues with injustice.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A man’s heart deviseth his way: but the LORD directeth his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A divine sentence is in the lips of the king: his mouth shall not transgress in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A just balance and scales are the LORD’S: all the weights of the bag are his work.</verse>
  <verse number="12">It is an abomination to kings to commit wickedness: for the throne is established by righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Righteous lips are the delight or kings; and they love him that speaketh right.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The wrath of a king is as messengers of death: but a wise man will pacify it.</verse>
  <verse number="15">In the light of the king’s countenance is life; and his favour is as a cloud of the latter rain.</verse>
  <verse number="16">How much better is it to get wisdom than gold! yea, to get understanding is rather to be chosen than silver.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The highway of the upright is to depart from evil: he that keepeth his way preserveth his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Pride goeth before destruction, and an haughty spirit before a fall.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Better it is to be of a lowly spirit with the poor, than to divide the spoil with the proud.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He that giveth heed unto the word shall find good: and whoso trusteth in the LORD, happy is he.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The wise in heart shall be called prudent: and the sweetness of the lips increaseth learning.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Understanding is a wellspring of life unto him that hath it: but the correction of fools is their folly.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The heart of the wise instructeth his mouth, and addeth learning to his lips.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Pleasant words are as an honeycomb, sweet to the soul, and health to the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="25">There is a way which seemeth right unto a man, but the end thereof are the ways of death.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The appetite of the labouring man laboureth for him; for his mouth craveth it of him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">A worthless man deviseth mischief: and in his lips there is as a scorching fire.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A froward man scattereth abroad strife: and a whisperer separateth chief friends.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A man of violence enticeth his neighbour, and leadeth him in a way that is not good.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He that shutteth his eyes, it is to devise froward things: he that compresseth his lips bringeth evil to pass.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The hoary head is a crown of glory, it shall be found in the way of righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty; and he that ruleth his spirit than he that taketh a city.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The lot is cast into the lap; but the whole disposing thereof is of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>