<chapter book="Proverbs" number="23" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When thou sittest to eat with a ruler, consider diligently him that is before thee;</verse>
  <verse number="2">And put a knife to thy throat, if thou be a man given to appetite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Be not desirous of his dainties; seeing they are deceitful meat.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Weary not thyself to be rich; cease from thine own wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Wilt thou set thine eyes upon that which is not? for riches certainly make themselves wings, like an eagle that flieth toward heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Eat thou not the bread of him that hath an evil eye, neither desire thou his dainties:</verse>
  <verse number="7">For as he reckoneth within himself, so is he: Eat and drink, saith he to thee; but his heart is not with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The morsel which thou hast eaten shalt thou vomit up, and lose thy sweet words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Speak not in the hearing of a fool; for he will despise the wisdom of thy words.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Remove not the ancient landmark; and enter not into the fields of the fatherless:</verse>
  <verse number="11">For their redeemer is strong; he shall plead their cause against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Apply thine heart unto instruction, and thine ears to the words of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Withhold not correction from the child: for if thou beat him with the rod, he shall not die.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thou shalt beat him with the rod, and shalt deliver his soul from Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, if thine heart be wise, my heart shall be glad, even mine:</verse>
  <verse number="16">Yea, my reins shall rejoice, when thy lips speak right things.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let not thine heart envy sinners: but be thou in the fear of the LORD all the day long:</verse>
  <verse number="18">For surely there is a reward; and thy hope shall not be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Hear thou, my son, and be wise, and guide thine heart in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Be not among winebibbers; among gluttonous eaters of flesh:</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the drunkard and the glutton shall come to poverty: and drowsiness shall clothe a man with rags.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Hearken unto thy father that begat thee, and despise not thy mother when she is old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Buy the truth, and sell it not; yea, wisdom, and instruction, and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The father of the righteous shall greatly rejoice: and he that begetteth a wise child shall have joy of him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let thy father and thy mother be glad, and let her that bare thee rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="26">My son, give me thine heart, and let thine eyes delight in my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For a whore is a deep ditch; and a strange woman is a narrow pit.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Yea, she lieth in wait as a robber, and increaseth the treacherous among men.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Who hath woe? who hath sorrow? who hath contentions? who hath complaining? who hath wounds without cause? who hath redness of eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="30">They that tarry long at the wine; they that go to seek out mixed wine.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Look not thou upon the wine when it is red, when it giveth its colour in the cup, when it goeth down smoothly.</verse>
  <verse number="32">At the last it biteth like a serpent, and stingeth like an adder.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Thine eyes shall behold strange things, and thine heart shall utter froward things.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Yea, thou shalt be as he that lieth down in the midst of the sea, or as he that lieth upon the top of a mast.</verse>
  <verse number="35">They have stricken me, shalt thou say, and I was not hurt; they have beaten me, and I felt it not: when shall I awake? I will seek it yet again.</verse>
</chapter>