<chapter book="Proverbs" number="10" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A wise son gladdens the father. Yet truly, a foolish son is the grief of his mother.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Treasures of impiety will profit nothing. Truly, justice shall liberate from death.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The Lord will not afflict with famine the soul of the just, and he will overthrow the treacheries of the impious.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The neglectful hand has wrought destitution. But the hand of the steadfast prepares riches. He who advances by lies, this one feeds on the wind. For he is the same as one who runs after flying birds.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He who gathers the harvest is a wise son. But he who snores in warm weather is a son of confusion.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The blessing of the Lord is on the head of the just. But iniquity covers the mouth of the impious.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The remembrance of the just is with praises. And the name of the impious shall decay.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The wise of heart accept precepts. The foolish are cut down by the lips.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He who walks in simplicity walks in confidence. But he who corrupts his ways shall be discovered.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He who winks with the eye gives sorrow. And the foolish in lips shall be beaten.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The mouth of the just is a vein of life. And the mouth of the impious covers iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Hatred rises up from disputes. And charity covers all offenses.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In the lips of the wise, wisdom is discovered. And a rod is for the back of one who lacks heart.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The wise store away knowledge. But the mouth of the foolish is a neighbor to confusion.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The substance of the rich is the city of his strength. The fear of the poor is their destitution.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The work of the just is unto life. But the fruit of the impious is unto sin.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The way of life is for those who observe discipline. But whoever abandons correction wanders astray.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Lying lips conceal hatred; whoever brings forth contempt is unwise.</verse>
  <verse number="19">In a multitude of speaking, sin will not be lacking. But whoever tempers his lips is most prudent.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The tongue of the just is choice silver. But the heart of the impious is exchanged for nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The lips of the just instruct many. But those who are unlearned shall die in destitution of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The blessing of the Lord causes riches. Affliction will not be a companion to them.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The foolish work wickedness as if in jest. But wisdom is prudence to a man.</verse>
  <verse number="24">What the impious fear will overwhelm them. The just shall be given their desire.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Like a passing tempest, so the impious one will be no more. But the just one is like an everlasting foundation.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Like vinegar to the teeth, and smoke to the eyes, so is a lazy one to those who sent him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The fear of the Lord adds days. And the years of the impious will be shortened.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The expectation of the just is rejoicing. But the hope of the impious will perish.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The strength of the simple is the way of the Lord, and it is fear to those who work evil.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The just in eternity shall not be moved. But the impious will not live upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The mouth of the just shall bring forth wisdom. The tongue of the depraved will perish.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The lips of the just consider what is acceptable. And the mouth of the impious considers perversities.</verse>
</chapter>