<chapter book="Proverbs" number="2" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if you would accept my words, and conceal my commandments within you,</verse>
  <verse number="2">so that your ears may listen to wisdom, then bend your heart in order to know prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For if you would call upon wisdom and bend your heart to prudence,</verse>
  <verse number="4">if you will seek her like money, and dig for her as if for treasure,</verse>
  <verse number="5">then you will understand the fear of the Lord, and you will discover the knowledge of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For the Lord bestows wisdom, and out of his mouth, prudence and knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He will preserve the salvation of the righteous, and he will protect those who walk in simplicity:</verse>
  <verse number="8">serving the paths of justice, and guarding the ways of sanctity.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then you shall understand justice and judgment, and equity, and every good path.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If wisdom is to enter into your heart, and if knowledge is to become pleasing to your soul,</verse>
  <verse number="11">then counsel must guard you, and prudence must serve you,</verse>
  <verse number="12">so that you may be rescued from the evil way, and from the man who speaks perversities,</verse>
  <verse number="13">from those who leave the straight path to walk in dark ways,</verse>
  <verse number="14">who rejoice when they have done evil, and who exult in the most wicked things.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Their ways are perverse, and their steps are infamous.</verse>
  <verse number="16">So may you be rescued from the foreign woman, and from the outsider, who softens her speech,</verse>
  <verse number="17">and who leaves behind the Guide of her youth,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and who has forgotten the covenant of her God. For her household inclines toward death, and her paths toward Hell.</verse>
  <verse number="19">All those who enter to her will not return again, nor will they take hold of the paths of life.</verse>
  <verse number="20">So may you walk in the good way, and keep to the difficult paths of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For those who are upright shall live upon the earth, and the simple shall continue upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Yet truly, the impious shall perish from the earth, and those who act unjustly shall be taken away from it.</verse>
</chapter>