<chapter book="Proverbs" number="25" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">These, too, are parables of Solomon, which the men of Hezekiah, king of Judah, transferred.</verse>
  <verse number="2">It is to the glory of God to conceal a word, and it is to the glory of kings to investigate speech.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Heaven above, and earth below, and the heart of kings are each unsearchable.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Take away the tarnish from silver, and a most pure vessel will go forth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Take away impiety from the face of the king, and his throne shall be made firm by justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Do not appear glorious before the king, and do not stand in the place of the great.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For it is better that it should be said to you, “Ascend to here,” than that you should be humbled before the prince.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The things that your eyes have seen, do not offer hastily in a quarrel, lest afterward you may not be able to make amends, when you have dishonored your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Argue your case with your friend, and do not reveal the secret to an outsider,</verse>
  <verse number="10">lest perhaps he may insult you, when he has heard it, and he might not cease to reproach you. Grace and friendship free a man; preserve these for yourself, lest you fall under reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Whoever speaks a word at an opportune time is like apples of gold on beds of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Whoever reproves the wise and obedient ear is like an earring of gold with a shining pearl.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Just like the cold of snow in a time of harvest, so also is a faithful messenger to him who sent him: he causes his soul to rest.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A man who boasts and does not fulfill his promises is like clouds and wind, when rain does not follow.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By patience, a leader shall be appeased, and a soft tongue shall break hardness.</verse>
  <verse number="16">You have discovered honey; eat what is sufficient for you, lest perhaps, being filled up, you may vomit it.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Withdraw your feet from the house of your neighbor, lest, when he has had his fill, he may hate you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A man who speaks false testimony against his neighbor is like a dart and a sword and a sharp arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Whoever sets his hopes on the unfaithful in a day of anguish is like a rotten tooth and weary foot,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and like one who loosens his garment in cold weather. Whoever sings verses to a wicked heart is like vinegar on baking soda. Just like a moth to a garment, and a worm to wood, so too does the sadness of a man do harm to the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If your enemy is hungry, feed him. If he is thirsty, give him water to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For you will gather hot coals upon his head, and the Lord will repay you.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The north wind brings forth the rain, and a sorrowful face brings forth a detracting tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">It is better to sit in a corner of the attic, than with an argumentative woman and in a shared house.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Like cold water to a thirsty soul, so too are good reports from a far away land.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The just falling down before the impious is like a fountain stirred up by feet and like a corrupted spring.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Just as whoever eats too much honey, it is not good for him, so also whoever is an investigator of what is majestic will be overwhelmed by glory.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Just like a city lying in the open and without surrounding walls, so also is a man who is unable to restrain his own spirit in speaking.</verse>
</chapter>