<chapter book="Proverbs" number="26" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">In the manner of snow in the summer, and rain at the harvest, so also is glory unfit for the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Like a bird flying away to another place, and like a sparrow that hurries away freely, so also a curse uttered against someone without cause will pass away.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A whip is for a horse, and a muzzle is for donkey, and a rod is for the back of the imprudent.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Do not respond to the foolish according to his folly, lest you become like him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Respond to the foolish according to his folly, lest he imagine himself to be wise.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whoever sends words by a foolish messenger has lame feet and drinks iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In the manner of a lame man who has beautiful legs to no purpose, so also is a parable unfit for the mouth of the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Just like one who casts a stone into the pile of Mercury, so also is he who gives honor to the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="9">In the manner of a thorn, if it were to spring up from the hand of a drunkard, so also is a parable in the mouth of the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Judgment determines cases. And whoever imposes silence on the foolish mitigates anger.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Like a dog that returns to his vomit, so also is the imprudent who repeats his foolishness.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Have you seen a man who seems wise to himself? There will be greater hope held for the unwise than for him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The lazy one says, “There is a lion along the way, and a lioness in the roads.”</verse>
  <verse number="14">Just as a door turns upon its hinges, so also does the lazy one turn upon his bed.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The lazy one conceals his hand under his arms, and it is a labor for him to move it to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The lazy one seems wiser to himself than seven men speaking judgments.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Just like one who takes hold of a dog by the ears, so also is he who crosses impatiently and meddles in the quarrels of another.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Just as he is guilty who let loose the arrows and the lances unto death,</verse>
  <verse number="19">so also is the man who harms his friend by deceitfulness. And when he has been apprehended, he says, “I did it jokingly.”</verse>
  <verse number="20">When the wood fails, the fire will be extinguished. And when the gossiper is taken away, conflicts will be quelled.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Just as charcoals are to burning coals, and wood is to fire, so also is an angry man who stirs up quarrels.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The words of a whisperer seem simple, but they penetrate to the innermost parts of the self.</verse>
  <verse number="23">In the same manner as an earthen vessel, if it were adorned with impure silver, conceited lips are allied with a wicked heart.</verse>
  <verse number="24">An enemy is known by his lips, though it is from his heart that he draws out deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="25">When he will have lowered his voice, do not believe him, for there are seven vices in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Whoever covers hatred with deceit, his malice shall be revealed in the assembly.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whoever digs a pit will fall into it. And whoever rolls a stone, it will roll back to him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A false tongue does not love truth. And a slippery mouth works ruin.</verse>
</chapter>