<chapter book="Proverbs" number="27" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Do not boast about tomorrow, for you do not know what the future day may bring.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Let another praise you, and not your own mouth: an outsider, and not your own lips.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A stone is weighty, and sand is burdensome; but the wrath of the foolish is heavier than both.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Anger holds no mercy, nor does fury when it erupts. And who can bear the assault of one who has been provoked?</verse>
  <verse number="5">An open rebuke is better than hidden love.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The wounds of a loved one are better than the deceitful kisses of a hateful one.</verse>
  <verse number="7">A sated soul will trample the honeycomb. And a hungry soul will accept even bitter in place of sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Just like a bird migrating from her nest, so also is a man who abandons his place.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Ointment and various perfumes delight the heart. And the good advice of a friend is sweet to the soul.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Do not dismiss your friend or your father’s friend. And do not enter your brother’s house in the day of your affliction. A close neighbor is better than a distant brother.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, study wisdom, and rejoice my heart, so that you may be able to respond to the one who reproaches.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The discerning man, seeing evil, hides himself. The little ones, continuing on, sustain losses.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Take away the garment of him who has vouched for an outsider. And take a pledge from him on behalf of foreigners.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Whoever blesses his neighbor with a grand voice, rising in the night, shall be like one who curses.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A roof leaking on a cold day, and an argumentative woman, are comparable.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He who would restrain her, he is like one who would grasp the wind, or who would gather together oil with his right hand.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Iron sharpens iron, and a man sharpens the countenance of his friend.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Whoever maintains the fig tree shall eat its fruit. And whoever is the keeper of his master shall be glorified.</verse>
  <verse number="19">In the manner of faces looking into shining water, so are the hearts of men made manifest to the prudent.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Hell and perdition are never filled; similarly the eyes of men are insatiable.</verse>
  <verse number="21">In the manner of silver being tested in the refinery, and gold in the furnace, so also is a man tested by the mouth of one who praises. The heart of the iniquitous inquires after evils, but the heart of the righteous inquires after knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Even if you were to crush the foolish with a mortar, as when a pestle strikes over pearled barley, his foolishness would not be taken from him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Be diligent to know the countenance of your cattle, and consider your own flocks,</verse>
  <verse number="24">for you will not always hold this power. But a crown shall be awarded from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The meadows are open, and the green plants have appeared, and the hay has been collected from the mountains.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Lambs are for your clothing, and goats are for the price of a field.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Let the milk of goats be sufficient for your food, and for the necessities of your household, and for the provisions of your handmaids.</verse>
</chapter>