<chapter book="Proverbs" number="28" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The impious flees, though no one pursues. But the just, like a confident lion, shall be without dread.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Because of the sins of the land, it has many princes. And because of the wisdom of a man, and the knowledge of those things that are said, the life of the leader shall be prolonged.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A poor man slandering the poor is like a violent rainstorm in advance of a famine.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Those who abandon the law praise the impious. Those who guard it are inflamed against him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Evil men do not intend judgment. But those who inquire after the Lord turn their souls toward all things.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Better is the pauper walking in his simplicity, than the rich walking in ways of depravity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Whoever keeps the law is a wise son. But whoever feeds gluttons brings shame to his father.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Whoever piles up riches by usury and profit gathers them for him who will give freely to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whoever turns away his ears from listening to the law: his prayer will be detestable.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Whoever deceives the just in a malicious way will fall into his own perdition. And the simple shall possess his goods.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The rich one seems wise to himself. But the poor one, being prudent, shall evaluate him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">In the exultation of the just, there is great glory. When the impious reign, men are brought to ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoever hides his crimes will not be guided. But whoever will have confessed and abandoned them shall overtake mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Blessed is the man who is ever fearful. Yet truly, whoever is hardened in mind will fall into evil.</verse>
  <verse number="15">An impious leader over a poor people is like a roaring lion and a hungry bear.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A leader destitute of prudence will oppress many through false accusations. But whoever hates avarice shall prolong his days.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A man who slanders the blood of a life, even if he flees to the pit, no one will tolerate him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Whoever walks simply shall be saved. Whoever is perverse in his steps will fall all at once.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Whoever works his land shall be satisfied with bread. But whoever pursues leisure will be filled with need.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A faithful man shall be greatly praised. But whoever rushes to become rich will not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Whoever shows favoritism in judgment does not do well; even if it is for a morsel of bread, he forsakes the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A man who hurries to become rich, and who envies others, does not know that destitution will overwhelm him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Whoever corrects a man, afterward he shall find favor with him, more so than he who deceives him with a flattering tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Whoever takes away anything from his father or mother, and who says, “This is not a sin,” is the associate of a murderer.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Whoever boasts and enlarges himself stirs up conflicts. Yet truly, whoever trusts in the Lord will be healed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Whoever trusts in his own heart is a fool. But whoever treads wisely, the same shall be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whoever gives to the poor shall not be in need. Whoever despises his petition will suffer scarcity.</verse>
  <verse number="28">When the impious rise up, men will hide themselves. When they perish, the just shall be multiplied.</verse>
</chapter>