<chapter book="Proverbs" number="3" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, do not forget my law, but let your heart guard my precepts.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For they shall set before you length of days, and years of life, and peace.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let not mercy and truth abandon you: encircle them around your throat, and inscribe them on the tablets of your heart.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And so shall you discover grace and good discipline, in the sight of God and men.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Have confidence in the Lord with all your heart, and do not depend upon your own prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In all your ways, consider him, and he himself will direct your steps.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Do not seem wise to yourself. Fear God, and withdraw from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Certainly, it shall be health to your navel, and refreshment to your bones.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Honor the Lord with your substance, and give to him from the first of all your fruits,</verse>
  <verse number="10">and then your storehouses will be filled with abundance, and your presses shall overflow with wine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, do not discard the discipline of the Lord, and do not fall away when you are corrected by him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For whomever the Lord loves, he corrects, and just as a father does with a son, he wins him over.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Blessed is the man who finds wisdom and who advances to prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Her acquisition is better than trading in silver, and her fruit is better than the first and purest gold.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She is more precious than all riches, and all that can be desired cannot prevail in comparison to her.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Length of days is at her right hand, and at her left hand is wealth and glory.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Her ways are beautiful ways, and all her paths are peaceful.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She is a tree of life to those who overtake her, and he who shall take hold of her is blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The Lord founded the earth on wisdom. He secured the heavens with prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By his wisdom, the abyss erupted and the clouds increased with dew.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, let not these things move away from your eyes. Preserve law as well as counsel.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And so shall there be life in your soul and grace in your voice.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then you shall walk confidently in your way, and your feet will not stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When you slumber, you shall not fear. When you rest, your sleep also will be sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Do not fear unexpected terror, nor the power of the impious falling upon you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the Lord will be at your side, and he will guard your feet, so that you may not be seized.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Do not prevent him who is able from doing good. When you are able, do good yourself too.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Do not say to your friend: “Go away, and then return. Tomorrow I will give to you.” When you are able to do so, give in the present.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Do not undertake evil against your friend, even though he has trust in you.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Do not contend against a man without cause, even though he has done no evil to you.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Do not rival an unjust man, and do not imitate his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For everyone who ridicules is an abomination to the Lord, and his communication is for the simple.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Destitution in the house of the impious is from the Lord. But the habitations of the just shall be blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="34">He will ridicule those who ridicule, but he will bestow grace upon the mild.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The wise will possess glory. The exaltation of the foolish is disgraceful.</verse>
</chapter>