<chapter book="Proverbs" number="31" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of king Lamuel. The vision by which his mother instructed him:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“What, O my beloved? What, O beloved of my womb? What, O beloved of my vows?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do not give your substance to women, or your riches to overthrow kings.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Not to kings, O Lamuel, not to kings give wine. For there are no secrets where drunkenness reigns.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And perhaps they may drink and forget judgments, and alter the case of the sons of the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Give strong drink to the grieving, and wine to those who are bitter in soul.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Let them drink, and forget their needs, and remember their sorrow no more.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Open your mouth for the mute and for all the cases of the sons who are passing through.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Open your mouth, declare what is just, and do justice to the indigent and the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Who shall find a strong woman? Far away, and from the furthest parts, is her price.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The heart of her husband confides in her, and he will not be deprived of spoils.</verse>
  <verse number="12">She will repay him with good, and not evil, all the days of her life.</verse>
  <verse number="13">She has sought wool and flax, and she has worked these by the counsel of her hands.</verse>
  <verse number="14">She has become like a merchant’s ship, bringing her bread from far away.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And she has risen in the night, and given a prey to her household, and provisions to her maids.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She has considered a field and bought it. From the fruit of her own hands, she has planted a vineyard.</verse>
  <verse number="17">She has wrapped her waist with fortitude, and she has strengthened her arm.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She has tasted and seen that her tasks are good; her lamp shall not be extinguished at night.</verse>
  <verse number="19">She has put her hand to strong things, and her fingers have taken hold of the spindle.</verse>
  <verse number="20">She has opened her hand to the needy, and she has extended her hands to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="21">She shall not fear, in the cold of snow, for her household. For all those of her household have been clothed two-fold.</verse>
  <verse number="22">She has made embroidered clothing for herself. Fine linen and purple is her garment.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Her husband is noble at the gates, when he sits among the senators of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="24">She has made finely woven cloth and sold it, and she has delivered a waistband to the Canaanite.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Strength and elegance are her clothing, and she will laugh in the final days.</verse>
  <verse number="26">She has opened her mouth to wisdom, and the law of clemency is on her tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="27">She has considered the paths of her household, and she has not eaten her bread in idleness.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Her sons rose up and predicted great happiness; her husband rose up and praised her.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Many daughters have gathered together riches; you have surpassed them all.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Charm is false, and beauty is vain. The woman who fears the Lord, the same shall be praised.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Give to her from the fruit of her own hands. And let her works praise her at the gates.</verse>
</chapter>