<chapter book="Proverbs" number="5" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, pay attention to my wisdom, and incline your ear to my prudence,</verse>
  <verse number="2">so that you may guard your thinking, and so that your lips may preserve discipline. Do not pay attention to the deceit of a woman.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the lips of a loose woman are like a dripping honeycomb, and her voice is smoother than oil.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But in the end, she is as bitter as wormwood, and as sharp as a two-edged sword.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Her feet descend into death, and her steps reach even to Hell.</verse>
  <verse number="6">They do not walk along the path of life; her steps are wandering and untraceable.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Therefore, my son, listen to me now, and do not withdraw from the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Make your way at a distance from her, and do not approach the doors of her house.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Do not give your honor to foreigners, and your years to the cruel.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Otherwise, outsiders may be filled with your strength, and your labors may be in a foreign house,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and you may mourn in the end, when you will have consumed your flesh and your body. And so you may say:</verse>
  <verse number="12">“Why have I detested discipline, and why has my heart not been quieted by correction?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And why have I not listened to the voice of those who guided me? And why has my ear not inclined to my teachers?</verse>
  <verse number="14">I have almost been with all evil in the midst of the church and of the assembly.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">Drink water from your own cistern and from the springs of your own well.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Let your fountains be diverted far and wide, and divide your waters in the streets.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Hold them for yourself alone, and do not let strangers be partakers with you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Let your spring be blessed, and rejoice with the wife of your youth:</verse>
  <verse number="19">a beloved doe and most pleasing fawn. Let her breasts inebriate you at all times. Be delighted continually by her love.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why are you seduced, my son, by a strange woman, and why are you kept warm by the bosom of another?</verse>
  <verse number="21">The Lord beholds the ways of man, and he considers all his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="22">His own iniquities take hold of the impious, and he is bound by the cords of his own sins.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He shall die, for he has not held to discipline. And by the multitude of his foolishness, he shall be deceived.</verse>
</chapter>