<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if you have taken a pledge on behalf of your friend, then you have bound your hand to an outsider,</verse>
  <verse number="2">then you are ensnared by the words of your own mouth, and taken captive by your own words.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Therefore, my son, do what I say, and free yourself, for you have fallen into the hand of your neighbor. Run, hurry, awaken your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Do not grant sleep to your eyes, nor let your eyelids slumber.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Rescue yourself like a gazelle from the hand, and like a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go to the ant, you lazy one, and consider her ways, and so learn wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For though she has no ruler, nor instructor, nor leader,</verse>
  <verse number="8">she provides meals for herself in the summer, and she gathers at the harvest what she may eat.</verse>
  <verse number="9">How long will you slumber, you lazy one? When will you rise up from your sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">You will sleep a little, you will slumber a little, you will fold your hands a little to sleep,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and then destitution will meet with you, like a traveler, and poverty, like an armed man. Yet truly, if you would be diligent, then your harvest will arrive like a fountain, and destitution will flee far from you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">An apostate man, a harmful man, walks with a perverse mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="13">he winks with the eyes, touches with the foot, speaks with the finger.</verse>
  <verse number="14">With a depraved heart he devises evil, and at all times he sows conflict.</verse>
  <verse number="15">To this one, his perdition will arrive promptly, and he shall be crushed suddenly: he will no longer have any remedy.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Six things there are that the Lord hates, and the seventh, his soul detests:</verse>
  <verse number="17">haughty eyes, a lying tongue, hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
  <verse number="18">a heart that devises the most wicked thoughts, feet running swiftly unto evil,</verse>
  <verse number="19">a deceitful witness bringing forth lies, and he who sows discord among brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, preserve the precepts of your father, and do not dismiss the law of your mother.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Bind them to your heart unceasingly, and encircle them around your throat.</verse>
  <verse number="22">When you walk, let them keep step with you. When you sleep, let them guard you. And when you keep watch, speak with them.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For commandment is a lamp, and law is a light, and the reproofs of discipline are the way of life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">So may they guard you from an evil woman, and from the flattering tongue of the outsider.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let not your heart desire her beauty; do not be captivated by her winks.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the price of a prostitute is only one loaf. Yet the woman seizes the precious soul of a man.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Would a man be able to conceal fire in his bosom, so that his garments would not burn?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Or could he walk over burning coals, so that his feet would not be burned?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So also, he who enters to the wife of his neighbor shall not be clean when he touches her.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Not so great is the fault when someone has stolen. For he steals so as to satisfy a hungry soul.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Also, if he is apprehended, he shall repay sevenfold and hand over all the substance of his house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">But whoever is an adulterer, because of the emptiness of his heart, will destroy his own soul.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He gathers shame and dishonor to himself, and his disgrace will not be wiped away.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For the jealousy and fury of the husband will not spare him on the day of vindication,</verse>
  <verse number="35">nor will he agree to the pleadings of anyone, nor will he accept, as repayment, a multitude of gifts.</verse>
</chapter>