<chapter book="Proverbs" number="7" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, guard my words and conceal my precepts within you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Son, preserve my commandments, and you shall live. And keep my law as the pupil of your eye.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Bind it with your fingers; write it on the tablets of your heart.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Say to wisdom, “You are my sister,” and call prudence your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="5">So may she guard you from the woman who is an outsider, and from the stranger who sweetens her words.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For I gaze from the window of my house, through the lattice,</verse>
  <verse number="7">and I see little ones. I consider a frenzied youth,</verse>
  <verse number="8">who crosses the street at the corner and close to the way of that house.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He steps into shadows, as day becomes evening, into the darkness and gloom of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And behold, a woman meets him, dressed like a harlot, prepared to captivate souls: chattering and rambling,</verse>
  <verse number="11">unwilling to bear silence, unable to keep her feet at home,</verse>
  <verse number="12">now outside, now in the streets, now lying in ambush near the corners.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And overtaking the youth, she kisses him, and with a provocative face, she flatters him, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="14">“I vowed sacrifices for well-being. Today I have repaid my vows.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Because of this, I have gone out to meet you, desiring to see you, and I have found you.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I have woven my bed with cords. I have strewn it with embroidered tapestries from Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I have sprinkled my bed with myrrh, aloe, and cinnamon.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Come, let us be inebriated in abundance, and let us delight in the embraces of desire, until the day begins to dawn.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For my husband is not in his house. He has gone away on a very long journey.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He took with him a bag of money. He will return to his house on the day of the full moon.”</verse>
  <verse number="21">She enmeshed him with many words, and she drew him forward with the flattery of her lips.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Immediately, he follows her, like an ox being led to the sacrifice, and like a lamb acting lasciviously, and not knowing that he is being drawn foolishly into chains,</verse>
  <verse number="23">until the arrow pierces his liver. It is just as if a bird were to hurry into the snare. And he does not know that his actions endanger his own soul.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Therefore, my son, hear me now, and attend to the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Do not let your mind be pulled into her ways. And do not be deceived by her paths.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For she has tossed aside many wounded, and some of those who were very strong have been slain by her.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Her household is the way to Hell, reaching even to the inner places of death.</verse>
</chapter>