<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="2" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these are the sons of Israel: Ruben, Simeon, Levi, Juda, Issachar, and Zabulon,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Dan, Joseph, Benjamin, Nephtali, Gad, and Aser.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The sons of Juda: Her, Onan and Sela. These three were born to him of the Chanaanitess the daughter of Sue. And Her the firstborn of Juda, was wicked in the sight of the Lord, and he slew him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Thamar his daughter in law bore him Phares and Zara. So all the sons of Juda were five.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the sons of Phares, were Hesron and Hamul.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the sons also of Zare: Zamri, and Ethan, and Eman, and Chalchal, and Dara, five in all.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sons of Charmi: Achar, who troubled Israel, and sinned by the theft of the anathema.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sons of Ethan: Azarias,</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the sons of Hesron that were born to him: Jerameel, and Ram, and Calubi.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Ram beget Aminadab, and Aminadab beget Nahasson, prince of the children of Juda.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Nahasson beget Salma, the father of Boot.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Boot beget Obed, and Obed beget Isai.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Isai beget Eliab his firstborn, the second Abinadab, the third Simmaa,</verse>
  <verse number="14">The fourth, Nathanael, the fifth Raddai,</verse>
  <verse number="15">The sixth Asom, the seventh David.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And their sisters were Sarvia, and Abigail. The sons of Sarvia: Abisai, Joab, and Asael, three.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Abigail bore Amasa, whose father was Jether the Ismahelite.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Caleb the son of Hesron took a wife named Azuba, of whom he had Jerioth: and her sons were Jaser, and Sobab, and Ardon.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And when Azuba was dead, Caleb took to wife Ephrata: who bore him Hur.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Hur beget Uri: and Uri beget Bezeleel.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And afterwards Hesron went in to the daughter of Machir the father of Galaad, and took her to wife when he was threescore years old: and she bore him Segub.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Segub beget Jair, and he had three and twenty cities in the land of Galaad.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he took Gessur, and Aram the towns of Jair, and Canath, and the villages thereof, threescore cities. All these, the sons of Machir father of Galaad.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And when Hesron was dead, Caleb went in to Ephrata. Hesron also had to wife Abia who bore him Ashur the father of Thecua.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the sons of Jerameel the firstborn of Hesron, were Ram his firstborn, and Buna, and Aram, and Asom, and Achia.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Jerameel married another wife, named Atara, who was the mother of Onam.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the sons of Ram the firstborn of Jerameel, were Moos, Jamin, and Achar.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Onam had sons Semei, and Jada. And the sons of Semei: Nadab, and Abisur.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And the name of Abisur’s wife was Abihail, who bore him Ahobban, and Molid.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the sons of Nadab were Saled, and Apphaim. And Saled died without children.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But the son of Apphaim was Jesi: and Jesi beget Sesan. And Sesan beget Oholai.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the sons of Jada the brother of Semei : Jether and Jonathan. And Jether also died without children.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But Jonathan beget Phaleth, and Ziza, These were the sons of Jerameel.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Sesan had no sons, but daughters and a servant an Egyptian, named Jeraa.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And he gave him his daughter to wife: and she bore him Ethei.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Ethei begot Nathan, and Nathan beget Zabad.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Zabad beget Ophlal, and Ophlal beget Obed.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Obed beget Jehu, Jehu beget Azarias.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Azarias beget Helles, and Helles begot Elasa.</verse>
  <verse number="40">Elasa beget Sisamoi, Sisamoi beget Sellum,</verse>
  <verse number="41">Sellum beget Icamia, and Icamia begot Elisama.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Now the sons of Caleb the brother of Jerameel were Mesa his firstborn, who was the father of Siph: and the sons of Maresa father of Hebron.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And the sons of Hebron, Core, and Thaphua, and Recem, and Samma.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And Samma beget Raham, the father of Jercaam, and Recem beget Sammai.</verse>
  <verse number="45">The son of Sammai, Maon: and Maon the father of Bethsur.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And Epha the concubine of Caleb bore Haran, and Mesa, and Gezez. And Haran beget Gezez.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And the sons of Jahaddai, Rogom, and Joathan, and Gesan, and Phalet, and Epha, and Saaph.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And Maacha the concubine of Caleb bore Saber, and Tharana.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Saaph the father of Madmena beget Sue the father of Machbena, and the father of Gabaa. And the daughter of Caleb was Achsa.</verse>
  <verse number="50">These were the sons of Caleb, the son of Hur the firstborn of Ephrata, Sobal the father of Cariathiarim.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Salma the father of Bethlehem, Hariph the father of Bethgader.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And Sobal the father of Cariathiarim had sons: he that saw half of the places of rest.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And of the kindred of Cariathiarim, the Jethrites, and Aphuthites, and Semathites, and Maserites. Of them came the Saraites, and Esthaolites.</verse>
  <verse number="54">The sons of Salma, Bethlehem, and Netophathi, the crowns of the house of Joab, and half of the place of rest of Sarai.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And the families of the scribes that dwell in Jabes, singing and making melody, and abiding in tents. These are the Cinites, who came of Calor (Chamath) father of the house of Rechab,</verse>
</chapter>