<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="3" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now these were the sons of David that were born to him in Hebron: the firstborn Amnon of Achinoam the Jezrahelitess, the second Daniel of Abigail the Carmelitess.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The third Absalom the son of Maacha the daughter of Tolmai king of Gessur, the fourth Adonias the son of Aggith,</verse>
  <verse number="3">The fifth Saphatias of Abital, the sixth Jethrahem of Egla, his wife.</verse>
  <verse number="4">So six sons were born to him in Hebron, where he reigned seven years and six months. And in Jerusalem he reigned three and thirty years.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And these sons were born to him in Jerusalem: Simmaa, and Sobab, and Nathan, and Solomon, four of Bethsabee the daughter of Ammiel.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Jebaar also and Elisama,</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Eliphaleeh, and Noge, and Nepheg, and Japhia,</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Elisama, and Eliada, and Elipheleth, nine:</verse>
  <verse number="9">All these the sons of David, beside the sons of the concubines: and they had a sister Thamar.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Solomon’s son was Roboam: whose son Abia beget Asa. And his son was Josaphat,</verse>
  <verse number="11">The father of Joram: and Joram be- got Ochozias, of whom was born Joas:</verse>
  <verse number="12">And his son Amasias begot Azarias. And Joathan the son of Azarias</verse>
  <verse number="13">Beget Achaz, the father of Ezechias, of whom was born Manasses.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Manasses beget Amen the father of Josias.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the sons of Josias were, the firstborn Johanan, the second Joakim, the third Sedecias, the fourth Sellum.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Of Joakim was born Jechonias, and Sedecias.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The sons of Jechonias were Asir, Salathiel,</verse>
  <verse number="18">Melchiram, Phadaia, Senneser and Jecemia, Sama, and Nadabia.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Of Phadaia were born Zorobabel and Semei. Zorobabel beget Mosollam, Hananias, and Salomith their sister:</verse>
  <verse number="20">Hasaba also, and Ohol, and Barachias, and Hasadias, Josabhesed, five.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the son of Hananias was Phaltias the father of Jeseias, whose son was Raphaia. And his son was Arnan, of whom was born Obdia, whose son was Sechenias.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The son of Sechenias, was Semeia, whose sons were Hattus, and Jegaal, and Baria, and Naaria, and Saphat, six in number.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The sons of Naaria, Elioenai, and Ezechias, and Ezricam, three.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The sons of Elioenai, Oduia, and Eliasub, and Pheleia, and Accub, and Johanan, and Dalaia, and Anani, seven.</verse>
</chapter>