<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="8" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now Benjamin beget Bale his firstborn, Asbel the second, Ahara the third,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Nohaa the fourth, and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the sons of Bale were Addar, and Gera, and Abiud,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Abisue, and Naamar, and Ahoe,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Gera, and Sephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
  <verse number="6">These are the sons of Ahod, heads of families that dwelt in Gabaa, who were removed into Mrtnahsth.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Naaman, and Achia, and Gera he removed them, and beget Oza, and Ahiud.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Saharim begot in the land of Moab, after he sent away Husim and Bara his wives.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he beget of Hodes his wife Jobab, and Sebia, and Mesa, and Molchom,</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jehus and Sechia, and Marma. These were his sons heads of their families.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Mehusim beget Abitob, and Elphaal.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the sons of Elphaal were Heber, and Misaam, and Samad: who built One, and Led, and its daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Baria, and Sama were heads of their kindreds that dwelt in Aialon: these drove away the inhabitants of Geth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Ahio, and Sesac, and Jerimoth,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Zabadia, and Arod, and Heder,</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Michael, and Jespha, and Joha, the sons of Baria.</verse>
  <verse number="17">17And Zabadia, and Mosollam, and Hezeci, and Heber,</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Jesamari, and Jezlia, and Jobab, sons of Elphaal,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Jacim, and Zechri, and Zabdi,</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Elioenai, and Selethai, and Elial,</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Adaia, and Baraia, and Samareth, the sons of Semei.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Jespham, and Heber, and Eliel,</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Abdon, and Zechri, and Hanan,</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Hanania, and Elam, and Anathothia.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Jephdaia, and Phanuel the sons of Sesac.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Samsari, and Sohoria and Otholia,</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Jersia, and Elia, and Zechri, the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
  <verse number="28">These were the chief fathers, and heads of their families who dwelt in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And at Gabaon dwelt Abigabaon, and the name of his wife was Maacha:</verse>
  <verse number="30">And his firstborn son Abdon, and Sur, and Cia, and Baal, and Nadab,</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Gedor, and Ahio, and Zacher, and Macelloth:</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Macelloth beget Samaa: and they dwelt over against their brethren in Jerusalem with their brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Ner begot Cia, and Cia begot Saul. And Saul begot Jonathan and Melchisua, and Abinadab, and Esbaal.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the son of Jonathan was Meribbaal: and Meribbaal begot Micha.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the sons of Micha were Phithon, and Melech, and Tharaa, and Ahaz.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Ahaz beget Joada: and Joada beget Alamath, and Azmoth, and Zamri: and Zamri beget Mesa,</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Mesa beget Banaa, whose son was Rapha, of whom was born Elasa, who beget Asel.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Asel had six sons whose names were Ezricam, Bochru, Ismahel, Saria, Obdia, and Hanan. All these were the sons of Asel.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And the sons of Esec, his brother, were Ulam the firstborn, and Jehus the second, and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the sons of Ulam were most valiant men, and archers of great strength: and they had many sons and grandsons, even to a hundred and fifty. All these were children of Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>