<chapter book="Numbers" number="2" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the LORD said to Moses and Aaron:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“The Israelites are to camp around the Tent of Meeting at a distance from it, each man under his standard, with the banners of his family.</verse>
  <verse number="3">On the east side, toward the sunrise, the divisions of Judah are to camp under their standard: The leader of the Judahites is Nahshon son of Amminadab,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and his division numbers 74,600.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The tribe of Issachar will camp next to it. The leader of the Issacharites is Nethanel son of Zuar,</verse>
  <verse number="6">and his division numbers 54,400.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Next will be the tribe of Zebulun. The leader of the Zebulunites is Eliab son of Helon,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and his division numbers 57,400.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The total number of men in the divisions of the camp of Judah is 186,400; they shall set out first.</verse>
  <verse number="10">On the south side, the divisions of Reuben are to camp under their standard: The leader of the Reubenites is Elizur son of Shedeur,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and his division numbers 46,500.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The tribe of Simeon will camp next to it. The leader of the Simeonites is Shelumiel son of Zurishaddai,</verse>
  <verse number="13">and his division numbers 59,300.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Next will be the tribe of Gad. The leader of the Gadites is Eliasaph son of Deuel,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and his division numbers 45,650.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The total number of men in the divisions of the camp of Reuben is 151,450; they shall set out second.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In the middle of the camps, the Tent of Meeting is to travel with the camp of the Levites. They are to set out in the order they encamped, each in his own place under his standard.</verse>
  <verse number="18">On the west side, the divisions of Ephraim are to camp under their standard: The leader of the Ephraimites is Elishama son of Ammihud,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and his division numbers 40,500.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The tribe of Manasseh will be next to it. The leader of the Manassites is Gamaliel son of Pedahzur,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and his division numbers 32,200.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Next will be the tribe of Benjamin. The leader of the Benjamites is Abidan son of Gideoni,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and his division numbers 35,400.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The total number of men in the divisions of the camp of Ephraim is 108,100; they shall set out third.</verse>
  <verse number="25">On the north side, the divisions of Dan are to camp under their standard: The leader of the Danites is Ahiezer son of Ammishaddai,</verse>
  <verse number="26">and his division numbers 62,700.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The tribe of Asher will camp next to it. The leader of the Asherites is Pagiel son of Ocran,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and his division numbers 41,500.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Next will be the tribe of Naphtali. The leader of the Naphtalites is Ahira son of Enan,</verse>
  <verse number="30">and his division numbers 53,400.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The total number of men in the camp of Dan is 157,600; they shall set out last, under their standards.”</verse>
  <verse number="32">These are the Israelites, numbered according to their families. The total of those counted in the camps, by their divisions, was 603,550.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But the Levites were not counted among the other Israelites, as the LORD had commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="34">So the Israelites did everything the LORD commanded Moses; they camped under their standards in this way and set out in the same way, each man with his clan and his family.</verse>
</chapter>