<chapter book="Numbers" number="34" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Command the Israelites and say to them: When you enter the land of Canaan, it will be allotted to you as an inheritance with these boundaries:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Your southern border will extend from the Wilderness of Zin along the border of Edom. On the east, your southern border will run from the end of the Salt Sea,</verse>
  <verse number="4">cross south of the Ascent of Akrabbim, continue to Zin, and go south of Kadesh-barnea. Then it will go on to Hazar-addar and proceed to Azmon,</verse>
  <verse number="5">where it will turn from Azmon, join the Brook of Egypt, and end at the Sea.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Your western border will be the coastline of the Great Sea; this will be your boundary on the west.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Your northern border will run from the Great Sea directly to Mount Hor,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and from Mount Hor to Lebo-hamath, then extend to Zedad,</verse>
  <verse number="9">continue to Ziphron, and end at Hazar-enan. This will be your boundary on the north.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And your eastern border will run straight from Hazar-enan to Shepham,</verse>
  <verse number="11">then go down from Shepham to Riblah on the east side of Ain and continue along the slopes east of the Sea of Chinnereth.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Then the border will go down along the Jordan and end at the Salt Sea. This will be your land, defined by its borders on all sides.”</verse>
  <verse number="13">So Moses commanded the Israelites, “Apportion this land by lot as an inheritance. The LORD has commanded that it be given to the nine and a half tribes.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the tribes of the Reubenites and Gadites, along with the half-tribe of Manasseh, have already received their inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="15">These two and a half tribes have received their inheritance across the Jordan from Jericho, toward the sunrise.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
  <verse number="17">“These are the names of the men who are to assign the land as an inheritance for you: Eleazar the priest and Joshua son of Nun.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Appoint one leader from each tribe to distribute the land.</verse>
  <verse number="19">These are their names: Caleb son of Jephunneh from the tribe of Judah;</verse>
  <verse number="20">Shemuel son of Ammihud from the tribe of Simeon;</verse>
  <verse number="21">Elidad son of Chislon from the tribe of Benjamin;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Bukki son of Jogli, a leader from the tribe of Dan;</verse>
  <verse number="23">Hanniel son of Ephod, a leader from the tribe of Manasseh son of Joseph;</verse>
  <verse number="24">Kemuel son of Shiphtan, a leader from the tribe of Ephraim;</verse>
  <verse number="25">Eli-zaphan son of Parnach, a leader from the tribe of Zebulun;</verse>
  <verse number="26">Paltiel son of Azzan, a leader from the tribe of Issachar;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Ahihud son of Shelomi, a leader from the tribe of Asher;</verse>
  <verse number="28">and Pedahel son of Ammihud, a leader from the tribe of Naphtali.”</verse>
  <verse number="29">These are the ones whom the LORD commanded to apportion the inheritance to the Israelites in the land of Canaan.</verse>
</chapter>