<chapter book="Numbers" number="7" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">On the day Moses finished setting up the tabernacle, he anointed and consecrated it and all its furnishings, along with the altar and all its utensils.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the leaders of Israel, the heads of their families, presented an offering. These men were the tribal leaders who had supervised the registration.</verse>
  <verse number="3">They brought as their offering before the LORD six covered carts and twelve oxen—an ox from each leader and a cart from every two leaders—and presented them before the tabernacle.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the LORD said to Moses,</verse>
  <verse number="5">“Accept these gifts from them, that they may be used in the work of the Tent of Meeting. And give them to the Levites, to each man according to his service.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">So Moses took the carts and oxen and gave them to the Levites.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He gave the Gershonites two carts and four oxen, as their service required,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and he gave the Merarites four carts and eight oxen, as their service required, all under the direction of Ithamar son of Aaron the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But he did not give any to the Kohathites, since they were to carry on their shoulders the holy objects for which they were responsible.</verse>
  <verse number="10">When the altar was anointed, the leaders approached with their offerings for its dedication and presented them before the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the LORD said to Moses, “Each day one leader is to present his offering for the dedication of the altar.”</verse>
  <verse number="12">On the first day Nahshon son of Amminadab from the tribe of Judah drew near with his offering.</verse>
  <verse number="13">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="14">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="15">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="16">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="17">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Nahshon son of Amminadab.</verse>
  <verse number="18">On the second day Nethanel son of Zuar, the leader of Issachar, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The offering he presented was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="20">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="21">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="22">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="23">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Nethanel son of Zuar.</verse>
  <verse number="24">On the third day Eliab son of Helon, the leader of the Zebulunites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="25">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="26">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="27">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="28">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="29">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Eliab son of Helon.</verse>
  <verse number="30">On the fourth day Elizur son of Shedeur, the leader of the Reubenites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="31">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="32">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="33">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="34">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="35">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Elizur son of Shedeur.</verse>
  <verse number="36">On the fifth day Shelumiel son of Zurishaddai, the leader of the Simeonites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="37">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="38">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="39">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="40">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="41">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Shelumiel son of Zurishaddai.</verse>
  <verse number="42">On the sixth day Eliasaph son of Deuel, the leader of the Gadites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="43">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="44">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="45">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="46">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="47">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Eliasaph son of Deuel.</verse>
  <verse number="48">On the seventh day Elishama son of Ammihud, the leader of the Ephraimites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="49">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="50">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="51">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="52">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="53">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Elishama son of Ammihud.</verse>
  <verse number="54">On the eighth day Gamaliel son of Pedahzur, the leader of the Manassites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="55">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="56">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="57">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="58">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="59">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Gamaliel son of Pedahzur.</verse>
  <verse number="60">On the ninth day Abidan son of Gideoni, the leader of the Benjamites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="61">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="62">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="63">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="64">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="65">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Abidan son of Gideoni.</verse>
  <verse number="66">On the tenth day Ahiezer son of Ammishaddai, the leader of the Danites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="67">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="68">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="69">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="70">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="71">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Ahiezer son of Ammishaddai.</verse>
  <verse number="72">On the eleventh day Pagiel son of Ocran, the leader of the Asherites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="73">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="74">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="75">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="76">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="77">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Pagiel son of Ocran.</verse>
  <verse number="78">On the twelfth day Ahira son of Enan, the leader of the Naphtalites, drew near.</verse>
  <verse number="79">His offering was one silver platter weighing a hundred and thirty shekels, and one silver bowl weighing seventy shekels, both according to the sanctuary shekel and filled with fine flour mixed with oil for a grain offering;</verse>
  <verse number="80">one gold dish weighing ten shekels, filled with incense;</verse>
  <verse number="81">one young bull, one ram, and one male lamb a year old for a burnt offering;</verse>
  <verse number="82">one male goat for a sin offering;</verse>
  <verse number="83">and a peace offering of two oxen, five rams, five male goats, and five male lambs a year old. This was the offering of Ahira son of Enan.</verse>
  <verse number="84">So these were the offerings from the leaders of Israel for the dedication of the altar when it was anointed: twelve silver platters, twelve silver bowls, and twelve gold dishes.</verse>
  <verse number="85">Each silver platter weighed a hundred and thirty shekels, and each silver bowl seventy shekels. The total weight of the silver articles was two thousand four hundred shekels, according to the sanctuary shekel.</verse>
  <verse number="86">The twelve gold dishes filled with incense weighed ten shekels each, according to the sanctuary shekel. The total weight of the gold dishes was a hundred and twenty shekels.</verse>
  <verse number="87">All the livestock for the burnt offering totaled twelve bulls, twelve rams, and twelve male lambs a year old—together with their grain offerings—and twelve male goats for the sin offering.</verse>
  <verse number="88">All the livestock sacrificed for the peace offering totaled twenty-four bulls, sixty rams, sixty male goats, and sixty male lambs a year old. This was the dedication offering for the altar after it was anointed.</verse>
  <verse number="89">When Moses entered the Tent of Meeting to speak with the LORD, he heard the voice speaking to him from between the two cherubim above the mercy seat on the ark of the Testimony. Thus the LORD spoke to him.</verse>
</chapter>