<chapter book="Ephesians" number="5" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Be ye therefore imitators of God, as beloved children;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and walk in love, even as Christ also loved you, and gave himself up for us, an offering and a sacrifice to God for an odor of a sweet smell.</verse>
  <verse number="3">But fornication, and all uncleanness, or covetousness, let it not even be named among you, as becometh saints;</verse>
  <verse number="4">nor filthiness, nor foolish talking, or jesting, which are not befitting: but rather giving of thanks.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For this ye know of a surety, that no fornicator, nor unclean person, nor covetous man, who is an idolater, hath any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let no man deceive you with empty words: for because of these things cometh the wrath of God upon the sons of disobedience.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be not ye therefore partakers with them;</verse>
  <verse number="8">for ye were once darkness, but are now light in the Lord: walk as children of light</verse>
  <verse number="9">(for the fruit of the light is in all goodness and righteousness and truth),</verse>
  <verse number="10">proving what is well-pleasing unto the Lord;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and have no fellowship with the unfruitful works of darkness, but rather even reprove them;</verse>
  <verse number="12">for the things which are done by them in secret it is a shame even to speak of.</verse>
  <verse number="13">But all things when they are reproved are made manifest by the light: for everything that is made manifest is light.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Wherefore he saith, Awake, thou that sleepest, and arise from the dead, and Christ shall shine upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Look therefore carefully how ye walk, not as unwise, but as wise;</verse>
  <verse number="16">redeeming the time, because the days are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Wherefore be ye not foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And be not drunken with wine, wherein is riot, but be filled with the Spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="19">speaking one to another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody with your heart to the Lord;</verse>
  <verse number="20">giving thanks always for all things in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ to God, even the Father;</verse>
  <verse number="21">subjecting yourselves one to another in the fear of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Wives, be in subjection unto your own husbands, as unto the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the husband is the head of the wife, as Christ also is the head of the church, being himself the saviour of the body.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But as the church is subject to Christ, so let the wives also be to their husbands in everything.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Husbands, love your wives, even as Christ also loved the church, and gave himself up for it;</verse>
  <verse number="26">that he might sanctify it, having cleansed it by the washing of water with the word,</verse>
  <verse number="27">that he might present the church to himself a glorious church, not having spot or wrinkle or any such thing; but that it should be holy and without blemish.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Even so ought husbands also to love their own wives as their own bodies. He that loveth his own wife loveth himself:</verse>
  <verse number="29">for no man ever hated his own flesh; but nourisheth and cherisheth it, even as Christ also the church;</verse>
  <verse number="30">because we are members of his body.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and shall cleave to his wife; and the two shall become one flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="32">This mystery is great: but I speak in regard of Christ and of the church.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Nevertheless do ye also severally love each one his own wife even as himself; and let the wife see that she fear her husband.</verse>
</chapter>