<chapter book="Matthew" number="10" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And when he had called to him his twelve disciples, he gave them power against unclean spirits, to cast them out, and to heal all manner of sickness and all manner of disease.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Now the names of the twelve apostles are these; The first, Simon, who is called Peter, and Andrew his brother; James the son of Zebedee, and John his brother;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Philip, and Bartholomew; Thomas, and Matthew the publican; James the son of Alphaeus, and Lebbaeus, whose surname was Thaddaeus;</verse>
  <verse number="4">Simon the Canaanite, and Judas Iscariot, who also betrayed him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">These twelve Jesus sent forth, and commanded them, saying, Go not into the way of the Gentiles, and into any city of the Samaritans enter you not:</verse>
  <verse number="6">But go rather to the lost sheep of the house of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And as you go, preach, saying, The kingdom of heaven is at hand.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Heal the sick, cleanse the lepers, raise the dead, cast out devils: freely you have received, freely give.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Provide neither gold, nor silver, nor brass in your purses,</verse>
  <verse number="10">Nor money for your journey, neither two coats, neither shoes, nor yet staves: for the workman is worthy of his meat.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And into whatever city or town you shall enter, inquire who in it is worthy; and there abide till you go there.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And when you come into an house, salute it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And if the house be worthy, let your peace come on it: but if it be not worthy, let your peace return to you.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And whoever shall not receive you, nor hear your words, when you depart out of that house or city, shake off the dust of your feet.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Truly I say to you, It shall be more tolerable for the land of Sodom and Gomorrha in the day of judgment, than for that city.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, I send you forth as sheep in the middle of wolves: be you therefore wise as serpents, and harmless as doves.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But beware of men: for they will deliver you up to the councils, and they will whip you in their synagogues;</verse>
  <verse number="18">And you shall be brought before governors and kings for my sake, for a testimony against them and the Gentiles.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But when they deliver you up, take no thought how or what you shall speak: for it shall be given you in that same hour what you shall speak.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For it is not you that speak, but the Spirit of your Father which speaks in you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the brother shall deliver up the brother to death, and the father the child: and the children shall rise up against their parents, and cause them to be put to death.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And you shall be hated of all men for my name’s sake: but he that endures to the end shall be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="23">But when they persecute you in this city, flee you into another: for truly I say to you, You shall not have gone over the cities of Israel, till the Son of man be come.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The disciple is not above his master, nor the servant above his lord.</verse>
  <verse number="25">It is enough for the disciple that he be as his master, and the servant as his lord. If they have called the master of the house Beelzebub, how much more shall they call them of his household?</verse>
  <verse number="26">Fear them not therefore: for there is nothing covered, that shall not be revealed; and hid, that shall not be known.</verse>
  <verse number="27">What I tell you in darkness, that speak you in light: and what you hear in the ear, that preach you on the housetops.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And fear not them which kill the body, but are not able to kill the soul: but rather fear him which is able to destroy both soul and body in hell.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Are not two sparrows sold for a farthing? and one of them shall not fall on the ground without your Father.</verse>
  <verse number="30">But the very hairs of your head are all numbered.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Fear you not therefore, you are of more value than many sparrows.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Whoever therefore shall confess me before men, him will I confess also before my Father which is in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But whoever shall deny me before men, him will I also deny before my Father which is in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Think not that I am come to send peace on earth: I came not to send peace, but a sword.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For I am come to set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her mother, and the daughter in law against her mother in law.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And a man’s foes shall be they of his own household.</verse>
  <verse number="37">He that loves father or mother more than me is not worthy of me: and he that loves son or daughter more than me is not worthy of me.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And he that takes not his cross, and follows after me, is not worthy of me.</verse>
  <verse number="39">He that finds his life shall lose it: and he that loses his life for my sake shall find it.</verse>
  <verse number="40">He that receives you receives me, and he that receives me receives him that sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="41">He that receives a prophet in the name of a prophet shall receive a prophet’s reward; and he that receives a righteous man in the name of a righteous man shall receive a righteous man’s reward.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And whoever shall give to drink to one of these little ones a cup of cold water only in the name of a disciple, truly I say to you, he shall in no wise lose his reward.</verse>
</chapter>