<chapter book="Ezra" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these the sons of the province coming up from the captivity of the exiles which Nebuchadnezzar carried into exile to Babel; and they will turn back to Jerusalem and Judah, a man to his city;</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who came with Zerubbabel: Joshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mizpar, Bigvai, Rehum, Baanah. The number of men of the people of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The sons of Parosh, two thousand one hundred seventy and two.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The sons of Shephatiah, three hundred seventy and two.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The sons of Arah, seven hundred five and seventy.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The sons of Pahath-Moab, to the sons of Joshua of Joab, two thousand eight hundred and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The sons of Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sons of Zattu, nine hundred and forty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The sons of Zaccai, seven hundred and sixty.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The sons of Bani, six hundred forty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The sons of Bebai, six hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The sons of Azgad, a thousand two hundred twenty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The sons of Adonikam, six hundred sixty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The sons of Bigvai, two thousand fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The sons of Adin, four hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The sons of Ater to Hezekiah, ninety and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The sons of Bezel, three hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The sons of Jorah, a hundred and and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The sons of Hashum, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The sons of Gibber, ninety and five.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The sons of the house of bread, a hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The men of Netophah, fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The men of Anathoth, a hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The sons of Azmaveth, forty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The sons of Kirjath-Arim, Chephiroth and Beeroth, seven hundred and forty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sons of Ramah and Gabe, six hundred twenty and one.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The men of Michmas, a hundred twenty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The men of the house of God and Ai, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The sons of Nebo, fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The sons of Magbish, a hundred fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The sons of the other Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The sons of Harim, three hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The sons of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, seven hundred twenty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="34">The sons of Jericho, three hundred forty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The sons of Senaah, three thousand and six hundred and thirty.</verse>
  <verse number="36">The priests: the sons of Jedaiah to the house of Joshua, nine hundred seventy and three.</verse>
  <verse number="37">The sons of Immer, a thousand fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="38">The sons of Pashur, a thousand two hundred forty and seven.</verse>
  <verse number="39">The sons of Harim, a thousand and seventeen.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The Levites: the sons of Joshua and Kadmiel, to the sons of Hodaviah, seventy and four.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Those singing: the sons of Asaph, a hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="42">The sons of the gates: the sons of Shallum, the sons of Ater, the sons of Talmon, the sons of Akkub, the sons of Hatite, the sons of Shobi, all, a hundred thirty and nine.</verse>
  <verse number="43">The Nethinims: the sons of Ziha, the sons of Hasupha, the sons of Tabbaoth.</verse>
  <verse number="44">The sons of Keros, the sons of Siaha, the sons of Padon,</verse>
  <verse number="45">The sons of Lebanah, the sons of Hagabah, the sons of Akkub,</verse>
  <verse number="46">The sons of Hagab, the sons of Shalmi, the sons of Hanan.</verse>
  <verse number="47">The sons of Giddel, the sons of Gahar, the sons of Reaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="48">The sons of Rezin, the sons of Nekoda, the sons of Gazztam,</verse>
  <verse number="49">The sons of Uzza, the sons of Paseah, the sons of Besai,</verse>
  <verse number="50">The sons of Asnah, the sons of Mehunim, the sons of Nephusim,</verse>
  <verse number="51">The sons of Bakbuk, the sons of Hakupha, the sons of Harhur,</verse>
  <verse number="52">The sons of Bazluth, the sons of Mehida, the sons of Harsha,</verse>
  <verse number="53">The sons of Barkos, the sons of Sisera, the sons of Thamah,</verse>
  <verse number="54">The sons of Neziah, the sons of Hatipha.</verse>
  <verse number="55">The sons of Solomon’s servants: the sons of Sotai, the sons of Sophereth, the sons of Peruda,</verse>
  <verse number="56">The sons of Jaalah, the sons of Darkon, the eons of Giddel,</verse>
  <verse number="57">The sons of Shephatiah, the sons of Hattil, the sons of Pochereth of Zebaim, the sons of Ami.</verse>
  <verse number="58">All the Nethinims, the sons of Solomon’s servants, three hundred ninety and two.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And these going up from Tel-Melah Tel-Harsa, Cherub, Addan, Immer and they were not able to announce their father’s house, and their seed, if they were from Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="60">The sons of Delaiah, the sons of Tobiah, the sons of Nekoda, six hundred fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="61">From the sons of the priests: the sons of Habiah, the sons of Koz, the sons of Barzillai, who took a wife from the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and he will be called by their name.</verse>
  <verse number="62">These sought their writing of those being enrolled, and they found not: and they will be polluted from the priesthood.</verse>
  <verse number="63">And the Tirshatha will say to them, that they shall not eat from the holy of holies till there stood up a priest for Lights and Truth.</verse>
  <verse number="64">All the convocation as one, four myriads two thousand three hundred and sixty,</verse>
  <verse number="65">Besides their servants and their maids, these seven thousand three hundred thirty and seven: and to them singing men and singing women, two hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="66">Their horses seven hundred thirty and six; their mules, two hundred forty and five;</verse>
  <verse number="67">Their camels, four hundred thirty and five; the asses, six thousand seven hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="68">And from the heads of the fathers in their coming to the house of Jehovah which is in Jerusalem, gave willingly to the house of God to cause it to stand upon its foundation:</verse>
  <verse number="69">According to their power they gave to the treasure of the work of gold six myriads and a thousand darics, and of silver, five thousand portions, and of priests’ tunics, a hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And the priests dwelt, and the Levites, and from the people, and those singing, and those opening the gates, and the Nethinims, in their cities, and all Israel in their cities.</verse>
</chapter>