<chapter book="Leviticus" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will call to Moses, and speak to him from the tent of appointment, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Speak to the sons of Israel and say to them, A man when he shall bring near from you an offering to Jehovah, from the cattle, from the oxen and from the sheep, ye shall bring near your offering.</verse>
  <verse number="3">If a burnt-offering, his sacrifice from the oxen, a blameless male: they shall bring it near to the door of the tent of appointment; he shall bring it near according to his will before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he placed his hand upon the head of the burnt-offering, and it was accepted for him to expiate for him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And he slaughtered the son of the cow before Jehovah: and the sons of Aaron the priests brought near the blood, and they sprinkled the blood upon the altar round about, which is at the door of the tent of appointment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And he flayed the burnt-offering, and cut in pieces according to its pieces.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sons of Aaron, the priests, gave fire upon the altar, and arranged the wood upon the fire.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Aaron’s sons, the priests, shall arrange the pieces, the head and the fat, upon the wood which is upon the fire which is upon the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And its bowels and its legs he shall wash in water: and the priest burnt all upon the altar, a burnt-offering a sacrifice, an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And if from the sheep his offering, from the lambs, or from the goats, for a burnt-offering; a blameless male he shall bring it near.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he slaughtered it upon the thigh of the altar, northward before Jehovah: and Aaron’s sons, the priests, sprinkled his blood upon the altar round about.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And he cut it in pieces, according to its pieces, and his head and his fat: and the priest arranged them upon the wood which is upon the fire which is upon the altar:</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the bowels and the legs he shall wash in water: and the priest shall bring near all, and burn upon the altar: it is a burnt-offering, a sacrifice, an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And if from the birds he brought near a burnt-offering to Jehovah, and he brought near from the turtle-doves, or from the sons of the dove his offering,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the priest brought it near to the altar, and broke off the head, and burnt upon the altar: and pressed out its blood upon the wall of the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he took away the crop with its feathers, and cast it at the side of the altar eastward, at the place of the ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he cleft it with its wings; he shall not divide; and the priest burnt it upon the altar, upon the wood which is upon the fire: it is a burnt-offering, a sacrifice, an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>