<chapter book="Leviticus" number="13" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, and to Aaron, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">When to a man there shall be a lifting up in the skin of his flesh, or a scab, or brightness, and it was in the skin of his flesh for the stroke of leprosy; and he shall be brought to Aaron the priest, or to one of his sons the priests.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the priest saw the stroke in the skin of the flesh: and the hair in the stroke turned white, and the sight of the stroke deep from the skin of his flesh, it is the stroke of leprosy: and the priest saw him and defiled him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And if the brightness it white in the skin of his flesh, and its sight not deep from the skin, and the hair not turned white; and the priest shut up the stroke seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the priest saw him in the seventh day: and behold, the stroke stood; in his eyes, the stroke spread not in the skin, and the priest shut him up the second seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the priest saw him in the seventh day, the second time, and behold, the stroke dim, and the stroke spread not in the skin, and the priest cleansed him: it is a scab: and he washed his garments and was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And if spreading, the scab shall spread in the skin, after his being seen to the priest for his cleansing, and he was seen the second time to the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the priest saw, and behold, the scab spread in the skin, and the priest defiled him: it is leprosy.</verse>
  <verse number="9">When the stroke of leprosy shall be in a man, and he shall be brought to the priest:</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the priest saw, and behold, a lifting up white in the skin, and it turned the hair white, and the quickening of living flesh in the lifting up:</verse>
  <verse number="11">It is an old leprosy in the skin of his flesh, and the priest shall defile him; he shall not shut him up for he is unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if breaking out, the leprosy shall break out in the skin, and the leprosy covered all the skin, the stroke from his head and even to his feet, to all the sight of the eyes of the priest:</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the priest saw, and behold, the leprosy covered all his flesh, and he cleansed the stroke: all of it turned white: he is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="14">In the day of seeing in him the living flesh, he shall be unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the priest saw the living flesh, and he defiled him: the living flesh it is unclean: it is leprosy.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Or when the living flesh shall turn back and turn to white, he shall be brought to the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the priest saw him, and behold, the stroke turned to white; and the priest cleansed the stroke: he is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And when the flesh shall be in it, in his skin, a burning sore, and was healed,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And there was in the place of the burning sore a white rising, or brightness, white, reddish, and he was seen to the priest;</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the priest saw, and behold, the sight low from the skin, and its hair turned white: and the priest defiled him: it is the stroke of leprosy broken out in the burning sore.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And if the priest shall see it, and behold, no white hair in it, and it not low from the skin, and it was dim; and the priest shut him up seven days:</verse>
  <verse number="22">And if spreading, it shall spread in the skin, and the priest defiled him: it the stroke.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And if the brightness shall stand still, lowest, spreading not, it the scar of the burning sore; and the priest cleansed him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Or when there shall be flesh in his skin a burning of fire, and there was a quickening of the burning, a brightness reddish white, or white;</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the priest saw it, and behold, the hair in the brightness was turned white, and the sight was deep from the skin; it leprosy in the burning broken out: and the priest defiled him: it the stroke of leprosy.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And if the priest shall see it, and behold, no white hair in the burning, and it not being low from the skin, and it was dim; and the priest shut him up seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the priest saw him in the seventh day: if spreading, it shall spread in the skin, and the priest shall defile him: it the stroke of leprosy.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And if the brightness shall stand still, the lowest, spreading not in the skin, and it was dim; it a rising of the burning, and the priest cleansed him: for it a scar of the burning.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And when a man or woman there shall be in him a stroke upon the head, or in the beard;</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the priest saw the stroke, and behold, its sight deep from the skin, and in it thin, yellow hair; and the priest defiled him: it a scall, it a leprosy of the head, or of the beard.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And when the priest shall see the stroke of the scall, and behold, its sight not deep from the skin, and no black hair in it; and the priest shut up the stroke of the scall seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the priest saw the stroke in the seventh day: and behold, the scab spread not, and there was no yellow hair in it, and the sight of the scall not deep from the skin;</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he was shaved, and the scall he shall not shave, and the priest shut up the scall seven days the second time.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the priest saw the scall in the seventh day, and behold, the scall spread not in the skin, and its sight not deep from the skin; and the priest cleansed him; and he washed his garments and was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And if spreading, the scall shall spread in the skin after his purification;</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the priest saw him: and behold, the scall spread in the skin, the priest shall not search for yellow hair; he is unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And if in his eyes the scall stood still, and black hair sprang up in it, the scall was healed; he is clean: and the priest cleansed him.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And when a man or woman shall be in the skin of their flesh a brightness, a white brightness;</verse>
  <verse number="39">And the priest saw, and behold, in the skin of their flesh a brightness, a dim white; it is a white scurf breaking out in the skin: he is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And if a man when his head shall become bald, he being bald; he is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And if from the side of his face his head shall become bald, he is bald; he is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And when there shall be in his baldness behind, or in his baldness in front, a stroke, reddish white, it is a leprosy broken out in his baldness behind, or in his baldness in front.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And the priest saw it, and behold, the rising of the stroke, a reddish white, in his baldness behind, or in his baldness in front, as the sight of leprosy, in the skin of the flesh;</verse>
  <verse number="44">He a leprous man, he unclean: he being unclean the priest shall defile him; his stroke in his head.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And the leprous in whom the stroke, his garments shall be rent, and his head shall be uncovered, and upon the lips he shall be covered, and he shall cry, Unclean, unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All the days which the stroke is in him, he shall be unclean: he is unclean: he shall dwell separately; without the camp is his dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="47">When a garment the stroke of leprosy shall be in it, whether in the garment of wool or in the garment of linen;</verse>
  <verse number="48">Or in the warp, or in the woof, to the linen or to the wool: or in the skin, or in any work of skin:</verse>
  <verse number="49">And the stroke was greenish, or reddish in the garment, or in the skin, or in the warp, or in the woof, or in any vessel of skin; it is the stroke of leprosy, and it was seen to the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And the priest saw the stroke, and shut up the stroke seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And he saw the stroke in the seventh day: when the stroke spread in the garment, or in the warp, or in the woof, or in the skin, and all which made of skin for work; the stroke a painful leprosy; it unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And he burnt the garment, or the warp, or the woof, or in wool, or in linen, or any vessel of skin which shall be in it the stroke: for it a painful leprosy; in fire shall it be burnt.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And if the priest shall see, and behold, the stroke spread not in the garment, or in the warp or in the woof, or in any vessel of skin;</verse>
  <verse number="54">And the priest commanded, and they washed that in which was the stroke, and he shut it up seven days, the second time.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And the priest saw after the washing, the stroke, and behold, the stroke turned not its eye, and the stroke spread not; it unclean; in fire thou shalt burn it; it a hollow in his baldness behind, or in his baldness in front.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And if the priest saw, and behold, the stroke dim after washing it: he rent it out of the garment or from the skin, or from the warp, or from the woof.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And if it shall be seen still in the garment, or in the warp, or in the woof, or in any vessel of skin; it is breaking out: in the fire thou shalt burn it, that in which is the stroke.</verse>
  <verse number="58">And the garment, or the warp or the woof, or any vessel of skin which thou shalt wash, and the stroke departed from them, and it was washed the second time, and it was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="59">This the law of the stroke of leprosy of the garment of wool, or of linen, or the warp or the woof, or every vessel of skin, to cleanse it or to defile it.</verse>
</chapter>