<chapter book="Leviticus" number="14" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">This shall be the law of the leprous in the day of his cleansing: he was brought to the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the priest shall go forth without the camp: and the priest saw, and behold, the stroke of leprosy was healed from the leprous.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the priest commanded, and took for him being cleansed, two clean living birds, and cedar wood, and double scarlet, and hyssop.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the priest commanded, and killed one of the birds into a vessel of earthen, over living water.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The living bird he will take it, and the cedar wood and the double scarlet, and the hyssop, and he dipped them and the living bird in the blood of the bird slain over the living water.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And he sprinkled upon him, being cleansed from the leprosy, seven times and cleansed him, and he sent forth the living bird upon the face of the field.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he being cleansed, washed his garments and shaved all his hair, and washed in water and was clean: and afterwards he shall come into the camp and dwelt without his tent seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And it was in the seventh day, he shall shave all his hair off his head, and his beard, and the front of his eyes; and all his hair shall he shave off; and he washed his garments, and washed his flesh in water, and was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And in the eighth day he shall take two blameless lambs, and one blameless ewe lamb, the daughter of her year, and three tenths of fine flour, a gift mingled with oil, and one measure of oil.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the priest cleansing, made the man being cleansed stand, and the things, before Jehovah, at the door of the tent of appointment.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the priest took one he lamb and brought him near for trespass, and the measure of oil, and lifted them up, a waving before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he slaughtered the lamb in the place where he shall slaughter the sin and the burnt-offering, in the holy place: for as the sin the trespass, it is to the priest; it is the holy of holies.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the priest took from the blood of the trespass, and the priest gave upon the extremity of the right ear of him being cleansed, and upon the thumb of his right hand, and upon the great toe of his right foot.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the priest took from the measure of oil, and poured upon the priest’s left hand.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the priest dipped his right finger from the oil which upon his left hand, and he sprinkled from the oil with his finger, seven times before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And from the remainder of the oil which was upon his hand, the priest will give upon the extremity of the right ear of hint being cleansed, and upon the thumb of his right hand, and upon the great toe of his right foot, upon the blood of the trespass.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And that remaining of the oil which was upon the priest’s hand, he will give upon the head of him being cleansed, and the priest expiated for him before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the priest did the sin, and expiated for him being cleansed from his uncleanness; and afterwards he will slaughter the burnt-offering.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the priest brought up the burnt-offering and the gift upon the altar: and the priest expiated for him, and he was cleansed.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And if he be poor, and his hand attaining not; and he took one lamb a trespass, for a waving to expiate for him, and one tenth of fine flour mingled with oil, for the gift, and a measure of oil.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And two turtle-doves, or two sons of the dove, which his hand shall attain; and one was the sin, and one the burnt-offering.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he brought them in the eighth day for his cleansing, to the priest at the door of the tent of appointment before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the priest took the lamb of the trespass and the measure of oil, and the priest lifted them up, a waving before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he slaughtered the lamb of the trespass, and the priest took from the blood of the trespass, and gave upon the extremity of the right ear of him being cleansed, and upon the thumb of his right hand, and upon the great toe of his right foot:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And from the oil the priest poured out upon the priest’s left hand.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the priest sprinkled with his right finger from the oil which was upon his left hand, seven times, before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the priest gave from the oil which was upon his hand, upon the extremity of the right ear of him being cleansed, and upon the thumb of his right hand, and upon the great toe of his right foot, upon the place of the blood of the trespass.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And that remaining from the oil which was upon the priest’s hand, he will give upon the head of him being cleansed; and he expiated for him before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he did the one from the turtle-doves, or from the sons of the dove, from what his hand shall attain.</verse>
  <verse number="31">What his hand shall attain, the one the sin, and the one the burnt-offering upon the gift. And the priest expiated for him being cleansed, before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="32">This the law of him in whom the stroke of leprosy, which his hand attained not in his cleansing.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Jehovah will speak to Moses and to Aaron, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="34">When ye shall come into the land of Canaan which I give to you for a possession, and I gave the stroke of leprosy in a house of the land of your possession;</verse>
  <verse number="35">And he to whom is the house, came and announced to the priest, saying, It was seen to me as a stroke in the house.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the priest commanded, and they cleared the house, before the priest shall go in to see the stroke, and all which is in the house shall not be unclean; and after this the priest shall go in to see the house.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And he saw the stroke; and behold, the stroke in the walls of the house, the hollows greenish, or reddish and their sight low from the wall.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And the priest shall go forth from the house to the door of the house, and he shut up the house seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And the priest turned back in the seventh day, and saw, and behold, the stroke spread in the walls of the house.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the priest commanded, and they took away the stones which in them was the stroke, and they cast them without the city into an unclean place.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And he shall scrape the house from within round about, and they poured out the dust which they scraped off without the city, into an unclean place.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And they took other stones and brought instead of these stones; and he shall take other clay and spread over the house.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And if the stroke shall turn back and break out in the house after he took away the stones, and after he scraped off the house, and after it was spread over;</verse>
  <verse number="44">And the priest came and saw, and behold, the stroke spread in the house; it a painful leprosy in the house: it is unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And he tore down the house, and its stones, and its wood, and all the dust of the house: and he brought forth without the city, into an unclean place.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And he coming in to the house all the days it is shut up, shall be unclean till the evening.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And he lying in the house shall wash his garments: and he eating in the house shall wash his garments.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And if the priest coming in, shall come in and see, and behold, the stroke spread not in the house after spreading over the house: and the priest cleansed the house, for the stroke was healed.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And he took to cleanse the house two birds, and cedar wood, and double scarlet, and hyssop.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And he slaughtered the one bird into a vessel of earthen, over living water.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And he took the cedar wood, and the hyssop and the double scarlet, and the living bird, and dipped them in the blood of the slain bird, and in the living water, and sprinkled into the house seven times.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And he cleansed the house with the blood of the bird in living water, and with the living bird, and with the cedar wood, and with the double scarlet.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And he sent away the living bird without the city to the face of the field, and he expiated for the house: and it was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="54">This the law for every stroke of leprosy and for scall,</verse>
  <verse number="55">And for the leprosy of a garment, and for a house,</verse>
  <verse number="56">And for a rising, and for a scab, and for a brightness;</verse>
  <verse number="57">And to teach in the day of being unclean, and in the day of cleansing: this the law of leprosy.</verse>
</chapter>