<chapter book="Leviticus" number="17" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Speak to Aaron and to his sons, and to all the sons of Israel, and say to them, This the word which Jehovah commanded, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="3">A man, a man from the house of Israel, who shall slaughter an ox or lamb or goat, in the camp, or who shall slaughter without the camp,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And at the door of the tent of appointment brought it not in to bring near an offering to Jehovah before the dwelling of Jehovah, blood shall be reckoned to that man: he shed blood; and that man was cut off from the midst of his people:</verse>
  <verse number="5">So that the sons of Israel shall bring their sacrifices which they sacrificed upon the face of the field, and they brought them to Jehovah at the door of the tent of appointment, to the priest, and they sacrificed them, sacrifices of peace to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the priest shall sprinkle the blood upon the altar of Jehovah, at the door of the tent of appointment; and he burnt the fat for an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they shall no more sacrifice their sacrifices to satyrs with whom they committed fornication after them: this shall be to them a law forever to their generations.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And thou shalt say to them, A man, a man from the house of Israel, and from the stranger who shall sojourn in the midst of you, who shall bring up a burnt-offering or a sacrifice,</verse>
  <verse number="9">And at the door of the tent of appointment brought it not to do it to Jehovah; and that man was cut off from his people.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And a man, a man from the house of Israel, and from the stranger sojourning in the midst of you, who shall eat any blood; and I gave my face against the soul eating the blood, and I cut it off from the midst of its people.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the soul of the flesh it is in the blood; and I gave it to you upon the altar to expiate for your souls: for the blood shall expiate for the soul.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For this I said to the sons of Israel, Every soul from you shall eat no blood, and the stranger sojourning in the midst of you shall not eat blood.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And a man, a man from the sons of Israel, and from the stranger sojourning in the midst of you, who shall hunt a hunting, a beast or bird which shall be eaten, and he poured out its blood and covered it with dust.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the soul of all flesh it is its blood in its soul: and say to the sons of Israel, The blood of all flesh ye shall not eat, for the soul of all flesh it is its blood: all eating it shall be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And every soul which shall eat a carcass and torn in pieces among the native or the stranger, and he washed his garments and washed in water, and was unclean till the evening: and he was clean.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And if he shall not wash his garments, and bathe not his flesh, and he shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
</chapter>