<chapter book="Leviticus" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And when a soul shall bring near an offering, a gift to Jehovah, his offering shall be fine flour; and he shall pour oil upon it, and give frankincense upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he brought it to Aaron’s sons the priests: and he pressed together from it his hand full from its fine flour, and from its oil, upon all its frankincense, and the priest burnt its memorial upon the altar, a sacrifice, an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the remainder from the gift, to Aaron and his sons; holy of holies from the sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And when thou shalt bring an offering, a gift, a baking of the oven, fine flour of unleavened cakes mingled with oil, and thin unleavened cakes anointed with oil.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And if a gift upon the frying pan their offering, fine flour mingled with oil, unleavened it shall be.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Break it to bits and pour oil upon it: it is a gift.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And if a gift of the pot thine offering, fine flour with oil it shall be made.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And bring the gift which shall be made from these to Jehovah: and bring it near to the priest, and he brought it near to the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the priest lifted up from the gift its memorial, and burnt upon the altar: a sacrifice, an odor of sweetness to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the remainder from the gift for Aaron and for his sons: holy of holies, from the sacrifices to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Every gift which ye shall bring near to Jehovah shall not be made leavened: for all leaven and all honey ye shall not burn from it a sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The offering of the first fruits ye shall bring them near to Jehovah: and to the altar they shall not go up for an odor of sweetness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And every offering of thy gift, thou shalt salt with salt; and thou shalt not cause the salt of the covenant of thy God to cease from thy gift: upon every offering of thine thou shalt bring near salt.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And if thou shalt bring near a gift of the first fruits to Jehovah, green ears parched in the fire, grits of early grain crushed shalt thou bring near, the gift of thy first fruits.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And give oil upon it and put frankincense upon: it is a gift.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the priest burnt its memorial from its crushing and from its oil, upon all its frankincense: a sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>