<chapter book="Leviticus" number="20" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">And to the sons of Israel thou shalt say, A man, a man from the sons of Israel, and from the stranger sojourning in Israel which shall give of his seed to Molech, dying, he shall die: the people of the land shall stone him with stones.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will give my face against that man and cut him off from the midst of his people; for he gave from his seed to Molech, in order to defile my holy place and to profane my holy name.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And if the people of the land, hiding, shall hide their eyes from that man in his giving his seed to Molech, so as not to put him to death;</verse>
  <verse number="5">And I set my face against that man and against his family, and I cut him off, and all committing fornication after him to commit fornication after Molech, from the midst of their people.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the soul which shall turn to necromancers and to wizards, to commit fornication after them, and I gave my face against that soul and I cut him off from the midst of his people.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And ye were consecrated and ye were holy: for I Jehovah your God.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And ye watched my laws, and ye did them: I Jehovah consecrating you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">When a man, a man who shall lightly esteem his father and his mother, dying, he shall die: he lightly esteemed ha father and his mother: his blood is upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And a man who shall commit adultery with a man’s wife, who shall commit adultery with his friend’s wife, dying, he shall die, the adulterer and the adulteress.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And a man who shall lie with his father’s wife, uncovered his father’s nakedness: dying, they shall die: they two their blood is upon them,</verse>
  <verse number="12">And a man who shall lie with his daughter-in-law, dying, they shall die, they two: they did profanation; their blood is upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And a man who shall lie with a male in a woman’s bed, they did abomination: they two, dying, shall die; their blood is upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A man who shall take a woman and her mother, it wickedness: in fire they shall be burnt, he and they: and there shall not be wickedness in the midst of you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And a man who shall give his bed with a quadruped, dying, he shall die: and ye shall kill the quadruped.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And a woman who shall come near to any quadruped to lie down with it, and didst thou kill the woman and the quadruped; dying, they shall die; their blood is upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And a man who shall take his sister, his father’s daughter, or his mother’s daughter, and he saw her nakedness, and she shall see his nakedness; it is a reproach; and they were cut off in the eyes of the sons of their people; he uncovered his sister’s nakedness; he shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And a man who shall lie with a woman being sick, and uncovered her nakedness; he made naked her fountain, and she uncovered the fountain of her blood: and they two were cut off from the midst of their people.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the nakedness of thy mother’s sister, and of thy father’s sister, thou shalt not uncover; for he made naked his remainder; they shall bear their iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And a man who shall lie with his aunt, uncovered the nakedness of his uncle: they shall bear their sin: they shall die childless.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And a man who shall take his brother’s wife, it is uncleanness: he uncovered his brother’s nakedness: they shall die childless.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And ye watched all my laws, and all my judgments, and did them: and the land shall not vomit you forth, which I brought you there to dwell in it.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And ye shall not walk in the laws of the nations which I sent out from before you: for they did all these things and I shall be disgusted with them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And I said to you, Ye shall inherit their land, and I will give it to you to inherit it, a land flowing with milk and honey: I Jehovah your God, who separated you from the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And ye separated between clean cattle to unclean, and between unclean birds and clean: and ye shall not make you souls abhorred by cattle or bird, and by any which shall creep upon the earth which I separated to you for unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And, ye were holy to me: for I Jehovah am holy, and I will separate you from the nations to be to me.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When a man or a woman shall be among them a necromancer, or a wizard, dying, they shall die: with stone shall they stone them: their blood is upon them.</verse>
</chapter>