<chapter book="Leviticus" number="22" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Speak to Aaron and to his sons, and they shall separate themselves from the holies of the sons of Israel, and they shall not profane my holy name which they consecrate to me: I Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Say to them, For your generations every man who shall come near from all your seed to the holies which the sons of Israel: shall consecrate to Jehovah, and his uncleanness upon him, and that soul was cut off from before me: I Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A man, a man from the seed of Aaron, and he leprous or flowing; he shall not eat of the holies till he shall be clean. And he touching upon any unclean soul, or a man which shall go forth from him the effusion of seed;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Or a man who shall touch upon any creeping thing which shall be unclean to him, or upon a man who shall be unclean to him for all his uncleanness;</verse>
  <verse number="6">The soul which shall touch upon it, and it shall be unclean till the evening, and he shall not eat from the holies, except he washed his flesh in water.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sun went down and he was clean; and afterwards he shall eat from the holies for it is his bread.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A carcass or torn of wild beast, he shall not eat to be defiled with it: I Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they watched my watches, and they bore not sin upon it, and they died when they profaned it: I Jehovah consecrating them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And any stranger shall not eat the holy thing: a sojourner of the priest and a hireling shall not eat the holy thing.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And when the priest shall buy a soul, the purchase of his silver, he shall eat of it, and they born in his house; they shall eat from his bread.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if the priest’s daughter shall be for a man, a stranger, she shall not eat from the offering of the holies.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And when the daughter of the priest shall be a widow, or driven out, and no seed to her, and she turned back to her father’s house as in her youth, she shall eat from her father’s bread; and any stranger shall not eat of it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And when a man shall eat the holy thing in error, and he shall add its fifth upon it, and give the holy thing to the priest.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And they shall not profane the holies of the sons of Israel which they shall lift up to Jehovah;</verse>
  <verse number="16">And for them to take up the sin of trespass in their eating the holies: for I Jehovah consecrating them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Speak to Aaron and to his sons, and to all the sons of Israel, and say to them, A man, a man from the house of Israel and from the stranger in Israel, who shall bring near his offering, for all their vows, and for all their willing gifts which they will offer to Jehovah for a burnt-offering:</verse>
  <verse number="19">For your acceptance a blameless male among the cattle, among the sheep, and among the goats.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And every one which in it is a blemish ye shall not bring it: for it shall not be for acceptance for you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And when a man shall bring a sacrifice of peace to Jehovah, to separate a vow or a willing gift in cattle or in sheep, it shall be blameless for acceptance: not any blemish shall be in it.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Blind, or broken, or cut, or flowing, or scurvy, or scabby, they shall not bring these to Jehovah, and a sacrifice ye shall not give from them upon the altar to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And an ox, and a sheep stretched out, and contracted, thou shalt do it a voluntary gift; and for a vow it shall not be accepted.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the bruised, and the smitten, and the torn, and the cut, ye shall not bring to Jehovah, and ye shall not do in your land.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And from the hand of the son of the stranger ye shall not bring near the bread of your God from all these, because their destruction is in them; a blemish in them; they shall not be accepted for you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="27">When a calf or lamb, or goat, shall be brought forth, it shall be seven days under its mother; and from the eighth day and beyond, it shall be accepted for an offering, a sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And an ox or a sheep, it and its son, thou shalt not slaughter in one day.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And when ye shall sacrifice a sacrifice of praise to Jehovah, ye shall sacrifice for your acceptance.</verse>
  <verse number="30">In that day it shall be eaten; ye shall not leave from it till morning: I Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And ye watched my commands and did them: I Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And ye did not profane my holy name; I was consecrated in the midst of the sons of Israel: I Jehovah consecrating you.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Having brought you forth from the land of Egypt to be to you for God: I Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>