<chapter book="Leviticus" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Command the sons of Israel, and they shall take to thee pure olive oil beaten for the light, to cause the lamp to ascend always.</verse>
  <verse number="3">From without the vail of the testimony, in the tent of appointment, shall Aaron arrange it from evening to morning, before Jehovah always: a law forever to your generations.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Upon the pure chandelier shall he arrange the lamps before Jehovah always.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And take the fine flour and bake it, twelve cakes; two tenths shall be the one cake.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And put them two rows, six the row, upon the pure table before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And give upon the row pure frankincense, and it was to the bread for a remembrance; a sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="8">In the day of the Sabbath, in the day of the Sabbath he shall arrange it before Jehovah always, from the sons of Israel, a covenant forever.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And it was to Aaron and to his sons, and they shall eat it in the holy place: for it is holy of holies to him from the sacrifices of Jehovah a law forever.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the son of a woman, an Israelitess, will go forth (he the son of a man an Egyptian) into the midst of the sons of Israel: and they will strive in the camp, the son of the Israelitess, and the man the Israelite.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the son of the woman the Israelitess, will curse the name, and will vilify, and they will bring him to Moses: and his mother’s name Shelomith, the daughter of Dibri, to the tribe of Dan.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And they placed him in watch, to declare distinctly to them by the mouth of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Bring him vilifying, without the camp; and all they hearing, placed their hands upon his head, and all the assembly stoned him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And to the sons of Israel thou shalt speak, saying, When a man, a man shall curse his God and he bore his sin.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he vilifying the name of Jehovah, dying, shall die; stoning, all the assembly shall stone him: as the stranger so the native, in his vilifying the name, he shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And when a man shall smite any soul of man, dying, he shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he smiting the soul of cattle, shall recompense soul for soul.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And when a man shall give a blemish in his neighbor, as he did so it shall be done to him:</verse>
  <verse number="20">Fracture for fracture, eye for eye, tooth for tooth: as he shall give a blemish in a man so it shall be given in him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And be smiting cattle shall recompense it; and he smiting man, shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="22">One judgment to you; as the stranger so the native shall it be: for I Jehovah your God.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Moses will speak to the sons of Israel, and they will bring forth him cursing, without the camp, and they will stone him with stone: and the sons of Israel did as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
</chapter>