<chapter book="Leviticus" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Take Aaron and his sons with him, and the garments, and the oil of anointing, and a bullock of the sin, and two rams, and a basket of the unleavened;</verse>
  <verse number="3">And gather together all the assembly to the door of the tent of appointment.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Moses will do as Jehovah commanded him: and the assembly will be gathered together to the door of the tent of appointment.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Moses will say to the assembly, This the word which Jehovah commanded to do.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Moses will bring near Aaron and his sons, and will wash them in water.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And he will give upon him the tunic, and he will gird him with the girdle, and he will put upon him the robe, and will give upon him the ephod, and will gird him with the girdle of the ephod, and will gird on him with it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he will put upon him the breast-plate: and will give to the breastplate the Lights and the Truth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he will put the turban upon his head; and he will put upon the turban, at the front of his face, the brightness of gold, the holy diadem, as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Moses will take the oil of anointing, and will anoint the dwelling and all which is in it, and he will consecrate them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he will sprinkle from it upon the altar seven times, and anoint the altar and all its vessels, and the wash-basin, and its foot, to consecrate them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And he will pour out from the oil of anointing upon the head of Aaron, and anoint him to consecrate him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Moses will bring near the sons of Aaron, and he will put tunics upon them, and he will gird on them with the girdle and he will bind to them caps; as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he will bring near the bullock of sin: and Aaron and his sons will place their hands upon the head of the bullock of sin.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he will slaughter; and Moses will take the blood and give upon the horns of the altar round about with his finger, and he will purify the altar, and he will sour out the blood at the foundation of the altar, and he will consecrate it to expiate upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he will take all the fat which upon the bowels, and the lobe of the liver, and the two kidneys, and their fat, and Moses will burn upon the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the bullock and his skin, and his flesh, and his dung, he burnt in fire without the camp, as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he will bring the ram of the burnt-offering: and Aaron and his sons will place their hands upon the head of the ram.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he will slaughter, and Moses will sprinkle the blood upon the altar round about.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he cut the ram into its pieces; and Moses will burn the head and the pieces, and the fat.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the bowels and the legs he washed in water; and Moses will burn all the ram upon the altar: it is a burnt-offering for an odor of sweetness; it is a sacrifice to Jehovah; as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he will bring the second ram, the ram of the filling up: and Aaron and his sons will place their hands upon the head of the ram.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he will slaughter, and Moses will take from its blood, and will give upon the extremity of Aaron’s right ear, and upon the thumb of his right hand, and upon the great toe of his right foot.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he will bring near Aaron’s sons, and Moses will give from the blood upon the extremity of their right ear, and upon the thumb of their right hand, and upon the great toe of their right feet: and Moses will sprinkle the blood upon the altar round about.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he will take the fat and the fat tail, and all the fat which is upon the bowels, and the lobe of the liver, and the two kidneys and their fat, and the right leg:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And from the basket of unleavened which is before Jehovah he took one unleavened cake and a cake of bread of oil, and one thin cake, and he will put upon the fat and upon the right leg:</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he will give the whole upon the hands of Aaron, and upon the hands of his sons, and he shall lift them up a waving before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Moses will take them from their hands and burn upon the altar upon the burnt-offering: they fillings up for an odor of sweetness: it is a sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Moses will take the breast and will lift it up; a waving before Jehovah: from the ram of the fillings up it was to Moses for a portion; as Jehovah commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Moses will take from the oil of anointing, and from the blood which is upon the altar, and will sprinkle upon Aaron, upon his garments, and upon his sons, and upon his sons’ garments with him; and will consecrate Aaron and his garments, and his sons, and his sons’ garments with him.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Moses will say to Aaron and to his sons, Boil the flesh at the door of the tent of appointment; and there ye shall eat it, and the bread which is in the basket of the fillings up, as I commanded, saying, Aaron and his sons shall eat it.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the remainder of the flesh and of the bread ye shall burn in fire.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And ye shall not go out from the door of the tent of appointment, seven days, till the day of filling up the days of your fillings up: for seven days shall he fill your hands.</verse>
  <verse number="34">As he did in this day, Jehovah commanded to do, to expiate for you.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And at the door of the tent of appointment shall ye sit day and night seven days, and watch the watches of Jehovah, and ye shall not die: for so I was commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Aaron did and his sons all the word which Jehovah commanded by the hand of Moses.</verse>
</chapter>