<chapter book="Judges" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And a messenger of Jehovah will go up from Gilgal to Bochim, and he will say, I will bring you up out of Egypt, and I will bring you in to the land which I sware to your fathers; and he said I will not break my covenant with you forever.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And ye shall not cut out a covenant to the inhabitants of this land; their altars ye shall break down: and ye heard not to my voice: why did ye this?</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I also said, I will not drive them out from your face; and they were to you for adversaries, and their gods shall be to you for a snare.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And it will be when the messenger of Jehovah spake these words to all the sons of Israel, and the people will lift up their voice and weep.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they will call the name of that place Bochim: and they will sacrifice there to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Joshua will send away the people, and the sons of Israel will go a man to his inheritance to inherit the land.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the people will serve Jehovah all the days of Joshua, and all the days of the old men who prolonged the days after Joshua, who saw all the great works of Jehovah which he did to Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Joshua the son of Nun, the servant of Jehovah, will die, the son of a hundred and ten years.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they will bury him in the bound of his inheritance in Timnath-Serah, in mount Ephraim, from the north to the mount of Gaash.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And also all that generation were gathered to its fathers; and another generation will arise after them not knowing Jehovah, and also the works which he did to Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the sons of Israel will do evil in the eyes of Jehovah, and will serve the Baalims.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And they will forsake Jehovah the God of their fathers bringing them out of the land of Egypt, and go after other gods from the gods of the peoples which are round about them, and they will worship to them and provoke Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they will forsake Jehovah, and will serve Baal and Ashtaroth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the wrath of Jehovah will kindle against Israel, and he will give them into the hand of plunderers, and they will plunder them; and he will sell them into the hand of their enemies from round about, and they will no more be able to stand before the face of their enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="15">In all where they will go forth, the hand of Jehovah was against them for evil, as Jehovah spake and as Jehovah sware to them: and he will press them greatly.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Jehovah will raise up judges, and they will save them from the hand of their plunderers.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And also they will not hear to their judges, for they committed fornications after other gods, and they will worship to them: they turned aside quickly from the way which their fathers went to hear the commands of Jehovah; they did not so.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And when Jehovah raised up to them judges, and Jehovah was with the judge, and saved them from the hand of their enemies all of the days of the judge: for Jehovah will grieve from their groaning from the face of those pressing them and thrusting them.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And it was in the dying of the judge, they will turn back and be corrupted above their fathers to go after other gods to serve them and to worship to them: they let nothing fall from their deeds and from their hard way.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the wrath of Jehovah will kindle against Israel; and he will say, Because that this nation passed by my covenant which I commanded their fathers, and heard not to my voice,</verse>
  <verse number="21">I also will not add to drive out a man from their face from the nations which Joshua left, and he died,</verse>
  <verse number="22">So as to try Israel by them, whether they are watching the way of Jehovah to go in them, as their fathers watched, or not.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Jehovah will leave these nations, not to drive them out quickly, and he gave them not into the hand of Joshua.</verse>
</chapter>