<chapter book="Judges" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Deborah will sing, and Barak, son of Abinoam, in that day, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">In the leading on of the leaders in Israel, In the willingness of the people, praise ye Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Hear, ye kings; give ear ye princes; I, to Jehovah, will I sing; I will play to Jehovah, God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Jehovah, in thy going forth from Seir, In thy ascending from the field of Edom, The earth trembled, the heavens also dropped, Also the clouds dropped water.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The mountains flowed from before Jehovah, This Sinai from before Jehovah, the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the days of Shamgar, son of Anath, In the days of Jael, they left the ways; They went the by-ways; they will go the winding ways.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The rulers ceased in Israel: they ceased Till I, Deborah, arose: I arose a mother in Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He will choose new gods; Then war in the gates: If a shield was seen, and a lance, Among forty thousand in Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My heart to the leaders of Israel, Those giving voluntarily among the people: Praise ye Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Ye riding upon white asses, Sitting upon jurisdiction, And going upon the way, speak ye.</verse>
  <verse number="11">From the voice of arrows between the watering-troughs, There will they give the justices of Jehovah, The justices of his rule in Israel: Then will the people of Jehovah go down to the gates.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Awake, awake! Deborah; Awake, awake! speak a song: Arise, Barak, and lead captive, thy captivity, son of Abinoam.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then the one left shall go down to the chiefs of the people: Jehovah will come down to me among the mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The fate of Ephraim uprooted them in Amalek; After thee, Benjamin, among thy tribes; From Machir the lawgivers came down, And from Zebulon they drawing with the rod of the scribe.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the chiefs in Issachar with Deborah; And Issachar, so Barak: In the valley sent he, upon his feet. In the divisions of Reuben, Great decrees of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Wherefore didst thou dwell in the midst of the folds, To hear the pipings of the flocks? For the divisions of Reuben, great searching’s of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In Gilead beyond Jordan he dwelt; And Dan, wherefore will he sojourn in ships? Asher will dwell by the shore of the seas, And upon his harbors will he dwell.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Zebulon a people reproached his soul to death, And Naphtali upon the heights of the field.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Kings came: they fought: Then fought the kings of Canaan, Tanach, upon the water of Megiddo: Plunder of silver took they not.</verse>
  <verse number="20">From the heavens they fought; The stars from their raised ways fought with Sisera.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The torrent Kishon snatched them away The torrent of ancient days, the torrent of Kishon. Thou wilt tread down strength, O my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then were the horse heels smitten From the courses, the courses of his strong ones.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Curse ye Meroz, said the messenger of Jehovah: Cursing, curse ye her inhabitants; For they came not to the help of Jehovah To the help of Jehovah against the mighty ones.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Blessed shall be Jael above women, The wife of Heber the Kenite, Above women in the tent shall she be blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He asked water, she gave milk; In a prince’s dish brought she curdled milk.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Her hand to the peg will she stretch forth, And her right hand to the hammer of labor, And she struck Sisera; she smote through his head, And she crushed and pierced through his temples.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Between her feet he bowed, he fell, he lay down: Between her feet he bowed, he fell: Where he bowed, there he fell, destroyed.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Through the window she looked forth and cried out, The mother of Sisera, through the lattice Why did his chariot delay to come? Why lingered the paces of his chariots?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Her wise chiefs will answer, Surely, will she turn back words to herself,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Will they not find? They will divide the spoil; He compassionated compassions to head of man; The spoil of dyed garments to Sisera, A spoil of dyed garments of variegation, Dyed of double variegation for the necks of the spoil.</verse>
  <verse number="31">So shall all thine enemies perish, O Jehovah: And those loving him, as the going forth of the sun in his strength. And the land will rest forty years.</verse>
</chapter>