<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="7" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A good name is better than precious ointment; and the day of death than the day of one’s birth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">It is better to go to the house of mourning, than to go to the house of feasting: for that is the end of all men; and the living will lay it to his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Sorrow is better than laughter: for by the sadness of the countenance the heart is made better.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The heart of the wise is in the house of mourning; but the heart of fools is in the house of mirth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">It is better to hear the rebuke of the wise, than for a man to hear the song of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For as the crackling of thorns under a pot, so is the laughter of the fool: this also is vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Surely oppression makes a wise man mad; and a gift destroys the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Better is the end of a thing than the beginning thereof: and the patient in spirit is better than the proud in spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be not hasty in your spirit to be angry: for anger rests in the bosom of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Say not you, What is the cause that the former days were better than these? for you do not inquire wisely concerning this.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wisdom is good with an inheritance: and by it there is profit to them that see the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For wisdom is a defense, and money is a defense: but the excellency of knowledge is, that wisdom gives life to them that have it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Consider the work of God: for who can make that straight, which he has made crooked?</verse>
  <verse number="14">In the day of prosperity be joyful, but in the day of adversity consider: God also has set the one over against the other, to the end that man should find nothing after him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">All things have I seen in the days of my vanity: there is a just man that perishes in his righteousness, and there is a wicked man that prolongs his life in his wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Be not righteous over much; neither make yourself over wise: why should you destroy yourself ?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Be not over much wicked, neither be you foolish: why should you die before your time?</verse>
  <verse number="18">It is good that you should take hold of this; yes, also from this withdraw not your hand: for he that fears God shall come forth of them all.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wisdom strengthens the wise more than ten mighty men which are in the city.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For there is not a just man on earth, that does good, and sins not.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Also take no heed to all words that are spoken; lest you hear your servant curse you:</verse>
  <verse number="22">For oftentimes also your own heart knows that you yourself likewise have cursed others.</verse>
  <verse number="23">All this have I proved by wisdom: I said, I will be wise; but it was far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="24">That which is far off, and exceeding deep, who can find it out?</verse>
  <verse number="25">I applied my heart to know, and to search, and to seek out wisdom, and the reason of things, and to know the wickedness of folly, even of foolishness and madness:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And I find more bitter than death the woman, whose heart is snares and nets, and her hands as bands: whoever pleases God shall escape from her; but the sinner shall be taken by her.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Behold, this have I found, said the preacher, counting one by one, to find out the account:</verse>
  <verse number="28">Which yet my soul seeks, but I find not: one man among a thousand have I found; but a woman among all those have I not found.</verse>
  <verse number="29">See, this only have I found, that God has made man upright; but they have sought out many inventions.</verse>
</chapter>