<chapter book="Amos" number="5" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hear this word that I am bearing to you, A lamentation, O house of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="2">‘Fallen, not again to rise, hath the virgin of Israel, Left on her land—she hath no raiser up.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">For thus said the Lord Jehovah: The city that is going out a thousand, Doth leave an hundred, And that which is going out an hundred, Doth leave ten to the house of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For thus said Jehovah to the house of Israel: Seek ye Me, and live,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And seek not Beth-El, and Gilgal enter not, And Beer-Sheba pass not through, For Gilgal doth utterly remove, And Beth-El doth become vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Seek ye Jehovah, and live, Lest He prosper as fire against the house of Joseph, And it hath consumed, And there is no quencher for Beth-El.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ye who are turning to wormwood judgment, And righteousness to the earth have put down,</verse>
  <verse number="8">The maker of Kimah and Kesil, And the turner to morning of death-shade, And day as night He hath made dark, Who is calling to the waters of the sea, And poureth them on the face of the earth, Jehovah is His name;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who is brightening up the spoiled against the strong, And the spoiled against a fortress cometh.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They have hated a reprover in the gate, And a plain speaker they abominate.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore, because of your trampling on the poor, And the tribute of corn ye take from him, Houses of hewn work ye have built, And ye do not dwell in them, Desirable vineyards ye have planted, And ye do not drink their wine.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I have known—many are your transgressions, And mighty your sins, Adversaries of the righteous, taking ransoms, And the needy in the gate ye turned aside.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Therefore is the wise at that time silent, For an evil time it is.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Seek good, and not evil, that ye may live, And it is so; Jehovah, God of Hosts, is with you, as ye said.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Hate evil, and love good, And set up judgment in the gate, It may be Jehovah, God of Hosts, doth pity the remnant of Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Therefore, thus said Jehovah, God of Hosts, the Lord, In all broad places is lamentation, And in all out-places they say, ‘Alas, alas,’ And called the husbandman to mourning, And to lamentation the skilful of wailing.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And in all vineyards is lamentation, For I pass into thy midst, said Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Ho, ye who are desiring the day of Jehovah, Why is this to you—the day of Jehovah? It is darkness, and not light,</verse>
  <verse number="19">As when one fleeth from the face of the lion, And the bear hath met him, And he hath come in to the house, And hath leant his hand on the wall, And the serpent hath bitten him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Is not the day of Jehovah darkness and not light, Even thick darkness that hath no brightness?</verse>
  <verse number="21">I have hated—I have loathed your festivals, And I am not refreshed by your restraints.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For though ye cause burnt-offerings and your presents to ascend to Me, I am not pleased, And the peace-offering of your fatlings I behold not.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn aside from Me the noise of thy songs, Yea, the praise of thy psaltery I hear not.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And roll on as waters doth judgment, And righteousness as a perennial stream.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Sacrifices and offering did ye bring nigh to Me, In a wilderness forty years, O house of Israel?</verse>
  <verse number="26">And ye bare Succoth your king, and Chiun your images, The star of your god, that ye made for yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And I removed you beyond Damascus, Said Jehovah, God of Hosts is His name.</verse>
</chapter>