<chapter book="Job" number="10" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My soul is weary of my life: I will give free course to my complaint; I will speak in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will say unto +God, Do not condemn me; shew me wherefore thou strivest with me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Doth it please thee to oppress, that thou shouldest despise the work of thy hands, and shine upon the counsel of the wicked?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Hast thou eyes of flesh? or seest thou as man seeth?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Are thy days as the days of a mortal? are thy years as a man’s days,</verse>
  <verse number="6">That thou searchest after mine iniquity, and inquirest into my sin;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Since thou knowest that I am not wicked, and that there is none that delivereth out of thy hand?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thy hands have bound me together and made me as one, round about; yet dost thou swallow me up!</verse>
  <verse number="9">Remember, I beseech thee, that thou hast made me as clay, and wilt bring me into dust again.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Hast thou not poured me out as milk, and curdled me like cheese?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thou hast clothed me with skin and flesh, and knit me together with bones and sinews;</verse>
  <verse number="12">Thou hast granted me life and favour, and thy care hath preserved my spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="13">And these things didst thou hide in thy heart; I know that this was with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If I sinned, thou wouldest mark me, and thou wouldest not acquit me of mine iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If I were wicked, woe unto me! and righteous, I will not lift up my head, being [so] full of shame, and beholding mine affliction;—</verse>
  <verse number="16">And it increaseth: thou huntest me as a fierce lion; and ever again thou shewest thy marvellous power upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou renewest thy witnesses before me and increasest thy displeasure against me; successions [of evil] and a time of toil are with me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And wherefore didst thou bring me forth out of the womb? I had expired, and no eye had seen me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I should be as though I had not been; I should have been carried from the womb to the grave.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Are not my days few? cease then and let me alone, that I may revive a little,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Before I go, and never to return,—to the land of darkness and the shadow of death;</verse>
  <verse number="22">A land of gloom, as darkness itself; of the shadow of death, without any order, where the light is as thick darkness.</verse>
</chapter>