<chapter book="Job" number="11" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Zophar the Naamathite answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Should not the multitude of words be answered? and should a man of much talk be justified?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Should thy fictions make men hold their peace? and shouldest thou mock, and no one make [thee] ashamed?</verse>
  <verse number="4">For thou sayest, My doctrine is pure, and I am clean in thine eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But oh that +God would speak, and open his lips against thee;</verse>
  <verse number="6">And that he would shew thee the secrets of wisdom, how that they are the double of what is realised; and know that +God passeth by [much] of thine iniquity!</verse>
  <verse number="7">Canst thou by searching find out +God? canst thou find out the Almighty to perfection?</verse>
  <verse number="8">[It is as] the heights of heaven; what wilt thou do? deeper than Sheol; what canst thou know?</verse>
  <verse number="9">The measure thereof is longer than the earth, and broader than the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If he pass by, and shut up, and call to judgment, who can hinder him?</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he knoweth vain men, and seeth wickedness when [man] doth not consider it;</verse>
  <verse number="12">Yet a senseless man will make bold, though man be born [like] the foal of a wild ass.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If thou prepare thy heart and stretch out thy hands toward him,</verse>
  <verse number="14">If thou put far away the iniquity which is in thy hand, and let not wrong dwell in thy tents;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Surely then shalt thou lift up thy face without spot, and thou shalt be stedfast and shalt not fear:</verse>
  <verse number="16">For thou shalt forget misery; as waters that are passed away shalt thou remember it;</verse>
  <verse number="17">And life shall arise brighter than noonday; though thou be enshrouded in darkness, thou shalt be as the morning,</verse>
  <verse number="18">And thou shalt have confidence, because there shall be hope; and having searched about [thee], thou shalt take rest in safety.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Yea, thou shalt lie down, and none shall make thee afraid; and many shall seek thy favour.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But the eyes of the wicked shall fail, and [all] refuge shall vanish from them, and their hope [shall be] the breathing out of life.</verse>
</chapter>