<chapter book="Job" number="13" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Lo, mine eye hath seen all [this], mine ear hath heard and understood it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">What ye know, I know also: I am not inferior to you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">But I will speak to the Almighty, and will find pleasure in reasoning with God;</verse>
  <verse number="4">For ye indeed are forgers of lies, ye are all physicians of no value.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Oh that ye would be altogether silent! and it would be your wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Hear now my defence, and hearken to the pleadings of my lips.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Will ye speak unrighteously for God? and for him speak deceit?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Will ye accept his person? will ye contend for God?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will it be well if he should search you out? or as one mocketh at a man, will ye mock at him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">He will certainly reprove you, if ye do secretly accept persons.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Shall not his excellency terrify you? and his dread fall upon you?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Your memorable sayings are proverbs of ashes, your bulwarks are bulwarks of mire.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hold your peace from me, and I will speak, and let come on me what [will]!</verse>
  <verse number="14">Wherefore should I take my flesh in my teeth, and put my life in my hand?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, if he slay me, yet would I trust in him; but I will defend mine own ways before him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This also shall be my salvation, that a profane man shall not come before his face.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Hear attentively my speech and my declaration with your ears.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Behold now, I have ordered the cause; I know that I shall be justified.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Who is he that contendeth with me? For if I were silent now, I should expire.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Only do not two things unto me; then will I not hide myself from thee.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Withdraw thy hand far from me; and let not thy terror make me afraid:</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then call, and I will answer; or I will speak, and answer thou me.</verse>
  <verse number="23">How many are mine iniquities and sins? Make me to know my transgression and my sin.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Wherefore dost thou hide thy face, and countest me for thine enemy?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Wilt thou terrify a driven leaf? and wilt thou pursue dry stubble?</verse>
  <verse number="26">For thou writest bitter things against me, and makest me to possess the iniquities of my youth;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And thou puttest my feet in the stocks, and markest all my paths; thou settest a bound about the soles of my feet;—</verse>
  <verse number="28">One who, as a rotten thing consumeth, as a garment that the moth eateth.</verse>
</chapter>