<chapter book="Job" number="16" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">I have heard many such things: grievous comforters are ye all.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Shall words of wind have an end? or what provoketh thee that thou answerest?</verse>
  <verse number="4">I also could speak as ye: if your soul were in my soul’s stead, I could join together words against you, and shake my head at you;</verse>
  <verse number="5">[But] I would encourage you with my mouth, and the solace of my lips should assuage [your pain].</verse>
  <verse number="6">If I speak, my pain is not assuaged; and if I forbear, what am I eased?</verse>
  <verse number="7">But now he hath made me weary;... thou hast made desolate all my family;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thou hast shrivelled me up! it is become a witness; and my leanness riseth up against me, it beareth witness to my face.</verse>
  <verse number="9">His anger teareth and pursueth me; he gnasheth with his teeth against me; [as] mine adversary he sharpeneth his eyes at me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They gape upon me with their mouth; they smite my cheeks reproachfully; they range themselves together against me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">God hath delivered me over to the iniquitous man, and hurled me into the hands of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I was at rest, but he hath shattered me; he hath taken me by the neck and shaken me to pieces, and set me up for his mark.</verse>
  <verse number="13">His arrows encompass me round about, he cleaveth my reins asunder and doth not spare; he poureth out my gall upon the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He breaketh me with breach upon breach; he runneth upon me like a mighty man.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I have sewed sackcloth upon my skin, and rolled my horn in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My face is red with weeping, and on my eyelids is the shadow of death;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Although there is no violence in my hands, and my prayer is pure.</verse>
  <verse number="18">O earth, cover not my blood, and let there be no place for my cry!</verse>
  <verse number="19">Even now, behold, my Witness is in the heavens, and he that voucheth for me is in the heights.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My friends are my mockers; mine eye poureth out tears unto +God.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Oh that there were arbitration for a man with +God, as a son of man for his friend!</verse>
  <verse number="22">For years [few] in number shall pass,—and I shall go the way [whence] I shall not return.</verse>
</chapter>