<chapter book="Job" number="22" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Eliphaz the Temanite answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can a man be profitable to God? surely it is unto himself that the wise man is profitable.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it any pleasure to the Almighty if thou art righteous? And is it gain [to him] that thou makest thy ways perfect?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will he reason with thee for fear of thee? Will he enter with thee into judgment?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Is not thy wickedness great? and thine iniquities without end?</verse>
  <verse number="6">For thou hast taken a pledge of thy brother for nought, and stripped off the clothing of the naked.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thou hast not given water to the fainting to drink, and thou hast withholden bread from the hungry.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But the powerful man, he had the land; and the man of high rank dwelt in it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Widows hast thou sent empty away, and the arms of the fatherless have been broken.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore snares are round about thee, and sudden fear troubleth thee;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Or darkness, that thou canst not see, and floods of waters cover thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is not +God in the height of the heavens? And behold the summit of the stars: how exalted are they!</verse>
  <verse number="13">And thou sayest, What doth God know? will he judge through the dark cloud?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thick clouds are a covering to him, that he seeth not; and he walketh on the vault of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Dost thou mark the ancient path which wicked men have trodden?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Who were carried off before the time, whose foundation was overflowed with a flood;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Who said unto God, Depart from us! and what could the Almighty do to them?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Yet he filled their houses with good. But the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The righteous see it, and are glad; and the innocent laugh them to scorn:</verse>
  <verse number="20">Is not he who rose against us destroyed, and doth not the fire consume his residue?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Reconcile thyself now with him, and be at peace: thereby good shall come unto thee.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Receive, I pray thee, instruction from his mouth, and lay up his words in thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If thou return to the Almighty, thou shalt be built up. If thou remove unrighteousness far from thy tents,</verse>
  <verse number="24">And put the precious ore with the dust, and [the gold of] Ophir among the stones of the torrents,</verse>
  <verse number="25">Then the Almighty will be thy precious ore, and silver heaped up unto thee;</verse>
  <verse number="26">Yea, then shalt thou delight thyself in the Almighty, and shalt lift up thy face unto +God:</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thou shalt make thy prayer unto him, and he will hear thee, and thou shalt pay thy vows;</verse>
  <verse number="28">And thou shalt decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee; and light shall shine upon thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When they are made low, then thou shalt say, Rise up! and he shall save him that is of downcast eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="30">[Even] him that is not innocent shall he deliver; yea, he shall be delivered by the pureness of thy hands.</verse>
</chapter>