<chapter book="Job" number="27" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job continued his parable and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">[As] God liveth, who hath taken away my right, and the Almighty, who hath embittered my soul,</verse>
  <verse number="3">All the while my breath is in me, and the spirit of +God is in my nostrils,</verse>
  <verse number="4">My lips shall not speak unrighteousness, nor my tongue utter deceit!</verse>
  <verse number="5">Be it far from me that I should justify you; till I die I will not remove my blamelessness from me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">My righteousness I hold fast, and will not let it go: my heart reproacheth [me] not one of my days.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Let mine enemy be as the wicked, and he that riseth up against me as the unrighteous.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For what is the hope of the ungodly, when [God] cutteth him off, when +God taketh away his soul?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will God hear his cry when distress cometh upon him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Doth he delight himself in the Almighty? will he at all times call upon +God?</verse>
  <verse number="11">I will teach you concerning the hand of God; what is with the Almighty will I not conceal.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Behold, ye yourselves have all seen [it]; and why are ye thus altogether vain?</verse>
  <verse number="13">This is the portion of the wicked man with God, and the heritage of the violent, which they receive from the Almighty:—</verse>
  <verse number="14">If his children be multiplied, it is for the sword, and his offspring shall not be satisfied with bread;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Those that remain of him shall be buried by death, and his widows shall not weep.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Though he heap up silver as the dust, and prepare clothing as the clay;</verse>
  <verse number="17">He may prepare it, but the just shall put it on; and the innocent shall divide the silver.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He buildeth his house as the moth, and as a booth that a keeper maketh.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He lieth down rich, but will do so no more; he openeth his eyes, and he is not.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Terrors overtake him like waters; a whirlwind stealeth him away in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The east wind carrieth him away and he is gone; and as a storm it hurleth him out of his place.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And [God] shall cast upon him and not spare: he would fain flee out of his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="23">[Men] shall clap their hands at him, and shall hiss him out of his place.</verse>
</chapter>