<chapter book="Job" number="3" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After this, Job opened his mouth and cursed his day.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Job answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let the day perish in which I was born, and the night that said, There is a man child conceived.</verse>
  <verse number="4">That day—let it be darkness, let not +God care for it from above, neither let light shine upon it:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Let darkness and the shadow of death claim it; let clouds dwell upon it; let darkeners of the day terrify it.</verse>
  <verse number="6">That night—let gloom seize upon it; let it not rejoice among the days of the year; let it not come into the number of the months.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Behold, let that night be barren; let no joyful sound come therein;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Let them curse it that curse the day, who are ready to rouse Leviathan;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Let the stars of its twilight be dark; let it wait for light, and have none, neither let it see the eyelids of the dawn:</verse>
  <verse number="10">Because it shut not up the doors of the womb that bore me, and hid not trouble from mine eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wherefore did I not die from the womb,—come forth from the belly and expire?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why did the knees meet me? and wherefore the breasts, that I should suck?</verse>
  <verse number="13">For now should I have lain down and been quiet; I should have slept: then had I been at rest,</verse>
  <verse number="14">With kings and counsellors of the earth, who build desolate places for themselves,</verse>
  <verse number="15">Or with princes who had gold, who filled their houses with silver;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Or as a hidden untimely birth I had not been; as infants that have not seen the light.</verse>
  <verse number="17">There the wicked cease from troubling; and there the wearied are at rest.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The prisoners together are at ease; they hear not the voice of the taskmaster.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The small and great are there, and the bondman freed from his master.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wherefore is light given to him that is in trouble, and life to those bitter of soul,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Who long for death, and it [cometh] not, and dig for it more than for hidden treasures;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Who rejoice even exultingly and are glad when they find the grave?—</verse>
  <verse number="23">To the man whose way is hidden, and whom +God hath hedged in?</verse>
  <verse number="24">For my sighing cometh before my bread, and my groanings are poured out like the waters.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For I feared a fear, and it hath come upon me, and that which I dreaded hath come to me.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I was not in safety, neither had I quietness, neither was I at rest, and trouble came.</verse>
</chapter>