<chapter book="Job" number="38" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah answered Job out of the whirlwind and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who is this that darkeneth counsel by words without knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Gird up now thy loins like a man; and I will demand of thee, and inform thou me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where wast thou when I founded the earth? Declare, if thou hast understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who set the measures thereof—if thou knowest? or who stretched a line upon it?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whereupon were the foundations thereof sunken? or who laid its corner-stone,</verse>
  <verse number="7">When the morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
  <verse number="8">And who shut up the sea with doors, when it burst forth, issuing out of the womb?</verse>
  <verse number="9">When I made the cloud its garment, and thick darkness a swaddling band for it;</verse>
  <verse number="10">When I cut out for it my boundary, and set bars and doors,</verse>
  <verse number="11">And said, Hitherto shalt thou come and no further, and here shall thy proud waves be stayed?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Hast thou since thy days commanded the morning? hast thou caused the dawn to know its place,</verse>
  <verse number="13">That it might take hold of the ends of the earth, and the wicked might be shaken out of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">It is changed like the signet-clay; and [all things] stand forth as in a garment:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And from the wicked their light is withholden, and the uplifted arm is broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Hast thou entered as far as the springs of the sea? and hast thou walked in the recesses of the deep?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Have the gates of death been revealed unto thee? and hast thou seen the gates of the shadow of death?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Hath thine understanding compassed the breadths of the earth? Declare if thou knowest it all.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Where is the way to where light dwelleth? and the darkness, where is its place,</verse>
  <verse number="20">That thou shouldest take it to its bound, and that thou shouldest know the paths to its house?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Thou knowest, for thou wast then born, and the number of thy days is great!</verse>
  <verse number="22">Hast thou entered into the storehouses of the snow, and hast thou seen the treasuries of the hail,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Which I have reserved for the time of distress, for the day of battle and war?</verse>
  <verse number="24">By what way is the light parted, [and] the east wind scattered upon the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who hath divided a channel for the rain-flood, and a way for the thunder’s flash;</verse>
  <verse number="26">To cause it to rain on the earth, where no one is; on the wilderness wherein there is not a man;</verse>
  <verse number="27">To satisfy the desolate and waste [ground], and to cause the sprout of the grass to spring forth?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Hath the rain a father? or who begetteth the drops of dew?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Out of whose womb cometh the ice? and the hoary frost of heaven, who bringeth it forth?</verse>
  <verse number="30">When the waters lie hidden as in stone, and the face of the deep holdeth fast together.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Canst thou fasten the bands of the Pleiades, or loosen the cords of Orion?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Dost thou bring forth the constellations each in its season? or dost thou guide the Bear with her sons?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Knowest thou the ordinances of the heavens? dost thou determine their rule over the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Dost thou lift up thy voice to the clouds, that floods of waters may cover thee?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Dost thou send forth lightnings that they may go, and say unto thee, Here we are?</verse>
  <verse number="36">Who hath put wisdom in the inward parts? or who hath given understanding to the mind?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who numbereth the clouds with wisdom? or who poureth out the bottles of the heavens,</verse>
  <verse number="38">When the dust runneth as into a molten mass, and the clods cleave fast together?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Dost thou hunt the prey for the lioness, and dost thou satisfy the appetite of the young lions,</verse>
  <verse number="40">When they crouch in [their] dens, [and] abide in the thicket to lie in wait?</verse>
  <verse number="41">Who provideth for the raven his food, when his young ones cry unto God, [and] they wander for lack of meat?</verse>
</chapter>