<chapter book="Job" number="6" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Oh that my grief were thoroughly weighed, and all my calamity laid in the balances!</verse>
  <verse number="3">For now it would be heavier than the sand of the seas; therefore my words are vehement.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For the arrows of the Almighty are within me, their poison drinketh up my spirit: the terrors of +God are arrayed against me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Doth the wild ass bray by the grass? loweth an ox over his fodder?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Shall that which is insipid be eaten without salt? Is there any taste in the white of an egg?</verse>
  <verse number="7">What my soul refuseth to touch, that is as my loathsome food.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Oh that I might have my request, and that +God would grant my desire!</verse>
  <verse number="9">And that it would please +God to crush me, that he would let loose his hand and cut me off!</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then should I yet have comfort; and in the pain which spareth not I would rejoice that I have not denied the words of the Holy One.</verse>
  <verse number="11">What is my strength, that I should hope? and what is mine end, that I should have patience?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is my strength the strength of stones? is my flesh of brass?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Is it not that there is no help in me, and soundness is driven away from me?</verse>
  <verse number="14">For him that is fainting kindness [is meet] from his friend; or he forsaketh the fear of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My brethren have dealt deceitfully as a stream, as the channel of streams which pass away,</verse>
  <verse number="16">Which are turbid by reason of the ice, in which the snow hideth itself:</verse>
  <verse number="17">At the time they diminish, they are dried up; when heat affecteth them, they vanish from their place:</verse>
  <verse number="18">They wind about in the paths of their course, they go off into the waste and perish.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The caravans of Tema looked, the companies of Sheba counted on them:</verse>
  <verse number="20">They are ashamed at their hope; they come thither, and are confounded.</verse>
  <verse number="21">So now ye are nothing; ye see a terrible object and are afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Did I say, Bring unto me, and make me a present from your substance?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Or, rescue me from the hand of the oppressor, and redeem me from the hand of the violent?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Teach me, and I will hold my tongue; and cause me to understand wherein I have erred.</verse>
  <verse number="25">How forcible are right words! but what doth your upbraiding reprove?</verse>
  <verse number="26">Do ye imagine to reprove words? The speeches of one that is desperate are indeed for the wind.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Yea, ye overwhelm the fatherless, and dig [a pit] for your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Now therefore if ye will, look upon me; and it shall be to your face if I lie.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Return, I pray you, let there be no wrong; yea, return again, my righteousness shall be in it.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Is there wrong in my tongue? cannot my taste discern mischievous things?</verse>
</chapter>