<chapter book="Exodus" number="21" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these the judgments which thou shalt set before them.</verse>
  <verse number="2">If thou shalt buy a Hebrew servant, six years shall he serve: and in the seventh he shall go forth free gratuitously.</verse>
  <verse number="3">If he shall come in by himself, he shall go out by himself: if he possessed a wife, and his wife shall go forth with him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If his lord shall give to hint a wife, and she brought to him sons or daughters, the wife and her children shall be to her lord, and he shall go forth by himself.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And if saying, the servant shall say, I loved my lord, my wife and my sons; I will not go forth free:</verse>
  <verse number="6">And his lord brought him near to God, and he brought him near to the door, or to the door-post, and his lord pierced his ear with an awl; and he served him forever.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And if a man shall sell his daughter for a maid, she shall not go forth as the servants went forth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">If evil in the eyes of her lord, he did not betroth her and he ransomed her: to a strange people he shall not have power to sell her, in his acting deceitfully by her.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And if to a son he shall betroth her, according to the judgment of daughters he shall do to her.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If he shall take to him another, her food and her covering and her cohabitation he shall not take away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And if he shall not do these three to her, she shall go forth gratuitously without silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He striking a man and he died, dying, he shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And when he hunted not after, and God let fall into his hand, and I set to thee a place where he shall flee there.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And if a man shall act proudly against his friend to kill him with craftiness, from mine altar shalt thou take him to die.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he striking his father and his mother, dying be shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he stealing a man, and selling him, and being found in his hand, dying, he shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he making light of his father and his mother, dying, he shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And if men shall contend, and a man struck his friend with a stone or with the fist, and he shall not die, and he fell upon the bed:</verse>
  <verse number="19">If he shall rise and go forth without upon his support, and he smiting being innocent, only he shall give his resting, and healing, he shall be healed.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And if a man shall strike his servant or his maid with a rod, and he died under his hand, avenging, he shall be avenged.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But if a day or two days he shall stand, he shall not be avenged, for he is his silver.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And if men shall quarrel and strike a woman pregnant, and her child shall go forth, and there shall not be harm, punishing, he shall be punished, as the husband of the woman shall put upon him; and he giving in justice.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And if there shall be harm, and he gave soul for soul,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Eye for eye, tooth for tooth, hand for hand, foot for foot,</verse>
  <verse number="25">Burning for burning, wound for wound, stripe for stripe.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And if a man strike the eye of his servant or the eye of his maid, and he destroyed it; he shall send him forth free for the sake of his eye.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And if the tooth of his servant or the tooth of his maid he shall cast out, he shall send him forth free for his tooth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And if an ox shall push (with the horns) a man or a woman, and he died; stoning, the ox shall be stoned, and he shall not eat his flesh; and the lord of the ox being innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And if this ox pushed (with the horns) from yesterday the third day, and being testified to its lord, and he will not watch him and he killed the man or the woman; the ox shall be stoned, and also his lord shall be put to death.</verse>
  <verse number="30">If an expiation shall be put upon him, the price of redemption of his soul according to all which shall be put upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If he shall push (with his horns) a son, or shall push a daughter, according to this judgment it shall be done to him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">If the ox shall push a servant, or a maid, he shall give thirty shekels of silver to his lord, and the ox shall be stoned.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And if a man shall open a pit, or if a man shall dig a pit, and shall not cover it, and an ox fall there, or an ass:</verse>
  <verse number="34">The lord of the pit shall recompense; he shall turn back silver to his lord and the dead shall be to him.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And if a man’s ox shall strike the ox of his friend and he died, and they shall sell the living ox and divide the silver, and also the dead ox they shall divide.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Or if this ox was known to push from yesterday, the third day, and his lord guarded him not; recompensing, he shall recompense, ox for ox, and the dead shall be to him.</verse>
</chapter>