<chapter book="Exodus" number="23" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Thou shalt not take up a false report: thou shalt not put thy hand with the unjust one to be a witness of wrong.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thou shalt not be after multitudes for evil; thou shalt not answer for the multitude to stretch out after multitudes to pervert justice.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the poor one thou shalt not make proud in his cause.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If thou shalt meet thine enemy’s ox or his ass wandering, turning back, thou shalt turn him back to him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">If thou shalt see the ass of him hating thee, lying down under his load, and thou didst desist from cutting loose for him, releasing, thou shall release with him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thou shalt not pervert the judgment of thy needy in his cause.</verse>
  <verse number="7">From the word of falsehood thou shalt go far away; and the innocent and the just one thou shalt not kill: for I will not justify the unjust one.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And thou shalt not take a gift; for the gift will blind the seeing, and will pervert just words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou shalt not press the stranger: and ye knew the soul of the stranger, for ye were strangers in the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Six years shalt thou sow thy land, and gather its produce:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the seventh thou shalt remit, and let it be; and the poor of thy people shall eat; and the remains, the beast of the field shall eat. So shalt thou do to thy vineyard and to thy olive tree.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Six days thou shalt do thy works, and in the seventh day thou shalt rest: that thine ox shall rest, and thine ass, and the son of thy maid shall be refreshed, and the stranger.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And in all which I said to you ye shall watch; and ye shall not call to mind the name of other gods; it shall not be heard above thy mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Three times thou shalt keep a festival to me in the year.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Thou shalt watch the festival of unleavened: seven days shalt thou eat unleavened as I commanded thee according to the appointment of the month Abib; for in it thou camest forth out of Egypt: and they shall not be seen before me empty.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the festival of the harvest, the first fruits of thy works, which thou shalt sow in the field: and the festival of gathering in the going out of the year, in thy gathering thy works out of the field.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Three times in the year every male of thine shall be seen to the face of the Lord Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Thou shalt not sacrifice upon leaven: the blood of my sacrifice, and the fat of my festival shall not remain over till morning.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The sacrifice of the first fruits of thy land thou shalt bring to the house of Jehovah thy God. Thou shalt not boil a kid in his mother’s milk.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Behold, I send a messenger before thee to guard thee in the way, and to bring thee to the place which I prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Watch from his face, and hear to his voice; thou shalt not rebel against him: he will not lift up your transgression; for my name is in the midst of him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For if hearing thou shalt hear to his voice, and to all that I shall speak; and I was an enemy to thine enemies, and I was hostile to thine adversaries.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For my messenger shall go before thee, and bring thee to the Amorites, and the Hittites and the Perizzites, and the Canaanites, the Hivites and the Jebusites; and I destroyed them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Thou shalt not worship to their gods, and thou shalt not serve them, and thou shalt not do according to their works: for destroying, thou shalt destroy them, and breaking, thou shalt break in pieces their pillars.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And serve ye Jehovah your God, and he blessed thy bread, and thy waters; and I turned away disease from the midst of thee.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And there shall not be bereaving of children or barren upon thy land: the number of thy days I will fill up.</verse>
  <verse number="27">I will send my terror before thee and I killed all the people which thou shalt come to them; and I gave all thine enemies the back to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And I sent hornets before thee and to drive out the Hivite, the Canaanite, and the Hittite from before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I will not drive them out from thy face in one year, lest the land shall be desolate, and the beast of the field multiply upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="30">By little and little I will drive them out from thy face, till when thou shalt be fruitful and thou didst inherit the land.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And I put thy bounds from the sea of sedge, and even to the sea of the Philistines, and from the desert even to the river: for I will give into your hand those inhabiting the land, and thou drove them out from before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Thou shalt not make a covenant with them and to their gods.</verse>
  <verse number="33">They shall not dwell in thy land, lest they shall cause thee to sin against me: if thou shalt serve their gods, surely shall it be to thee for a snare.</verse>
</chapter>