<chapter book="Exodus" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And he said to Moses, Come up to Jehovah, thou, and Aaron, Nadab, and Abihu, and seventy from the old men of Israel; and worship from far off.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Moses alone drawing near to Jehovah: and they shall not draw near; and the people shall not go up with him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Moses will come and recount to the people all the words of Jehovah, and all the judgments: and all the people will answer with one voice, and will say, All the words which Jehovah spake, we will do.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Moses will write all the words of Jehovah, and he will rise early in the morning, and will build an altar under the mountain, and twelve pillars for the twelve tribes of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And he will send forth young men sons of Israel, and they will bring up burnt-offerings, and they will sacrifice sacrifices of peace to Jehovah of bullocks.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Moses will take half of the blood, and put in basins; and half the blood he sprinkled upon the altar.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And he will take the book of the covenant and read in the ears of the people: and they will say, All which Jehovah spake we will do, and we will heed.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Moses will take the blood, and sprinkle upon the people, and will say, Behold the blood of the covenant, which Jehovah made with you concerning all these words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Moses will go up, and Aaron, Nadab, and Abihu, and seventy from the old men of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they will see the God of Israel: and under his feet as the work of the whiteness of sapphire, and as the body of the heavens for cleanness.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And to the sides of the sons of Israel he stretched not forth his hand: and they will see God, and eat and drink.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Come up to me to the mountain, and be there: and I will give to thee tablets of stone, and the law and the commands which I wrote, to teach them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Moses will rise up, and Joshua, his minister; and Moses will go up to the mountain of God.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he said to the old men, Abide for us here, till when we shall turn back to you: and behold, Aaron and Hur with you; whoever having words shall draw near to them.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Moses will go up to the mountain and the cloud will cover the mount.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the glory of Jehovah will settle down upon mount Sinai, and the cloud will cover it six days: and he will call to Moses in the seventh day from the midst of the cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the appearance of the glory of Jehovah as consuming fire upon the head of the, mountain in the eyes of the sons of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Moses will come into the midst of the cloud, and will go up to the mountain: and Moses will be in the mountain forty days and forty nights.</verse>
</chapter>