<chapter book="Exodus" number="33" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, Go, come up from here, thou, and the people which thou didst bring up out of the land of Egypt to the land which I sware to Abraham, to Isaak, and to Jacob, saying, to thy seed will I give it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I sent a messenger before thee, and I drove out the Canaanite, the Amorite, and the Hittite, and the Perizzite, the Hivite, and the Jebusite:</verse>
  <verse number="3">To a land flowing with milk and honey: for I will not go up in the midst of thee; for thou art a people of a hard neck; lest I shall consume thee in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the people will hear this evil word, and they will mourn: and they put not each his ornaments upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Say to the sons of Israel, Ye are a people of a hard neck: one moment I will come up in the midst of thee, and finish thee: and now bring down thy ornaments from thee, and I shall know what I shall do to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the sons of Israel will take away their ornaments from mount Horeb.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Moses will take the tent and stretched it from without the camp afar off from the camp, and he called it the tent of appointment And it was every one seeking Jehovah went forth to the tent of appointment, which is from without the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And it was when Moses went forth to the tent, all the people will rise up, and they stood each at the door of his tent, and they looked after Moses till his going into the tent.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And it was as Moses went to the tent, the pillar of the cloud came down and stood at the door of the tent, and spake with Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And all the people saw the pillar of the cloud standing at the door of the tent: and all the people rose up and worshipped it, each at the door of his tent.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Jehovah spake to Moses face to face, as a man will speak to his friend. And he turned back to the camp; and his minister Joshua, the son of Nun, a young man, departed not from the midst of the tent.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Moses will say to Jehovah, See, thou sayest to me, Bring up this people: and thou madest not known to me whom thou wilt send with me. And thou saidst, I knew thee by name, and also thou didst find favor in mine eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And now, if now I found grace in thine eyes, make known to me now thy way, and I shall know thee, so that I shall find grace in thine eyes: and see that thy people is this nation.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he will say, My face and my rest shall go to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he will say to him, If thy face led them not, thou wilt not bring us up from here.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And in what shall it be known here that I found favor in thine eyes, I and thy people? Is it not in thy going with us? and we shall be distinguished, I and thy people, above all the people which are upon the face of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Also this word which thou spakest, I will do: for thou didst find grace in mine eyes and I shall know thee by name.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he will say, Cause me now to see thy glory.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he will say, I will cause all my good to pass by before thee, and I called upon the name of Jehovah before thee; and I compassionated whom I will compassionate, and I pitied whom I will pity.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he will say, Thou shalt not be able to see my face: for none shall see my face, and live.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Jehovah will say, Behold, a place with me, and stand thou upon the rock.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And it was in the passing by of my glory, and I put thee in a cavern of the rock; and I hedged in with my hand upon thee till I passed by.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And I turned aside my hand, and thou sawest behind me: and they shall not see my face.</verse>
</chapter>