<chapter book="Exodus" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Go to Pharaoh and say to him, So said Jehovah, Send forth my people, and they shall serve me.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And if thou refusest to send forth, behold, I smite all thy bounds with.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the river abounded with frogs, and they went up and came into thy house, and into the chamber of thy bed, and upon thy bed, and into the house of thy servants, and upon thy people, and into thine ovens, and into thy kneading troughs:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And upon thee, and upon thy people, and upon all thy servants shall the frogs go up.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Say to Aaron, Stretch forth thy hand with thy rod upon the rivers, and upon the canal; and upon the pools, and bring up frogs upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Aaron will stretch forth his hand upon the waters of Egypt; and the frog will come up and will cover the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sacred scribes will do so with their charms; and they will bring up frogs upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Pharaoh will call to Moses and to Aaron, and will say, Pray to Jehovah, and he will remove the frogs from me and from my people: and I will send forth the people and they shall sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Moses will say to Pharaoh, Be honored over me: at what time shall I pray for thee and for thy servants and for thy people, to cut off the frogs from thee and from thy houses, only in the river shall they remain?</verse>
  <verse number="10">And he will say, To-morrow. And he will say, According to thy word: for thou shalt know, that there is not as Jehovah our God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the frogs shall turn away from thee and from thy houses and from thy servants and from thy people; only in the river shall they remain.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Moses will go forth and Aaron from Pharaoh; and Moses will cry to Jehovah, for the word of the frogs which he set against Pharaoh.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Jehovah will do according to the word of Moses, and the frogs will die out of the houses, out of the villages and out of the fields.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they will gather them together, heaps, heaps: and the land will be loathsome.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Pharaoh will see that there was enlargement, and he made his heart heavy, and he heard not to them; as Jehovah spake.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the sacred scribes will do so with their enchantments to bring forth gnats, and they will not be able: and there will be gnats upon man and upon quadrupeds.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Say to Aaron, Stretch forth thy rod and smite the dust of the earth, and it shall be for gnats upon all the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they will do so; and Aaron will stretch forth his hand with his rod, and will smite the dust of the earth, and it will be gnats upon man and in quadrupeds: all the dust of the earth was gnats upon all the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the sacred scribes will say to Pharaoh, This the finger of God: and Pharaoh’s heart will be strengthened, and he heard not to them: as Jehovah said.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Jehovah will say to Moses, Rise early in the morning, and thou shalt stand before Pharaoh (behold he will go forth to the water); and say to him, Thus said Jehovah, Send forth my people, and they shall serve me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And I separated in that day the land of Goshen, which my people stood upon it, for no gad-fly to be there; that thou shalt know that I am Jehovah in the midst of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For if thou sendest not my people forth, behold me sending upon thee and upon thy servants, and upon thy people and upon thy houses, the gad-fly: and the houses of the Egyptians shall be filled with the gad-fly, and also the land which they are upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And I put a redemption between my people and between thy people; and in the morrow shall be this sign.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Jehovah will do so; and the gad-fly will come forth a multitude into the house of Pharaoh and the house of his servants, and into all the land of Egypt: and the land will be destroyed from before the gad-fly.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Pharaoh will call to Moses, and to Aaron, and will say, Go, sacrifice to your God in the land.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Moses will say, It not being right to do so; for we shall sacrifice the abomination of the Egyptians to Jehovah our God: Behold, shall we sacrifice the abomination of the Egyptians in their eyes, and will they not stone us?</verse>
  <verse number="27">A way of three days will we go into the desert and sacrifice to Jehovah our God as he shall say to us.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Pharaoh will say, I will send you forth and sacrifice ye to Jehovah your God in the desert; only departing, ye shall not go far away: pray for me.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Moses will say, Behold, I will go forth from thee, and pray for thee to Jehovah; and the gad-fly shall depart from Pharaoh, from his servants and from his people, to-morrow: only Pharaoh shall not add to deceive, not to send away the people to sacrifice to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Moses will go forth from Pharaoh, and will pray to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Jehovah will do according to the word of Moses; and he will remove the gad-fly from Pharaoh, and from his servants, and from his people; not one was left over.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Pharaoh will make his heart heavy also in this time; he sent not forth the people.</verse>
</chapter>