<chapter book="Genesis" number="16" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now Abram’s wife Sarai had borne him no children, but she had an Egyptian maidservant named Hagar.</verse>
  <verse number="2">So Sarai said to Abram, “Look now, the LORD has prevented me from bearing children. Please go to my maidservant; perhaps I can build a family by her.” And Abram listened to the voice of Sarai.</verse>
  <verse number="3">So after he had lived in Canaan for ten years, his wife Sarai took her Egyptian maidservant Hagar and gave her to Abram to be his wife.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he slept with Hagar, and she conceived. But when Hagar realized that she was pregnant, she began to despise her mistress.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then Sarai said to Abram, “May the wrong done to me be upon you! I delivered my servant into your arms, and ever since she saw that she was pregnant, she has treated me with contempt. May the LORD judge between you and me.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">“Here,” said Abram, “your servant is in your hands. Do whatever you want with her.” Then Sarai treated Hagar so harshly that she fled from her.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Now the angel of the LORD found Hagar by a spring of water in the desert—the spring along the road to Shur.</verse>
  <verse number="8">“Hagar, servant of Sarai,” he said, “where have you come from, and where are you going?” “I am running away from my mistress Sarai,” she replied.</verse>
  <verse number="9">So the angel of the LORD told her, “Return to your mistress and submit to her authority.”</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then the angel added, “I will greatly multiply your offspring so that they will be too numerous to count.”</verse>
  <verse number="11">The angel of the LORD proceeded: “Behold, you have conceived and will bear a son. And you shall name him Ishmael, for the LORD has heard your cry of affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He will be a wild donkey of a man, and his hand will be against everyone, and everyone’s hand against him; he will live in hostility toward all his brothers.”</verse>
  <verse number="13">So Hagar gave this name to the LORD who had spoken to her: “You are the God who sees me,” for she said, “Here I have seen the One who sees me!”</verse>
  <verse number="14">Therefore the well was called Beer-lahai-roi. It is located between Kadesh and Bered.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Hagar bore Abram a son, and Abram gave the name Ishmael to the son she had borne.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Abram was eighty-six years old when Hagar bore Ishmael to him.</verse>
</chapter>