<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="2" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But I determined this within myself, not to return again to you in sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For if I make you sorrowful, then who is it that can make me glad, except the one who is made sorrowful by me?</verse>
  <verse number="3">And so, I wrote this same thing to you, so that I might not, when I arrive, add sorrow to sorrow for those with whom I ought to rejoice, having confidence in you in all things, so that my joy may be entirely yours.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For with much tribulation and anguish of heart, I wrote to you with many tears: not so that you would be sorrowful, but so that you might know the charity that I have more abundantly toward you.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But if anyone has brought sorrow, he has not sorrowed me. Yet, for my part, this is so that I might not burden all of you.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let this rebuke be sufficient for someone like this, for it has been brought by many.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So then, to the contrary, you should be more forgiving and consoling, lest perhaps someone like this may be overwhelmed with excessive sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Because of this, I beg you to confirm your charity toward him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">It was for this reason, also, that I wrote, so that I might know, by testing you, whether you would be obedient in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="10">But anyone whom you have forgiven of anything, I also forgive. And then, too, anyone I have forgiven, if I have forgiven anything, it was done in the person of Christ for your sakes,</verse>
  <verse number="11">so that we would not be circumvented by Satan. For we are not ignorant of his intentions.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And when I had arrived at Troas, because of the Gospel of Christ, and a door had opened to me in the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="13">I had no rest within my spirit, because I was not able to find Titus, my brother. So, saying goodbye to them, I set out for Macedonia.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But thanks be to God, who always brings triumph to us in Christ Jesus, and who manifests the fragrance of his knowledge through us in every place.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For we are the sweet fragrance of Christ for God, both with those who are being saved and with those who are perishing.</verse>
  <verse number="16">To the one, certainly, the fragrance is of death unto death. But to the other, the fragrance is of life unto life. And concerning these things, who is so suitable?</verse>
  <verse number="17">For we are not like many others, adulterating the Word of God. But instead, we speak with sincerity: from God, before God, and in Christ.</verse>
</chapter>