<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="6" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But, as a help to you, we exhort you not to receive the grace of God in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For he says: “In a favorable time, I heeded you; and on the day of salvation, I helped you.” Behold, now is the favorable time; behold, now is the day of salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="3">May we never give offense to anyone, so that our ministry may not be disparaged.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But in all things, let us exhibit ourselves as ministers of God with great patience: through tribulation, difficulties, and distress;</verse>
  <verse number="5">despite wounds, imprisonment, and rebellion; with hard work, vigilance, and fasting;</verse>
  <verse number="6">by chastity, knowledge, and longsuffering; in pleasantness, in the Holy Spirit, and in unfeigned charity;</verse>
  <verse number="7">with the Word of truth, with the power of God, and with the armor of justice to the right and to the left;</verse>
  <verse number="8">through honor and dishonor, despite good reports and bad, whether seen as deceivers or truth-tellers, whether ignored or acknowledged;</verse>
  <verse number="9">as if dying and yet truly alive; as if chastised and yet not subdued;</verse>
  <verse number="10">as if sorrowful and yet always rejoicing; as if needy and yet enriching many; as if having nothing and possessing everything.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Our mouth is open to you, O Corinthians; our heart is enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="12">You are not narrowed by us, but it is by your own inner selves that you are narrowed.</verse>
  <verse number="13">But since we have the same recompense, (I am speaking as if to my own sons), you, too, should be enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Do not choose to bear the yoke with unbelievers. For how can justice be a participant with iniquity? Or how can the fellowship of light be a participant with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And how can Christ join together with Belial? Or what part do the faithful have with the unfaithful?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And what consensus does the temple of God have with idols? For you are the temple of the living God, just as God says: “I will dwell with them, and I will walk among them. And I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Because of this, you must depart from their midst and be separate, says the Lord. And do not touch what is unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then I will accept you. And I will be a Father to you, and you shall be sons and daughters to me, says the Lord Almighty.”</verse>
</chapter>