<chapter book="Acts" number="18" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After this, Paul left Athens and went to Corinth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">There he found a Jew named Aquila, a native of Pontus, who had recently come from Italy with his wife Priscilla because Claudius had ordered all the Jews to leave Rome. Paul went to visit them,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and he stayed and worked with them because they were tentmakers by trade, just as he was.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Every Sabbath he reasoned in the synagogue, trying to persuade Jews and Greeks alike.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And when Silas and Timothy came down from Macedonia, Paul devoted himself fully to the word, testifying to the Jews that Jesus is the Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But when they opposed and insulted him, he shook out his garments and told them, “Your blood be on your own heads! I am innocent of it. From now on I will go to the Gentiles.”</verse>
  <verse number="7">So Paul left the synagogue and went next door to the house of Titus Justus, a worshiper of God.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Crispus, the synagogue leader, and his whole household believed in the Lord. And many of the Corinthians who heard the message believed and were baptized.</verse>
  <verse number="9">One night the Lord spoke to Paul in a vision: “Do not be afraid; keep on speaking; do not be silent.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For I am with you and no one will lay a hand on you, because I have many people in this city.”</verse>
  <verse number="11">So Paul stayed for a year and a half, teaching the word of God among the Corinthians.</verse>
  <verse number="12">While Gallio was proconsul of Achaia, the Jews coordinated an attack on Paul and brought him before the judgment seat.</verse>
  <verse number="13">“This man is persuading the people to worship God in ways contrary to the law,” they said.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But just as Paul was about to speak, Gallio told the Jews, “If this matter involved a wrongdoing or vicious crime, O Jews, it would be reasonable for me to hear your complaint.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But since it is a dispute about words and names and your own law, settle it yourselves. I refuse to be a judge of such things.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he drove them away from the judgment seat.</verse>
  <verse number="17">At this, the crowd seized Sosthenes the synagogue leader and beat him in front of the judgment seat. But none of this was of concern to Gallio.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Paul remained in Corinth for quite some time before saying goodbye to the brothers. He had his head shaved in Cenchrea to keep a vow he had made, and then he sailed for Syria, accompanied by Priscilla and Aquila.</verse>
  <verse number="19">When they reached Ephesus, Paul left Priscilla and Aquila. He himself went into the synagogue there and reasoned with the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="20">When they asked him to stay for a while longer, he declined.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But as he left, he said, “I will come back to you if God is willing.” And he set sail from Ephesus.</verse>
  <verse number="22">When Paul had landed at Caesarea, he went up and greeted the church at Jerusalem. Then he went down to Antioch.</verse>
  <verse number="23">After Paul had spent some time in Antioch, he traveled from place to place throughout the region of Galatia and Phrygia, strengthening all the disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Meanwhile a Jew named Apollos, a native of Alexandria, came to Ephesus. He was an eloquent man, well versed in the Scriptures.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He had been instructed in the way of the Lord and was fervent in spirit. He spoke and taught accurately about Jesus, though he knew only the baptism of John.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And he began to speak boldly in the synagogue. When Priscilla and Aquila heard him, they took him aside and explained to him the way of God more accurately.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When Apollos resolved to cross over to Achaia, the brothers encouraged him and wrote to the disciples there to welcome him. On his arrival, he was a great help to those who by grace had believed.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For he powerfully refuted the Jews in public debate, proving from the Scriptures that Jesus is the Christ.</verse>
</chapter>