<chapter book="Mark" number="16" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">AND when the sabbath was past, Mary Magdalen, and Mary the mother of James, and Salome, bought sweet spices, that coming, they might anoint Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And very early in the morning, the first day of the week, they come to the sepulchre, the sun being now risen.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And they said one to another: Who shall roll us back the stone from the door of the sepulchre?</verse>
  <verse number="4">And looking, they saw the stone rolled back. For it was very great.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And entering into the sepulchre, they saw a young man sitting on the right side, clothed with a white robe: and they were astonished.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Who saith to them: Be not affrighted; you seek Jesus of Nazareth, who was crucified: he is risen, he is not here, behold the place where they laid him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But go, tell his disciples and Peter that he goeth before you into Galilee; there you shall see him, as he told you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But they going out, fled from the sepulchre. For a trembling and fear had seized them: and they said nothing to any man; for they were afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But he rising early the first day of the week, appeared first to Mary Magdalen, out of whom he had cast seven devils.</verse>
  <verse number="10">She went and told them that had been with him, who were mourning and weeping.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And they hearing that he was alive, and had been seen by her, did not believe.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And after that he appeared in another shape to two of them walking, as they were going into the country.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they going told it to the rest: neither did they believe them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">At length he appeared to the eleven as they were at table: and he upbraided them with their incredulity and hardness of heart, because they did not believe them who had seen him after he was risen again.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he said to them: Go ye into the whole world, and preach the gospel to every creature.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He that believeth and is baptized, shall be saved: but he that believeth not shall be condemned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And these signs shall follow them that believe: In my name they shall cast out devils: they shall speak with new tongues.</verse>
  <verse number="18">They shall take up serpents; and if they shall drink any deadly thing, it shall not hurt them: they shall lay their hands upon the sick, and they shall recover.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the Lord Jesus, after he had spoken to them, was taken up into heaven, and sitteth on the right hand of God.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But they going forth preached every where: the Lord working withal, and confirming the word with signs that followed.</verse>
</chapter>