<chapter book="Mark" number="3" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">AND he entered again into the synagogue, and there was a man there who had a withered hand.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And they watched him whether he would heal on the sabbath days; that they might accuse him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he said to the man who had the withered hand: Stand up in the midst.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he saith to them: Is it lawful to do good on the sabbath days, or to do evil? to save life, or to destroy? But they held their peace.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And looking round about on them with anger, being grieved for the blindness of their hearts, he saith to the man: Stretch forth thy hand. And he stretched it forth: and his hand was restored unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the Pharisees going out, immediately made a consultation with the Herodians against him, how they might destroy him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But Jesus retired with his disciples to the sea; and a great multitude followed him from Galilee and Judea,</verse>
  <verse number="8">And from Jerusalem, and from Idumea, and from beyond the Jordan. And they about Tyre and Sidon, a great multitude, hearing the things which he did, came to him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he spoke to his disciples that a small ship should wait on him because of the multitude, lest they should throng him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For he healed many, so that they pressed upon him for to touch him, as many as had evils.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the unclean spirits, when they saw him, fell down before him: and they cried, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Thou art the Son of God. And he strictly charged them that they should not make him known.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And going up into a mountain, he called unto him whom he would himself: and they came to him.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he made that twelve should be with him, and that he might send them to preach.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he gave them power to heal sicknesses, and to cast out devils.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And to Simon he gave the name Peter:</verse>
  <verse number="17">And James the son of Zebedee, and John the brother of James; and he named them Boanerges, which is, The sons of thunder:</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Andrew and Philip, and Bartholomew and Matthew, and Thomas and James of Alpheus, and Thaddeus, and Simon the Cananean:</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Judas Iscariot, who also betrayed him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And they come to a house, and the multitude cometh together again, so that they could not so much as eat bread.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And when his friends had heard of it, they went out to lay hold on him. For they said: He is become mad.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the scribes who were come down from Jerusalem, said: He hath Beelzebub, and by the prince of devils he casteth out devils.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And after he had called them together, he said to them in parables: How can Satan cast out Satan?</verse>
  <verse number="24">And if a kingdom be divided against itself, that kingdom cannot stand.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And if a house be divided against itself, that house cannot stand.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And if Satan be risen up against himself, he is divided, and cannot stand, but hath an end.</verse>
  <verse number="27">No man can enter into the house of a strong man and rob him of his goods, unless he first bind the strong man, and then shall he plunder his house.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Amen I say to you, that all sins shall be forgiven unto the sons of men, and the blasphemies wherewith they shall blaspheme:</verse>
  <verse number="29">But he that shall blaspheme against the Holy Ghost, shall never have forgiveness, but shall be guilty of an everlasting sin.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Because they said: He hath an unclean spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And his mother and his bretheren came; and standing without, sent unto him, calling him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the multitude sat about him; and they say to him: Behold thy mother and thy brethren without seek for thee.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And answering them, he said: Who is my mother and my brethren?</verse>
  <verse number="34">And looking round about on them who sat about him, he saith: Behold my mother and my brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For whosoever shall do the will of God, he is my brother, and my sister, and mother.</verse>
</chapter>