<chapter book="Galatians" number="4" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now I say, That the heir, as long as he is a child, differs nothing from a servant, though he be lord of all;</verse>
  <verse number="2">But is under tutors and governors until the time appointed of the father.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Even so we, when we were children, were in bondage under the elements of the world:</verse>
  <verse number="4">But when the fullness of the time was come, God sent forth his Son, made of a woman, made under the law,</verse>
  <verse number="5">To redeem them that were under the law, that we might receive the adoption of sons.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And because you are sons, God has sent forth the Spirit of his Son into your hearts, crying, Abba, Father.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Why you are no more a servant, but a son; and if a son, then an heir of God through Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="8">However, then, when you knew not God, you did service to them which by nature are no gods.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But now, after that you have known God, or rather are known of God, how turn you again to the weak and beggarly elements, whereunto you desire again to be in bondage?</verse>
  <verse number="10">You observe days, and months, and times, and years.</verse>
  <verse number="11">I am afraid of you, lest I have bestowed on you labor in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Brothers, I beseech you, be as I am; for I am as you are: you have not injured me at all.</verse>
  <verse number="13">You know how through infirmity of the flesh I preached the gospel to you at the first.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And my temptation which was in my flesh you despised not, nor rejected; but received me as an angel of God, even as Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Where is then the blessedness you spoke of? for I bear you record, that, if it had been possible, you would have plucked out your own eyes, and have given them to me.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Am I therefore become your enemy, because I tell you the truth?</verse>
  <verse number="17">They zealously affect you, but not well; yes, they would exclude you, that you might affect them.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But it is good to be zealously affected always in a good thing, and not only when I am present with you.</verse>
  <verse number="19">My little children, of whom I travail in birth again until Christ be formed in you,</verse>
  <verse number="20">I desire to be present with you now, and to change my voice; for I stand in doubt of you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Tell me, you that desire to be under the law, do you not hear the law?</verse>
  <verse number="22">For it is written, that Abraham had two sons, the one by a female slave, the other by a free woman.</verse>
  <verse number="23">But he who was of the female slave was born after the flesh; but he of the free woman was by promise.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Which things are an allegory: for these are the two covenants; the one from the mount Sinai, which engenders to bondage, which is Agar.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For this Agar is mount Sinai in Arabia, and answers to Jerusalem which now is, and is in bondage with her children.</verse>
  <verse number="26">But Jerusalem which is above is free, which is the mother of us all.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For it is written, Rejoice, you barren that bore not; break forth and cry, you that travail not: for the desolate has many more children than she which has an husband.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Now we, brothers, as Isaac was, are the children of promise.</verse>
  <verse number="29">But as then he that was born after the flesh persecuted him that was born after the Spirit, even so it is now.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Nevertheless what said the scripture? Cast out the female slave and her son: for the son of the female slave shall not be heir with the son of the free woman.</verse>
  <verse number="31">So then, brothers, we are not children of the female slave, but of the free.</verse>
</chapter>