<chapter book="Ruth" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Boaz went up to the gate and sat there: and behold, the blood relation whom Boaz spake of, passing by; and he will say, Turn aside, sit down here; thou such a one. And he will turn aside, and sit down.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he will take ten men from the old men of the city, and he will say, Sit ye down here. And they will sit down.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he will say to the blood relative, The portion of the field which was to our brother Elimelech, Naomi turning back from the field of Moab, sells:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I said, I will reveal to thine ear, saying, Buy before the inhabitants, and before the old men of my people. If thou wilt redeem, redeem: and if thou wilt not redeem, announce to me, and I shall know: for none besides thee to redeem; and I after thee; and he will say, I will redeem.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Boaz will say, In the day of thy buying the field from the hand of Naomi, and from Ruth the Moabitess, the wife of the dead, thou boughtest it to raise up the name of the dead upon his inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the near relative will say, I shall not be able to redeem for me, lest I shall destroy my inheritance: redeem to thyself; thou the near relative: for I shall not be able to redeem.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And this before in Israel upon redemption and upon exchange, to set up all the word; a man drew off his shoe and gave to his neighbor: and this the precept in Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the blood relative will say to Boaz, Buy for thee. And he will draw off his shoe.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Boaz will say to the old men and all the people, Ye are witnesses this day that I bought all which was to Elimelech, and all which was to Chilion and Mahlon, from the hand of Naomi.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And also Ruth the Moabitess, the wife of Mahlon, I bought to me for a wife, to raise up the name of the dead upon his inheritance; and the name of the dead shall not be cut off from his brethren and from the gate of his place: ye are witnesses this day.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And all the people which are in the gate will say, and the old men, Witnesses. Jehovah will give the woman coming into thy house as Rachel and as Leah, which they two built up the house of Israel: and make thou power in Ephratah, and call a name in the house of bread.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And thy house shall be as the house of Pharez which Tamar bare to Judah, from the seed which Jehovah shall give to thee from this maiden.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Boaz will take Ruth, and she will be to him for a wife: and he will come in to her, and Jehovah will give to her conception, and she will bring forth a son.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the women will say to Naomi, Blessed be Jehovah who caused not to cease to thee a blood relation this day; and his name shall be called in Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And being to thee for the turning back the soul, and to nourish thy gray hairs: for thy daughter-in-law who loved thee brought him forth; for she is good to thee above seven sons.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Naomi will take the child and put him in her bosom, and she will be to him for nurse.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the neighbors will call to him a name, saying, A son was born to Naomi; and they will call his name Obed: he the father of Jesse, the father of David.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And these the generations of Pharez: Pharez begat Hezron,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Hezron begat Ram, and Ram begat Aminadab,</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Aminadab begat Nashon, and Nashon begat Salmon,</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Salmon begat Boaz, and Boaz begat Obed,</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Obed begat Jesse, and Jesse begat David.</verse>
</chapter>