<chapter book="2 Timothy" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, the sent of Jesus Christ by the will of God, according to the promise of life in Christ Jesus,</verse>
  <verse number="2">To Timothy, dearly beloved child: Grace, mercy, peace, from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I have grace to God, whom I serve from the forefathers in pure consciousness, as I have continual remembrance concerning thee in my prayers night and day;</verse>
  <verse number="4">Desiring earnestly to see thee, remembering thy tears, that I may be filled with joy;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Receiving the report of unfeigned faith in thee, which dwelt first in thy grandmother Lois, and thy mother Eunice; and I am persuaded that in thee also.</verse>
  <verse number="6">By which I remind thee of the cause to light up the favor of God, which is in thee by the putting on of my hands.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For God gave not to us the spirit of timidity; but of power, and love, and of soundness of mind.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Therefore shouldest thou not be ashamed of the testimony of our Lord, nor of me his imprisoned: but partake of afflictions with the good news according to the power of God;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who having saved us, and called us with a holy calling, not according to our works, but according to his own purpose and grace, given us in Christ Jesus before eternal times,</verse>
  <verse number="10">And now made manifest by the appearance of our Saviour Jesus Christ, having truly left death unemployed, and having brought life and immortality to light by the good news:</verse>
  <verse number="11">To which I was set a herald, and sent, teacher of the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="12">By which cause I also suffer these things: but I am not ashamed: for I know whom I have believed, and have been persuaded that he is able to watch my deposits to that day.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hold the model of sound words, which thou didst hear of me, in the faith and love which in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Watch the good deposit by the Holy Spirit dwelling in us.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Thou knowest this, that all they dwelling in Asia turned away from me; of whom are Phygellus and Hermogenes.</verse>
  <verse number="16">May the Lord give mercy to the house of Onesiphorus; for many times he refreshed me, and was not ashamed of my perplexity:</verse>
  <verse number="17">But, being in Rome, he sought me very diligently, and found.</verse>
  <verse number="18">(May, the Lord give to him to find mercy of the Lord in that day:) and in how many things he served in Ephesus, thou knowest better.</verse>
</chapter>