<chapter book="2 Timothy" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Thou therefore, my child, be strong in the grace which is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And what thou hast heard from me by many witnesses, these things lay by for faithful men, who will be sufficient to teach others also.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Thou therefore suffer ill treatment, as a good soldier of Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="4">None making war is entangled with the affairs of life: that he may please him having enlisted him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And also if any contend for a prize, he is not crowned, except he contend for a prize lawfully.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The farmer toiling must first participate in the fruits.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Observe what I say; for may the Lord give to thee understanding in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Remember Jesus Christ raised from the dead, of the seed of David, according to my good news:</verse>
  <verse number="9">In which I suffer ill treatment, to bonds, as an evil doer; but the word of God has not been bound.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this I endure all things for the chosen, that they also might attain the salvation which is in Christ Jesus with eternal glory.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Faithful the word: For if we died together, we shall also live together:</verse>
  <verse number="12">If we endure, we shall also reign together: if we deny, he will also deny us:</verse>
  <verse number="13">If we believe not, he remains faithful: he cannot deny himself.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Put these things in mind, calling to witness before the Lord not to wrangle for nothing useful, to the subversion of them hearing.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Be earnest to present thyself acceptable to God, a worker without shame, dividing rightly the word of truth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And avoid profane, empty discourses: for they will proceed to more of profanation.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And this word as a gangrene, will have an eating ulcer: of whom is Hymeneus and Philetus;</verse>
  <verse number="18">Who concerning the truth missed their aim, saying the rising up has already been; and they subvert the faith of some.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Truly the firm foundation of God has stood, having this seal, The Lord knows them being his. And, Let every one naming the name of Christ remove from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And in a great house there is not only gold and silver vessels, but also wood and earthen; and some truly for honour, and some for dishonour.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If therefore any cleanse himself from these, he shall be a vessel for honour, consecrated, and useful for the master, prepared for every good work.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And flee youthful, eager desires: and follow justice, faith, love, peace, with them calling upon the Lord from a pure heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And silly and ignorant questions refuse, knowing that they produce strifes.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the servant of the Lord must not contend; but be gentle to all, giving instruction, enduring evil,</verse>
  <verse number="25">In meekness instructing them being in a contrary state; lest perhaps God may give them repentance to the acknowledgment of the truth;</verse>
  <verse number="26">That they may return to a state of sobriety from the snare of the devil, being taken alive by him at his will.</verse>
</chapter>