<chapter book="2 Timothy" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And this know, that in the last days difficult times shall interpose.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For men shall be self-lovers, lovers of money, boastful, proud, slandering, disobedient to parents, unthankful, wicked,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Devoid of natural affection, not observing treaties, accusers, ungoverned, wild, not loving the good,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Traitors, rash, haughty, devoted to pleasure more than loving God;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Having a form of devotion, and having denied its power: and these renounce.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For of these are they going into houses, and taking captive little women heaped up with sins, led away with various eager desires,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Always learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And as Jannes and Jambres withstood Moses, so also these have withstood the truth: men corrupted in mind, not tried concerning the faith.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But they shall proceed no further: for their folly shall be manifest to all, as theirs also was.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And thou hast closely followed my doctrine, mode of life, purpose, faith, long suffering, love, patience,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Expulsions, sufferings, which were to me in Antioch, in Iconium, in Lystra; what expulsions I endured: and the Lord delivered me from all.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And all wishing to live devotedly in Christ Jesus shall be driven out.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And evil men and impostors shall proceed to worse, deceiving, and being deceived.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And remain thou in what things thou hast learned and hast been convinced of, knowing of whom thou hast learned;</verse>
  <verse number="15">And that from infancy thou hast known the holy letters, able to render thee wise to salvation by faith which in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="16">All writing divinely inspired, and profitable for doctrine, for refutation, for correction, for instruction in justice:</verse>
  <verse number="17">That the man of God might be perfect, finished for every good work.</verse>
</chapter>