<chapter book="2 Timothy" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I call to witness before God there fore, and the Lord Jesus Christ, being about to judge the living and the dead according to his appearance and his kingdom;</verse>
  <verse number="2">Proclaim the word; keep fixed seasonably, and unseasonably; refute, censure, beseech, in all longsuffering and teaching.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the time will be when they will not hear sound doctrine; but according to their own eager desires they will heap up to themselves teachers, feeling itchings for a report;</verse>
  <verse number="4">And truly from the truth will they turn away the hearing, and be turned aside to fictions.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And thou be sober in all things, suffer ill treatment, do the work of the bearer of good news, render thy service perfectly certain.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For I am already poured out, and the time of my deliverance has been fixed.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I have contended earnestly the good contest, I have completed the course, I have kept the faith:</verse>
  <verse number="8">As to the rest, the crown of justice is laid up for me, which the Lord will assign to me in that day, the just judge: and not only to me, but also to all them having loved his appearance.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be earnest to come to me quickly.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For Demas has forsaken me, having loved the time now, and has gone to Thessalonica; Crescens to Galatia, Titus to Dalmatia.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Luke alone is with me. Having taken Mark, bring with thyself: for he is useful for the service.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Tychicus I sent to Ephesus.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The cloak which I left in Troas with Carpus, coming, bring, and the books, chiefly the parchments.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Alexander the coppersmith showed me much evil: (may the Lord give back to him according to his works:)</verse>
  <verse number="15">Whom watch thou also; for he greatly withstood our words.</verse>
  <verse number="16">In my first defence none was present with me, but all forsook me; (may it not be reckoned to them.)</verse>
  <verse number="17">But the Lord stood with me, and strengthened me; that by me the promulgation might be rendered perfectly certain, and all the nations might hear: and I was delivered out of the lion’s mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the Lord will deliver me from every evil work, and save for his heavenly kingdom: to whom the glory for the times of times. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Greet Prisca and Aquila, and the house of Onesiphorus.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Erastus remained in Corinth: and Trophimus I left in Miletum sick.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Be earnest to come before winter Eubulus greets thee, and Pudens, and Linus, and Claudia, and all the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The Lord Jesus Christ with thy Spirit. Grace with you. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>