<chapter book="Numbers" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah spoke to Moses and to Aaron, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">The children of Israel shall encamp every one by his standard, with the ensign of their father’s house; round about the tent of meeting, afar off, opposite to it shall they encamp.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And [for] those encamping eastward toward the sun-rising [there shall be] the standard of the camp of Judah according to their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Judah shall be Nahshon the son of Amminadab;</verse>
  <verse number="4">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, were seventy-four thousand six hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And those that encamp next unto him shall be the tribe of Issachar; and the prince of the sons of Issachar shall be Nethaneel the son of Zuar;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and his host, even those that were numbered thereof, fifty-four thousand four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="7">[With them shall be] the tribe of Zebulun; and the prince of the sons of Zebulun shall be Eliab the son of Helon;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and his host, even those that were numbered thereof, fifty-seven thousand four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="9">All that were numbered of the camp of Judah were a hundred and eighty-six thousand four hundred, according to their hosts. They shall set forth first.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The standard of the camp of Reuben shall be southward according to their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Reuben shall be Elizur the son of Shedeur;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and his host, even those that were numbered thereof, forty-six thousand five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And those that encamp by him shall be the tribe of Simeon; and the prince of the sons of Simeon shall be Shelumiel the son of Zurishaddai;</verse>
  <verse number="13">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, fifty-nine thousand three hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And [with them shall be] the tribe of Gad; and the prince of the sons of Gad shall be Eliasaph the son of Reuel;</verse>
  <verse number="15">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, forty-five thousand six hundred and fifty.</verse>
  <verse number="16">All that were numbered of the camp of Reuben were a hundred and fifty-one thousand four hundred and fifty, according to their hosts. And they shall set forth second.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the tent of meeting shall set forth, the camp of the Levites in the midst of the camps; as they encamp, so shall they set forth, every man in his place, according to their standards.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The standard of the camp of Ephraim according to their hosts shall be westward; and the prince of the sons of Ephraim shall be Elishama the son of Ammihud;</verse>
  <verse number="19">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, forty thousand five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And by him shall be the tribe of Manasseh; and the prince of the sons of Manasseh shall be Gamaliel the son of Pedahzur;</verse>
  <verse number="21">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, thirty-two thousand two hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And [with them shall be] the tribe of Benjamin; and the prince of the sons of Benjamin shall be Abidan the son of Gideoni;</verse>
  <verse number="23">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, thirty-five thousand four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="24">All that were numbered of the camp of Ephraim were a hundred and eight thousand one hundred, according to their hosts. And they shall set forth third.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The standard of the camp of Dan shall be northward according to their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Dan shall be Ahiezer the son of Ammishaddai;</verse>
  <verse number="26">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, sixty-two thousand seven hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And those that encamp by him shall be the tribe of Asher; and the prince of the sons of Asher shall be Pagiel the son of Ocran;</verse>
  <verse number="28">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, forty-one thousand five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And [with them shall be] the tribe of Naphtali; and the prince of the sons of Naphtali shall be Ahira the son of Enan;</verse>
  <verse number="30">and his host, even those that were numbered of them, fifty-three thousand four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="31">All that were numbered of the camp of Dan were a hundred and fifty-seven thousand six hundred. They shall set forth last according to their standards.</verse>
  <verse number="32">These are those that were numbered of the children of Israel, according to their fathers’ houses: all those that were numbered of the camps, according to their hosts, were six hundred and three thousand five hundred and fifty.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But the Levites were not numbered among the children of Israel; as Jehovah had commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the children of Israel did according to all that Jehovah had commanded Moses: so they encamped according to their standards, and so they journeyed, every one according to their families, according to their fathers’ houses.</verse>
</chapter>