<chapter book="Joshua" number="15" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the lot for the tribe of the sons of Judah, for their families, is unto the border of Edom; the wilderness of Zin southward, at the extremity of the south;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and to them the south border is at the extremity of the salt sea, from the bay which is looking southward;</verse>
  <verse number="3">and it hath gone out unto the south to Maaleh-Akrabbim, and passed over to Zin, and gone up on the south to Kadesh-Barnea, and passed over to Hezron, and gone up to Adar, and turned round to Karkaa,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and passed over to Azmon, and gone out at the brook of Egypt, and the outgoings of the border have been at the sea; this is to you the south border.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the east border is the salt sea, unto the extremity of the Jordan, and the border at the north quarter is from the bay of the sea, at the extremity of the Jordan;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and the border hath gone up to Beth-Hoglah, and passed over on the north of Beth-Arabah, and the border hath gone up to the stone of Bohan son of Reuben:</verse>
  <verse number="7">and the border hath gone up towards Debir from the valley of Achor, and northward looking unto Gilgal, which is over-against the ascent of Adummim, which is on the south of the brook, and the border hath passed over unto the waters of En-Shemesh, and its outgoings have been unto En-Rogel;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and the border hath gone up the valley of the son of Hinnom, unto the side of the Jebusite on the south (it is Jerusalem), and the border hath gone up unto the top of the hill-country which is on the front of the valley of Hinnom westward, which is in the extremity of the valley of the Rephaim northward;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and the border hath been marked out, from the top of the hill-country unto the fountain of the waters of Nephtoah, and hath gone out unto the cities of mount Ephron, and the border hath been marked out to Baalah, (it is Kirjath-Jearim);</verse>
  <verse number="10">and the border hath gone round from Baalah westward, unto mount Seir, and passed over unto the side of mount Jearim (it is Chesalon), on the north, and gone down to Beth-Shemesh, and passed over to Timnah;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and the border hath gone out unto the side of Ekron northward, and the border hath been marked out to Shicron, and hath passed over to mount Baalah, and gone out to Jabneel; and the outgoings of the border have been at the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the west border is to the great sea, and its border; this is the border of the sons of Judah round about for their families.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And to Caleb son of Jephunneh hath he given a portion in the midst of the sons of Judah, according to the command of Jehovah to Joshua, even the city of Arba, father of Anak—it is Hebron.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Caleb is dispossessing thence the three sons of Anak, Sheshai, and Ahiman, and Talmai, children of Anak,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and he goeth up thence unto the inhabitants of Debir; and the name of Debir formerly is Kirjath-Sepher.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Caleb saith, ‘He who smiteth Kirjath-Sephar, and hath captured it—I have given to him Achsah my daughter for a wife.’</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Othniel son of Kenaz, brother of Caleb, doth capture it, and he giveth to him Achsah his daughter for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And it cometh to pass, in her coming in, that she persuadeth him to ask from her father a field, and she lighteth from off the ass, and Caleb saith to her, ‘What—to thee?’</verse>
  <verse number="19">And she saith, ‘Give to me a blessing; when the land of the south thou hast given me, then thou hast given to me springs of waters;’ and he giveth to her the upper springs and the lower springs.</verse>
  <verse number="20">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Judah, for their families.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the cities at the extremity of the tribe of the sons of Judah are unto the border of Edom in the south, Kabzeel, and Eder, and Jagur,</verse>
  <verse number="22">and Kinah, and Dimonah, and Adadah,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and Kedesh, and Hazor, and Ithnan,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Ziph, and Telem, and Bealoth,</verse>
  <verse number="25">and Hazor, Hadattah, and Kerioth, Hezron, (it is Hazor,)</verse>
  <verse number="26">Amam, and Shema, and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and Hazar-Gaddah, and Heshmon, and Beth-Palet,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and Hazar-Shual, and Beer-Sheba, and Bizjothjah,</verse>
  <verse number="29">Baalah, and Iim, and Azem,</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Eltolad, and Chesil, and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="31">and Ziklag, and Madmannah, and Sansannah,</verse>
  <verse number="32">and Lebaoth, and Shilhim, and Ain, and Rimmon; all the cities are twenty and nine, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="33">In the low country: Eshtaol, and Zoreah, and Ashnah,</verse>
  <verse number="34">and Zanoah, and En-Gannim, Tappuah, and Enam,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Jarmuth, and Adullam, Socoh, and Azekah,</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Sharaim, and Adithaim, and Gederah, and Gederothaim; fourteen cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Zenan, and Hadashah, and Migdal-Gad,</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Dilean, and Mizpeh, and Joktheel,</verse>
  <verse number="39">Lachish, and Bozkath, and Eglon,</verse>
  <verse number="40">and Cabbon, and Lahmam, and Kithlish,</verse>
  <verse number="41">and Gederoth, Beth-Dagon, and Naamah, and Makkedah; sixteen cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Libnah, and Ether, and Ashan,</verse>
  <verse number="43">and Jiphtah, and Ashnah, and Nezib,</verse>
  <verse number="44">and Keilah, and Achzib, and Mareshah; nine cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Ekron and its towns and its villages,</verse>
  <verse number="46">from Ekron and westward, all that are by the side of Ashdod, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Ashdod, its towns and its villages, Gaza, its towns and its villages, unto the brook of Egypt, and the great sea, and its border.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And in the hill-country: Shamir, and Jattir, and Socoh,</verse>
  <verse number="49">and Dannah, and Kirjath-Sannah (it is Debir)</verse>
  <verse number="50">and Anab, and Eshtemoh, and Anim,</verse>
  <verse number="51">and Goshen, and Holon, and Giloh; eleven cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Arab, and Dumah, and Eshean,</verse>
  <verse number="53">and Janum, and Beth-Tappuah, and Aphekah,</verse>
  <verse number="54">and Humtah, and Kirjath-Arba (it is Hebron), and Zior; nine cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="55">Maon, Carmel, and Ziph, and Juttah,</verse>
  <verse number="56">and Jezreel, and Jokdeam, and Zanoah,</verse>
  <verse number="57">Cain, Gibeah, and Timnah; ten cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="58">Halhul, Beth-Zur, and Gedor,</verse>
  <verse number="59">and Maarath, and Beth-Anoth, and Eltekon; six cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="60">Kirjath-Baal (it is Kirjath-Jearim), and Rabbah; two cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="61">In the wilderness: Beth-Arabah, Middin, and Secacah,</verse>
  <verse number="62">and Nibshan, and the city of Salt, and En-Gedi; six cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="63">As to the Jebusites, inhabitants of Jerusalem, the sons of Judah have not been able to dispossess them, and the Jebusite dwelleth with the sons of Judah in Jerusalem unto this day.</verse>
</chapter>