<chapter book="Joshua" number="19" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the second lot goeth out for Simeon, for the tribe of the sons of Simeon, for their families; and their inheritance is in the midst of the inheritance of the sons of Judah,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and they have in their inheritance Beer-Sheba, and Sheba, and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and Hazar-Shual, and Balah, and Azem,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and Eltolad, and Bethul, and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Ziklag, and Beth-Marcaboth, and Hazar-Susah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Beth-Lebaoth, and Sharuhen; thirteen cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ain, Remmon, and Ether, and Ashan; four cities and their villages;</verse>
  <verse number="8">also all the villages which are round about these cities, unto Baalath-Beer, Ramoth of the south. This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Simeon, for their families;</verse>
  <verse number="9">out of the portion of the sons of Judah is the inheritance of the sons of Simeon, for the portion of the sons of Judah hath been too much for them, and the sons of Simeon inherit in the midst of their inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the third lot goeth up for the sons of Zebulun, for their families; and the border of their inheritance is unto Sarid,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and their border hath gone up towards the sea, and Maralah, and come against Dabbasheth, and come unto the brook which is on the front of Jokneam,</verse>
  <verse number="12">and turned back from Sarid eastward, at the sun-rising, by the border of Chisloth-Tabor, and gone out unto Daberath, and gone up to Japhia,</verse>
  <verse number="13">and thence it hath passed over eastward, to the east, to Gittah-Hepher, to Ittah-Kazin, and gone out to Rimmon-Methoar to Neah;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and the border hath gone round about it, from the north to Hannathon; and its outgoings have been in the valley of Jiphthah-El,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Kattath, and Nahallal, and Shimron, and Idalah, and Beth-Lehem; twelve cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This is the inheritance of the sons of Zebulun, for their families, these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For Issachar hath the fourth lot gone out, for the sons of Issachar, for their families;</verse>
  <verse number="18">and their border is at Jezreel, and Chesulloth, and Shunem,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and Haphraim, and Shihon, and Anaharath,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and Rabbith, and Kishion, and Abez,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Remeth, and En-Gannim, and En-Haddah, and Beth-Pazzez;</verse>
  <verse number="22">and the border hath touched against Tabor, and Shahazimah, and Beth-Shemesh, and the outgoings of their border have been at the Jordan; sixteen cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Issachar, for their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the fifth lot goeth out for the tribe of the sons of Asher, for their families;</verse>
  <verse number="25">and their border is Helkath, and Hali, and Beten, and Achshaph,</verse>
  <verse number="26">and Alammelech, and Amad, and Misheal; and it toucheth against Carmel westward, and against Shihor-Libnath;</verse>
  <verse number="27">and hath turned back, at the sun-rising, to Beth-Dagon, and come against Zebulun, and against the valley of Jiphthah-El toward the north of Beth-Emek, and Neiel, and hath gone out unto Cabul on the left,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and Hebron, and Rehob, and Hammon, and Kanah, unto great Zidon;</verse>
  <verse number="29">and the border hath turned back to Ramah, and unto the fenced city Tyre; and the border hath turned back to Hosah, and its outgoings are at the sea, from the coast to Achzib,</verse>
  <verse number="30">and Ummah, and Aphek, and Rehob; twenty and two cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="31">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Asher, for their families, these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the sons of Naphtali hath the sixth lot gone out, for the sons of Naphtali, for their families;</verse>
  <verse number="33">and their border is from Heleph, from Allon in Zaanannim, and Adami, Nekeb, and Jabneel, unto Lakkum, and its outgoings are at the Jordan;</verse>
  <verse number="34">and the border hath turned back westward to Aznoth-Tabor, and gone out thence to Hukkok, and touched against Zebulun on the south, and against Asher it hath touched on the west, and against Judah at the Jordan, at the sun-rising;</verse>
  <verse number="35">and the cities of defence are Ziddim, Zer, and Hammath, Rakkath, and Chinnereth,</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Adamah, and Ramah, and Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and Kedesh, and Edrei, and En-Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Iron, and Migdal-El, Horem, and Beth-Anath, and Beth-Shemesh; nineteen cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="39">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Naphtali, for their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="40">For the tribe of the sons of Dan, for their families, hath the seventh lot gone out;</verse>
  <verse number="41">and the border of their inheritance is Zorah, and Eshtaol, and Ir-Shemesh,</verse>
  <verse number="42">and Shalabbin, and Aijalon, and Jethlah,</verse>
  <verse number="43">and Elon, and Thimnathah, and Ekron,</verse>
  <verse number="44">and Eltekeh, and Gibbethon, and Baalath,</verse>
  <verse number="45">and Jehud, and Bene-Barak, and Gath-Rimmon,</verse>
  <verse number="46">and Me-Jarkon, and Rakkon, with the border over-against Japho.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And the border of the sons of Dan goeth out from them, and the sons of Dan go up and fight with Leshem, and capture it, and smite it by the mouth of the sword, and possess it, and dwell in it, and call Leshem, Dan, according to the name of Dan their father.</verse>
  <verse number="48">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Dan, for their families, these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And they finish to give the land in inheritance, by its borders, and the sons of Israel give an inheritance to Joshua son of Nun in their midst;</verse>
  <verse number="50">by the command of Jehovah they have given to him the city which he asked, Timnath-Serah, in the hill-country of Ephraim, and he buildeth the city and dwelleth in it.</verse>
  <verse number="51">These are the inheritances which Eleazar the priest, and Joshua son of Nun, and the heads of the fathers of the tribes of the sons of Israel, have caused to inherit by lot, in Shiloh, before Jehovah, at the opening of the tent of meeting; and they finish to apportion the land.</verse>
</chapter>