<chapter book="Matthew" number="10" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And having called his twelve disciples, he gave them power over unclean spirits, to cast them out, and to cure every disease and every weakness.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the names of the twelve sent are these: first, Simon, called Peter, and Andrew his brother; James, he of Zebedee and John his brother;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Philip, and Bartholomew; Thomas, and Matthew the tax collector; James, he of Alpheus, and Lebbeus, he surnamed Thaddeus;</verse>
  <verse number="4">Simon the Canaanite, and Judas Iscariot, he also having delivered him up.</verse>
  <verse number="5">These twelve Jesus sent, having announced to them, saying, Go not in the way of the nations, and into the city of the Samaritans enter ye not.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But rather go to the lost sheep of the house of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And going, proclaim, saying, That the kingdom of the heavens has drawn near.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Cure the sick, cleanse the leprous, rouse the dead, cast out demons; as a gift ye have received, as a gift give.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Provide not gold, nor silver, nor brass in your purses;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Nor wallet for the way, nor two coats, nor shoes, nor rod: for the laborer is worthy of his food.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And to whatever city or town ye should come in, examine who in it is worthy; and there remain till ye go forth.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And entering into a house, do ye greet it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And if the house should be worthy, let your peace come upon it; but if it be not worthy let your peace return to you.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And whoever should not receive you, nor hear your words, coming out of that house or that city, shake off the cloud of the dust of your feet.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Verily I say to you, it shall be more supportable for the land of Sodom and Gomorrha in the day of judgment, than for that city.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold I send you as sheep in the midst of wolves; be ye therefore discerning as serpents, and pure as doves.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And hold ye from men: for they will deliver you up to councils, and in their assemblies will they scourge you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And ye shalt be brought before leaders and kings for my sake, for a testimony to them and to the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And when they deliver you up, have no care how or what ye should speak: for it shall be given you in that hour what ye shall speak.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For ye yourselves are not speaking, but the spirit of your father speaking in you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And brother shall deliver up brother to death, and father child: and children shall rise up in revolt against parents, and kill them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And ye shall be hated by all for my name: and he having remained to the end shall be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And when they drive you out in this city, flee ye to another; for verily I say to you, Ye shall not finish the cities of Israel till the Son of man come.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The disciple is not above the teacher, nor the servant above his lord.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Sufficient to the disciple that he be as his teacher, and the servant as his lord. If they have called the master of the house Beelzeboul, how much more those pertaining to his household?</verse>
  <verse number="26">Therefore fear them not; for nothing has been covered, which shall not be revealed; and concealed, that shall not be known.</verse>
  <verse number="27">What I say to you in darkness, speak ye in light: and what ye hear in the ear, proclaim upon the houses.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And fear not from those killing the body, and not able to kill the soul: but rather fear him able to destroy also soul and body in hell.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Are not two little sparrows sold for a farthing? and one of them shall not fall to the earth without your Father.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And also the hairs of your head are all numbered.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Fear not therefore; ye have the preeminence over many sparrows.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Every one therefore who shall agree with me before men, I also will agree with him before my Father, him in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But whoever should deny me before men, him will I also deny before my Father, him in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Think not that I came to cast peace upon earth; I came not to cast peace, but a sword.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For I came to set a man at variance against his father, and the daughter against her mother, and the bride against her mother-in-law.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And a man’s enemies, they pertaining to his household.</verse>
  <verse number="37">He loving father or mother above me, is not worthy of me; and he loving son or daughter above me, is not worthy of me.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And whoever takes not his cross, and follows after me, is not worthy of me.</verse>
  <verse number="39">He finding his soul shall lose it; and he having lost his soul for my sake shall find it.</verse>
  <verse number="40">He receiving you, receives me; and he receiving me, receives him sending me.</verse>
  <verse number="41">He receiving a prophet in a prophet’s name, shall receive a prophet’s reward; and he receiving the just in the name of the just, shall take the reward of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And whoever should give to drink one of these little ones a cup of cold water only, in the name of a disciple, verily I say to you, he shall not lose his reward.</verse>
</chapter>