<chapter book="Matthew" number="18" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">In that hour came the disciples to Jesus, saying, Who is the greater in the kingdom of the heavens?</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Jesus, having called a young child, set it in the midst of them,</verse>
  <verse number="3">And said, Truly I say to you, Except ye be turned, and become as young children, ye should not come into the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Whoever, therefore, should be humbled as this young child, the same is the greater in the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And whoever shall receive such a young child in my name, receives me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And whoever should offend one of these little ones believing in me, it is profitable for him that the millstone of an ass be hung upon his neck, and he be sunk in the midst of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Woe to the world for offences I for there is necessity for offences to come; but woe to that man by whom the offence comes!</verse>
  <verse number="8">And if thy hand or thy foot give thee cause of offence, cut them off, and cast from thee: it is good for thee to come into life lame or maimed, than having two hands or two feet to be cast into eternal fire.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And if thine eye give thee cause of offence, take it out, and east from thee: it is good for thee, one-eyed, to enter into life, than having two eyes to be cast into a hell of fire.</verse>
  <verse number="10">See that ye despise not one of these little ones; for I say to you, That their messengers in the heavens always behold the face of my Father which is in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the Son of man has come to save the lost.</verse>
  <verse number="12">What does it seem to you? if there be to any man a hundred sheep, and one of them have been led astray, does he not, having left the ninety-nine upon the mountains, having gone, seek the one led astray?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And if it be found, truly I say to you, he rejoices more over it, than over the ninety-nine not led astray.</verse>
  <verse number="14">So is not the will of your Father, he in the heavens, that one of these little ones be lost.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And if thy brother sin against thee, retire, and refute him between thee and him alone; if he hear thee, thou hast gained thy brother.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But if he hear thee not, take with thee yet one or two, that at the mouth of two or three witnesses every word might stand.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And if he refuse hearing them, speak to the church: and if he refuse hearing the church, let him be to thee as of the nations and a publican.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Truly I say to you, Whatever things ye should bind on earth shall be bound in heaven; and whatever things ye should loose upon earth shall be loosed in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Again, I say to you, That if two of you agree in opinion for everything which they ask, it shall be to them of my Father, he in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For where two or three are assembled in my name, there am I in the midst of them.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Then Peter, having come to him, said, Lord, how often shall my brother sin against me, and I let him go? Till seven times?</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Jesus says to him, I say not to thee, till seven times; but till seventy times seven.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Therefore the kingdom of the heavens was likened to a man, the king, who wished to lift up the word together with his servants.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he having begun to settle accounts, one was brought him, a debtor of ten thousand talents.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he not having to give back, his lord ordered him to be sold, and his wife and his children, and all which he had also to be given back.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then the servant, having fallen, worshipped him, saying, Lord, be slow to anger towards me, and I will give back all to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the lord of that servant, having felt compassion, loosed him, and let go to him the money lent.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But that servant having come, found one of his fellow-servants who owed him one hundred drachmas, and having seized, he choked him, saying, Give back to me what thou owest.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Then his fellow-servant having fallen at his feet besought him, saying, Be slow to anger towards me, and I will give back all to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he would not; but having departed he cast him into prison till he should give back that being owed.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And his fellow-servants having seen the thing done, were greatly grieved, and having come, made known to their lord all things done.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Then his lord, having called him, said unto him, O thou evil servant, I let go to you all that debt since thou besoughtest me:</verse>
  <verse number="33">Oughtest thou not also to pity thy fellow-servant, as I also pitied thee.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And his lord having become angry, delivered him to the torturers even till he should give back all being owed to him.</verse>
  <verse number="35">So also will my heavenly Father do to you, if ye let not go each to his brother from your hearts their falls.</verse>
</chapter>