<chapter book="Matthew" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jesus born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of Herod the king, behold the magi from the sunrisings arrived in Jerusalem, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Where is he born King of the Jews? for we have seen his star in the sunrising, and have come to worship him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Herod the king having heard, was stirred up, and all Jerusalem with him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And assembling all the chief priests and scribes of the people, he inquired of them where Christ should be born.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they said to him, In Bethlehem of Judea: for thus has it been written by the prophet:</verse>
  <verse number="6">And thou Bethlehem, land of Judah, by no means art thou least among the leaders of Judah for out of thee shall come forth the leader, who shall feed my people.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Then Herod having secretly called for the magi, searched thoroughly from them the time of the star appearing.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And having sent them to Bethlehem, he said, Having gone, examine thoroughly concerning the child; and when ye should find, announce ye to me, so that I also, having gone, will worship him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they having heard the king went forth; and, behold the star they saw in the sunrising, it led before them, till having come, it stood above where the young child was.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And seeing the star, they rejoiced with great joy exceedingly.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And having come into the house, they found the young child with Mary his mother, and having fallen, they worshipped him; and having opened their treasures they brought forward to him gifts, gold, and frankincense, and myrrh.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And having received intimation of the divine will in a dream not to turn back to Herod, by another way they went back to their own country.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they, having gone back, lo, the messenger of the Lord appears in a dream to Joseph, saying, Having risen, take to thyself the young child and his mother and flee into Egypt, and be there till I speak to thee; for Herod is about to seek the young child to destroy him.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And having risen, he took to himself the young child and his mother by night, and turned back in Egypt:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And was there till the death of Herod: that it might be completed having been spoken by the Lord through the prophet, saying, Out of Egypt have I called my son.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then Herod, seeing he was deluded by the magi, was very angry, and having sent, destroyed all the children which in Bethlehem, and in all its bounds, from two years and under, according to the time he examined thoroughly of the magi.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Then was completed that spoken by Jeremiah the prophet, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="18">A voice was heard in Rama, wailing, and weeping, and much lamentation; Rachel weeping for her children, and would not be comforted, for they are not.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Herod having died, behold a messenger of the Lord appeared in a dream to Joseph in Egypt, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Having risen, take to thyself the young child and his mother, and go into the land of Israel; for they seeking the soul of the young child have died.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And having risen, he took the young child and his mother, and came into the land of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And having heard that Archelaus reigned over Judea, instead of Herod his father, he was afraid to go there; and having received intimation of the divine will in a dream, he turned back into the parts of Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And having come, he dwelt in a city called Nazareth: that it might be completed spoken by the prophets, That he shall be called a Nazarite.</verse>
</chapter>