<chapter book="Matthew" number="26" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it was when Jesus finished all the words, he said to his disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Ye know that after two days is the passover, and the Son of man shall be delivered to be crucified.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then were gathered together the chief priests, and scribes, and the more ancient of the people, into the court-yard of the chief priest, called Caiaphas,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they counselled together, that they might obtain Jesus by stratagem, and might kill.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they said, Not in the festival, lest there should be an uproar among the people.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Jesus having been in Bethany, in the house of Simon the leprous,</verse>
  <verse number="7">There came to him a woman having an alabaster box of costly perfumed ointment, and she poured upon the head of him, reclining at table.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And his disciples seeing, felt pain, saying, For what this loss?</verse>
  <verse number="9">For this perfumed oil could have been sold for much, and have been given to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jesus having known, said to them, Why offer ye toils to the woman? for a good work has she worked upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For always the poor ye have with you, but me ye have not always.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For she, casting this perfumed oil upon my body, did to prepare me for interment,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Truly I say to you, Wheresoever this good news be proclaimed in the whole world, shall it also be spoken what she did, for a remembrance of her.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then one of the twelve having gone forth, he being called Judas Iscariot, to the chief priests,</verse>
  <verse number="15">Said, What will ye give me, and I will deliver him to you? and they placed to him thirty silver coins.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And from then he sought opportunity, that he might deliver him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And in the first of the unleavened loaves, the disciples came to Jesus, saying to him, Where wilt thou we should prepare for thee to eat the pascha?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he said, Retire ye into the city, to a certain person, and say to him, The teacher says, My time is near; with thee do I the pascha with my disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the disciples did as Jesus commanded them: and they prepared the passover.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And it being evening, he reclined at table with the twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they eating, he said, Truly I say to you, that one of you shall deliver me up.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And they being greatly grieved, began each of them to say to him, Far from it am I, O Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he having answered, said, He having dipped with me the hand in the small dish, the same shall deliver me up.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Truly the Son of man retires as has been written concerning him; and woe to that man by whom the Son of man is delivered up! it was good for him if that man had not been born.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Judas delivering him up, having answered, said, Far from it, am I, Rabbi? He said to him, Thou hast said.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they eating, Jesus, having taken the bread and praised, brake and gave to the disciples, and said, Take, eat; this is my body.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And having taken the cup, and given thanks, he gave to them, saying, Drink of it all ye.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For this is my blood, that of the new covenant, having been poured out for many, for the remission of sins.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And I say to you, that I drink not from henceforth of this fruit of the vine, even till that day when I drink it new with you, in the kingdom of my Father.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And having sung, they went forth to the mount of Olives.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Then says Jesus to them, All ye shall be scandalized in me this night; for it has been written, I will smite the shepherd, and the sheep of the flock shall be scattered up and down.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And after I be raised, I will lead before you into Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Peter having answered, said to him, And if all men shall be scandalized in thee, I will never be scandalized.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Jesus says to him, Truly I say to thee that in this night, before the cock utters a sound, thou shalt deny me thrice.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Peter says to him, Though it should be necessary for me to die with thee, I will not deny thee: likewise also said all the disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Then comes Jesus with them into the place called Gethsemane, and says to the disciples, Sit here, till I, having gone, shall pray.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And having taken Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, he began to be grieved, and to be dejected.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Then says he to them, My soul is sorely grieved, even to death: remain here, and watch ye with me.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And having gone forward a little, he fell upon his face, praying, and saying, My Father, if it is possible, let this cup pass away from me: but not as I will, but as thou.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And he comes to his disciples, and finds them sleeping, and says to Peter, So were ye not able to watch with me one hour?</verse>
  <verse number="41">Watch and pray, lest ye come into temptation: truly the spirit of a ready will, and the flesh weak.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Again of a second time, having gone away, he prayed, saying, My Father if this cup cannot pass away from me except I drink it, let thy will be.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And having gone he finds them again sleeping: for their eyes were loaded.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And having left them, having gone away again, he prayed of the third time, speaking the same word.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then comes he to his disciples, and says to them, Sleep for the remaining time, and take rest: behold, the hour has drawn near, and the Son of man is delivered into the hands of the sinful.</verse>
  <verse number="46">Be aroused, let us lead forth; behold, he delivering me up, has drawn near.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And he yet speaking, behold, Judas, one of the twelve, came, and with him a great crowd, with swords, and sticks, from the chief priests, and the more ancient of the people.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And he delivering him up, gave them a sign, saying, Whomsoever I shall kiss, the same is he: hold him firmly.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And quickly having come to Jesus, he said, Hail, Rabbi! and kissed him.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And Jesus said to him, Friend, for what comest thou? Then having come near, they put hands upon Jesus, and held him firmly.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And, behold, one of them with Jesus, having stretched out the hand, pulled out his sword, having struck the chief priest’s servant, took away his ear.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Then says Jesus to him, Turn back thy sword to its place: for all they having taken the sword, shall perish by the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="53">Thinkest thou that I am not able to call to my Father for aid, and he will set before me more than twelve legions of messengers?</verse>
  <verse number="54">How then would the writings be filled up, that so it must be?</verse>
  <verse number="55">In that hour, Jesus said to the crowds, As against a robber came ye out, with swords and sticks, to take me? In the day I sat down with you, teaching, and ye took not hold of me.</verse>
  <verse number="56">But this has been wholly that the writings of the prophets might be filled up. Then all the disciples, having left him, fled.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And they having held Jesus, brought to Caiaphas the chief priest, where the scribes and elders were gathered together.</verse>
  <verse number="58">And Peter followed him from far, even to the court-yard of the chief priest, and having entered within, he sat with the attendants, to see the end.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And the chief priests, and the elders, and the whole council sought false testimony against Jesus, so that they might put him to death;</verse>
  <verse number="60">And they found not: and many false witnesses having come near, they found not.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And afterwards two false witnesses, having come near, said, This said, I can loosen the temple of God, and after three days build it.</verse>
  <verse number="62">And the chief priest, having risen, said to him, Answerest thou nothing? what do these witness against thee?</verse>
  <verse number="63">But Jesus was silent. And the chief priest having answered, said to him, I cause thee to swear by the living God, that thou tell us, if thou art Christ, the Son of God.</verse>
  <verse number="64">And Jesus says to him, Thou hast said: but I say to you, from henceforth ye shall see the Son of man, sitting from the right hand of power, and coming in the clouds of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="65">Then the chief priest tore his garments, saying, That he blasphemed: what further need have we of witnesses? see, now ye have heard his blasphemy.</verse>
  <verse number="66">What seems to you? And they having answered, said, He is liable to the penalty of death.</verse>
  <verse number="67">Then did they spit in his face, and cuffed him, and struck him with a rod:</verse>
  <verse number="68">Saying, Prophesy to us, O Christ, Who is he having struck thee.</verse>
  <verse number="69">And Peter sat without in the court-yard, and one young girl came to him saying, Thou also wast with Jesus of Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And he denied before all, saying, I know not what thou sayest.</verse>
  <verse number="71">And he having gone out into the gate, another saw him, and she says to them there, This also was with Jesus the Nazarite.</verse>
  <verse number="72">And again he denied with an oath, That I know not the man.</verse>
  <verse number="73">And a little after, those standing, having come near, said to Peter, Truly thou also art of them; for also thy speech makes thee manifest.</verse>
  <verse number="74">Then began he to anathematize, and to swear, That I know not the man: and quickly the cock uttered a sound.</verse>
  <verse number="75">And Peter remembered the word of Jesus, having said to him, That before the cock utter a sound, thou shalt deny me thrice. And having gone forth without, he wept bitterly.</verse>
</chapter>