<chapter book="Matthew" number="27" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And having been morning, all the chief priests and elders of the people took counsel against Jesus, to kill him:</verse>
  <verse number="2">And having bound they brought him away, and they delivered him to Pontius Pilate, the leader.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Judas, he delivering him up, having seen that he was condemned, having felt regret, returned the thirty silver coins to the chief priests, and the more ancient,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Saying, I have sinned, having delivered up guiltless blood. And they said, What to us? thou shalt see.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And having cast down the silver coins in the temple, he withdrew and having gone away, he strangled him self.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the chief priests, having taken the silver coins, said, It is not lawful to cast them for an offering, since it is the price of blood.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And having taken counsel, they purchased with them the potter’s field, for the interment to strangers.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Wherefore, that field was called, The field of blood, even to this day.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then was completed that having been spoken by Jeremiah the prophet, saying, And they took the thirty silver coins, the price of him prized, whom they from the sons of Israel prized;</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they gave them for the potter’s field, as the Lord commanded me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Jesus stood before the leader: and the leader asked him, saying, Art thou King of the Jews? Jesus said to him, Thou sayest.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And in the accusing him by the chief priests and the more ancient, he answered nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then says Pilate to him, Hearest thou not what they witness against thee?</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he answered him not to one word: so that the leader wondered greatly.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And in the festival the leader was accustomed to loose one imprisoned to the crowd, which they desired.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they had then an imprisoned distinguished, called Barabbas.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore they assembled together, Pilate laid to them, Whom will ye I shall loose to you? Barabbas, or Jesus, called Christ?</verse>
  <verse number="18">For he knew that through envy, they had delivered him, up.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he sitting upon the judgment seat, his wife sent to him, saying, Nothing to thee and that just one: for I have suffered this day many things in a dream, on his account.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the chief priests and the elders persuaded the crowds that they should ask Barabbas, and destroy Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the leader having answered, said to them, Which of the two will ye I shall loose to you? And they said, Barabbas.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Pilate says to them, What then shall I do with Jesus, called Christ? They all say to him, Let him be crucified.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the leader said, For what evil hath he done? and they cried excessively, saying, Let him be crucified.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Pilate, seeing that it profits nothing, but there is rather an uproar, having taken water, he washed his hands before the crowd, saying, I am guiltless of the blood of this just one: ye shall see yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And all the people having answered, said, His blood upon us, and upon our children.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then he loosed to them Barabbas: and having scourged Jesus, delivered him up, that, he might be crucified.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Then the soldiers of the leader, having taken Jesus to the Pretorium, gathered together the whole band against him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And having unclothed him, they put round him a scarlet, loose, warm cloak.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And having twined a crown of thorns, they put upon, his head: and a reed upon his right hand: and having fallen upon the knees before him, they mocked him, saying, Hail, King of the Jews!</verse>
  <verse number="30">And having spit upon him, they took the reed, and struck upon his head.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And when they mocked him, they put off from him the loose, warm cloak, and put on him his garments, and brought him away to crucify.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And coming, they found a man, a Cyrenian, Simon by name; they compelled him that he should lift up his cross.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And having come, to the place called Golgotha, which is called the place of the skull,</verse>
  <verse number="34">They gave him vinegar to drink. (mingled with bile: and having tasted, he would not drink.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And having crucified him, they divided his garments among them, casting lot: that that spoken by the prophet might be filled up: They divided among them my garments, and upon my clothing they cast lot.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And sitting down, they observed him there.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And they set above his head his accusation, having been written: THIS IS JESUS THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Then were crucified with him two robbers; one from the right hand, and the other from the left.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And they coming near, blasphemed him, shaking their heads,</verse>
  <verse number="40">And saying, He loosing the temple, and building in three days, save thyself: if thou art the Son of God, come down from the cross.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And likewise also the chief priests mocking, with the scribes and elders, said,</verse>
  <verse number="42">Others he saved; himself he cannot save. If he is King of Israel, let him now come down from the cross, and we will believe him:</verse>
  <verse number="43">He trusted upon God; let him now deliver him, if he desires him: for he said, That I am the Son of God.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And the robbers crucified with him, reproached him with the same.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And from the sixth hour, darkness was upon all the earth, even to the ninth hour.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And about the ninth hour, Jesus cried out with a great voice, saying, Eli, Eli, lama sabachthani I this is, My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?</verse>
  <verse number="47">And some of them standing there, having heard, said, That he calls Elias.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And quickly one of them, having run, and taken a sponge, and filled with vinegar, and put upon a reed, gave him to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And the rest said, Let go: we should see if Elias comes, going to save him.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And Jesus, again having cried with a great voice, let go the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And, behold, the covering of the temple was cleft in two, from above to below; and the earth was shaken; and the rocks were cleft:</verse>
  <verse number="52">And the tombs were opened: and many bodies of the holy ones, having been set to sleep, were raised,</verse>
  <verse number="53">And having come forth from the tombs, after his arising, went into the holy city, and were exhibited to many.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And the centurion, and they with him, observing Jesus, having seen the shaking, and the things having been, were greatly afraid, saying, Truly this was the Son of God.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And many women were there, beholding from far off, who followed Jesus out of Galilee, serving him:</verse>
  <verse number="56">Among whom was Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James and Joses, and the mother of Zebedee’s sons.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And being evening, then there came a rich man from Arimathea, Joseph by name, who also himself was a disciple to Jesus:</verse>
  <verse number="58">He having come to Pilate, asked the body of Jesus. Then Pilate ordered the body to be given back.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And Joseph having taken the body, inwrapped it in clean fine linen:</verse>
  <verse number="60">And put it in his new tomb, which he quarried in the rock: and having rolled a great stone to the door of the tomb, he departed.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And Mary Magdalene was there, and the other Mary, sitting opposite the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="62">And in the morrow, which is after the preparation, the chief priests and the Pharisees were gathered together to Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="63">Saying, Lord, we remember that that impostor said, yet living, After three days, I arise.</verse>
  <verse number="64">Order therefore, the tomb to be rendered secure till the third day, lest his disciples, having come by night, should steal him, and say to the people, He was raised from the dead; and the last error shall be worse than the first.</verse>
  <verse number="65">And Pilate said to them, Ye have a watch: retire, render secure as ye know.</verse>
  <verse number="66">And they, having gone, rendered the tomb secure, having sealed the stone with the watch.</verse>
</chapter>