<chapter book="Matthew" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And seeing the multitudes, he went up into a mountain; and he having sat down, his disciples came to him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And having opened his mouth, he taught them, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Happy the poor in spirit: for their’s is the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Happy they suffering: for they shall be comforted.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Happy the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Happy they hungering and thirsting for Justice: for they shall be filled.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Happy the compassionate: for they shall be commiserated.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Happy the pure in heart: for they shall see God.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Happy they making peace: for they shall be called sons of God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Happy they driven out for justice: for their’s is the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Happy are ye, when they shall upbraid you, and drive you out, and say every evil word against you, lying, for my sake.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Rejoice and be transported with joy; for much your reward in the heavens for so they drove out the prophets which before you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Ye are the salt of the earth: and if the salt be rendered insipid, with what shall it be salted? it is yet strong for nothing, except to be cast without, and to be trodden under foot of men.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Ye are the light of the world. A city cannot be hid, set on a mountain.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Neither do they burn a light, and set it under a basket, but upon a chandelier: and it shines to all in the house.</verse>
  <verse number="16">So let your light shine before men, that they see your good works, and praise your Father, him in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Think not that I have come to abolish the law, or the prophets: for I have come not abolish, but to complete.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For verily I say to you, Till heaven pass away, and earth, one iota, or one mark, should not pass away from the law, till all should be.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Whoever therefore, should loose one of the least of these commands, and so teach men, he shall be called least in the kingdom of the heavens: but whoever should do and teach, he shall be called great in the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I say to you, That except your justice abound more than the scribes and Pharisees, ye should not come into the kingdom of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Ye have heard that it was said to the ancients, Thou shalt not kill: and whoever should kill shall be subject to judgment:</verse>
  <verse number="22">But I say to you, That every one becoming angry with his brother, shall be subject to judgment: and whoever should say to his brother, Raca, should be, subject to the council: and whoever should say, O foolish, shall be subject to a hell of fire.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If therefore, thou bring thy gift upon the altar, and there thou remember that thy brother has anything against thee,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Let go there thy gift, before the altar, and retire; first be reconciled to thy brother, and then, having come, bring thy gift.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Be kindly disposed to thy opponent quickly, while thou art in the way with him, lest thy opponent should deliver thee to the judge, and the judge should deliver thee to the assistant, and thou be cast into prison.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Verily I say to thee, Thou shouldst not come out thence, even till, thou shouldst give back the last fourth.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Ye have heard that it was said to the ancients, Thou shalt not commit adultery:</verse>
  <verse number="28">But I say to you, That every one seeing a woman, to eagerly desire her, has already committed adultery with her, in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And if thine eye give thee cause of offence, take it out, and cast it from thee: for it is profitable for thee that one of thy members be destroyed, and not thy whole body be cast into hell.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And if thy right hand give thee cause of offence, cut it off, and cast from thee; for it is profitable to thee, that one of thy members should be destroyed; and not thy whole body should be cast into hell.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And it was said, That whosoever should loose his wife, let him give her a repudiation.</verse>
  <verse number="32">But I say to you, That whosoever shall let go his wife except for the reason of adultery, makes her to commit adultery; and whosoever should marry her having been loosed, commits adultery.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Again, ye have heard, that it was said to the ancients, Thou shalt not swear a false oath, and thou shalt return to the Lord thine oaths.</verse>
  <verse number="34">But I say to you, Swear not at all; neither by heaven, it is the throne of God:</verse>
  <verse number="35">Neither by the earth; for it is the footstool of his feet: neither by Jerusalem, for it is the city of the great kings.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Neither shouldst thou swear by thy head, for thou cant not make one hair white or black.</verse>
  <verse number="37">But let your word be Yea, yea, and No, no: but that above this is of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Ye have heard, that it has been said, An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth:</verse>
  <verse number="39">But I say to you, not to resist evil: but whosoever shall smite thee with a rod upon thy right cheek, turn to him also the other.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And to him wishing to be judged with thee, and to take thy coat, let go to him also thy garment.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And whoever shall compel thee to carry dispatches one mile, go forward with him two.</verse>
  <verse number="42">To him asking thee, give thou, and him wishing to borrow from thee, thou shouldst not turn away.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Ye have heard that it has been said, Thou shalt love thy neighbor, and hate thine enemy.</verse>
  <verse number="44">But I say to you, Love your enemies, praise them cursing you, do well to them hating you, and pray for them threatening you, and driving you out.</verse>
  <verse number="45">So that ye might be sons of your Father, which in the heavens: for he makes his sun rise upon evil and good, and rains on the just and unjust.</verse>
  <verse number="46">For if ye love them loving you, what reward have you? do not also the tax collectors the same?</verse>
  <verse number="47">And if ye salute your brethren only, what do ye above ordinary? and do not the tax collectors the same?</verse>
  <verse number="48">Therefore, be ye perfected, as your Father which is in the heavens is perfected.</verse>
</chapter>