<chapter book="Matthew" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Judge not, that ye be not judged.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For with what judgment ye judge, ye shall be judged; and with what measure ye measure, it shall be repaid to you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And why seest thou the mote which is in thy brother’s eye, and the beam in thine eye thou observest not?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Or how wilt thou say to thy brother, Let go I will cast out the mote from thine eye: and behold a beam in thine eye.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thou hypocrite, cast out first the beam from thine eye, and thou shalt see clearly to cast out the mote from thy brother’s eye.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Ye should not give the holy thing to dogs neither should ye cast your pearls before swine, lest they tread them down with their feet, and having turned, should rend you.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ask, and it shall be given you. Seek, and ye shall find. Knock, and it shall be opened to you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For everyone asking, receives and he seeking, finds; and to him knocking shall be opened.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Or what man is of you, which, if his son ask bread, he will not give him a stone?</verse>
  <verse number="10">And if he ask a fish, he will not give him a serpent?</verse>
  <verse number="11">If ye, therefore, being evil, know to give good gifts to your children how much more will your Father which is in the heavens give good things to those asking him?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Therefore all whatever ye would that men should do to you, so also do ye to them; for this is the law and the prophets.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Enter ye in through the strait gate, for broad the gate and spacious the way leading to destruction, and many are they coming in through it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For strait the gate and afflicted the way leading into life, and few are they finding it.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And hold from false prophets which come in to you in sheep’s dresses, but within they are rapacious wolves.</verse>
  <verse number="16">By their fruits shall ye know them. Far from it, do they gather grapes from thorns, or figs from caltrops.</verse>
  <verse number="17">So every good tree makes good fruits; but the rotten tree makes evil fruits.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A good tree cannot make evil fruits, nor a rotten tree make good fruits.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Every tree not making good fruit is cut off, and cast into fire.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wherefore from their fruits shall ye know them.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Not every one saying to me, Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of the heavens; but he doing the will of my Father who is in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Many will say to me in that day, Lord, Lord, have we not prophesied in thy name, and in thy name have we cast out evil spirits, and in thy name done many powers?</verse>
  <verse number="23">And then shall I confess to them that I never knew you. Go away from me, ye working iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Therefore, every one which hears these my words and does them, I will liken him to a discerning man which built his house upon the rock.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the rain descended, and rivers came, and winds blew, and fell upon that house, and it fell not, for it was founded upon the rock.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And every one hearing these my words and doing them not, shall be likened to a foolish man, which built his house upon sand.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the rain descended, and rivers came, and winds blew and struck upon that house, and it fell, and great was its fall.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And it was when Jesus finished these words, the crowds were struck with amazement at his teaching:</verse>
  <verse number="29">For he was teaching them as having power, and not as the scribes.</verse>
</chapter>