<chapter book="Isaiah" number="21" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The burden of the wilderness of the sea. As whirlwinds in the South sweeping on, It cometh from the wilderness, from a dreadful land.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A grievous vision is declared unto me: ‘The treacherous dealer dealeth treacherously, and the spoiler spoileth. Go up, O Elam! besiege, O Media! All the sighing thereof have I made to cease.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">Therefore are my loins filled with convulsion; Pangs have taken hold upon me, as the pangs of a woman in travail; I am bent so that I cannot hear; I am affrighted so that I cannot see.</verse>
  <verse number="4">My heart is bewildered, terror hath overwhelmed me; The twilight that I longed for hath been turned for me into trembling.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They prepare the table, they light the lamps, they eat, they drink—‘Rise up, ye princes, anoint the shield.’</verse>
  <verse number="6">For thus hath the Lord said unto me: Go, set a watchman; let him declare what he seeth!</verse>
  <verse number="7">And when he seeth a troop, horsemen by pairs, A troop of asses, a troop of camels, He shall hearken diligently with much heed.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he cried as a lion: ‘Upon the watch-tower, O Lord, I stand continually in the daytime, And I am set in my ward all the nights.’</verse>
  <verse number="9">And, behold, there came a troop of men, horsemen by pairs. And he spoke and said: ‘Fallen, fallen is Babylon; And all the graven images of her gods are broken unto the ground.’</verse>
  <verse number="10">O thou my threshing, and the winnowing of my floor, That which I have heard from the LORD of hosts, The God of Israel, have I declared unto you.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The burden of Dumah. One calleth unto me out of Seir: ‘Watchman, what of the night? Watchman, what of the night?’</verse>
  <verse number="12">The watchman said: ‘The morning cometh, and also the night—If ye will inquire, inquire ye; return, come.’</verse>
  <verse number="13">The burden upon Arabia. In the thickets in Arabia shall ye lodge, O ye caravans of Dedanites.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Unto him that is thirsty bring ye water! The inhabitants of the land of Tema did meet the fugitive with his bread.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For they fled away from the swords, from the drawn sword, And from the bent bow, and from the grievousness of war.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For thus hath the Lord said unto me: ‘Within a year, according to the years of a hireling, and all the glory of Kedar shall fail;</verse>
  <verse number="17">and the residue of the number of the archers, the mighty men of the children of Kedar, shall be diminished; for the LORD, the God of Israel, hath spoken it.’</verse>
</chapter>