<chapter book="Isaiah" number="34" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Come near, ye nations, to hear, And attend, ye peoples; Let the earth hear, and the fulness thereof, The world, and all things that come forth of it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For the LORD hath indignation against all the nations, And fury against all their host; He hath utterly destroyed them, He hath delivered them to the slaughter.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Their slain also shall be cast out, And the stench of their carcasses shall come up, And the mountains shall be melted with their blood.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And all the host of heaven shall moulder away, And the heavens shall be rolled together as a scroll; And all their host shall fall down, As the leaf falleth off from the vine, And as a falling fig from the fig-tree.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For My sword hath drunk its fill in heaven; Behold, it shall come down upon Edom, And upon the people of My ban, to judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The sword of the LORD is filled with blood, It is made fat with fatness, With the blood of lambs and goats, With the fat of the kidneys of rams; For the LORD hath a sacrifice in Bozrah, And a great slaughter in the land of Edom.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the wild-oxen shall come down with them, And the bullocks with the bulls; And their land shall be drunken with blood, And their dust made fat with fatness.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For the LORD hath a day of vengeance, A year of recompense for the controversy of Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the streams thereof shall be turned into pitch, And the dust thereof into brimstone, And the land thereof shall become burning pitch.</verse>
  <verse number="10">It shall not be quenched night nor day, The smoke thereof shall go up for ever; From generation to generation it shall lie waste: None shall pass through it for ever and ever.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But the pelican and the bittern shall possess it, And the owl and the raven shall dwell therein; And He shall stretch over it The line of confusion, and the plummet of emptiness.</verse>
  <verse number="12">As for her nobles, none shall be there to be called to the kingdom; And all her princes shall be nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And thorns shall come up in her palaces, Nettles and thistles in the fortresses thereof; And it shall be a habitation of wild-dogs, An enclosure for ostriches.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the wild-cats shall meet with the jackals, And the satyr shall cry to his fellow; Yea, the night-monster shall repose there, And shall find her a place of rest.</verse>
  <verse number="15">There shall the arrowsnake make her nest, and lay, And hatch, and brood under her shadow; Yea, there shall the kites be gathered, Every one with her mate.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Seek ye out of the book of the LORD, and read; No one of these shall be missing, None shall want her mate; For My mouth it hath commanded, And the breath thereof it hath gathered them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And He hath cast the lot for them, And His hand hath divided it unto them by line; They shall possess it for ever, From generation to generation shall they dwell therein.</verse>
</chapter>