<chapter book="Isaiah" number="64" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Oh, that Thou wouldest rend the heavens, that Thou wouldest come down, That the mountains might quake at Thy presence, As when fire kindleth the brush-wood, And the fire causeth the waters to boil; To make Thy name known to Thine adversaries, That the nations might tremble at Thy presence,</verse>
  <verse number="2"></verse>
  <verse number="3">When Thou didst tremendous things Which we looked not for—Oh that Thou wouldest come down, that the mountains might quake at Thy presence!—</verse>
  <verse number="4">And whereof from of old men have not heard, nor perceived by the ear, Neither hath the eye seen a God beside Thee, Who worketh for him that waiteth for Him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thou didst take away him that joyfully worked righteousness, Those that remembered Thee in Thy ways—Behold, Thou wast wroth, and we sinned—Upon them have we stayed of old, that we might be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And we are all become as one that is unclean, And all our righteousnesses are as a polluted garment; And we all do fade as a leaf, And our iniquities, like the wind, take us away.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And there is none that calleth upon Thy name, That stirreth up himself to take hold of Thee; For Thou hast hid Thy face from us, And hast consumed us by means of our iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But now, O LORD, Thou art our Father; We are the clay, and Thou our potter, And we all are the work of Thy hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be not wroth very sore, O LORD, Neither remember iniquity for ever; Behold, look, we beseech Thee, we are all Thy people.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thy holy cities are become a wilderness, Zion is become a wilderness, Jerusalem a desolation.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Our holy and our beautiful house, Where our fathers praised Thee, Is burned with fire; And all our pleasant things are laid waste.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wilt Thou refrain Thyself for these things, O LORD? Wilt Thou hold Thy peace, and afflict us very sore?</verse>
</chapter>