<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The parables of Solomon, the son of David, king of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="2">To know wisdom, and instruction: To understand the words of prudence:</verse>
  <verse number="3">and to receive the instruction of doctrine, justice, and judgment, and equity:</verse>
  <verse number="4">To give subtilty to little ones, to the young man knowledge and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A wise man shall hear and shall be wiser: and he that understandeth, shall possess governments.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He shall understand a parable, and the interpretation, the words of the wise, and their mysterious sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom. Fools despise wisdom and instruction.</verse>
  <verse number="8">My son, hear the instruction of thy father, and forsake not the law of thy mother :</verse>
  <verse number="9">That grace may be added to thy head, and a chain of gold to thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if sinners shall entice thee, consent not to them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they shall say: Come with us, let us lie in wait for blood, let us hide snares for the innocent without cause:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let us swallow him up alive like hell, and whole as one that goeth down into the pit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">We shall find all precious substance, we shall fill our houses with spoils.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Cast in thy lot with us, let us all have one purse.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, walk not thou with them, restrain thy foot from their paths.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For their feet run to evil, and make haste to shed blood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But a net is spread in vain before the eyes of them that have wings.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they themselves lie in wait for their own blood, and practise deceits against their own souls.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So the wage of every covetous man destroy the souls of the possessors.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom preacheth abroad, she uttereth her voice in the streets:</verse>
  <verse number="21">At the head of multitudes she crieth out, in the entrance of the gates of the city she uttereth her words, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="22">O children, how long will you love childishness, and fools covet those things which are hurtful to themselves, and the unwise hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn ye at my reproof: behold I will utter my spirit to you, and will shew you my words.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I called, and you refused: I stretched out my hand, and there was none that regarded.</verse>
  <verse number="25">You have despised all my counsel, and have neglected my reprehensions.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I also will laugh in your destruction, and will mock when that shall come to you which you feared.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When sudden calamity shall fall on you, and destruction, as a tempest, shall be at hand: when tribulation and distress shall come upon you:</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then shall they call upon me, and I will not hear: they shall rise in the morning and shall not find me:</verse>
  <verse number="29">Because they have hated instruction and received not the fear of the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Nor consented to my counsel, but despised all my reproof.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Therefore they shall eat the fruit of their own way, and shall be filled with their own devices.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The turning away of little ones shall kill them, and the prosperity of fools shall destroy them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But he that shall hear me, shall rest without terror, and shall enjoy abundance, without fear of evils.</verse>
</chapter>