<chapter book="Proverbs" number="14" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A wise woman buildeth her house: but the foolish will pull down with her hands that also which is built.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He that walketh in the right way, and feareth God, is despised by him that goeth by an infamous way.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In the mouth of a fool is the rod of pride: but the lips of the wise preserve them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where there are no oxen, the crib is empty: but where there is much corn, there the strength of the ox is manifest.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A faithful witness will not lie: but a deceitful witness uttereth a lie.</verse>
  <verse number="6">A scorner seeketh wisdom, and findeth it not: the learning of the wise is easy.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Go against a foolish man, and he knoweth not the lips of prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The wisdom of a. discreet man is to understand his way: and the imprudence of fools erreth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A fool will laugh at sin, but among the just grace shall abide.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The heart that knoweth the bitterness of his own soul, in his joy the stranger shall not intermeddle.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The house of the wicked shall be destroyed: but the tabernacles of the just shall flourish.</verse>
  <verse number="12">There is a way which seemeth just to a man: but the ends thereof lead to death.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Laughter shall be mingled with sorrow, and mourning taketh hold of the end of joy.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A fool shall be filled with his own ways, and the good man shall be above him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The innocent believeth every word: the discreet man considereth his steps. No good shall come to the deceitful son: but the wise servant shall prosper in his dealings, and his way shall be made straight.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A wise man feareth and declineth from evil: the fool leapeth over and is confident.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The impatient man shall work folly: and the crafty man is hateful.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The childish shall possess folly, and the prudent, shall look for knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The evil shall fall down before the good: and the wicked before the gates of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The poor man shall be hateful even to his own neighbour: but the friends of the rich are many.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that despiseth his neighbour, sinneth: but he that sheweth mercy to the poor, shall be blessed. He that believeth in the Lord, loveth mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="22">They err that work evil: but mercy and truth prepare good things.</verse>
  <verse number="23">In much work there shall be abundance: but where there are many words, there is oftentimes want.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The crown of the wise is their riches: the folly of fools, imprudence.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A faithful witness delivereth souls: and the double dealer uttereth lies.</verse>
  <verse number="26">In the fear of the Lord is confidence of strength, and there shall be hope for his children.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The fear of the Lord is a fountain of life, to decline from the ruin of death.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the multitude of people is the dignity of the king: and in the small number of people the dishonour of the prince.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He that is patient, is governed with much wisdom: but he that is impatient, exalteth his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Soundness of heart is the life of the flesh: but envy is the rottenness of the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He that oppresseth the poor, upbraideth his Maker: but he that hath pity on the poor, honoureth him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The wicked man shall be driven out in his wickedness: but the just hath hope in his death.</verse>
  <verse number="33">In the heart of the prudent resteth wisdom, and it shall instruct all the ignorant.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Justice exalteth a nation: but sin maketh nations miserable.</verse>
  <verse number="35">A wise servant is acceptable to the king: he that is good for nothing shall feel his anger.</verse>
</chapter>