<chapter book="Proverbs" number="15" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A mild answer breaketh wrath: but a harsh word stirreth up fury.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The tongue of the wise adorneth knowledge: but the mouth of fools bubbleth out folly.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The eyes of the Lord in every place behold the good and the evil.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A peaceable tongue is a tree of life: but that which is immoderate, shall crush the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A fool laugheth at the instruction of his father: but he that regardeth reproofs shall become prudent. In abundant justice there is the greatest strength: but the devices of the wicked shall be rooted out.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The house of the just is very much strength: and in the fruits of the wicked is trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The lips of the wise shall disperse knowledge: the heart of fools shall be unlike.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The victims of the wicked are abominable to the Lord: the vows of the just are acceptable.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The way of the wicked is an abomination to the Lord: he that followeth justice is beloved by him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Instruction is grievous to him that forsaketh the way of life: he that hateth reproof shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Hell and destruction are before the Lord: how much more the hearts of the children of men?</verse>
  <verse number="12">A corrupt man loveth not one that reproveth him: nor will he go to the wise.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A glad heart maketh a cheerful countenance: but by grief of mind the spirit is cast down.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The heart of the wise seeketh instruction: and the mouth of fools feedeth on foolishness.</verse>
  <verse number="15">All the days of the poor are evil: a secure mind is like a continual feast.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Better is a little with the fear of the Lord, than great treasures without content,</verse>
  <verse number="17">It is better to be invited to herbs with love, than to a fatted calf with hatred.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A passionate man stirreth up strifes: he that is patient appeaseth those that are stirred up.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The way of the slothful is as a hedge of thorns; the way of the just is without offence.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A wise son maketh a father joyful: but the foolish man despiseth his mother.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Folly is joy to the fool: and the wise man maketh straight his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Designs are brought to nothing where there is no counsel: but where there are many counsellors, they are established.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A man rejoiceth in the sentence of his mouth: and a word in due time is best.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The path of life is above for the wise, that he may decline from the lowest hell.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The Lord will destroy the house of the proud: and will strengthen the borders of the widow.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Evil thoughts are an abomination to the Lord: and pure words most beautiful shall be confirmed by him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He that is greedy of gain troubleth his own house: but he that hateth bribes shall live. By mercy and faith sins are purged away: and by the fear of the Lord every one declineth from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The mind of the just studieth obedience: the mouth of the wicked over floweth with evils.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The Lord is far from the wicked: and he will hear the prayers of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The light of the eyes rejoiceth the soul: a good name maketh the bones fat.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The ear that heareth the reproofs of life, shall abide in the midst of the wise.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He that rejecteth instruction, despiseth his own soul: but he that yieldeth to reproof possesseth understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The fear of the Lord is the lesson of wisdom: and humility goeth before glory.</verse>
</chapter>