<chapter book="Proverbs" number="2" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if thou wilt receive my words, and wilt hide my commandments with thee,</verse>
  <verse number="2">That thy ear may hearken to wisdom: Incline thy heart to know prudence:</verse>
  <verse number="3">For if thou shalt call for wisdom, and incline thy heart to prudence:</verse>
  <verse number="4">If thou shalt seek her as money, and shalt dig for her as for a treasure:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then shalt thou understand the fear of the Lord, and shalt find the knowledge of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Because the Lord giveth wisdom: and out of his mouth cometh prudence and knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He will keep the salvation of the righteous, and protect them that walk in simplicity.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Keeping the paths of justice, and guarding the ways of saints.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then shalt thou understand justice, and judgment, and equity, and every good path.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If wisdom shall enter into thy heart, and knowledge please thy soul:</verse>
  <verse number="11">Counsel shall keep thee, and prudence shall preserve thee,</verse>
  <verse number="12">That thou mayst be delivered from the evil way, and from the man that speaketh perverse things:</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who leave the right way, and walk by dark ways:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who are glad when they have done evil, and rejoice in most wicked things:</verse>
  <verse number="15">Whose ways are perverse, and their steps infamous.</verse>
  <verse number="16">That thou mayst be delivered from the strange women, and from the stranger, who softeneth her words:</verse>
  <verse number="17">And forsaketh the guide of her youth,</verse>
  <verse number="18">And hath forgotten the covenant of her God: for her house inclineth unto death, and her paths to hell.</verse>
  <verse number="19">None that go in unto her shall return again, neither shall they take hold of the paths of life,</verse>
  <verse number="20">That thou mayst walk in a good way: and mayst keep the paths of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For they that are upright shall dwell in the earth, and the simple shall continue in it.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But the wicked shall be destroyed from the earth: and they that do unjustly shall be taken away from it.</verse>
</chapter>