<chapter book="Proverbs" number="21" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As the divisions of waters, so the heart of the king is in the hand of the Lord: whithersoever he will he shall turn it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Every way of a man seemeth right to himself: but the Lord weigheth the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To do mercy and judgment, pleaseth the Lord more than victims.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Haughtiness of the eyes is the enlarging of the heart: the lamp of the wicked is sin.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the industrious al- ways bring forth abundance: but every sluggard is always in want.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He that gathereth treasures by a lying tongue, is vain and foolish, and shall stumble upon the snares of death.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The robberies of the wicked shall be their downfall, because they would not do judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The perverse way of a man is strange: but as for him that is pure, his work is right.</verse>
  <verse number="9">It is better to sit in a corner of the housetop, than with a brawling women, and in a common house.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The soul of the wicked desireth evil, he will not have pity on his neighbour.</verse>
  <verse number="11">When a pestilent man is punished, the little one will be wiser: and if he follow the wise, he will receive knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The just considereth seriously the house of the wicked, that he may withdraw the wicked from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He that stoppeth his ear against the cry of the poor, shall also cry himself and shall not be heard.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A secret present quencheth anger: and a gift in the bosom the greatest wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It is joy to the just to do judgment: and dread to them that work iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A man that shall wander out of the way of doctrine, shall abide in the company of the giants.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that loveth good cheer, shall be in want: he that loveth wine, and fat things, shall not be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The wicked is delivered up for the just: and the unjust for the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="19">It is better to dwell in a wilderness, than with a quarrelsome and passionate woman.</verse>
  <verse number="20">There is a treasure to be desired, and oil in the dwelling of the just: and the foolish man shall spend it.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that followeth justice and mercy, shall find life, justice, and glory.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The wise man hath scaled the city of the strong, and hath cast down the strength of the confidence thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He that keepeth his mouth and his tongue, keepeth his soul from distress.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The proud and the arrogant is called ignorant, who in anger worketh pride.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Desires kill the slothful: for his hands have refused to work at all.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He longeth and desireth all the day : but he that is just, will give, and will not cease.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sacrifices of the wicked are abominable, because they are offered of wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A lying witness shall perish: an obedient man shall speak of victory.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The wicked man impudently hardeneth his face: but he that is righteous, correcteth his way.</verse>
  <verse number="30">There is no wisdom, there is no prudence, there is no counsel against the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The horse is prepared for the day of battle: but the Lord giveth safety.</verse>
</chapter>