<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if thou be surety for thy friend, thou hast engaged fast thy hand to a stranger.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thou art ensnared with the words of thy mouth, and caught with thy own words.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do therefore, my son, what I say, and deliver thyself: because thou art fallen into the hand of thy neighbour. Run about, make haste, stir up thy friend:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Give not sleep to thy eyes, neither let thy eyelids slumber.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Deliver thyself as a doe from the hand, and as a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go to the ant, O sluggard, and consider her ways, and learn wisdom:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Which, although she hath no guide, nor master, nor captain,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Provideth her meat for herself in the summer, and gathereth her food in the harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">How long wilt thou sleep, O sluggard? when wilt thou rise out of thy sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thou wilt sleep a little, thou wilt slumber a little, thou wilt fold thy hands a little to sleep:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And want shall come upon thee, as a traveller, and poverty as a man armed. But if thou be diligent, thy harvest shall come as a fountain, and want shall flee far from thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A man that is an apostate, an unprofitable man, walketh with a perverse mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="13">He winketh with the eyes, presseth with the foot, speaketh with the finger.</verse>
  <verse number="14">With a wicked heart he deviseth evil, and at all times he soweth discord.</verse>
  <verse number="15">To such a one his destruction shall presently come, and he shall suddenly be destroyed, and shall no longer have any remedy.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Six things there are, which the Lord hateth, and the seventh his soul detesteth:</verse>
  <verse number="17">Haughty eyes, a lying tongue, hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
  <verse number="18">A heart that deviseth wicked plots, feet that are swift to run into mischief,</verse>
  <verse number="19">A deceitful witness that uttereth lies, and him that soweth discord among brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, keep the commandments of thy father, and forsake not the law of thy mother.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Bind them in thy heart continually, and put them about thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="22">When thou walkest, let them go with thee: when thou sleepest, let them keep thee; and when thou awakest, talk with them.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Because the commandment is a lamp, and the law a light, and reproofs of instruction are the way of life:</verse>
  <verse number="24">That they may keep thee from the evil woman, and from the flattering tongue of the stranger.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let not thy heart covet her beauty, be not caught with her winks:</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the price of a harlot is scarce one loaf: but the woman catcheth the precious soul of a man.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Can a man hide fire in his bosom, and his garments not burn?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Or can he walk upon hot coals, and his feet not be burnt?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So he that goeth in to his neighbour’s wife, shall not be clean when he shall touch her.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The fault is not so great when a man hath stolen: for he stealeth to fill his hungry soul:</verse>
  <verse number="31">And if he be taken he shall restore sevenfold, and shall give up all the substance of his house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">But he that is an adulterer, for the folly of his heart shall destroy his own soul:</verse>
  <verse number="33">He gathereth to himself shame and dishonour, and his reproach shall not be blotted out:</verse>
  <verse number="34">Because the jealousy and rage of the husband will not spare in the day of revenge,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Nor will he yield to any man’s prayers, nor will he accept for satisfaction ever so many gifts.</verse>
</chapter>