<chapter book="Ephesians" number="3" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For this cause, I Paul, the prisoner of Jesus Christ, for you Gentiles;</verse>
  <verse number="2">If yet you have heard of the dispensation of the grace of God which is given me towards you:</verse>
  <verse number="3">How that, according to revelation, the mystery has been made known to me, as I have written above in a few words;</verse>
  <verse number="4">As you reading, may understand my knowledge in the mystery of Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Which in other generations was not known to the sons of men, as it is now revealed to his holy apostles and prophets in the Spirit:</verse>
  <verse number="6">That the Gentiles should be fellow heirs, and of the same body, and co-partners of his promise in Christ Jesus, by the gospel:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Of which I am made a minister, according to the gift of the grace of God, which is given to me according to the operation of his power:</verse>
  <verse number="8">To me, the least of all the saints, is given this grace, to preach among the Gentiles, the unsearchable riches of Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="9">And to enlighten all men, that they may see what is the dispensation of the mystery which hath been hidden from eternity in God, who created all things:</verse>
  <verse number="10">That the manifold wisdom of God may be made known to the principalities and powers in heavenly places through the church,</verse>
  <verse number="11">According to the eternal purpose, which he made, in Christ Jesus our Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="12">In whom we have boldness and access with confidence by the faith of him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore I pray you not to faint at my tribulations for you, which is your glory.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For this cause I bow my knees to the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="15">Of whom all paternity in heaven and earth is named,</verse>
  <verse number="16">That he would grant you, according to the riches of his glory, to be strengthened by his Spirit with might unto the inward man,</verse>
  <verse number="17">That Christ may dwell by faith in your hearts; that being rooted and founded in charity,</verse>
  <verse number="18">You may be able to comprehend, with all the saints, what is the breadth, and length, and height, and depth:</verse>
  <verse number="19">To know also the charity of Christ, which surpasseth all knowledge, that you may be filled unto all the fulness of God.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Now to him who is able to do all things more abundantly than we desire or understand, according to the power that worketh in us;</verse>
  <verse number="21">To him be glory in the church, and in Christ Jesus unto all generations, world without end. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>