<chapter book="Job" number="10" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My soul was weary in my life; I shall leave upon me my complaint; I shall speak in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Saying to God, Thou wilt not condemn me; make known to me for what thou wilt contend with me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it good to thee that thou wilt oppress, that thou wilt despise the labor of thy hinds, and thou didst shine upon the counsels of the unjust?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Were eyes of flesh to thee? or wilt thou see as man saw?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Are thy days as man’s days? or thy years as the days of man?</verse>
  <verse number="6">That thou wilt seek for mine iniquity, and wilt search out for my sins?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Upon thy knowledge that I will not do evil; and none delivering from thy hand.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thy hands formed me, and they will work me together round about; and thou wilt swallow me down.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Remember now, thou didst make me as day; and thou wilt turn me back to dust.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Wilt thou not weigh me out as milk, and coagulate me as cheese?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thou wilt clothe me with skin and flesh, and thou wilt hedge me with bones and sinews.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Thou didst with me life and mercy, and thy reviewing watched my spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And these thou didst hide in thy heart: I knew that this is with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If I sinned; and thou didst watch me, and thou wilt not acquit me from mine iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If I did evil, wo to me; and was I just, I shall not lift up my head, being filled with dishonor: and see thou mine affliction;</verse>
  <verse number="16">And shall it be lifted up? Thou wilt hunt me as the lion, and thou wilt turn back, thou wilt show thyself wonderful upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou wilt renew thy testimonies before me, and thou wilt increase thy wrath upon me; changes and war with me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And wherefore didst thou bring Me forth from the belly? I shall expire, and eye shall not see me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I shall be as I was not; I shall be brought from the womb to the grave.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Is it not my days few? He will cease; he will turn from me, and I shall be cheerful a little,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Before I shall go and turn back to the land of darkness and the shadow of death;</verse>
  <verse number="22">A land of darkness, as thick darkness; of the shadow of death, and not orders, and the brightness, as thick darkness.</verse>
</chapter>