<chapter book="Job" number="12" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Verily that ye are the people, and shall wisdom die with you?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Also to me a heart like you; I fall not more than you: and with whom not like these?</verse>
  <verse number="4">I shall be he laughing at his neighbor, calling to God, and he will answer him: the just blameless one being laughed at.</verse>
  <verse number="5">To misfortune is contempt to the thoughts of him at ease, being prepared for the waverings of the foot.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The tents to those oppressing will be secure, and confidence to those provoking God to anger: whom God will bring into his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But ask now the beasts and they shall teach thee; and the birds of the heavens, and they shall announce to thee:</verse>
  <verse number="8">Or speak to the earth and it shall teach thee; and the fishes of the sea shall recount to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who knew not in all these that the hand of God did this?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Which in his hand the soul of all living, and the spirit of all the flesh of man.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Shall not the ear try words? and the palate shall taste food to it?</verse>
  <verse number="12">With old men is wisdom, and length of days, understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="13">With him wisdom and strength, to him counsel and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Behold, he will pull down and it shall not be built up: he will shut up against man and it shall not be opened.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, he will hold back upon the waters, and they will dry up: and he will send them forth and they will overturn the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">With him strength and purpose: to him the one led astray and him leading astray.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Leading away counselors stripped off and he will make foolish the judges.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He loosed the bonds of kings, and he will gird upon their loins a girdle.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Leading away priests stripped off, and he will overthrow the mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Removing the lip to the faithful, and he will take discernment of old men.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Proving contempt upon nobles, and he slackened the girdle of the strong.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Revealing deep things from darkness, and he will bring to light the shadow of death.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Making great to the nations, and he will destroy them: he spread out to the nations, and he will guide them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Taking away the heart of the heads of the people of the earth, and he will cause them to wander in a waste, not a way.</verse>
  <verse number="25">They will feel darkness and not light, and he will cause them to wander as one intoxicated.</verse>
</chapter>