<chapter book="Job" number="13" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Behold all mine eye saw, and mine ear heard, and it will understand for it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">According to your knowledge I knew also: I fall not more than you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">But I will speak to the Almighty; I shall delight to plead before God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And on the contrary, ye devise falsehood; physicians all of you for nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who will give silence? Ye shall be silent, and it shall be to you for wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Hear now my proof, and attend to the pleadings of my lips.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Will ye speak wickedness for God? and will ye speak deceit to him?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Will ye accept his face? will ye contend for God?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Is it good that he shall search you out? or as he mocking against a man; will ye mock against him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Reproving, he will reprove you if in secret ye lift up faces.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Shall not his majesty make you afraid? and his terror fall upon you?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Your remembrances being likened to ashes, your backs to backs of clay.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Be silent from me and I will speak what shall pass upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For what shall I lift up my flesh in my teeth, and shall I put my soul in my hand?</verse>
  <verse number="15">If he shall slay me shall I not hope? only I will prove my ways to his face.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Also he is to me for salvation for a profane one shall not come before him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Hearing, hear ye my words, and my declaration in your ears.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Behold now I set in order judgment; I knew that I shall be justified.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Who is he will contend with me? for now shall I be silent and expire;</verse>
  <verse number="20">Only two things thou wilt not do with me: then I shall not hide from thy face.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Remove thy hand far from me, and thy terror shall not make me afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And call and I will answer, and I shall speak, and turn thou to me.</verse>
  <verse number="23">How many iniquities and sins to me? make known to me my transgression and my sin.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Why wilt thou hide thy face, and reckon me for an enemy to thee?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Wilt thou terrify the scattered leaf? and wilt thou pursue the dry straw?</verse>
  <verse number="26">For thou wilt write bitter things against me; and thou wilt give me to inherit the iniquities of my youth.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And thou wilt set my feet in the stocks, and thou wilt watch all my paths; thou wilt dig round the roots of my feet.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he as rottenness will fall away; as a garment the moth ate it.</verse>
</chapter>