<chapter book="Job" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Eli-Phaz the Temanite will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shall a wise one answer knowledge of wind, and fill his belly with the east wind?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Reproving with words he shall not profit, and speeches will be of no use in them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Also thou wilt bring to nought, fear, and thou wilt withhold meditation before God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For thy mouth will accustom itself to thine iniquity, and thou wilt choose the tongue of the crafty.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thy mouth will condemn thee, and not I: and thy lips will testify against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Shalt thou be the firm man born? and hadst thou a beginning before the hills?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Shalt thou hear in the consultation of God? and wilt thou reserve wisdom to thyself?</verse>
  <verse number="9">What knewest thou and we shall not know? wilt thou understand and it not be with us?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Also the gray headed and old man with us, great of days above thy fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Is it small with thee the consolations of God? and a word covered with thee?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why shall thy heart take thee? and why shall thine eyes wink?</verse>
  <verse number="13">That thou wilt turn thy spirit against God, and thou broughtest words from thy mouth?</verse>
  <verse number="14">What is man that he will be clean? and that he will be just, being born of woman?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, in his holy ones he will, not trust; and the heavens were not clean in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="16">How much more abominable and corrupt is man drinking iniquity as water!</verse>
  <verse number="17">I will show thee, hear to me; and that I saw I will recount;</verse>
  <verse number="18">Which the wise ones will announce, and he hid it not from their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="19">To them alone the earth was given, and a stranger passed not in the midst of them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">All the days the unjust one himself being pained, and numbering the years they were hidden to him terrifying.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The voice of fears in his ears: in peace he destroying shall come upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He will not believe to turn back from darkness, and he was waited for by the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He wandered about for bread, where he knew that the day of darkness was ready at his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Straitness and distress shall terrify him; they shall overpower him as a king ready for war.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For he stretched forth his hand against God, and he will strengthen himself against the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He will run against him upon the neck, upon the thicknesses of his shields:</verse>
  <verse number="27">For he covered his face with his fat, and he will make fatness upon the flank.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he will dwell in cities out off, the houses shall not be inhabited by them, which were ready for heaps.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He shall not be rich, and his wealth shall not rise up; their possession shall not extend upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He shall not depart from darkness; the flame shall dry up his suckers, and by the breath of his mouth shall he depart.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He being deceived shall not trust in vanity: for vanity shall be his compensation.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Before his day it shall be completed, and his branch was not green.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He will shake off as a vine his unripe grapes, and he will cast his flower as the olive.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For the assembly of the profane is hard, and fire consumed the tents of the gift.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He conceiving trouble and he bringing forth vanity, and their belly shall prepare deceit.</verse>
</chapter>