<chapter book="Job" number="16" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">I heard many like there: comforters of vexation ye all.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Was there an end to words of wind? or what will provoke thee that thou wilt answer?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Also I will speak as you: if it is your soul instead of my soul, I will join together with words against you, and shake my head against you upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I will strengthen you with my month, the moving of my lips shall hold back.</verse>
  <verse number="6">If I shall speak, my pain will not be held back, and shall I cease, what will go from me?</verse>
  <verse number="7">But now he made me weary: thou hast made desolate all mine assembly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thou wilt lay fast hold on me to be for a testimony, and my leanness will rise up in me; it will answer against my face.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He rent in his anger, and he will lie in wait for me, gnashing upon me with his teeth; mine enemy will sharpen his eyes against me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They gaped upon me with their mouth; with reproach they struck upon my cheek; they will fill out together against me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">God will shut me up to the evil one, and he will cast me into the hands of the unjust.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I was secure, and he will break me in pieces: and he seized upon my neck and he will disperse me, and he will set me up to him for a mark:</verse>
  <verse number="13">His multitudes will surround upon me, he will cleave my reins asunder, and not spare; he will pour my gall upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He will break me, breaking upon the face of breaking; he will run upon me as the strong one.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I sewed together sackcloth upon my skin, and I thrust my horn into the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My face became red from weeping, and upon my eye-lashes the shadow of death.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Not for violence in my hands: and my prayer is clean.</verse>
  <verse number="18">O earth, thou wilt not cover my blood; and shall there not be place for my cry?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Also now, behold, my witness in the heavens, and my testimony in the heights.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My friends mocking me: to God mine eye wept.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Shall he judge for a man with God? and the son of man for his neighbor?</verse>
  <verse number="22">When years of number shall come, and the way I shall go I shall not turn back.</verse>
</chapter>