<chapter book="Job" number="18" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Bildad the Shuhite will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will ye set an end to words? Ye shall understand, and afterwards we will speak.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Wherefore were we reckoned as cattle, and were unclean in your eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="4">He rent his soul in his anger: shall the earth be forsaken for thee? and shall the rock be removed from its place?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Also the light of the unjust shall be extinguished, and the flame of his fire shall not shine;</verse>
  <verse number="6">The light was darkened in his tent, and his lamp shall be extinguished for him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The steps of his strength shall be straightened, and his counsel shall cast him down.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For he was cast into a net by his feet, and he will go about upon latticework.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A snare shall lay hold upon the heel, the noose shall hold fast upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">His gin being hid in the earth, and his snare upon the beaten path.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Terrors made him afraid round about, and scattered him to his feet.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His strength shall be hunger, and destruction being prepared at his side.</verse>
  <verse number="13">It shall devour the bars of his skin: the first-born of death shall devour his bars.</verse>
  <verse number="14">His confidence shall be plucked out from his tent, and it shall drive him to the king of terrors.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It shall dwell in his tent, from not to him: brimstone shall be scattered upon his dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="16">From underneath, his roots shall be dried up, and from above, his harvest shall be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His remembrance shall perish from the earth, and not a name to him upon a face without.</verse>
  <verse number="18">They shall drive him out of light into darkness, and they shall exclude him from the habitable globe.</verse>
  <verse number="19">No offspring to him, and no progeny among his people, and not a survivor in his dwellings.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Others were astonished at his day, and the ancient took hold on shuddering.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Also these the dwellings of evil, and this the place of him not knowing God.</verse>
</chapter>