<chapter book="Job" number="19" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will ye, grieve my soul, and crush me with words?</verse>
  <verse number="3">These ten times ye will reproach me: ye will not be ashamed, ye will injure me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If indeed I erred my error will lodge with me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">If indeed ye will magnify yourselves against me, and prove against me my reproach:</verse>
  <verse number="6">Know ye now that God subverted me; and he folded his net about me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Behold, I shall cry violence, and shall I not be answered: I shall cry for help, and no judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He walled up my path and I shall not pass, and he will set darkness upon my beaten paths.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he put off from me my honor, and he removed the crown of my head.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He will lay me waste round about, and I shall go: and he will remove my hope as a tree.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he will kindle his anger against me, and he will reckon me to him as his enemy.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His troops shall come together and raise up their way against me, and they will encamp round about to my tent.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He removed my brethren far from me, and mine acquaintance truly turned aside from me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My kindred ceased, and they acquainted with me forgot me.</verse>
  <verse number="15">They sojourning in my house and my maids, mill reckon me for a stranger: I was a foreigner in their eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I called to my servant and he will not answer; I shall entreat him with my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">My spirit was loathsome to my wife, and I entreated to the sons of my belly.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Also children rejected me; I shall arise, and they will speak against me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">All the men of my intimacy will abhor me, and those I loved were turned against me.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My bone cleaved to my skin and to my flesh, and I shall escape with the skin of my teeth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Pity me, pity me, ye my friends, for the hand of God touched upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Why will ye pursue me as God, and will ye not be satisfied from my flesh?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Who will give now, and my words shall be written? who will give and they shall be delineated in a book?</verse>
  <verse number="24">They shall be cut in the rock with a style of iron and lead, forever.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And I knew he redeeming me lived, and at last he shall rise up upon the dust:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And after they destroyed my skin, this, and from my flesh I shall see God:</verse>
  <verse number="27">Which I shall see for myself, and mine eyes beheld, and not a stranger: my reins were finished in my bosom.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For ye shall say, Why shall we pursue after him and the root of the word was found in me?</verse>
  <verse number="29">And fear ye to yourselves, from the face of the sword? for wrath the iniquities of the sword, so that ye shall know there is judgment.</verse>
</chapter>