<chapter book="Job" number="20" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the Naainathite will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">For this my thoughts will turn back, and because of my haste in me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I shall hear the instruction of my shame, and the spirit of my understanding will cause me to answer.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou knewest this from everlasting when man was set upon the earth:</verse>
  <verse number="5">For the rejoicing of the unjust drawing near, and the gladness of the profane even for a moment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">If his elevation shall go up to the heavens, and his head shall reach to the cloud;</verse>
  <verse number="7">As his dung he shall perish forever: they seeing him shall say, Where is he?</verse>
  <verse number="8">As a dream he shall fly away, and they shall not find him: and he shall flee away as the vision of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The eye scanned him and shall not add; and his place shall no more look after him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The weak shall break his sons, and his hands shall turn back his wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="11">His bones were full of his youth, and shall lie down with him in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="12">If evil shall be sweet in his mouth he will cover it under his tongue;</verse>
  <verse number="13">He will spare over it, and forsake it not, and keep it back in the midst of his palate:</verse>
  <verse number="14">His bread in his bowels was turned, the gall of asps in his midst.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He swallowed down riches, and he shall vomit it up, and God shall drive it out of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He shall suck the poison of asps: the viper’s tongue shall kill him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He shall not look upon the streams, the rivers, the torrents of honey and curdled milk.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Turning back the labor, and he shall not swallow down: according to the substance of his exchange and he shall not exult.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For he oppressed, forsaking the poor; he stripped the house and he will not build it up.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For he knew not tranquillity in his belly, in his desire he shall not escape.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Nothing was left to his food; for this his good shall not be stable.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In the fulness of his abundance it shall be pressed to him: every laboring hand shall come to him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He will be for filling his belly, he will send upon him the burning of his anger, and will rain upon him in his eating.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He shall flee from the weapon of iron, the bow of brass shall pierce him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Being drawn it will come forth from the body; and the lightning will go from his bile, and terrors upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">All darkness hid for his secret places: a fire not blown upon shall devour him; and the remaining one shall do evil upon his tent.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The heavens shall uncover his iniquity, and the earth an adversary against him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The increase of his house shall be rolled off; they were poured out in the day of his anger.</verse>
  <verse number="29">This the portion of an unjust man and the lot of his command from God.</verse>
</chapter>