<chapter book="Job" number="21" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hearing, hear ye my speech, and this shall be your consolations.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Suffer me and I will speak; and after my word ye will mock.</verse>
  <verse number="4">I, is my complaint to man? and then wherefore shall not my spirit be shortened?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Look to me and be astonished, and put the hand upon the mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And when I remembered and trembled, and horror took hold of my flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Wherefore shall the unjust live? They grew old, also they were strong in power.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Their seed was established before their face with them, and their offspring before their eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Their houses peace from fear, and the rod of God not upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">His ox passed over and will not be cast away: his heifer will escape and will not be barren.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They will send forth their children as a flock, and their children will leap.</verse>
  <verse number="12">They will lift up with the drum and harp, and they will rejoice at the voice of the pipe.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Their days glided on in good, and in a moment they will lay hold of hades.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they will say to God, Depart from us; and we desired not the knowledge of thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">What the Almighty that we shall serve him? and what shall we be profited if we shall supplicate to him?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, their good not in the hand: the counsel of the unjust was far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">How often the light of the unjust shall be extinguished, and their destruction will come upon them. He will distribute pains in his anger.</verse>
  <verse number="18">They shall be as straw before the wind, and as chaff the storm stole it away.</verse>
  <verse number="19">God will lay up his iniquity for his sons: he will requite to him and be shall know.</verse>
  <verse number="20">His eyes shall see his destruction, and he shall drink from the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For what his delight in his house after him, and the number of? his months were divided out?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Shall he teach knowledge to God? and he will judge those lifted up.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This shall die in the strength of his fulness, altogether tranquil and at rest.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His sides were filled with fat, and the marrow of his bones will, be moistened.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And this will die in the soul of bitterness, and will not eat in good.</verse>
  <verse number="26">They will lie down together upon the dust, and the worm shall cover over them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Behold, I knew your purposes, and the devices ye will shake off against me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For ye will say, Where the house of the noble one; and where the tent of the dwellings of the unjust?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Did ye not ask them passing over the way? and shall ye not know their signs?</verse>
  <verse number="30">For the evil one will be spared for the day of destruction; they shalt be led away to the day of wraths.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Who shall announce his way upon his face? and who shall requite to him that he did?</verse>
  <verse number="32">And he shall be led away to the graves, and shall watch over the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And the clods of the valley were sweet to him, and every man shall draw after him, and before him no number.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And how will ye comfort me in vain, and your answers remained treachery?</verse>
</chapter>