<chapter book="Job" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wherefore were not times hidden from the Almighty? and they knowing him saw not his days.</verse>
  <verse number="2">They will remove the bound; they will strip off the flock, and they will feed.</verse>
  <verse number="3">They will lead away the ass of the orphans, and they will take for pledge, the widow’s ox.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They will turn the needy from the Way: the poor of the earth hid themselves together.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Behold, wild asses in the desert will go forth in their work, seeking for prey: the sterile region bread for him, and for the young.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the field they will harvest his meslin, and they will glean the vintage of the unjust one.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They will cause the naked to lodge without clothing, and no covering in the cold.</verse>
  <verse number="8">They will be wet from the pouring rains of the mountains, and they embraced the rock from no shelter.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They will strip the orphan from the breast, and take a pledge for the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They caused the naked to go without clothing, and from the hungry they took away the sheaf;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Between their walls they will press out oil; they trod their wine-presses, and they will thirst.</verse>
  <verse number="12">From the city men will groan, and the soul of the wounded will cry out: and God will not set folly.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They were among the rebels of light; they knew not his ways, and they dwelt not in his beaten paths.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The murderer will rise by light; he will kill the poor and needy; and in the night he will be as a thief.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the eye of the adulterer watched the twilight, saying, Eye shall not perceive me: and secretly he will set the face.</verse>
  <verse number="16">To break through houses in darkness in the day they shut up for themselves: they knew not light.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the morning altogether to them the shadow of death: if it shall be known, the terrors of the shadow of death.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He is swift upon the face of the waters; their portion will be cursed in the earth: he will not see the way of the vineyards.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Dryness, also heat, will strip the snow waters: hades him sinning.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The womb shall forget him; the worm sucked him; he shall be no more remembered: and iniquity shall be broken as a tree.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He did evil to the barren; she will not bear: and he will not do good to the widow.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he drew the mighty in his power: he will rise up and none shall be sure in living.</verse>
  <verse number="23">It will he given to him for confidence, and he will rest upon: and his eyes upon their ways.</verse>
  <verse number="24">They were lifted up a little while, and they are not, and they were brought low; as all they will be drawn together, and as the head of an ear of grain they shall be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And if not now, who will cause me to lie, and set my words for nought?</verse>
</chapter>