<chapter book="Job" number="27" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will add to take up his parable, and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">God lives, he removed my judgment; and the Almighty embittered my soul;</verse>
  <verse number="3">For all the while my breath is in me, and the spirit of God in my nose;</verse>
  <verse number="4">If my lips shall speak iniquity, and my tongue if it shall murmur deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Far be it to me if I shall justify you: till I expire I will not remove my integrity from me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">My justice I held fast, and I will not let it go: my heart shall not reproach from my days.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Mine enemy shall be as the unjust one, and he rising up against me, as the evil one.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For what the hope of the profane one if he shall plunder? for God shall draw out his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will God hear his cry when straits shall come upon him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">If he will delight himself upon the Almighty? will he call upon God in all time?</verse>
  <verse number="11">I will teach you by the hand of God: what is with the Almighty I will not hide.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Behold, all ye yourselves saw; and wherefore this, will ye breathe out vanity?</verse>
  <verse number="13">This the portion of an unjust man with God, and the inheritance of the terrible they shall take from the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If his sons shall be multiplied, for then the sword: and his offspring shall not be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="15">His surviving one shall be buried in death, and his widows shall not weep.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If he shall heap up silver as the dust, and prepare clothing as clay;</verse>
  <verse number="17">He shall prepare, and the just shall put on, and the innocent shall divide the silver.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He built his house as the moth, and as a booth he watching made.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The rich one shall lie down, and he shall not be gathered: he opened his eyes, and he is not.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Terrors shall hedge him about as waters, the night a tempest stole him away.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The east wind shall lift him up, and he shall go: and it shall sweep him away in storm from his place.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For he shall cast upon him and not spare: fleeing, he will flee from his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="23">It shall be clapped upon him with their hands, and it shall be hissed upon him from his place.</verse>
</chapter>