<chapter book="Job" number="28" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For there is a going forth for silver, and a place for gold they will purify it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Iron shall be taken from the dust, and stone will pour out brass.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He set an end to darkness, and he searched out for all completeness: the stone of darkness and the shadow of death.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The torrent broke out from the sojourner; being forgotten of the foot, they were weak, they wandered from men.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The earth, from it will come forth bread, and under it was turned as fire.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Its stones the place of the sapphire, and dust gold to it.</verse>
  <verse number="7">A beaten path the birds knew not, and the vulture’s eye scanned it not:</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sons of pride trod it not, and the lion passed not by upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He stretched forth his hand upon the flint; he overturned the mountains from the roots.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He cut rivers in the rocks, and his eye saw every precious thing.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He bound the rivers from weeping, and he will bring forth the hidden thing to light.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And from whence shall wisdom be found? and where this place of understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And man knew not its estimation, and it shall not be found in the land of the living.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The depth said, It is not in me: and the sea said, Not with me.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Shut up gold shall not be given for it, and silver shall not be weighed its price.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It shall not be weighed with gold of Ophir, with the precious onyx, and the sapphire.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Gold and crystal shall not compare with it, and its exchange, vessels of pure gold.</verse>
  <verse number="18">High things, and crystal, shall not be remembered: and the drawing out of wisdom above pearls.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The topaz of Cush shall not compare with it; with pure gold it shall not be weighed.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And from whence shall wisdom come? and where this place of understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="21">And being hid from the eyes of all living, and covered from the birds of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Destruction and death said, We heard its report with our ears:</verse>
  <verse number="23">God understood its way, and he knew its place.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For he will look to the ends of the earth, he will see under all the heavens;</verse>
  <verse number="25">To make the weight for the wind; and he weighed the waters by measure.</verse>
  <verse number="26">In his making a law for the rain, and a way for the lightning of the voices.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Then he saw, and he will recount it; he prepared it, and also he searched it out.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he will say to man, Behold, the fear of Jehovah, that is wisdom; and to depart from evil is understanding.</verse>
</chapter>