<chapter book="Job" number="29" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job will add to lift up his parable, and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who will give me as the months of old, as the days God will watch me?</verse>
  <verse number="3">In his causing his light to shine upon my head, before his light I shall go through darkness;</verse>
  <verse number="4">As I was in the days of my ripeness, in the intercourse of God upon my tent;</verse>
  <verse number="5">In the Almighty being yet with me, my youths round about me;</verse>
  <verse number="6">In washing my goings with butter, and the rock will pour out with me streams of oil;</verse>
  <verse number="7">In my going forth to the gate upon the city, in the street I shall prepare my seat.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The young men saw me and hid themselves, and the old men rose up and stood.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Chiefs held back in words, and they will put the hand to the mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The voice the leaders hid, and their tongue was joined to their palate.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If the ear heard, and it will pronounce me happy; and the eye saw, and it will testify to me:</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I shall deliver the poor crying, and the orphan, and none helping to him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The praise of him perishing will come upon me, and I shall cause the heart of the widow to rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I put on justice and it will clothe me: my judgment as an upper garment and a turban.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Eyes was I to the blind one, and feet to the lame was I.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I was a father to the needy, and the contention I knew not I shall search it out.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I shall break the biter’s teeth of the evil one, and I shall cast the prey from his teeth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And saying, I shall expire with my nest I shall multiply days as the sand.</verse>
  <verse number="19">My root opened to the waters, and the dew will lodge upon my foliage.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My glory new with me, and my bow will be changed in my hand.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To me they heard, and they waited, and they will be silent for them at my counsel.</verse>
  <verse number="22">After my words they will not repeat, and my speech will drop upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And they waited for me as the rain, and they opened wide their mouth for the latter rain.</verse>
  <verse number="24">I shall laugh at them, they will not believe; and the light of my face they will not cast down.</verse>
  <verse number="25">I shall choose their way, and I shall sit the head, and I shall dwell as king in the troop, as he shall comfort those mourning.</verse>
</chapter>