<chapter book="Job" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After this Job opened his mouth, and he will curse his day.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Job will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="3">The day shall perish I shall bring forth in it, and the night said, A male was conceived.</verse>
  <verse number="4">That day shall be darkness; God shall not search it out from above, and the light shall not shine upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Darkness shall pollute it, and the shadow of death; a cloud shall dwell upon it; the obscurations of day shall terrify it.</verse>
  <verse number="6">That night darkness shall take it; it shall not be joined upon the days of the year; it shall not come into the number of months.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Behold, that night shall be hard; no rejoicing shall be in it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">They cursing the day shall curse it, they being ready to rouse up the sea monster.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The stars of its twilight shall he dark; it shall wait for light, and none; and it shall not look upon the eyelashes of the dawn.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Because it shut not up the doors of my belly; and shall it hide the labor of mine eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wherefore shall I not die from the womb? and I came forth from the belly, and I shall expire.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why did the knees anticipate me? and wherefore the breasts that I shall suck?</verse>
  <verse number="13">For now I lay down and I shall rest; I slept: then there will be rest to me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">With kings and counselors of the earth building the wastes for themselves;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Or with chiefs, gold to them, filling their houses with silver:</verse>
  <verse number="16">Or as a hidden abortion I shall not be; as children they saw not light.</verse>
  <verse number="17">There the unjust ceased to be angry, and the weary in strength shall rest.</verse>
  <verse number="18">They being bound, rested together; they heard not the voice of the taskmaster.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The little and the great, he is there; and the servant being free from his lord.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wherefore shall light be given to him toiling, and life to the bitter of soul?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Waiting for death, and it is not; and they will dig more than for hidden treasures;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Rejoicing with joy when they find the grave;</verse>
  <verse number="23">To a man whose way was hid, and God will hedge about him?</verse>
  <verse number="24">For my sighing will come before any bread, and my groanings shall be poured put as waters.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For I feared a fear, and it will come upon me, and what I was afraid of will come to me.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I was not secure, and I rested not, and I was not quiet; and trouble will come.</verse>
</chapter>