<chapter book="Job" number="30" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And now the younger than I laughed upon me, which I rejected their fathers to set with the dogs of my flock.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Also the strength of their hands wherefore to me? Upon them old age perished.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In want and in hunger, barren, gnawing the dry land, yesternight desolation and burning.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Plucking off sea purslain upon the shrub, the root of broom their bread.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They shall be driven forth from the midst, they shall cry after them as a thief:</verse>
  <verse number="6">To dwell in the horror of the valleys, holes of the dust, and the rocks.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Between the shrubs they will bray; they will be poured out under the thorn bush.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sons of the foolish one, also the sons of no name: they were beaten from the land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And now I was their song, and I to them for a by word.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They abhorred me, they removed far from me, and withheld not spittle from my face.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Because he loosed his cord and he will afflict me, and they cast off the bridle from before me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Upon the right the brood will rise up; they cast away my feet, and they will cast up the paths of their destruction against me.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They tore up my beaten path, they helped for my fall, no help to them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They will come as a wide breach under a destroying tempest, they rolled themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Terror turned upon me, it will pursue my willingness as the wind, and my salvation passed away as a cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And now my soul shall be poured out upon me; and the days of affliction will hold me fast.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The night my bones pierced from above me, and my gnawers will not lie down.</verse>
  <verse number="18">By the multitude of power my clothing will be disguised: it will gird me about as the mouth of my coat.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He cast me to the clay; I shall become like as dust and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I shall cry to thee and thou wilt not answer me: I stood up and thou wilt not attend to me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Thou wilt turn to be cruel to me: with the strength of thy hand thou wilt lie in wait for me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Thou wilt lift me up to the wind; thou wilt cause me to ride, and thou wilt melt to me counsel.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For I knew thou wilt turn me back to death, and the house appointed to all living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But prayer is nothing; he will send forth the hand, if in his calamity to them a cry for help.</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I wept not for him being hard of day: my soul was grieved for the needy.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For I hoped for good and evil will come: and I shall wait for light and darkness will come.</verse>
  <verse number="27">My bowels boiled, and were not silent: the days of affliction anticipated me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I went darkened without warmth: I rose up, I shall cry in the convocation.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I was a brother to jackals, and a companion to the daughters of the ostrich.</verse>
  <verse number="30">My skin was black from above me, and my bones burnt from heat.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And my harp will be for mourning, and my pipe for the voice of those weeping.</verse>
</chapter>