<chapter book="Job" number="31" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I cut out a covenant for mine eyes; and why shall I show myself attentive to a virgin?</verse>
  <verse number="2">And what the portion of God from above? and the inheritance of the Almighty from the heights?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is not destruction to the evil one? and strangeness to those working iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will he not see my way, and number all my steps?</verse>
  <verse number="5">If I went with vanity, and my foot will haste upon deceit;</verse>
  <verse number="6">He shall weigh me in balances of justice, and God will know mine integrity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">If my going will incline from the way, and my heart went after mine eyes, and a blemish did cleave upon my hands:</verse>
  <verse number="8">I will sow and another shall eat; and my offspring shall be rooted up.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If my heart was seduced by woman, and I laid wait at the door of my neighbor;</verse>
  <verse number="10">My wife shall grind for another, and others shall bow down upon her.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For this is crime, and this is iniquity for the judges.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is a fire; it will devour even to destruction, and will root out upon all mine increase.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I shall despise the judgment of my servant and my maid in their contending with me;</verse>
  <verse number="14">And what shall I do when God shall rise up? And when he shall review, what shall I turn back to him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Did not he making me in the womb, make him? And he will prepare us in one belly.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If I shall withhold from the desire of the poor, and cause the eyes of the widow to fail;</verse>
  <verse number="17">And eating my morsel alone, and the orphan ate not from it;</verse>
  <verse number="18">(For from my youth he grew up to me as a father, and I shall guide her from my mother’s womb;)</verse>
  <verse number="19">If I shall see one perishing from not being clothed, and no covering to the needy;</verse>
  <verse number="20">If his loins did not praise me, and he will be warmed from the fleece of my sheep.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If I lifted up my hand against the orphan when I shall see, my help in the gate:</verse>
  <verse number="22">My shoulder shall fall from its shoulder-blade, and mine, arm shall be broken from the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the destruction of God is a terror to me, and from his lifting up I shall not prevail.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If I set gold my hope, and said to gold, My trust;</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I shall rejoice because of the Multitude of my riches, and because my hand found much;</verse>
  <verse number="26">If I shall see the light when it shall shine, and the moon going in splendor;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And my heart will be seduced in secret, and my hand shall kiss to my mouth:</verse>
  <verse number="28">Also this an iniquity for the judges: for I lied to God from above.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If I shall rejoice in the destruction of him hating me, and I exalted when evil found him:</verse>
  <verse number="30">And I gave not my palate to sin to ask in cursing his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If the men of my tent said not, Who will give from his flesh? We shall not be satisfied.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The stranger shall not lodge without: I shall open my doors to the traveler.</verse>
  <verse number="33">If I covered my transgression, as man, to hide mine iniquity in my bosom:</verse>
  <verse number="34">If I, shall fear a great multitude, and the contempt of families terrify me, and I will be silent and not go out of my door.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Who will give to me hearing to me? Behold, my sign, the Almighty will answer me, and the man contending with me wrote a book.</verse>
  <verse number="36">If not, I shall lift it up upon my shoulder, I will bind it a crown to me.</verse>
  <verse number="37">The number of my steps I shall announce to him: as a leader I shall draw near to him.</verse>
  <verse number="38">If my land shall cry against me, and its, furrows shall weep together;</verse>
  <verse number="39">If I ate its strength without silver, and caused its possessors to expire:</verse>
  <verse number="40">The thorn shall come forth, instead of wheat, and the weed instead of barley. The words of Job were completed.</verse>
</chapter>