<chapter book="Job" number="32" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these three men will cease from answering Job, for he is just in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the anger of Elihu will kindle, son of Barachel the Buzite, from the family of Ram: against Job was, his anger kindled, for his justifying his soul above God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And against his three friends was his anger kindled, because they, found not an answer, and they will condemn Job.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Elihu waited for Job in words, for they were old for days above him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Elihu will see that not an Answer in the mouth of the three men, and his anger will kindle,</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Elihu, the son of Barachel the Buzite will answer and say, I few for days, and ye old men; for this I was afraid, and I shall fear showing you my knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I said, days shall speak, and multitude of years shall make known wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But it is a spirit in man, and the breath of the Almighty will cause them to understand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Not the many will be wise: and old men understand judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this, I said, Hear to me; I also will show my knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Behold, I waited for your words, giving ear even to your understandings while ye will search out words.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I will show myself attentive even to you, and behold, none from you confuting to Job, answering his words.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Lest ye shall say, We found wisdom: God will thrust him, not man.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he arranged not words against me: and I will not turn back to him with your words.</verse>
  <verse number="15">They were confounded; they answered no more: they removed words from themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And I waited, (for they will not speak, for they stood, they answered no more:)</verse>
  <verse number="17">I also will answer my part, I also will show my knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For I was filled with words, the spirit of my belly pressed upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold, my belly as wine it will not open; it will break open as new wine skins.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I will speak, and it will breathe to me: I will open my lips and answer.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Not now shall I lift up the face of man, and I shall not flatter to man.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For I knew not, shall I flatter; for a little while, he making me will take me away.</verse>
</chapter>