<chapter book="Job" number="33" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And yet hear now, O Job, my speech, and give ear to all my words.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Behold, now, I opened my mouth, my tongue spake in my palate.</verse>
  <verse number="3">My sayings the uprightness of my heart, and my lips spake knowledge purely.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The spirit of God made me, and the breath of the Almighty will cause me to live.</verse>
  <verse number="5">If thou shalt be able to turn back to me, set in order before me, stand forth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Behold, I am according to thy mouth for God: from clay was I also broken off.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Behold, my terror shall not make thee afraid, and my hand shall not be heavy upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Surely thou spakest in mine ear and I will hear the voice of thy words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">I am clean without transgression; I am fair, and no iniquity to me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Behold, he will find enmity against me, and he will reckon me for an enemy to him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He will set my feet in the stocks, he will watch all my paths.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Behold, this thou wert not just: I will answer thee, for God will be great above man.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore didst thou contend against him? for he will not answer all his words.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For God will speak at once, and at a second time, and he shall not regard it.</verse>
  <verse number="15">In a dream, in a vision of the night, in the falling of deep sleep upon men, in slumbers upon the bed;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then he will uncover the ear of men, and will seal in their instruction,</verse>
  <verse number="17">To remove man from working, and he will bide pride from man.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He will keep back his soul from the pit, and his life from passing away by the spear.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he was chastened with pain upon his bed, and the multitude of his bones perpetually.</verse>
  <verse number="20">His life loathed bread, and his soul food of desire.</verse>
  <verse number="21">His flesh will consume away from seeing, and they saw not the nakedness of his bones.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And his soul will draw near to the pit, and his life to the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If there is a messenger upon him, an interpreter, one from a thousand, to announce to man his uprightness:</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he will compassionate him and say, Deliver him from going down to the pit: I found an expiation.</verse>
  <verse number="25">His flesh revived above a youth: he shall turn back to the days of his childhood.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He shall pray to God and he shall receive him into favor: and he shall see his face with rejoicing, and he will turn back to man his justice.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He will look upon men, and he shall say, I sinned, and I perverted the right, and it was not fitting to me;</verse>
  <verse number="28">Redeem my soul from passing into the pit, and my life shall look upon light.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Behold, all these God will work twice, thrice, with man,</verse>
  <verse number="30">To turn back his soul from the pit, to enlighten with the light of the living.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Attend, O Job, hear to me: be silent and I will speak.</verse>
  <verse number="32">If there be words, turn back to me: speak, for I desired to justify thee.</verse>
  <verse number="33">If not, hear thou to me: be silent, and I shall teach thee wisdom.</verse>
</chapter>