<chapter book="Job" number="34" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Elihu will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear, ye wise, my words; and ye knowing, give ear to me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the ear will try words, and the palate will taste of food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">We will choose to us judgment: we shall know between ourselves what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For Job said, I was just: and God removed my judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Shall I speak falsehood against my judgment? mine arrow was desperate without transgression.</verse>
  <verse number="7">What man as Job he will drink scoffing as water?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Going for company with those working iniquity, and to go with men of injustice?</verse>
  <verse number="9">For he said, It will not profit a man in delighting himself with God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this, ye men of heart, hear to me: far be it to God from doing evil; and the Almighty from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the work of man shall he recompense to him, and a man shall find himself according to his way.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Also surely God will not do evil, and the Almighty will not pervert judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who committed to him the earth? and who set up the habitable globe all of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">If he will set his heart to him, he will gather his spirit and his breath to him;</verse>
  <verse number="15">All flesh shall expire together, and man shall turn back to dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If now understanding, hear this: give ear to the voice of my words.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Also shall he hating judgment, rule? and if thou wilt condemn the just mighty one?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Saying to the king, Wickedness; (Belial) to nobles, Injustice.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Who accepted not the face of chiefs, and looked not upon the rich one before the poor: for his hand made all of them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In a moment shall they die, and the middle of the night shall the people be moved and pass away: and the mighty shall be removed with not a hand.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For his eyes are upon the ways of man, and he will see all his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Not darkness and not the shadow of death for those working iniquity to hide there.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For he will not yet set upon man to go to God in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He shall break in pieces the mighty, not searching out, and he will set others in their stead.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For this he will know their work, and he turned the night, and they will be crushed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He struck them for the unjust in the place of those seeing;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Who therefore turned away from after him, and they consider not all his ways,</verse>
  <verse number="28">To cause the cry of the poor one to come to him, and he will hear the cry of the humble.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And he will give quiet, and who shall disturb? and he will hide the face, and who shall look upon him? and against a nation and against man wholly:</verse>
  <verse number="30">From the reigning of the profane man from the people being snared.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For he said to God, I was lifted up, I will pervert no more.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Besides I shall see thou wilt teach it to me: if I did iniquity, I will not add.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Is it with thee? he will requite it, if thou didst refuse, if thou shalt choose, and not I: and what thou knewest, speak.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Men of heart will say to me, and a wise man heard to me.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Job will speak not with knowledge, and his word not with understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="36">My father, Job shall be tried even to the end, for turning back with men of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="37">He will add rebellion to his sin; he will clap between us, and he will multiply his words to God.</verse>
</chapter>