<chapter book="Job" number="36" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Elihu will add and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Wait for me a little, and I will show thee, for yet words for God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I will lift up my knowledge from far off, and to him making me, I will give justice.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For truly my words are not falsehood: the perfect of knowledge with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Behold, God is mighty, and he will not despise: mighty in strength of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He will not save alive the unjust one, and he will give the judgment of the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He will not take off his eyes from the just: and with kings upon the throne, and he will seat them for glory, and they shall be exalted.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they being bound in fetters shall be taken in the cords of affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he will announce to them their work, and their transgressions, for they will be strong.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And he will uncover their ear for instruction, and he will say that they shall turn back from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they will hear and will serve him, they shall finish their days in good, and their years in delights.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if they will not hear, they shall pass away by the spear, and they shall expire without knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the profane of heart shall set up anger: they will not cry if he bound them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Their soul will die in youth, and their life among the consecrated.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He will deliver the poor one in his affliction, and he will uncover their ear in oppression.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And also he moved thee from the mouth of the enemy to a broad, not straight place; and thy table came down full of fatness.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And thou didst fill up the judgment of the unjust one; judgment and right shall hold together.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Because of wrath, lest he shall remove thee with smiting, and a multitude of covering shall not turn thee away.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Will he value thy riches? not gold and all the powers of thy strength.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Thou shalt not pant after the night, for taking up peoples in their place.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Watch thyself; thou shalt not turn to iniquity: for upon this thou didst choose rather than affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Behold, God will exalt by his power: who teaches like him?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Who charged upon him his way? and who said, Thou didst iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Remember that thou shalt magnify his work which men beheld.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Every man looked upon it; man shall see from far off.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Behold, God is great, and we shall not know the number of his years, and it was not searched out.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For he will withhold the drops of water: they will pour out rain for its vapor.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Which the clouds will shake out; they will drop an abundance upon man.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Also if he shall understand the spreadings of the cloud, the noise of his booth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Behold, he spread upon it his light, and he covered the roots of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For by them he will judge the peoples; he will give food to abundance.</verse>
  <verse number="32">With the hands be covered the light; and he commanded concerning it with a mark.</verse>
  <verse number="33">His thunder will announce concerning him, and the flock also concerning the going up.</verse>
</chapter>