<chapter book="Job" number="38" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will answer Job from the whirlwind, and he will say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who this darkening counsel in words without knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Gird now thy loins as a man; and I will ask thee, and make thou known to me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where wert thou in my founding the earth? Announce, if thou knewest understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who set its measures, if thou shalt know? or who stretched the line upon it?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Upon what were its bases impressed? or who placed its corner-stone?</verse>
  <verse number="7">In the rejoicing together of the stars of morning, and all the sons of God will shout for joy?</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he will hedge in the sea with doors in its breaking forth, going forth from the womb.</verse>
  <verse number="9">In my making the cloud its garment, and darkness its bandage:</verse>
  <verse number="10">And I shall break upon it my law, and I shall set bars and doors;</verse>
  <verse number="11">And saying, Even to this shalt thou come, and thou shalt not add: and here in the pride of thy waves, stand thou.</verse>
  <verse number="12">In thy days didst thou command the morning? and didst thou make the dawning know its place?</verse>
  <verse number="13">To take hold upon the wings of the earth, and the unjust shall be shaken out of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">It shall be turned as clay to the seal; and they shall stand as clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And their light shall be withheld from the unjust, and the high arm shall be broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Didst thou go even to the fountains of the sea? and didst thou go about in searching the depth?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Were the gates of death uncovered to thee? and shalt thou see the gates of the shadow of death?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Wilt thou consider even to the breadth of the earth? Announce if thou knewest all of it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Where the way light shall dwell? and darkness, where its place?</verse>
  <verse number="20">That thou shalt take it to its bound, and that thou shalt understand the beaten paths of its house?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Knewest thou? for shalt thou then be born, and the number of thy days great?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Didst thou come into the treasures of snow? and shalt thou see the treasures of hail,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Which I kept back for the time of straits, for the day of encounter and war?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Where that way the light will divide, it will scatter the east wind upon the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who divided a channel for the overflowing, and a way for the lightning of the voices?</verse>
  <verse number="26">To cause it to rain upon the earth, not a man; the wilderness not a man in it?</verse>
  <verse number="27">To satisfy the desolation and burning, and to cause the springing up of the finding of the tender grass?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Is there a father to the rain? or who begat the reservoirs of the dew?</verse>
  <verse number="29">From whose womb came forth the ice? and the hoarfrost of the heavens, who brought it forth?</verse>
  <verse number="30">The waters shall be hid as a stone, and the face of the depth will be taken.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Wilt thou bind the bands of the cluster, or wilt thou open the cords of Orion?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Wilt thou bring forth the twelve signs in its time? and the great bear and his sons, wilt thou guide them?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Knewest thou the laws of the heavens? or wilt thou set up its dominion in the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Wilt thou lift up thy voice to the cloud, and abundance of waters shall cover thee?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Shalt thou send lightnings, and shall they go and shall they say to thee, Behold us?</verse>
  <verse number="36">Who put wisdom in the reins? or who gave understanding to the mind?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who shall number the clouds in wisdom? and who shall cause the bottles of heaven to lie down?</verse>
  <verse number="38">In the pouring out of the dust into a melted mass, and the clods will adhere.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Wilt thou hunt the prey for the lion? and wilt thou fill up the life of the young lions?</verse>
  <verse number="40">For they will sink down in the dwellings; they will dwell in the thicket to lie in wait.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Who will prepare for the raven his food? for his young will cry to God; they will wander without food.</verse>
</chapter>