<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Knewest thou the time of the bringing forth of the wild goats of the rock? and wilt thou watch the bearing of the hinds?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Wilt thou number the months they shall fill up? and didst thou know the time of their bringing forth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">They will bow, they will bring forth their children, they will cast forth their pains.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Their sons will be fat, they will increase with grain; they will go forth and not turn back to them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who sent the wild ass free? and who opened the bonds of the wild ass?</verse>
  <verse number="6">To whom did I set the desert his house, and the salt land his dwellings?</verse>
  <verse number="7">He will laugh at the multitude of the city; he will not hear the noise of him driving.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The searching out of the mountains his pasture, and he will seek after every green thing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will the buffalo be willing to serve thee, or will he lodge by thy stall?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Wilt thou bind the buffalo in the furrow with cords, or will he harrow the valleys after thee?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wilt thou trust in him because great his strength? and wilt thou leave to him thy labor?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wilt thou believe in him that he will turn back thy seed and gather to thy threshing-floor?</verse>
  <verse number="13">The wings of ostriches exulted; and the wing-feather of the stork and the pinion.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For she will leave her eggs to the earth, and she will warm them in the dust;</verse>
  <verse number="15">And she will forget that the foot will press it, and the beast of the field will crush it.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She made hard to her sons as not to her: her labor in vain without fear;</verse>
  <verse number="17">For God caused her to forget wisdom, and he divided not to her in understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the time she will lash herself up upon height, she will laugh at the horse and at his rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wilt thou give strength to the horse? wilt thou clothe his neck with thunder?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wilt thou cause him to tremble as the locust? the glory of his snorting is terror.</verse>
  <verse number="21">They will dig in the valley, and he will rejoice in strength: he will go forth to the meeting of the weapon.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He will laugh at fear, and he will not be dismayed; and he will not turn back from the face of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The quiver will give forth a whizzing against him, the flame of the spear and the javelin.</verse>
  <verse number="24">With leaping and rage he will swallow the earth; and he will not believe that it is the voice of the trumpet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He will say according to the multitude of the trumpet, Aha! and he will smell the battle from far off, the thunder of the chiefs, and the war cry.</verse>
  <verse number="26">From thy understanding will the hawk mount upwards? will it stretch its wings to the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">If at thy mouth the eagle will lift itself up, and if it will raise up its nest?</verse>
  <verse number="28">She will dwell in the rock, and she will lodge upon the cliff of the rock and the fortress.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From thence it sought food; far off shall its eyes behold.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Her young shall suck up the blood: and where the wounded, there is she.</verse>
</chapter>