<chapter book="Job" number="41" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wilt thou draw out the crocodile with a hook and with a cord wilt thou press down his tongue?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Wilt thou put a rope in his nose? and wilt thou hollow out his jaw with a thorn?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Will he multiply supplications to thee? will he speak soft things to thee?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will he cut out a covenant with thee? wilt thou take him for a servant forever?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Wilt thou play with him as a bird? and wilt thou bind him for thy maidens?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Shall companions give a feast upon him? shall they divide him between the Canaanites?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Wilt thou fill his skin with pointed weapons? and his head with fish spears?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Put thy hand upon him; remember the battle, thou shalt not add.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Behold, his hope was false: shall he not be cast down at his sight?</verse>
  <verse number="10">None fierce that he will rouse him up: and who is he will stand before me?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Who anticipated me, and I will recompense? under all the heavens it is to me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I will not be silent for him, and the word of powers and the beauty of his preparation.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who uncovered the face of his clothing? who shall come with his double bridle?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who opened the doors of his face? his teeth a terror round about.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Pride of strong shields shut up with a seal of straitness.</verse>
  <verse number="16">One shall touch upon another, and the wind shall not come between them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">They will adhere each in his brotherhood, they will hold together, and they will not be separated.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His sneezings a light will shine, and his eyes as the eyelashes of the dawning of day.</verse>
  <verse number="19">From his mouth flaming torches shall go forth; sparks of fire will escape.</verse>
  <verse number="20">From his nostrils smoke will come forth as a blown pot, and a caldron.</verse>
  <verse number="21">His soul will kindle coals, and a flame will go forth from his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In his neck will lodge strength, and terror will leap before him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The flaps of his flesh adhered: it will press upon him; it will not be moved.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His heart will press as a stone; and it will press as the under millstone.</verse>
  <verse number="25">His lifting up, the mighty will be stirred up: from breaking they shall purify themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sword reaching him, shall not be raised up: the spear, the dart, and the coat of mail.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He will reckon iron for straw, and brass for wood of rottenness.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The son of the bow shall not cause him to flee: sling-stones were turned to him for stubble.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The bludgeon was reckoned to him for stubble: and he will laugh at the shaking of the javelin.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Sharpnesses of the potsherd under him: he will spread a trench upon the mire.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He will cause the deep to boil as a pot: he will set the sea as ointment.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He will cause a beaten path to shine after him: the deep will be reckoned to be hoary.</verse>
  <verse number="33">None upon the dust being like him; he made him without fear.</verse>
  <verse number="34">He will see every thing high: he is king over all the sons of pride.</verse>
</chapter>