<chapter book="Job" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Bildad the Shuhite will answer and say,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long wilt thou speak these things? and the great spirit of the words of thy mouth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Will God pervert judgment? and if the Almighty will pervert justice?</verse>
  <verse number="4">If thy sons sinned to him, and he will send them away by the hand of their transgression;</verse>
  <verse number="5">If thou shalt seek to God, if thou shalt make supplication to him;</verse>
  <verse number="6">If thou wert pure and upright, for now he will awake for thee and requite the habitation of thy justice.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And thy beginning was small, and thy latter state shall increase greatly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For ask now to the first generation, and prepare to seek their fathers:</verse>
  <verse number="9">(For yesterday are we and we shall not know, for our days upon earth are a shadow:)</verse>
  <verse number="10">Shall they not teach thee, and say to thee, and bring forth words from their heart?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Shall the bulrush lift itself up without a marsh? shall the marsh grass grow without water?</verse>
  <verse number="12">While yet in its greenness it shall not break off, and it will dry up before grass.</verse>
  <verse number="13">So the paths of all forgetting God and the hope of the profane one shall perish.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Which his hope shall be cut off, and the spider’s house his trust.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He shall lean upon his house and it shall not stand: he shall hold fast upon it, and it shall not rise up.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It was moist before the sun, and its sprout will come forth upon his garden.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His roots were entwined upon a heap, he shall see a house of stones.</verse>
  <verse number="18">If he should swallow him down from his place, and it lied upon it: I saw thee not.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold, this the rejoicing of his way, and from the dust shall they cause another to grow.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Behold, God will not reject the blameless one, and he will not take hold upon the hand of those doing evil:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Till he shall fill thy mouth with laughing, and thy lips with shouts of joy.</verse>
  <verse number="22">They hating thee shall put on shame; and the tent of the unjust shall not be.</verse>
</chapter>