<chapter book="Galatians" number="1" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, an Apostle sent not from men nor by any man, but by Jesus Christ and by God the Father, who raised Jesus from among the dead—</verse>
  <verse number="2">and all the brethren who are with me: To the Churches of Galatia.</verse>
  <verse number="3">May grace and peace be granted to you from God the Father, and from our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="4">who gave Himself to suffer for our sins in order to rescue us from the present wicked age in accordance with the will of our God and Father.</verse>
  <verse number="5">To Him be the glory to the Ages of the Ages! Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I marvel that you are so readily leaving Him who called you by the grace of Christ, and are adhering to a different Good News.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For other “Good News” there is none; but there are some persons who are troubling you, and are seeking to distort the Good News concerning Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But if even we or an angel from Heaven should bring you a Good News different from that which we have already brought you, let him be accursed.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What I have just said I repeat—if any one is preaching to you a Good News other than that which you originally received, let him be accursed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For is it man’s favour or God’s that I aspire to? Or am I seeking to please men? If I were still a man-pleaser, I should not be Christ’s bondservant.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For I must tell you, brethren, that the Good News which was proclaimed by me is not such as man approves of.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For, in fact, it was not from man that I received or learnt it, but by a revelation from Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For you have heard of my early career in Judaism—how I furiously persecuted the Church of God, and made havoc of it;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and how in devotion to Judaism I outstripped many men of my own age among my people, being far more zealous than they on behalf of the traditions of my forefathers.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But when He who set me apart even from my birth, and called me by His grace,</verse>
  <verse number="16">saw fit to reveal His Son within me in order that I might tell among the Gentiles the Good News concerning Him, at once I did not confer with any human being,</verse>
  <verse number="17">nor did I go up to Jerusalem to those who were my seniors in the Apostleship, but I went away into Arabia, and afterwards came back to Damascus.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then, three years later, I went up to Jerusalem to inquire for Peter, and I spent a fortnight with him.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I saw none of the other Apostles, except James, the Lord’s brother.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In making these assertions I am speaking the truth, as in the sight of God.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Afterwards I visited Syria and Cilicia.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But to the Christian Churches in Judaea I was personally unknown.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They only heard it said, “He who was once our persecutor is now telling the Good News of the faith of which he formerly made havoc.”</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they gave glory to God on my account.</verse>
</chapter>