<chapter book="Galatians" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, sent, (not from men, neither by man, but by Jesus Christ, and God the Father, having raised him from the dead;)</verse>
  <verse number="2">And with me all the brethren, to the churches of Galatia:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Grace to you and peace from God the Father, and our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Having given himself for our sins, that he might take us away out of this present evil time, according to the will of God and our Father:</verse>
  <verse number="5">To whom the glory for the time of times. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I wonder that so quickly are ye transferred from him having called you by the grace of Christ to another good news:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Which is not another; except some are troubling you, and wishing to pervert the good news of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But also if we, or a messenger from heaven, announce good news to you, more than what: we have announced to you, let him be anathema.</verse>
  <verse number="9">As we said before, also now say I again, If any announce to you good news above what ye received, let him be anathema.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For now do I persuade men, or God? or seek I to please men? for if I had yet pleased men, I should not have been the servant of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But I make known to you, brethren, the good news announced by me that it is not according to man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I neither received it from man, neither was I taught, but by the revelation of Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For ye heard of my turning about when in Judaism, that in excess I drove out the church of God, and laid it waste:</verse>
  <verse number="14">And I advanced in Judaism above many like in my race, being more abundantly zealous of paternal traditions.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And when God was contented, having separated me from my mother’s womb, and having called me, by his grace,</verse>
  <verse number="16">To reveal his Son in me, that I might announce him the good news in the nations; I consulted not with flesh and blood:</verse>
  <verse number="17">Neither went I up to Jerusalem to them sent before me; but I went away to Arabia, and again returned to Damascus.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then after three years I came up to Jerusalem to examine Peter, and remained with him fifteen days.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And other of the sect I saw not, except James the Lord’s brother.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And what I write to you, behold, before God, that I lie not.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Then came I to the regions of Syria and Cilicia;</verse>
  <verse number="22">And was unknown by face to the churches of Judea there in Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And only they had heard, That he then driving us out, now announces the good news, the faith which he then felt the absence of.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they glorified God in me.</verse>
</chapter>