<chapter book="Galatians" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Therefore in the liberty which Christ has freed us, stand ye, and be not again held in the yoke of servitude.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Behold, I Paul say to you, that if ye be circumcised, Christ shall profit you nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And again to any man circumcised, I testify, that he is debtor to do the whole law.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Ye were neglected from Christ, whoever are justified in the law; ye have fallen from grace.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For we in spirit by faith expect the hope of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For in Christ Jesus neither circumcision has any power, nor uncircumcision; but faith being energetic through love.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ye were running well; who hindered you not to obey the truth?</verse>
  <verse number="8">The confidence not from him calling you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A little leaven leavens the whole mixture.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I have trusted to you in the Lord, that ye will have nothing different in mind; and he troubling you shall bear judgment, whoever he be.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I, brethren, if I yet proclaim circumcision, why am I. yet driven out? therefore the offence of the cross is left unemployed.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I would also they shall be cut off who having risen up against you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For ye were called to liberty brethren; only not liberty for an occasion to the flesh, but through love serve ye one another.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For all the law is completed in one word, in this; Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And if ye bite and devour one another, see ye that ye be not laid waste by one another.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And I say, Walk in Spirit, and complete not the desire of the flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the flesh desires against the Spirit, and the Spirit against the flesh: and these are adverse to one another: that not the things ye would, these should ye do.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And if ye are led by the Spirit, ye are not under the law.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the works of the flesh are manifest, which are; Adultery, fornication, uncleanness, licentiousness,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Idolatry, charm, enmities, strifes, jealousies, wraths, intriguings, seditions, sects.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Envyings, slaughters, drunkenness, revelries, and the like: to these which I foretell you, as I have also said before, that they doing such shall not inherit the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, kindness, goodness, faith,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Meekness, temperance: against such is no law.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they of Christ have crucified the flesh with the passions and desires.</verse>
  <verse number="25">If we live in the Spirit, let us also walk in the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Let us not be vainglorious, provoking one another, envying one another.</verse>
</chapter>