<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am the man that hath seen affliction by the rod of his wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Me hath he led, and brought into darkness, and not into light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Surely against me hath he turned again and again his hand all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="4">My flesh and my skin hath he wasted away, he hath broken my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He hath built against me, and encompassed [me] with gall and toil.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He hath made me to dwell in dark places as those that have been long dead.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He hath hedged me about that I cannot get out: he hath made my chain heavy.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Even when I cry and shout, he shutteth out my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He hath inclosed my ways with hewn stone, he hath made my paths crooked.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He is unto me [as] a bear lying in wait, a lion in secret places.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He hath turned aside my ways, and pulled me in pieces; he hath made me desolate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He hath bent his bow, and set me as a mark for the arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He hath caused the arrows of his quiver to enter into my reins.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I am become a derision to all my people; their song all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He hath sated me with bitterness, he hath made me drunk with wormwood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He hath also broken my teeth with gravel stones, he hath covered me with ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And thou hast removed my soul far off from peace: I have forgotten prosperity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And I said, My strength is perished, and my hope in Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Remember thou mine affliction and my wandering, the wormwood and the gall.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My soul hath [them] constantly in remembrance, and is humbled in me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">This I recall to heart, therefore have I hope.</verse>
  <verse number="22">It is of Jehovah’s loving-kindness we are not consumed, because his compassions fail not;</verse>
  <verse number="23">they are new every morning: great is thy faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Jehovah is my portion, saith my soul; therefore will I hope in him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Jehovah is good unto them that wait for him, to the soul [that] seeketh him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">It is good that one should both wait, and that in silence, for the salvation of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth:</verse>
  <verse number="28">He sitteth solitary and keepeth silence, because he hath laid it upon him;</verse>
  <verse number="29">he putteth his mouth in the dust, if so be there may be hope;</verse>
  <verse number="30">he giveth his cheek to him that smiteth him; he is filled full with reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For the Lord will not cast off for ever;</verse>
  <verse number="32">but if he have caused grief, he will have compassion according to the multitude of his loving-kindnesses:</verse>
  <verse number="33">for he doth not willingly afflict or grieve the children of men.</verse>
  <verse number="34">To crush under foot all the prisoners of the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="35">to turn aside the right of a man before the face of the Most High,</verse>
  <verse number="36">to wrong a man in his cause,—will not the Lord see it?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who is he that saith, and there cometh to pass, what the Lord hath not commanded?</verse>
  <verse number="38">Out of the mouth of the Most High doth not there proceed evil and good?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Wherefore doth a living man complain, a man for the punishment of his sins?</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let us search and try our ways, and turn again to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Let us lift up our heart with [our] hands unto God in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="42">We have transgressed and have rebelled: thou hast not pardoned.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Thou hast covered thyself with anger, and pursued us; thou hast slain, thou hast not spared.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Thou hast covered thyself with a cloud, that prayer should not pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Thou hast made us the offscouring and refuse in the midst of the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All our enemies have opened their mouth against us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Fear and the pit are come upon us, devastation and ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Mine eye runneth down with streams of water for the ruin of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">Mine eye poureth down, and ceaseth not, without any intermission,</verse>
  <verse number="50">till Jehovah look down and behold from the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Mine eye affecteth my soul, because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">They that are mine enemies without cause have chased me sore like a bird.</verse>
  <verse number="53">They have cut off my life in a pit, and cast a stone upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">Waters streamed over my head; I said, I am cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="55">I called upon thy name, Jehovah, out of the lowest pit.</verse>
  <verse number="56">Thou hast heard my voice: hide not thine ear at my sighing, at my cry.</verse>
  <verse number="57">Thou drewest near in the day that I called upon thee; thou saidst, Fear not.</verse>
  <verse number="58">Lord, thou hast pleaded the cause of my soul, thou hast redeemed my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">Jehovah, thou hast seen my wrong: judge thou my cause.</verse>
  <verse number="60">Thou hast seen all their vengeance, all their imaginations against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">Thou hast heard their reproach, O Jehovah, all their imaginations against me;</verse>
  <verse number="62">the lips of those that rise up against me and their meditation against me all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="63">Behold thou their sitting down and their rising up: I am their song.</verse>
  <verse number="64">Render unto them a recompence, O Jehovah, according to the work of their hands;</verse>
  <verse number="65">give them obduracy of heart, thy curse unto them;</verse>
  <verse number="66">pursue them in anger, and destroy them from under the heavens of Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>