<chapter book="Lamentations" number="5" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Remember, O Jehovah, what is come upon us; consider, and see our reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Our inheritance is turned to strangers, our houses to aliens.</verse>
  <verse number="3">We are orphans and fatherless, our mothers are as widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Our water have we to drink for money, our wood cometh unto us for a price.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Our pursuers are on our necks: we are weary, we have no rest.</verse>
  <verse number="6">We have given the hand to Egypt, [and] to Asshur, to be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Our fathers have sinned, [and] they are not; and we bear their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Bondmen rule over us: there is no deliverer out of their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">We have to get our bread at the risk of our lives, because of the sword of the wilderness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Our skin gloweth like an oven, because of the burning heat of the famine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They have ravished the women in Zion, the maids in the cities of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Princes were hanged up by their hand; the faces of elders were not honoured.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The young men have borne the mill, and the youths have stumbled under the wood.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The elders have ceased from the gate, the young men from their music.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The joy of our heart hath ceased; our dance is turned into mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The crown is fallen from our head: woe unto us, for we have sinned!</verse>
  <verse number="17">For this our heart is faint; for these things our eyes have grown dim,</verse>
  <verse number="18">Because of the mountain of Zion, which is desolate: foxes walk over it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou, Jehovah, dwellest for ever; thy throne is from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wherefore dost thou forget us for ever, dost thou forsake us so long time?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Turn thou us unto thee, Jehovah, and we shall be turned; renew our days as of old.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Or is it that thou hast utterly rejected us? Wouldest thou be exceeding wroth against us?</verse>
</chapter>