<chapter book="Daniel" number="9" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">In one year to Darius son of Ahasuerus, from the seed of Media who reigned over the kingdom of the Chaldeans.</verse>
  <verse number="2">In one year to the kingdom, I Daniel understood by books the number of years which the word of Jehovah was to Jeremiah the prophet, to fill up for the desolations of Jerusalem seventy years.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will give my face to Jehovah God to seek prayer and supplications, with fasting and sackcloth and ashes:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I will pray to Jehovah my God, and I will confess and say, Ah, Jehovah, the great and dreadful God, watching the covenant and the mercy to those loving him, and to those watching his commands:</verse>
  <verse number="5">We sinned, and we did iniquity, and were evil, and rebelled, and departing from thy commands and from thy judgments.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And we heard not to thy servants the prophets who spake in thy name to our kings and our chiefs and our fathers, and to all the people of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="7">To thee, O Jehovah, justice, and to us shame of face, as this day to the men of Judah, and to those dwelling in Jerusalem, and to all Israel being near and being far off, in all the lands where thou didst thrust them there in their transgression which they transgressed against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">O Jehovah, to us shame of face, to our kings, to our chiefs, and to our fathers, that we sinned against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">To Jehovah our God compassion and forgivenesses, for we rebelled against him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">We heard not to the voice of Jehovah our God to go in his laws which he gave before us in the hand of his servants the prophets.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And all Israel passed by thy Laws, and departing not to hear to thy voice; and the curse will be poured upon us, and the oath which was written in the law of Moses the servant of God, for we sinned against him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And he will set up his words which he spake against us, and against our judges who judged us to bring against us a great evil: which was not done under all the heavens according to what was done in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="13">As that written in the law of Moses all this evil came upon us, and we supplicated not the face of Jehovah our God to turn back from our iniquities and to understand in thy truth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Jehovah will watch for evil, and will bring it upon us: for Jehovah our God is just upon all his works which he did: and we heard not to his voice.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And now, O Jehovah our God, who brought thy people out of the land of Egypt with a strong hand, and thou wilt make to thee a name as this day; we sinned, we did evil.</verse>
  <verse number="16">O Jehovah, according to all thy justice, now shall thine anger be turned back, and thy wrath from thy city Jerusalem, thy holy mountain: for our sins and for the iniquities of our fathers, Jerusalem and thy people for a reproach to all those round about us.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And now, O our God, hear to the prayer of thy servant, and his supplications, and cause thy face to shine upon thy desolated holy place, for sake of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Incline, O my God, thine ear, and hear; open thine eyes, and see our desolations, and the city which thy name was called upon it: for not for our justice do we cause our supplications to fall before thee, but for thy many compassions.</verse>
  <verse number="19">O Jehovah hear; O Jehovah forgive; O Jehovah, attend and do; thou wilt not delay for thy sake, O my God: for thy name was called upon thy city and upon thy people.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And I yet speaking and praying and confessing my sins, and the sins of my people Israel, and causing my supplication to fall before Jehovah my God for the holy mountain of my God;</verse>
  <verse number="21">And I yet speaking in prayer, and the man Gabriel, whom I saw in the vision in the beginning, being wearied with weariness, touched upon me about the time of the evening gift.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he will cause to understand, and will speak with me, and say, O Daniel, now came I forth to teach thee understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="23">In the beginning of thy supplications the word came forth, and I came to announce; for thou art desires: and understand thou in the word, and consider in the sight.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Seventy seventy were divided upon thy people and upon thy holy city, to close the transgression, and to seal up sins, and to expiate iniquity, and to bring in eternal justice, and to seal up the vision and prophecy, and to anoint the holy of holies.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And thou shalt know and understand, from the going forth of the word to turn back and to build Jerusalem even to Messiah the leader, seventy weeks, and sixty and two weeks: and the street shall turn back and be built, and the ditch, in the trouble of the times.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And after sixty and two weeks, Messiah shall be cut off, and not for him: and the people of the leader coming shall destroy the city and the holy place; and its end with an overflowing, and even to the end of the war desolations were determined.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he made strong the covenant to many one week: and half the week he shall cause the sacrifice and gift to cease, and upon the wing of abominations laying waste, even to the completion, and that determined shall be poured upon the desolation.</verse>
</chapter>