<chapter book="1 Thessalonians" number="5" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now about the times and seasons, brothers, we do not need to write to you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For you are fully aware that the Day of the Lord will come like a thief in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="3">While people are saying, “Peace and security,” destruction will come upon them suddenly, like labor pains on a pregnant woman, and they will not escape.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But you, brothers, are not in the darkness so that this day should overtake you like a thief.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For you are all sons of the light and sons of the day; we do not belong to the night or to the darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">So then, let us not sleep as the others do, but let us remain awake and sober.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For those who sleep, sleep at night, and those who get drunk, get drunk at night.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But since we belong to the day, let us be sober, putting on the breastplate of faith and love, and the helmet of our hope of salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For God has not appointed us to suffer wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He died for us so that, whether we are awake or asleep, we may live together with Him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore encourage and build one another up, just as you are already doing.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But we ask you, brothers, to acknowledge those who work diligently among you, who care for you in the Lord and who admonish you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In love, hold them in highest regard because of their work. Live in peace with one another.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And we urge you, brothers, to admonish the unruly, encourage the fainthearted, help the weak, and be patient with everyone.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Make sure that no one repays evil for evil. Always pursue what is good for one another and for all people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Rejoice at all times.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Pray without ceasing.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Give thanks in every circumstance, for this is God’s will for you in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Do not extinguish the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Do not treat prophecies with contempt,</verse>
  <verse number="21">but test all things. Hold fast to what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Abstain from every form of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Now may the God of peace Himself sanctify you completely, and may your entire spirit, soul, and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The One who calls you is faithful, and He will do it.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Brothers, pray for us as well.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Greet all the brothers with a holy kiss.</verse>
  <verse number="27">I charge you before the Lord to have this letter read to all the brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
</chapter>