<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="2" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am a rose of Sharon, A lily of the valleys.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As a lily among thorns, So is my love among the daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="3">As the apple-tree among the trees of the wood, So is my beloved among the sons. I sat down under his shadow with great delight, And his fruit was sweet to my taste.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He brought me to the banqueting-house, And his banner over me was love.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Stay ye me with raisins, refresh me with apples; For I am sick from love.</verse>
  <verse number="6">His left hand is under my head, And his right hand doth embrace me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I adjure you, O daughters of Jerusalem, By the roes, or by the hinds of the field, That ye stir not up, nor awake my love, Until he please.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The voice of my beloved! behold, he cometh, Leaping upon the mountains, Skipping upon the hills.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My beloved is like a roe or a young hart: Behold, he standeth behind our wall; He looketh in at the windows; He glanceth through the lattice.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My beloved spake, and said unto me, Rise up, my love, my fair one, and come away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For, lo, the winter is past; The rain is over and gone;</verse>
  <verse number="12">The flowers appear on the earth; The time of the singing of birds is come, And the voice of the turtle-dove is heard in our land;</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fig-tree ripeneth her green figs, And the vines are in blossom; They give forth their fragrance. Arise, my love, my fair one, and come away.</verse>
  <verse number="14">O my dove, that art in the clefts of the rock, In the covert of the steep place, Let me see thy countenance, Let me hear thy voice; For sweet is thy voice, and thy countenance is comely.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Take us the foxes, the little foxes, That spoil the vineyards; For our vineyards are in blossom.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My beloved is mine, and I am his: He feedeth his flock among the lilies.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Until the day be cool, and the shadows flee away, Turn, my beloved, and be thou like a roe or a young hart Upon the mountains of Bether.</verse>
</chapter>