<chapter book="Job" number="18" translation="King James Bible" translationID="kjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Bildad the Shuhite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long [will it be ere] ye make an end of words? mark, and afterwards we will speak.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Wherefore are we counted as beasts, [and] reputed vile in your sight?</verse>
  <verse number="4">He teareth himself in his anger: shall the earth be forsaken for thee? and shall the rock be removed out of his place?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Yea, the light of the wicked shall be put out, and the spark of his fire shall not shine.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The light shall be dark in his tabernacle, and his candle shall be put out with him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The steps of his strength shall be straitened, and his own counsel shall cast him down.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For he is cast into a net by his own feet, and he walketh upon a snare.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The gin shall take [him] by the heel, [and] the robber shall prevail against him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The snare [is] laid for him in the ground, and a trap for him in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Terrors shall make him afraid on every side, and shall drive him to his feet.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His strength shall be hungerbitten, and destruction [shall be] ready at his side.</verse>
  <verse number="13">It shall devour the strength of his skin: [even] the firstborn of death shall devour his strength.</verse>
  <verse number="14">His confidence shall be rooted out of his tabernacle, and it shall bring him to the king of terrors.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It shall dwell in his tabernacle, because [it is] none of his: brimstone shall be scattered upon his habitation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">His roots shall be dried up beneath, and above shall his branch be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His remembrance shall perish from the earth, and he shall have no name in the street.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He shall be driven from light into darkness, and chased out of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He shall neither have son nor nephew among his people, nor any remaining in his dwellings.</verse>
  <verse number="20">They that come after [him] shall be astonied at his day, as they that went before were affrighted.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Surely such [are] the dwellings of the wicked, and this [is] the place [of him that] knoweth not God.</verse>
</chapter>