<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="1" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The Song of songs, which is Solomon’s.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Let him kiss me with the kisses of his mouth; for your love is better than wine.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Your oils have a pleasing fragrance. Your name is oil poured forth, therefore the virgins love you.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Take me away with you. Let us hurry. The king has brought me into his rooms. We will be glad and rejoice in you. We will praise your love more than wine! They are right to love you.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I am dark, but lovely, you daughters of Jerusalem, like Kedar’s tents, like Solomon’s curtains.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Don’t stare at me because I am dark, because the sun has scorched me. My mother’s sons were angry with me. They made me keeper of the vineyards. I haven’t kept my own vineyard.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Tell me, you whom my soul loves, where you graze your flock, where you rest them at noon; For why should I be as one who is veiled beside the flocks of your companions?</verse>
  <verse number="8">If you don’t know, most beautiful among women, follow the tracks of the sheep. Graze your young goats beside the shepherds’ tents.</verse>
  <verse number="9">I have compared you, my love, to a steed in Pharaoh’s chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Your cheeks are beautiful with earrings, your neck with strings of jewels.</verse>
  <verse number="11">We will make you earrings of gold, with studs of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">While the king sat at his table, my perfume spread its fragrance.</verse>
  <verse number="13">My beloved is to me a sachet of myrrh, that lies between my breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My beloved is to me a cluster of henna blossoms from the vineyards of En Gedi.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, you are beautiful, my love. Behold, you are beautiful. Your eyes are doves.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, you are beautiful, my beloved, yes, pleasant; and our couch is verdant.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The beams of our house are cedars. Our rafters are firs.</verse>
</chapter>