<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="1" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of Ecclesiastes, the son of David, the king of Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Ecclesiastes said: Vanity of vanities! Vanity of vanities, and all is vanity!</verse>
  <verse number="3">What more does a man have from all his labor, as he labors under the sun?</verse>
  <verse number="4">A generation passes away, and a generation arrives. But the earth stands forever.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The sun rises and sets; it returns to its place, and from there, being born again,</verse>
  <verse number="6">it circles through the south, and arcs toward the north. The spirit continues on, illuminating everything in its circuit, and turning again in its cycle.</verse>
  <verse number="7">All rivers enter into the sea, and the sea does not overflow. To the place from which the rivers go out, they return, so that they may flow again.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Such things are difficult; man is not able to explain them with words. The eye is not satisfied by seeing, nor is the ear fulfilled by hearing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What is it that has existed? The same shall exist in the future. What is it that has been done? The same shall continue to be done.</verse>
  <verse number="10">There is nothing new under the sun. Neither is anyone able to say: “Behold, this is new!” For it has already been brought forth in the ages that were before us.</verse>
  <verse number="11">There is no remembrance of the former things. Indeed, neither shall there be any record of past things in the future, for those who will exist at the very end.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I, Ecclesiastes, was king of Israel at Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I was determined in my mind to seek and to investigate wisely, concerning all that is done under the sun. God has given this very difficult task to the sons of men, so that they may be occupied by it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I have seen all that is done under the sun, and behold: all is emptiness and an affliction of the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The perverse are unwilling to be corrected, and the number of the foolish is boundless.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I have spoken in my heart, saying: “Behold, I have achieved greatness, and I have surpassed all the wise who were before me in Jerusalem.” And my mind has contemplated many things wisely, and I have learned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I have dedicated my heart, so that I may know prudence and doctrine, and also error and foolishness. Yet I recognize that, in these things also, there is hardship, and affliction of the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Because of this, with much wisdom there is also much anger. And whoever adds knowledge, also adds hardship.</verse>
</chapter>