<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="10" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Dying flies ruin the sweetness of the ointment. Wisdom and glory is more precious than a brief and limited foolishness.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The heart of a wise man is in his right hand, and the heart of a foolish man is in his left hand.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Moreover, as a foolish man is walking along the way, even though he himself is unwise, he considers everyone to be foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If the spirit of one who holds authority rises over you, do not leave your place, because attentiveness will cause the greatest sins to cease.</verse>
  <verse number="5">There is an evil which I have seen under the sun, proceeding from the presence of a prince, as if by mistake:</verse>
  <verse number="6">a foolish man appointed to a high dignity, and the rich sitting beneath him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I have seen servants on horses, and princes walking on the ground like servants.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Whoever digs a pit will fall into it. And whoever tears apart a hedge, a snake will bite him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whoever carries away stones will be harmed by them. And whoever cuts down trees will be wounded by them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If the iron is dull, and if it was not that way before, but has been made dull by much labor, then it will be sharpened. And wisdom will follow after diligence.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Whoever slanders in secret is nothing less than a snake that bites silently.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Words from the mouth of a wise man are graceful, but the lips of a foolish man will throw him down with violence.</verse>
  <verse number="13">At the beginning of his words is foolishness, and at the end of his talk is a most grievous error.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The fool multiplies his words. A man does not know what has been before him, and who is able to reveal to him what will be in the future after him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">The hardship of the foolish will afflict those who do not know to go into the city.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Woe to you, the land whose king is a boy, and whose princes consume in the morning.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Blessed is the land whose king is noble, and whose princes eat at the proper time, for refreshment and not for self-indulgence.</verse>
  <verse number="18">By laziness, a framework shall be brought down, and by the weakness of hands, a house shall collapse through.</verse>
  <verse number="19">While laughing, they make bread and wine, so that the living may feast. And all things are obedient to money.</verse>
  <verse number="20">You should not slander the king, even in your thoughts, and you should not speak evil of a wealthy man, even in your private chamber. For even the birds of the air will carry your voice, and whatever has wings will announce your opinion.</verse>
</chapter>