<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="4" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I turned myself to other things, and I saw the false accusations which are carried out under the sun, and the tears of the innocent, and that there was no one to console them; and that they were not able to withstand their violence, being destitute of all help.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And so, I praised the dead more than the living.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And happier than both of these, I judged him to be, who has not yet been born, and who has not yet seen the evils which are done under the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Again, I was contemplating all the labors of men. And I took notice that their endeavors are open to the envy of their neighbor. And so, in this, too, there is emptiness and superfluous anxiety.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The foolish man folds his hands together, and he consumes his own flesh, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="6">“A handful with rest is better than both hands filled with labors and with affliction of the soul.”</verse>
  <verse number="7">While considering this, I also discovered another vanity under the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He is one, and he does not have a second: no son, no brother. And yet he does not cease to labor, nor are his eyes satisfied with wealth, nor does he reflect, saying: “For whom do I labor and cheat my soul of good things?” In this, too, is emptiness and a most burdensome affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Therefore, it is better for two to be together, than for one to be alone. For they have the advantage of their companionship.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If one falls, he shall be supported by the other. Woe to one who is alone. For when he falls, he has no one to lift him up.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And if two are sleeping, they warm one another. How can one person alone be warmed?</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if a man can prevail against one, two may withstand him, and a threefold cord is broken with difficulty.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Better is a boy, poor and wise, than a king, old and foolish, who does not know to look ahead for the sake of posterity.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For sometimes, one goes forth from prison and chains, to a kingdom, while another, born to kingly power, is consumed by need.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I saw all the living who are walking under the sun, and I saw the next generation, who shall rise up in their places.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The number of people, out of all who existed before these, is boundless. And those who will exist afterwards shall not rejoice in them. But this, too, is emptiness and an affliction of the spirit.</verse>
</chapter>