<chapter book="John" number="4" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When therefore the LORD knew how the Pharisees had heard that Jesus made and baptized more disciples than John,</verse>
  <verse number="2">(Though Jesus himself baptized not, but his disciples,)</verse>
  <verse number="3">He left Judaea, and departed again into Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he must needs go through Samaria.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then comes he to a city of Samaria, which is called Sychar, near to the parcel of ground that Jacob gave to his son Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Now Jacob’s well was there. Jesus therefore, being wearied with his journey, sat thus on the well: and it was about the sixth hour.</verse>
  <verse number="7">There comes a woman of Samaria to draw water: Jesus said to her, Give me to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="8">(For his disciples were gone away to the city to buy meat.)</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then said the woman of Samaria to him, How is it that you, being a Jew, ask drink of me, which am a woman of Samaria? for the Jews have no dealings with the Samaritans.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Jesus answered and said to her, If you knew the gift of God, and who it is that said to you, Give me to drink; you would have asked of him, and he would have given you living water.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The woman said to him, Sir, you have nothing to draw with, and the well is deep: from where then have you that living water?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Are you greater than our father Jacob, which gave us the well, and drank thereof himself, and his children, and his cattle?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Jesus answered and said to her, Whoever drinks of this water shall thirst again:</verse>
  <verse number="14">But whoever drinks of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I shall give him shall be in him a well of water springing up into everlasting life.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The woman said to him, Sir, give me this water, that I thirst not, neither come here to draw.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Jesus said to her, Go, call your husband, and come here.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The woman answered and said, I have no husband. Jesus said to her, You have well said, I have no husband:</verse>
  <verse number="18">For you have had five husbands; and he whom you now have is not your husband: in that said you truly.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The woman said to him, Sir, I perceive that you are a prophet.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Our fathers worshipped in this mountain; and you say, that in Jerusalem is the place where men ought to worship.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Jesus said to her, Woman, believe me, the hour comes, when you shall neither in this mountain, nor yet at Jerusalem, worship the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="22">You worship you know not what: we know what we worship: for salvation is of the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="23">But the hour comes, and now is, when the true worshippers shall worship the Father in spirit and in truth: for the Father seeks such to worship him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">God is a Spirit: and they that worship him must worship him in spirit and in truth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The woman said to him, I know that Messias comes, which is called Christ: when he is come, he will tell us all things.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Jesus said to her, I that speak to you am he.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And on this came his disciples, and marveled that he talked with the woman: yet no man said, What seek you? or, Why talk you with her?</verse>
  <verse number="28">The woman then left her water pot, and went her way into the city, and said to the men,</verse>
  <verse number="29">Come, see a man, which told me all things that ever I did: is not this the Christ?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then they went out of the city, and came to him.</verse>
  <verse number="31">In the mean while his disciples prayed him, saying, Master, eat.</verse>
  <verse number="32">But he said to them, I have meat to eat that you know not of.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Therefore said the disciples one to another, Has any man brought him ought to eat?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Jesus said to them, My meat is to do the will of him that sent me, and to finish his work.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Say not you, There are yet four months, and then comes harvest? behold, I say to you, Lift up your eyes, and look on the fields; for they are white already to harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And he that reaps receives wages, and gathers fruit to life eternal: that both he that sows and he that reaps may rejoice together.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And herein is that saying true, One sows, and another reaps.</verse>
  <verse number="38">I sent you to reap that where on you bestowed no labor: other men labored, and you are entered into their labors.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And many of the Samaritans of that city believed on him for the saying of the woman, which testified, He told me all that ever I did.</verse>
  <verse number="40">So when the Samaritans were come to him, they sought him that he would tarry with them: and he stayed there two days.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And many more believed because of his own word;</verse>
  <verse number="42">And said to the woman, Now we believe, not because of your saying: for we have heard him ourselves, and know that this is indeed the Christ, the Savior of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Now after two days he departed there, and went into Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="44">For Jesus himself testified, that a prophet has no honor in his own country.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then when he was come into Galilee, the Galilaeans received him, having seen all the things that he did at Jerusalem at the feast: for they also went to the feast.</verse>
  <verse number="46">So Jesus came again into Cana of Galilee, where he made the water wine. And there was a certain nobleman, whose son was sick at Capernaum.</verse>
  <verse number="47">When he heard that Jesus was come out of Judaea into Galilee, he went to him, and sought him that he would come down, and heal his son: for he was at the point of death.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Then said Jesus to him, Except you see signs and wonders, you will not believe.</verse>
  <verse number="49">The nobleman said to him, Sir, come down ere my child die.</verse>
  <verse number="50">Jesus said to him, Go your way; your son lives. And the man believed the word that Jesus had spoken to him, and he went his way.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And as he was now going down, his servants met him, and told him, saying, Your son lives.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Then inquired he of them the hour when he began to amend. And they said to him, Yesterday at the seventh hour the fever left him.</verse>
  <verse number="53">So the father knew that it was at the same hour, in the which Jesus said to him, Your son lives: and himself believed, and his whole house.</verse>
  <verse number="54">This is again the second miracle that Jesus did, when he was come out of Judaea into Galilee.</verse>
</chapter>