<chapter book="John" number="8" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Jesus went to the mount of Olives.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And early in the morning he came again into the temple, and all the people came to him; and he sat down, and taught them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the scribes and Pharisees brought to him a woman taken in adultery; and when they had set her in the middle,</verse>
  <verse number="4">They say to him, Master, this woman was taken in adultery, in the very act.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Now Moses in the law commanded us, that such should be stoned: but what say you?</verse>
  <verse number="6">This they said, tempting him, that they might have to accuse him. But Jesus stooped down, and with his finger wrote on the ground, as though he heard them not.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So when they continued asking him, he lifted up himself, and said to them, He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone at her.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And again he stooped down, and wrote on the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they which heard it, being convicted by their own conscience, went out one by one, beginning at the oldest, even to the last: and Jesus was left alone, and the woman standing in the middle.</verse>
  <verse number="10">When Jesus had lifted up himself, and saw none but the woman, he said to her, Woman, where are those your accusers? has no man condemned you?</verse>
  <verse number="11">She said, No man, Lord. And Jesus said to her, Neither do I condemn you: go, and sin no more.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Then spoke Jesus again to them, saying, I am the light of the world: he that follows me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The Pharisees therefore said to him, You bore record of yourself; your record is not true.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Jesus answered and said to them, Though I bear record of myself, yet my record is true: for I know from where I came, and where I go; but you cannot tell from where I come, and where I go.</verse>
  <verse number="15">You judge after the flesh; I judge no man.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And yet if I judge, my judgment is true: for I am not alone, but I and the Father that sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">It is also written in your law, that the testimony of two men is true.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I am one that bear witness of myself, and the Father that sent me bears witness of me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Then said they to him, Where is your Father? Jesus answered, You neither know me, nor my Father: if you had known me, you should have known my Father also.</verse>
  <verse number="20">These words spoke Jesus in the treasury, as he taught in the temple: and no man laid hands on him; for his hour was not yet come.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Then said Jesus again to them, I go my way, and you shall seek me, and shall die in your sins: where I go, you cannot come.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then said the Jews, Will he kill himself? because he said, Where I go, you cannot come.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he said to them, You are from beneath; I am from above: you are of this world; I am not of this world.</verse>
  <verse number="24">I said therefore to you, that you shall die in your sins: for if you believe not that I am he, you shall die in your sins.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Then said they to him, Who are you? And Jesus said to them, Even the same that I said to you from the beginning.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I have many things to say and to judge of you: but he that sent me is true; and I speak to the world those things which I have heard of him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">They understood not that he spoke to them of the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then said Jesus to them, When you have lifted up the Son of man, then shall you know that I am he, and that I do nothing of myself; but as my Father has taught me, I speak these things.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And he that sent me is with me: the Father has not left me alone; for I do always those things that please him.</verse>
  <verse number="30">As he spoke these words, many believed on him.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Then said Jesus to those Jews which believed on him, If you continue in my word, then are you my disciples indeed;</verse>
  <verse number="32">And you shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.</verse>
  <verse number="33">They answered him, We be Abraham’s seed, and were never in bondage to any man: how say you, You shall be made free?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Jesus answered them, Truly, truly, I say to you, Whoever commits sin is the servant of sin.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the servant stays not in the house for ever: but the Son stays ever.</verse>
  <verse number="36">If the Son therefore shall make you free, you shall be free indeed.</verse>
  <verse number="37">I know that you are Abraham’s seed; but you seek to kill me, because my word has no place in you.</verse>
  <verse number="38">I speak that which I have seen with my Father: and you do that which you have seen with your father.</verse>
  <verse number="39">They answered and said to him, Abraham is our father. Jesus said to them, If you were Abraham’s children, you would do the works of Abraham.</verse>
  <verse number="40">But now you seek to kill me, a man that has told you the truth, which I have heard of God: this did not Abraham.</verse>
  <verse number="41">You do the deeds of your father. Then said they to him, We be not born of fornication; we have one Father, even God.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Jesus said to them, If God were your Father, you would love me: for I proceeded forth and came from God; neither came I of myself, but he sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Why do you not understand my speech? even because you cannot hear my word.</verse>
  <verse number="44">You are of your father the devil, and the lusts of your father you will do. He was a murderer from the beginning, and stayed not in the truth, because there is no truth in him. When he speaks a lie, he speaks of his own: for he is a liar, and the father of it.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And because I tell you the truth, you believe me not.</verse>
  <verse number="46">Which of you convinces me of sin? And if I say the truth, why do you not believe me?</verse>
  <verse number="47">He that is of God hears God’s words: you therefore hear them not, because you are not of God.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Then answered the Jews, and said to him, Say we not well that you are a Samaritan, and have a devil?</verse>
  <verse number="49">Jesus answered, I have not a devil; but I honor my Father, and you do dishonor me.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And I seek not my own glory: there is one that seeks and judges.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Truly, truly, I say to you, If a man keep my saying, he shall never see death.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Then said the Jews to him, Now we know that you have a devil. Abraham is dead, and the prophets; and you say, If a man keep my saying, he shall never taste of death.</verse>
  <verse number="53">Are you greater than our father Abraham, which is dead? and the prophets are dead: whom make you yourself?</verse>
  <verse number="54">Jesus answered, If I honor myself, my honor is nothing: it is my Father that honors me; of whom you say, that he is your God:</verse>
  <verse number="55">Yet you have not known him; but I know him: and if I should say, I know him not, I shall be a liar like to you: but I know him, and keep his saying.</verse>
  <verse number="56">Your father Abraham rejoiced to see my day: and he saw it, and was glad.</verse>
  <verse number="57">Then said the Jews to him, You are not yet fifty years old, and have you seen Abraham?</verse>
  <verse number="58">Jesus said to them, Truly, truly, I say to you, Before Abraham was, I am.</verse>
  <verse number="59">Then took they up stones to cast at him: but Jesus hid himself, and went out of the temple, going through the middle of them, and so passed by.</verse>
</chapter>