<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Proverbs of Solomon, son of David, king of Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="2">To know wisdom and instruction; to discern the words of understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">To receive the instruction of wisdom, justice and judgment, and uprightness;</verse>
  <verse number="4">To give craftiness to the simple, and to the youth, knowledge and meditation.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The wise one will hear and he will add learning: and he understanding, shall obtain guidance:</verse>
  <verse number="6">To understand a proverb, and an enigma: the words of the wise and their parables.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The fear of Jehovah is the beginning of knowledge: the foolish despised wisdom and instruction.</verse>
  <verse number="8">My son, hear the instruction of thy father, and thou shalt not reject the law of thy mother:</verse>
  <verse number="9">For they a garland of grace to thy head, and necklaces for thy throat.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if they sinning shall entice thee, thou shalt not go in.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they shall say, Go with us, we will lie in wait for blood, we will hide for the innocent gratuitously;</verse>
  <verse number="12">We will swallow them down living, as hades, and whole, as they going down to the pit:</verse>
  <verse number="13">We shall find precious riches, we will fill our houses with spoil:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Wilt thou cast thy lot in the midst of us; one purse shall be to all:</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, thou shalt not go in the way with them; withhold thy foot from their beaten paths:</verse>
  <verse number="16">For their feet will run to evil, and they will hasten to pour out blood:</verse>
  <verse number="17">For gratuitously the net was spread in the eyes of all possessing a wing.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they will lie in wait for their blood; they will hide for their souls.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So the ways of every one plundering plunder; he will take the soul of those possessing it.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom will cry without; in the broad places she will give her voice:</verse>
  <verse number="21">She will call in the head of sound, in the entrances of the gates: in the city she will say her words:</verse>
  <verse number="22">How long, ye simple, will ye love simplicity? and mockers delight to mock for them, and the foolish hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Ye shall turn back at my reproofs: behold, I will pour forth my spirit to you, I will make known my words to you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I called and ye will refuse; I stretched forth my hands, and none attending;</verse>
  <verse number="25">And ye will reject all my counsels, and ye desired not my reproofs:</verse>
  <verse number="26">Also I will laugh at your ruin: I will deride in the coming of your terror;</verse>
  <verse number="27">In your terror coming as a destroying tempest, and your ruin shall come as a whirlwind; in the coming upon you of straits and distress.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then they shall call upon me, and I will not answer; they shall seek me, and shall not find me;</verse>
  <verse number="29">For that they hated knowledge, and chose not the fear of Jehovah:</verse>
  <verse number="30">They desired not for my counsels: and derided all my reproofs.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they shall eat from the fruit of their way, and be filled with their purposes.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the turning away of the simple shall slay them, and the error of the foolish shall destroy them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he hearing to me shall dwell in confidence, and being quiet from fear of evil.</verse>
</chapter>