<chapter book="Proverbs" number="14" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The wise woman built her house but the foolish will pull it down with her hands.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He going in his uprightness will fear Jehovah: and he perverted in his ways, despised him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In the month of the foolish one a rod of pride: and the lips of the wise shall watch them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">In no oxen the stall clean, and much increase in the strength of the ox.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A witness of faithfulnesses will not lie: and a witness of falsehood will breathe out lies.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He mocking sought wisdom, and none: and knowledge being easy to him understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Go from before to the foolish man and thou knewest not the lips of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The wisdom of the prudent is to understand his way: and the folly of the foolish is deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The foolish will mock at guilt: and between the upright acceptance.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The heart will know the bitterness of its soul, and in its joys the stranger shall not mingle.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The house of the unjust shall be destroyed: and the tent of the upright shall flourish.</verse>
  <verse number="12">There is a way straight before man, and its latter state the ways of death.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Also in laughter the heart shall have pain, and its latter state of joy, grief.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He drawing back the heart shall be filled from his ways: and a good man from above him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The simple will believe to every word: and the prudent will understand to his going.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The wise one feared and departed from evil: and the foolish overflowing, and being confident.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He reaping anger will do folly: and a man of mischiefs will be hated.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The simple inherit folly: and the prudent shall be surrounded with knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The evil bowed before the good, and the unjust at the gates of the just one.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Also the poor shall be hated by his neighbor: and many loving the rich one.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He despising to his neighbor, sins: and he compassionating the poor, he is happy.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Shall they not go astray, seeking evil? and mercy, and truth to those seeking good.</verse>
  <verse number="23">In all labor will be profit: and the word of the lips only to want.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The crown of the wise is their riches: the folly of the foolish, folly.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A witness of truth delivers souls: and deceit will breathe out lies.</verse>
  <verse number="26">In the fear of Jehovah the trust of strength, and to his sons a refuge.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The fear of Jehovah a fountain of life, to depart from the snares of death.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In a multitude of people the king’s decoration: and in the cessation of the people the destruction of the prince.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The slow to anger of much understanding: and the short of spirit exalts folly.</verse>
  <verse number="30">A heart of healing, the life of the flesh: and jealousy the rottenness of the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He oppressing the poor reproached him making him: and he honoring him compassionated the needy.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The unjust one shall be driven away in his evil: and the just one trusted in his death.</verse>
  <verse number="33">In the heart of him understanding, wisdom shall rest: and in the midst of fools it shall be made known.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Justice will exalt a nation: and sin a reproach to nations.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The acceptance of the king to a servant of understanding: and his wrath shall be to him causing shame.</verse>
</chapter>