<chapter book="Proverbs" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A soft answer will turn away wrath, and a word of pain will bring up anger.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The tongue of the wise will make knowledge good: and the mouth of the foolish will gush forth folly.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In every place are the eyes of Jehovah observing closely the evil and the good.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The healing of the tongue the tree of life: and perverseness in it a breaking in the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The foolish will deride his father’s instruction: and he watching reproof will be crafty.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The house of the just much treasure: and in the increase of the unjust the being troubled.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The lips of the wise will disperse knowledge: and the heart of the foolish not so.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sacrifice of the unjust an abomination of Jehovah: and the prayer of the upright his acceptance.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The way of the unjust an abomination of Jehovah: and he will love him pursuing justice.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Correction is evil to him forsaking the way: he hating reproof shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Hades and destruction are before Jehovah: much more the hearts of the sons of man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He mocking will not love him reproving him: to the wise he will not go.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A heart of joy will do the face good: and by pains of heart the spirit was dejected.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The heart of him understanding will seek knowledge: and the face of the foolish will feed folly.</verse>
  <verse number="15">All the days of the afflicted are evil: and the good of heart drinking always.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Good is little with the fear of Jehovah more than much treasure and confusion with it.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Good a ration of herbs and love there, above an ox of the stall and hatred with it.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A man of wrath will excite strife: and he slow to anger will appease contention.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The way of the slothful as the cutting of the thorn: and the path of the upright was raised up.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A wise son will gladden the father: and the foolish man despised his mother.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Folly is joy to him wanting heart: and the man of understanding will make straight to go.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The frustrating purposes with no counsel, but in the multitude of counselors it shall be set up.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Joy to the man in the answer of his mouth: and a word in its time how good.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The path of life is above to the understanding one, to depart from hades below.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The house of the proud will Jehovah sweep away, and he will set up the bound of the widow.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The purposes of evil an abomination of Jehovah: and the pure speaking of pleasantness.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He plundering plunder troubled his house; and he hating gifts shall live.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The heart of the just one shall meditate to answer: and the mouth of the unjust shall gush out evil.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Jehovah is far off from the unjust: and he will hear the prayer of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="30">From the light of the eyes the heart will rejoice: and a good report will fatten the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The ear hearing the reproof of life shall lodge in the midst of the wise.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He driving away instruction despised his soul: and he hearing reproof obtained a heart.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The fear of Jehovah the instruction of wisdom; and before honor humility.</verse>
</chapter>