<chapter book="Proverbs" number="21" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Steams of waters the heart of the king, in the hand of Jehovah: upon all which he shall delight in he will turn it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Every way of a man right in his eyes: and Jehovah will prepare hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To do justice and judgment was chosen by Jehovah above gold.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Lifting up the eyes and enlarging the heart, the light of the unjust is sin.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The purposes of the active only to abundance; and every one hastening only to want.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The making treasures by the tongue of falsehood is vanity scattered from those seeking death.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The violence of the unjust shall sweep them away, for they refuse to do judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The way of man is crooked and strange: and the pure his work is right.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Good to dwell upon the corner of the roof rather than with a woman of strifes and a house of community.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The soul of the unjust one desired evil: his neighbor shall not be compassionated in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">In punishing him mocking, the simple shall become wise: and in instruction to the wise one he will take knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The just one being circumspect for the house of the unjust one: overthrowing the unjust for evil.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He stopping his ear from the cry of the poor one also himself shall call and shall not be answered.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Giving in secret will subdue anger: and a gift in the bosom, strong wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Joy to the just one to do judgment: and destruction to those working iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A man wandering from the way of understanding shall rest in the convocation of the shades.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A man of poverty loving joy: he loving wine and oil shall not be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The unjust one a ransom for the just one, and he transgressing, instead of the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Good to dwell in the land of the desert rather than with a woman of contentions and anger.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A treasure desired, and oil in the house of the wise one; and the foolish man will swallow it down.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He pursuing justice and mercy shall find life, justice and honor.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The wise one ascended the city of the strong, and he will bring down the strength of its confidence.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He watching his mouth and his tongue watches his soul from straits.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Proud, arrogant, mocking, is his name doing in the wrath of pride.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The desire of the slothful shall kill him, for his hands refused to work,</verse>
  <verse number="26">He longed a longing all the day: and the just one shall give and not keep back.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sacrifice of the unjust is an abomination, for also he will bring it in mischief.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A witness of lies shall perish: and a man hearing, shall speak clearly.</verse>
  <verse number="29">An unjust man strengthened with his face: and the upright he will prepare his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="30">No wisdom and no understanding, and no counsel against Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The horse is prepared for the day of war and salvation is to Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>