<chapter book="Proverbs" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Thou shalt not envy against men of evil, thou shalt not desire to be with them.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For their heart will meditate destruction, and their lips will speak labor.</verse>
  <verse number="3">By wisdom a house will be built, and it will be prepared by understanding:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And by knowledge shall the chambers be filled with all precious and pleasant riches.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A wise man is in strength, and a man of knowledge strengthens power.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For by guidance thou shalt make to thee war, and in the multitude of counselors salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="7">High things to the foolish is wisdom: in the gate he will not open his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He purposing to do evil for himself shall be called the master of mischief.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The purpose of folly is sin, and he mocking, an abomination to man.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Wilt thou be discouraged in the day of straits thy strength is narrow.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If thou shalt refrain to deliver those being brought to death, and those going to be slain;</verse>
  <verse number="12">If thou shalt say, Behold, we knew not this; will not he trying hearts, understand? and he guarding thy soul, knew? and he turned back to man according to his work.</verse>
  <verse number="13">My son, eat honey, for it is good; and the dropping of honey being sweet to thy palate.</verse>
  <verse number="14">So the knowledge of wisdom to thy soul if thou shalt find: and there is a latter state and thine expectation shall not be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Thou shalt not lay wait, O wicked one, against the dwelling of the just one; thou shalt not destroy his resting place:</verse>
  <verse number="16">For the just one shall fall seven times, and rise: and the unjust shall be weak in evil.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In the falling of thine enemies thou shalt not rejoice, and in his stumbling thy heart shall not exult:</verse>
  <verse number="18">Lest Jehovah shall see and it be evil in his eyes, and he turn back from him his anger.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou shalt not be angry against the evil; thou shalt not envy against the unjust:</verse>
  <verse number="20">For there shall be no latter state to the evil one: the light of the unjust shall be extinguished.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, fear thou Jehovah and the king: thou shalt not intermingle with those changing:</verse>
  <verse number="22">For suddenly shall their calamity rise, and who shall make known the misfortune of them two?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Also these to the wise. To look upon the face in judgment is not good.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He saying to the unjust, Thou art just; peoples shall curse him, and nations shall curse him:</verse>
  <verse number="25">And it shall be pleasant to those reproving, and a blessing of good shall come upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He shall kiss the lips turning back right words.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Prepare thy work without, and make it ready for thee in the field afterwards; and build thy house.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Thou shalt not be a witness gratuitously against thy neighbor, and deceive not with thy lips.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Thou shalt not say, According to what he did to me, thus will I do to him: I will turn back to the man according to his work.</verse>
  <verse number="30">I passed upon the field of the slothful man, and upon the vineyard of the man wanting heart;</verse>
  <verse number="31">And behold, it came up all of it with thorns; brambles covered its face, and the wall of its stones was overthrown.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And I shall see and set my heart: I looked, I took instruction.</verse>
  <verse number="33">A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to lie down:</verse>
  <verse number="34">And thy poverty came going about, and thy want as a man of shield.</verse>
</chapter>