<chapter book="Proverbs" number="25" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Also these the proverbs of Solomon which the men of Hezekiah king of Judah transcribed.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The glory of God to conceal the word: and the glory of kings to search the word.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The heavens for height, and the earth for depth, and the heart of kings not searched out.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Take ye away the dross from the silver, and a vessel shall come forth for the goldsmith.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Take ye away the unjust one from before the king, and his throne shall be prepared in justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thou shalt not show thyself proud before the king, and thou shalt not stand in the place of the great.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For good to say to thee, Come up hither, rather than humbling thyself before the noble whom thine eye saw.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thou shalt not go forth hastily to strive, lest what thou shalt do in its latter state in thy neighbor putting thee to shame.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Contend thy contention with thy neighbor; and thou shalt not reveal the secret of another:</verse>
  <verse number="10">Lest he hearing shall reproach thee, and thine infamy shall not turn away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Apples of gold in images of silver is the word spoken upon its wheels.</verse>
  <verse number="12">An earring of gold and a necklace of gold, the wise one reproving upon the hearing ear.</verse>
  <verse number="13">As the cold of snow in the day of harvest a faithful messenger to those sending him: he shall restore the soul of his lord.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Clouds and wind and not rain, a man boasting in a gift of falsehood.</verse>
  <verse number="15">In slowness to anger shall the prince be persuaded, and the soft tongue shall break the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Thou didst find honey; eat thy sufficiency, lest thou shalt be satiated, and thou vomit it forth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Make rare thy foot from thy neighbor’s house, lest he shall be satiated with thee, and hate thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A mallet and a sword and an arrow sharpened, the man answering against his neighbor testimony of falsehood.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A bad tooth and a wavering foot, the confidence of the faithless one in the day of straits.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He removing a covering in the day of cold, and vinegar upon nitre, and he singing in songs to an evil heart.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If thine enemy hunger, give him bread to eat; and if he thirst, give him water to drink:</verse>
  <verse number="22">For thou tookest up coals of fire upon his head, and Jehovah will recompense to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The north wind will set free the rain, and an angry face, a hidden tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Good to dwell upon a corner of the roof rather than with a woman of strifes and a house of community.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Cold waters to the fainting soul, and a good message from a land far off.</verse>
  <verse number="26">A fountain trampled down, and a fountain corrupted, the just one turned aside before the unjust one.</verse>
  <verse number="27">To eat much honey is not good: and to seek out their honor, not honor.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A city being broken down, and not a wall, a man who restrains not to his spirit.</verse>
</chapter>