<chapter book="Proverbs" number="26" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As snow in summer and as rain in harvest, so honor not becoming to the foolish one.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As the sparrow for wandering, as the swallow for flying, so the curse shall not come in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A whip for the horse, the curb for the ass, and the rod for the back of the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou shalt not answer the foolish according to his folly lest thou shalt be like to him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Answer the foolish according to his folly lest he shall be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He drank violence, cutting off the feet, sending words by the hand of the foolish one.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The legs of the lame were weak, and a parable in the mouth of the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="8">As a bundle of stones in a heap of stones, so he giving honor to the foolish one.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A thorn going up into the hand of a drunkard, a parable in the mouth of the foolish.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The great one piercing all, and he hired the foolish one, and those passing by.</verse>
  <verse number="11">As a dog turned back upon his vomit, the foolish one repeated in his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Sawest thou a man wise in his eyes? hope is for the foolish one more than for him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The slothful one said, A lion in the way; a lion between the broad places.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A door will turn upon its hinge, and the slothful upon his bed.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The slothful one hid his hand in the dish; he was weary to turn it back to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The slothful one is wise in his eyes more than seven turning back a reason.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Laying hold upon the ears of a dog, he passing by overflowing upon strife not to him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">As a madman casting fiery darts, arrows and death,</verse>
  <verse number="19">So the man deceiving his neighbor and saying, Am I not sporting?</verse>
  <verse number="20">In the ceasing of wood, fire will go out: and in not being a tale-bearer, strife will subside.</verse>
  <verse number="21">As charcoal to burning coals and woods to fire, and a man of strifes to kindle strife.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The words of a tale-bearer as dainty morsels, and they will go down to the chambers of the belly.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Silver dross covering over a pot-sherd, burning lips and an evil heart.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He hating will be known by his lips, and he will set deceit in his midst;</verse>
  <verse number="25">When his voice will compassionate, thou shalt not believe him, for seven abominations in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Hatred will be covered by deceit, his evil will be revealed in the convocation.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He digging a pit shall fall into it: and he rolling a stone it shall turn back upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A tongue of falsehood will hate its crushing, and a smooth mouth will make an overthrow.</verse>
</chapter>