<chapter book="Proverbs" number="28" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The unjust fled and none pursuing, and the just shall be confident as the young lion.</verse>
  <verse number="2">In the transgression of a land many its chiefs: and by a man understanding to know, the place shall be extended.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A poor man oppressing the poor, a sweeping rain and no bread.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They forsaking the law will praise the unjust: and they watching the law, shall contend with them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Men of evil shall not understand judgment: and they seeking Jehovah shall understand all.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Good the poor one going in his integrity above him perverting the ways, and he the rich.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He watching the law a son understanding: and the companion of squanderers will shame his father.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He increasing by interest and usury, he shall gather it for him compassionating the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He turning away his ear from hearing the law, also his prayer is an abomination.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He causing the upright to wander in an evil way, into his pit shall he fall: and the good shall inherit complete things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The rich man is wise in his eyes, and the poor one understanding shall search him out.</verse>
  <verse number="12">In the rejoicing of the just, much glory: in the rising up of the unjust, man will hide himself.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He covering his transgression shall not prosper: but he confessing and forsaking, shall be compassionated.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Happy the man fearing always: and he hardening his heart shall fall into evil.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A roaring lion and a greedy bear the unjust one ruling over a poor people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A prince wanting understanding and great in oppressions: he hating gain shall lengthen the days.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He terrifying violence upon the blood of a soul shall flee even to the pit; none shall hold fast upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He going uprightly shall be saved; and he being violent in the ways shall fall at once.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He working his land shall be filled with bread: and he pursuing the vain shall be filled with poverty.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A man of faithfulness multiplied blessings: and he hasting to be rich shall not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To look upon faces is not good and for a morsel of bread the man will transgress.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A man of evil eye hasted for riches, and knew not that want shall come upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He reproving a man, afterwards shall find favor more than he smoothing the tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He stripping his father and his mother, and saying, No transgression; is companion to a man destroying.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He enlarging the soul shall excite strife: and he trusting upon Jehovah shall he made fat.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He trusting in his heart is foolish: and he going in wisdom shall be delivered.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He giving to the poor wants not: and he hiding his eyes increased curses.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the rising up of the unjust, man shalt hide: and in their perishing, the lust shall increase.</verse>
</chapter>