<chapter book="Proverbs" number="29" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A Man of reproofs hardening the neck, shall be suddenly broken, and no healing.</verse>
  <verse number="2">In the increasing of the just the people will rejoice: and in the ruling of the unjust one the people will groan.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A man loving wisdom will gladden his father: and he feeding harlots shall destroy riches.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A king in judgment shall establish the land: and a man of presents shall overthrow it.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A man making smooth against his neighbor spreads a net for his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the transgression of an evil man is a snare: and the just one shall rejoice and be glad:</verse>
  <verse number="7">The just one knew the judgment of the poor: the unjust one will not understand knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Men of derision will kindle up a city: and the wise will turn away anger.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A wise man contending with a foolish man and raging and laughing, and no rest.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Men of bloods will hate the upright one: and the upright will seek his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The foolish one will bring forth all his spirit; and the wise one will restrain it back.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A ruler listening to the word of falsehood, all serving him are unjust.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The poor one and the man of oppressions met together: Jehovah enlightening the eyes of them both.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The king judging the poor in truth, his throne shall be established for a testimony.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The rod and reproofs will give wisdom: and the youth being left shames his mother.</verse>
  <verse number="16">In increasing the unjust, transgressions will increase: and the just all look upon their fall.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Correct thy son and he shall cause thee to rest, and he shall give delight to thy soul.</verse>
  <verse number="18">In no vision the people shall be unruly: and he watching the law, happy is he.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A servant will not be corrected by words: for he will understand and not answer.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Thou sawest a man hasty in his words: hope to the foolish one more than to him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He bringing up his servant delicately from youth, and his latter state will be a child.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A man of anger will excite strife, and the possessor of wrath increased transgression.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A man’s pride shall bring him low: and honor shall uphold him humble of spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He dividing with a thief, hates his soul: he shall hear cursing and shall not announce.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The fear of man will give a snare: and he trusting in Jehovah shall be exalted.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Many are seeking the face of the ruler, and from Jehovah a man’s judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="27">A man of iniquity is an abomination of the just; and the upright of way, an abomination of the unjust one.</verse>
</chapter>