<chapter book="Proverbs" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, thou shalt not forget my law, and thy heart shall guard my commands:</verse>
  <verse number="2">For length of days and years of life, and peace they shall add to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Mercy and truth shall not forsake thee: bind them upon thy throat; write them upon the tablet of thy heart:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And find grace and good understanding in the eyes of God and man.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Trust to Jehovah with all thy heart; and thou shalt not lean to thine understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In all thy ways know him, and he will make straight thy paths.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thou shalt not be wise in thine eyes: fear Jehovah and depart from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">It shall be healing to thy sinews, and moistening to thy bones.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Honor Jehovah from thy substance, and from the first-fruits of all thy produce.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And thy storehouses shall be filled with abundance, and thy wine-vats shall break forth with new wine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, thou shalt not reject the instruction of Jehovah, and thou shalt not loathe upon his reproofs:</verse>
  <verse number="12">For whom Jehovah shall love he will rebuke, as a father the son he will delight in.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Happy the man finding wisdom; and the man shall bring forth understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For good her gain above the gain of silver, and her increase above gold.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She is precious above red corals: and all thy delights shall not be equal with her.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Length of days in her right hand; in her left, riches and honor.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Her ways the ways of pleasantness, and all her beaten paths, peace.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She is a tree of life to all holding upon her: and happy he holding her fast.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Jehovah by wisdom founded the earth; he prepared the heavens by understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By his knowledge the depths were rent, and the clouds will drop dew.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, they shall not depart from thine eyes: keep counsel and meditation:</verse>
  <verse number="22">And they shall be life to thy soul, and grace to thy throat.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then shalt thou go thy way confidently, and thy foot shall not stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If thou shalt lie down thou shalt not be afraid: and thou liest down and thy sleep shall be sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Thou shalt not be afraid from sudden terror, and from the destruction of the unjust when it shall come.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For Jehovah shall be in thy confidence, and he watched thy foot from being taken.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thou shalt not withhold good from those possessing it in its being to the power of thy hand to do.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Thou shalt not say to thy neighbor, Go, and turn back, and to-morrow I will give; and there is with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Thou shalt not fabricate evil upon thy neighbor, and he dwelling confidently with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Thou shalt not contend with man to no purpose, if he did thee no evil.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Thou shalt not envy against a man of violence, and thou shalt choose in all his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the perverse is an abomination of Jehovah: and his intercourse with the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The curse of Jehovah is in the house of the unjust one: and he will bless the dwelling of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="34">But he will deride to those deriding: and he will give grace to the humble.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The wise shall inherit glory, and the foolish exalt dishonor.</verse>
</chapter>