<chapter book="Proverbs" number="31" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of Lemuel the king, the lifting up which his mother will instruct him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">What, my son? and what the son of my womb? and what the son of my vows?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Thou shalt not give thy strength to women, and thy ways to the destroying of kings.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Not for kings, O Lemuel, not for kings to drink and for princes the desire of strong drink:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Lest he shall drink and forget what is prescribed, and change the judgment of all the sons of affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Ye shall give strong drink to him perishing, and wine to the bitter of soul.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He shall drink and forget his poverty, and shall no more remember his toil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Open thy mouth for the dumb, for the judgment of all the sons of the surviving.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Open thy mouth; judge justly, and contend for the poor and needy.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Who shall find a woman of virtue? for her price is far above pearls.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The heart of her husband trusted in her, and he shall not want spoil.</verse>
  <verse number="12">She rewarded him good and not evil all the days of her life.</verse>
  <verse number="13">She sought wool and flax, and she will work in delight with her hands.</verse>
  <verse number="14">She was as the ships of the merchant; from far off she will bring her bread.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She will rise while yet night, and she will give food to her house, and a portion to her girls.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She purposed a field, and he will take it: from the fruit of her hands she planted a vineyard.</verse>
  <verse number="17">She girded her loins with strength, and she will strengthen her arms.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She tasted that her traffic is good: her light will not go out by night.</verse>
  <verse number="19">She sent forth her hands upon the spindle, and her hands take hold of the whirl.</verse>
  <verse number="20">She spread forth her hands to the poor, and sent forth her hands to the needy.</verse>
  <verse number="21">She will not fear for her house from snow, for all her house put on double.</verse>
  <verse number="22">She made for herself coverings; byssus and purple her clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Her husband was known in the gates, in his sitting with the old men of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="24">She made the under garment, and she will sell; and she gave a girdle to the Canaanite.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Strength and ornament her clothing; and she will laugh to the last day.</verse>
  <verse number="26">She opened her mouth in wisdom, and the law of mercy upon her tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="27">She viewed the goings of her house, and the bread of sloth she will not eat.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Her sons rose up and they will call her happy; her husband, and he will praise her.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Many daughters did virtue, and thou wentest up over all of them.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Favor a falsehood, and beauty vanity: a woman fearing Jehovah, she shall be praised.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Ye shall give her from the fruit of her hands, and her works shall praise her in the gates.</verse>
</chapter>