<chapter book="Proverbs" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hear, ye sons, the instruction of a father, and attend to know understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For I gave to you good instruction; ye shall not forsake my law.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For I was son to my father; tender and only before the face of my mother.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he taught me, and he will say to me, Thy heart shall hold fast my words: watch my commands and live.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Obtain wisdom, obtain understanding: thou shalt not forget, and thou shalt not decline from the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thou shalt not forsake her, and she will watch thee: love her, and she will guard thee.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Wisdom the beginning; obtain wisdom, and with all thine acquisition, obtain understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Lift her up and she shall exalt thee: she will honor thee when thou shalt embrace her.</verse>
  <verse number="9">She will give to thy head a garland of grace: a crown of glory she will deliver thee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Hear, my son, and receive my words, and the years of life shall be multiplied to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="11">In the way of wisdom I taught thee; I caused thee to tread in the tracks of uprightness.</verse>
  <verse number="12">In thy going, thy steps shall not be pressed; and if thou shalt run thou shalt not be weak.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Lay hold upon instruction, thou shalt not let go: guard her for she is thy life.</verse>
  <verse number="14">In the path of the unjust thou shalt not go, and thou shalt not advance in the way of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Reject it, thou shalt not pass in it; turn aside from it and pass by.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For they slept not, if they shall not do evil; and their sleep was taken away, if they shall not cause to falter.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For they ate the bread of injustice, and they will drink the wine of violences:</verse>
  <verse number="18">The path of the just as the light shining, going and shining even to the day prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The way of the unjust as darkness: they shall not know in what they shall stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, attend to my word; incline thine ear to my sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="21">They shall not turn aside from thine eyes; watch them in the midst of thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For they are life to those finding them, and healing to all their flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Guard thy heart with all watching, for from it the goings forth of life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Turn away from thee perverseness of mouth, and frowardness of lips remove far oft from thee.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Thine eyes shall look straight before, and thine eyelashes shall be right before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Make level the track of thy feet, and all thy ways shall be prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thou shalt not decline to the right and the left: turn away thy foot from evil.</verse>
</chapter>