<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if thou becamest surety for thy friend, thou didst strike thy hands for a stranger;</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thou wert snared with the sayings of thy mouth, thou wert taken with the sayings of thy mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do this now, my son, and deliver thyself when thou camest into the hand of thy friend; go humble thyself and enlarge thy friend.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou shalt not give sleep to thine eyes, and slumber to thine eyelashes.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Deliver thyself as the roe from the hand, and as the bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go to the ant, thou slothful one; see her ways, and be wise:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Which no leader to her, scribe and ruler;</verse>
  <verse number="8">She will prepare in summer her bread, gathering her food in harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">How long, O slothful one, wilt thou lie down? when wilt thou rise from thy sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to lie down:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And thy poverty came as he going, and thy want as a man of the shield.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A man of Belial, a man of iniquity, goes with perverseness of mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Pinching the eyes, speaking with the feet, teaching with his fingers;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Perverseness in his heart, fabricating evil in all time, he will send forth strifes.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For this, his destruction shall come suddenly; in a moment he shall be broken, and none healing.</verse>
  <verse number="16">These six Jehovah hated, and seven an abomination of his soul:</verse>
  <verse number="17">Eyes being lifted up; a tongue of falsehood, and hands shedding innocent blood,</verse>
  <verse number="18">A heart fabricating purposes of iniquity; feet being quick to run to evil,</verse>
  <verse number="19">A witness of falsehood, breathing out lies, and sending strife between brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, watch the commands of thy father, and thou shalt not reject the laws of thy mother:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Tie them always upon thy heart; bind them upon thy throat.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In thy going about it shall lead thee; in thy lying down it shall watch over thee; and awaking, it shall speak to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the command is a lamp, and the law a light; and the way of life the reproof of instruction:</verse>
  <verse number="24">To watch thee from the woman of evil, from the smoothness of the strange tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Thou shalt not desire her beauty in thy heart, and she shall not take thee with her eyelashes.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For by a woman a harlot, even to a round of bread: and a man’s wife will hunt the precious soul.</verse>
  <verse number="27">A man taking fire in his bosom, shall his garments not be burnt?</verse>
  <verse number="28">If a man shall go upon burning coals shall his feet not be burnt?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So he going in to his neighbor’s wife; all touching upon her shall not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="30">They will not despise a thief if he shall steal to fill up his soul; for he will be hungry.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And being found he shall recompense seven fold; he shall give all the substance of his house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He committing adultery with a woman lacked a heart: destroying his soul he will do it.</verse>
  <verse number="33">A blow and contempt shall he find; and his reproach shall not be wiped away.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For jealousy is the wrath of man, and he will not spare in the day of vengeance.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He will not lift up the face of any ransom, and he will not be willing if thou shalt increase the reward.</verse>
</chapter>