<chapter book="Proverbs" number="9" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wisdom built her house, she hewed out her seven pillars:</verse>
  <verse number="2">She slaughtered her slaughter; she mingled her wine; also she prepared her table.</verse>
  <verse number="3">She sent forth her girls: she will call upon the wings of the heights of the city,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who the simple, he shall turn aside here: he wanting heart, she said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Come ye, eat of my bread, and drink ye of the wine I mingled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Forsake ye the foolish, and live; and go straight in the way of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He instructing him mocking received to himself dishonor: and he reproving to the unjust one, his blemish.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thou shalt not reprove him mocking, lest he shall hate thee: reprove to the wise one and he will love thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou shalt give to the wise one and he will be more wise: make known to the just one and he will add receiving.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The beginning of wisdom is the fear of Jehovah, and the knowledge of the holy ones is understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For in me thy days shall be multiplied, and years of life shall be added to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">If thou wert wise, thou wert wise for thyself: and thou mockedst, thou alone shalt suffer.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A woman of folly being noisy, simple, and she knew not anything.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And sitting at the door of her house, upon the throne of the heights of the city,</verse>
  <verse number="15">To call to those passing the way, making straight their paths:</verse>
  <verse number="16">Who is simple, he shall turn aside here: and he wanting heart, and she said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Stolen waters will be sweet, and the bread of secrets shall be pleasant.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he knew not that there the shades; her called ones in the depths of hades.</verse>
</chapter>