<chapter book="1 Kings" number="4" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now king Solomon was reigning over all of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And these were the leaders that he had: Azariah, the son of Zadok, the priest;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Elihoreph and Ahijah, the sons of Shisha, the scribes; Jehoshaphat, the son of Ahilud, the keeper of records;</verse>
  <verse number="4">Benaiah, the son of Jehoiada, over the army; and Zadok, and Abiathar, priests;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Azariah, the son of Nathan, over those who were assisting the king; Zabud, the son of Nathan, the priest, the friend of the king;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Ahishar, first ruler of the house; and Adoniram, the son of Abda, over the tribute.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Solomon had twelve commanders over all of Israel, who offered yearly provisions for the king and his house. For each was ministering the necessities, by each month of the year.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And these are their names: Benhur, on mount Ephraim;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Bendeker, in Makaz, and in Shaalbim, and in Beth-shemesh, and in Elon, and in Beth-hanan;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Benhesed, in Arubboth: his was Socoh and the entire land of Hepher;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Benabinadab, to whom was all of Naphath-Dor, who had Taphath, the daughter of Solomon, as wife;</verse>
  <verse number="12">Baana, the son of Ahilud, who was reigning in Taanach, and Megiddo, and all of Bethshean, which is beside Zarethan and below Jezreel, from Bethshean as far as Abelmeholah, opposite Jokmeam;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Bengeber, in Ramoth Gilead, who had the town of Jair, the son of Manasseh, in Gilead; the same was first in the entire region of Argob, which is in Bashan, sixty great cities with walls that had bronze bars;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Ahinadab, the son of Iddo, who was first in Mahanaim;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Ahimaaz, in Naphtali, and he also had Basemath, the daughter of Solomon, in marriage;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Baana, the son of Hushai, in Asher and in Bealoth;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Jehoshaphat, the son of Paruah, in Issachar;</verse>
  <verse number="18">Shimei, the son of Ela, in Benjamin;</verse>
  <verse number="19">Geber, the son of Uri, in the land of Gilead, in the land of Sihon, king of the Amorites, and of Og, king of Bashan, over all who were in that land.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Judah and Israel were innumerable, like the sand of the sea in multitude: eating and drinking, and rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Now Solomon had, in his dominion, all the kingdoms, from the river to the land of the Philistines, even to the border of Egypt. And they offered gifts to him, and they served him all the days of his life.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the provisions of Solomon, for each day, were thirty cor of fine wheat flour, and sixty cor of meal,</verse>
  <verse number="23">ten fattened oxen, and twenty oxen from the pastures, and one hundred rams, aside from the venison of stags, roe deer, and gazelles, and fattened poultry.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For he had obtained the entire region which was beyond the river, from Tiphsah as far as Gaza, and all the kings of those regions. And he had peace on every side all around.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And so, Judah and Israel were living without any fear, each one under his own vine and under his own fig tree, from Dan as far as Beersheba, during all the days of Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Solomon had forty thousand stalls of chariot horses, and twelve thousand riding horses.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the above-stated commanders of the king nourished these. And they also offered the necessities for the table of king Solomon, with immense diligence, each in his time.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Also, they brought barley and straw for the horses and beasts of burden, to the place where the king was, just as it was appointed to them.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And God gave wisdom to Solomon, and an exceedingly great prudence, and a spacious heart, like the sand which is on the shore of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the wisdom of Solomon surpassed the wisdom of all the East, and of the Egyptians.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And he was wiser than all men: wiser than Ethan, the Ezrahite, and Heman, and Calcol, and Darda, the sons of Mahol. And he was renowned in all the nations on every side.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Solomon also spoke three thousand parables. And his verses were one thousand and five.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he discoursed about trees, from the cedar which is in Lebanon, to the hyssop which grows out from the wall. And he explained about beasts, and birds, and reptiles, and fish.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And they came from all the peoples in order to hear the wisdom of Solomon, and from all the kings of the earth, who were hearing about his wisdom.</verse>
</chapter>