<chapter book="Numbers" number="10" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah will speak to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Make to thyself two trumpets of silver; turned work shalt thou make them: and they were to thee for calling the assembly and for the removing the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And they sounded with them, and they assembled to thee all the assembly at the door of the tent of appointment.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And if they shall sound with one, and to thee assembled the chiefs of the heads of the thousands of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And ye sounded the signal, and the camps encamping eastward, removed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And ye sounded the signal the second time, and the camps encamping to the south, removed: they shall sound the signal for their removings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And in the assembly being gathered together, ye shall sound, and shall not sound loud.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the sons of Aaron, the priests, shall sound with the trumpets; and they were to you for a law forever to your generations.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And when ye shall go out to war in your land against the enemy pressing you, and ye sounded the signal in the trumpets; and ye were remembered before Jehovah your God, and ye were saved from your enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And in the day of your gladness, and in your appointments, and in the heads of your mouths, and ye shall sound with the trumpets over your burnt-offerings and over the sacrifices of your peace; and they were to you for a remembrance before your God: I am Jehovah your God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And it shall be in the second year, in the second month, in the twentieth of the month, the cloud was taken up from the dwelling of testimony.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the sons of Israel will remove for their departure from the desert of Sinai; and the cloud will dwell in the desert of Paran.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they will remove first, at the mouth of Jehovah, by the hand of Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the flag of the camp of Judah will remove first according to their army: and over his army, Nashon, son of Amminadab.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Issachar, Nethaneel, son of Zuar.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Zebulon, Eliab, son of Helon.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the dwelling was taken down, and the sons of Gershon and the sons of Merari removed, lifting up the dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the flag of the camp of Reuben removed according to their army, and over his army, Elizur, son of Shedur.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Simeon, Shelumiel, son of Zurishaddai.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Gad, Eliasaph, son of Deuel.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the Kohathites removed, lifting up the holy place, and they raised up the dwelling till their coining.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the flag of the camp of the sons of Ephraim removed according to their army, and over his army, Elishama, son of Ammihud.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Manasseh, Gamaliel, son of Pedahzur.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Benjamin, Abidan, son of Gideoni.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the flag of the camp of the sons of Dan removed, bringing up the rear to all the camps according to their army: and over his army, Ahiezer, son of Ammishaddai.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And over the army of the tribe of the sons of Asher, Pagiel, the son of Ocran.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And over the army of the tribe of the sons is of Naphtali, Ahira, son of Enan.</verse>
  <verse number="28">These the departures of the sons of Israel according to their army, and they shall remove.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Moses will say to Hobab, son of Raguel the Midianite, father-in-law of Moses, We are removing to the place which Jehovah said, I will give it to you: come thou with us, and we did good to thee; for Jehovah spake good concerning Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he will say to him, I will not go; but to my land, and to my kindred I will go.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And he will say, Thou shalt not leave us now, for upon this thou knewest we encamped in the desert, and thou wert to us for eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And it being when thou shalt go with us, it being that which Jehovah will do good with us and we did good to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And they will remove from the mountain of God, a way of three days: and the ark of the covenant of Jehovah removed before them, a way of three days, to search out for them a rest.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the cloud of Jehovah upon them the day in their removing out of the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And it shall be in removing the ark Moses will say, Rise, Jehovah, and thine enemies shall be scattered; and they hating thee shall flee from before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And in its encamping, he will say, Turn back, Jehovah, to the ten thousand thousands of Israel.</verse>
</chapter>