<chapter book="Numbers" number="32" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And much cattle was to the sons of Reuben and to the sons of Gad exceedingly strong: and they will see the land of Jazer and the land of Gilead, and behold, the place a place of cattle.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the sons of Gad and the sons of Reuben will come and will say to Moses, and to Eleazar the priest, and to the chiefs of the assembly, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Ataroth, and Dibon, and Jazer, and Nimrah, and Heshbon, and Elealeh, and Shebam, and Nebo, and Beon,</verse>
  <verse number="4">The land which Jehovah smote before the assembly of Israel, it is a land of cattle, and to thy servants are cattle.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they will say, If we found grace in thine eyes, will this land be given to thy servants for a possession; ye will not cause us to pass over Jordan.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Moses will say to the sons of Gad And to the sons of Reuben, Shall your brethren go forth to battle, and will ye sit here?</verse>
  <verse number="7">And wherefore will ye hinder the heart of the sons of Israel from passing over to the land which Jehovah gave to them?</verse>
  <verse number="8">So did your fathers in my sending them from Kadesh-Barnea to see the land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they will go up to the valley of Eshcol, and will see the land, and hinder the heart of the sons of Israel not to go to the land which Jehovah gave to them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jehovah’s anger will kindle in that day, and he will swear, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="11">If the men coming up out of Egypt, from the son of twenty years and above, shall see the land which I sware to Abraham, to Isaak and to Jacob; for they filled not up after me:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Except Caleb, son of Jephunneh the Kenezite, and Joshua, son of Nun: for they filled up after Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the anger of Jehovah will kindle against Israel, and he will cause them to wander in the desert forty years, till the finishing of all the generation having done evil in the eyes of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And behold, ye rise up instead of your fathers, a growth of men sinners, to add yet to the burning anger of Jehovah to Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="15">When ye shall turn back from after him, and he will add yet to leave him in the desert; and ye will destroy all this people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they will draw near to him, and say, Sheep-folds will we build for our cattle here, and cities for our little ones.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And we will arm ourselves, basting on before the sons of Israel, till we brought them to their place: and our little ones shall dwell in fortified cities because of the inhabitants of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="18">We will not turn back to our houses till the sons of Israel inherit each his inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For we will not inherit with them from the other side of Jordan and forward; for our inheritance has come to us from this side of Jordan from the risings.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Moses will say to them, If ye will do this word, if ye will arm yourselves before Jehovah for battle,</verse>
  <verse number="21">And all to you being armed, pass over Jordan before Jehovah, till his driving out his enemies from his face,</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the land subdued before Jehovah: and afterwards ye shall turn back, and be unpunished from Jehovah and from Israel; and this land shall be to you for a possession before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And if ye shall not do this, behold, ye sinned to Jehovah: and know ye, your sin which shall find you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Build to you cities for your little ones, and folds for your sheep; and ye shall do that coming out of your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the sons of Gad and the sons of Reuben will speak to Moses, saying, Thy servants will do as my lord commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Our little ones, our wives, our possessions, and all our cattle, shall be there in the cities of Gilead:</verse>
  <verse number="27">And thy servants will pass over, all being armed, to war before Jehovah for battle, as my lord spake.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Moses will command Eleazar the priest, concerning them, and Joshua, the son of Nun, and the heads of the fathers of the tribes of the sons of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Moses will say to them, If the sons of Gad and the sons of Reuben will pass over Jordan with you, all being armed for battle before Jehovah, and the land be subdued before you; and give ye to them the land of Gilead for a possession.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And if they will not pass over armed with you, and they possessed in the midst of you in the land of Canaan.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And the sons of Gad and the sons of Reuben will answer, saying, What Jehovah spake to thy servants, so will we do.</verse>
  <verse number="32">We will pass over armed before Jehovah to the land of Canaan, and to us shall be the possession of our inheritance from the other side to Jordan.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Moses will give to them, to the sons of Gad and to the sons of Reuben, and to half the tribe of Manasseh, son of Joseph, the kingdom of Sihon, king of the Amorites, and the kingdom of Og, king of Bashan, the land with its cities in the bounds, the cities of the land round about.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the sons of Gad will build Dibon and Ataroth, and Aroer,</verse>
  <verse number="35">And Atroth, Shophan, and Jazer, and Jogbehah,</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the house of Nimrah, and the house of Haran, fortified cities: and sheep-folds.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And the sons of Reuben built Heshbon, and Elealeh, and Kirjathaim,</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Nebo, and Baal-Meon (the name being changed), and Shibmah: and they will call by names the names of the cities which they built.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And the sons of Machir, the son of Manasseh, will go to Gilead, and take it and drive out the Amorite which is in it.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And Moses will give Gilead to Machir, son of Manasseh, and he will dwell in it.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And Jair, the son of Manasseh, went, and he will take their villages, and he will call them the villages of Jair.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And Nobah went, and he will take Kenath and its houses, and he will call it Nobah in his name.</verse>
</chapter>