<chapter book="Mark" number="15" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">At earliest dawn, after the High Priests had held a consultation with the Elders and Scribes, they and the entire Sanhedrin bound Jesus and took Him away and handed Him over to Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="2">So Pilate questioned Him. “Are *you* the King of the Jews?” he asked. “I am,” replied Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then, as the High Priests went on heaping accusations on Him,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Pilate again and again asked Him, “Do you make no reply? Listen to the many charges they are bringing against you.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">But Jesus made no further answer: so that Pilate wondered.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Now at the Festival it was customary for Pilate to release to the Jews any one prisoner whom they might beg off from punishment;</verse>
  <verse number="7">and at this time a man named Barabbas was in prison among the insurgents—persons who in the insurrection had committed murder.</verse>
  <verse number="8">So the people came crowding up, asking Pilate to grant them the usual favour.</verse>
  <verse number="9">“Shall I release for you the King of the Jews?” answered Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For he could see that it was out of sheer spite that the High Priests had handed Him over.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But the High Priests urged on the crowd to obtain Barabbas’s release in preference;</verse>
  <verse number="12">and when Pilate again asked them, “What then shall I do to the man you call King of the Jews?”</verse>
  <verse number="13">they once more shouted out, “Crucify Him!”</verse>
  <verse number="14">“Why, what crime has he committed?” asked Pilate. But they vehemently shouted, “Crucify Him!”</verse>
  <verse number="15">So Pilate, wishing to satisfy the mob, released Barabbas for them, and after scourging Jesus handed Him over for crucifixion.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then the soldiers led Him away into the court of the Palace (the Praetorium)</verse>
  <verse number="17">they arrayed Him in crimson, placed on His head a wreath of thorny twigs which they had twisted,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and went on to salute Him with shouts of “Long live the King of the Jews.”</verse>
  <verse number="19">Then they began to beat Him on the head with a cane, to spit on Him, and to do Him homage on bended knees.</verse>
  <verse number="20">At last, having finished their sport, they took the robe off Him, put His own clothes on Him, and led Him out to crucify Him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">One Simon, a Cyrenaean, the father of Alexander and Rufus, was passing along, coming from the country: him they compelled to carry His cross.</verse>
  <verse number="22">So they brought Him to the place called Golgotha, which, being translated, means ‘Skull-ground.’</verse>
  <verse number="23">Here they offered Him wine mixed with myrrh; but He refused it.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Then they crucified Him. This done, they divided His garments among them, drawing lots to decide what each should take.</verse>
  <verse number="25">It was nine o’clock in the morning when they crucified Him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Over His head was the notice in writing of the charge against Him: THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And together with Jesus they crucified two robbers, one at His right hand and one at His left.</verse>
  <verse number="28"></verse>
  <verse number="29">And all the passers-by reviled Him. They shook their heads at Him and said, “Ah! you who were for destroying the Sanctuary and building a new one in three days,</verse>
  <verse number="30">come down from the cross and save yourself.”</verse>
  <verse number="31">In the same way the High Priests also, as well as the Scribes, kept on scoffing at Him, saying to one another, “He has saved others: himself he cannot save!</verse>
  <verse number="32">This Christ, the King of Israel, let him come down now from the cross, that we may see and believe.” Even the men who were being crucified with Him heaped insults on Him.</verse>
  <verse number="33">At noon there came a darkness over the whole land, lasting till three o’clock in the afternoon.</verse>
  <verse number="34">But at three o’clock Jesus cried out with a loud voice, “Elohi, Elohi, lama sabachthani?” which means, “My God, My God, why hast Thou forsaken me?”</verse>
  <verse number="35">Some of the bystanders, hearing Him, said, “Listen, he is calling for Elijah!”</verse>
  <verse number="36">Then a man ran to fill a sponge with sour wine, and he put it on the end of a cane and placed it to His lips, saying at the same time, “Wait! let us see whether Elijah will come and take him down.”</verse>
  <verse number="37">But Jesus uttered a loud cry and yielded up His spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And the curtain in the Sanctuary was torn in two, from top to bottom.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And when the Centurion who stood in front of the cross saw that He was dead, he exclaimed, “This man was indeed God’s Son.”</verse>
  <verse number="40">There were also a party of women looking on from a distance; among them being both Mary of Magdala and Mary the mother of James the Little and of Joses, and Salome—</verse>
  <verse number="41">all of whom in the Galilaean days had habitually been with Him and cared for Him, as well as many other women who had come up to Jerusalem with Him.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Towards sunset, as it was the Preparation—that is, the day preceding the Sabbath—</verse>
  <verse number="43">Joseph of Arimathaea came, a highly respected member of the Council, who himself also was living in expectation of the Kingdom of God. He summoned up courage to go in to see Pilate and beg for the body of Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="44">But Pilate could hardly believe that He was already dead. He called, however, for the Centurion and inquired whether He had been long dead;</verse>
  <verse number="45">and having ascertained the fact he granted the body to Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="46">He, having bought a sheet of linen, took Him down, wrapped Him in the sheet and laid Him in a tomb hewn in the rock; after which he rolled a stone against the entrance to the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Mary of Magdala and Mary the mother of Joses were looking on to see where He was put.</verse>
</chapter>