<chapter book="Mark" number="3" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">At another time, when He went to the synagogue, there was a man there with one arm shrivelled up.</verse>
  <verse number="2">They closely watched Him to see whether He would cure him on the Sabbath—so as to have a charge to bring against Him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">“Come forward,” said He to the man with the shrivelled arm.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Then He asked them, “Are we allowed to do good on the Sabbath, or to do evil? to save a life, or to destroy one?” They remained silent.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Grieved and indignant at the hardening of their hearts, He looked round on them with anger, and said to the man, “Stretch out your arm.” He stretched it out, and the arm was completely restored.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But no sooner had the Pharisees left the synagogue than they held a consultation with the Herodians against Jesus, to devise some means of destroying Him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Accordingly Jesus withdrew with His disciples to the Lake, and a vast crowd of people from Galilee followed Him;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and from Judaea and Jerusalem and Idumaea and from beyond the Jordan and from the district of Tyre and Sidon there came to Him a vast crowd, hearing of all that He was doing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">So He gave directions to His disciples to keep a small boat in constant attendance on Him because of the throng—to prevent their crushing Him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For He had cured many of the people, so that all who had any ailments pressed upon Him, to touch Him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the foul spirits, whenever they saw Him, threw themselves down at His feet, screaming out: “You are the Son of God.”</verse>
  <verse number="12">But He many a time checked them, forbidding them to say who He was.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then He went up the hill; and those whom He Himself chose He called, and they came to Him.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He appointed twelve of them, that they might be with Him, and that He might also send them to proclaim His Message,</verse>
  <verse number="15">with authority to expel the demons.</verse>
  <verse number="16">These twelve were Simon (to whom He gave the surname of Peter)</verse>
  <verse number="17">James the son of Zabdi and John the brother of James (these two He surnamed Boanerges, that is ‘Sons of Thunder’)</verse>
  <verse number="18">Andrew, Philip, Bartholomew, Matthew, Thomas, James the son of Alphaeus, Thaddaeus, Simon the Cananaean,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and Judas Iscariot, the man who also betrayed Him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And He went into a house. But again the crowd assembled, so that there was no opportunity for them even to snatch a meal.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Hearing of this, His relatives came to seize Him by force, for they said, “He is out of his mind.”</verse>
  <verse number="22">The Scribes, too, who had come down from Jerusalem said, “He has Baal-zebul in him; and it is by the power of the Prince of the demons that he expels the demons.”</verse>
  <verse number="23">So He called them to Him, and using figurative language He appealed to them, saying, “How is it possible for Satan to expel Satan?</verse>
  <verse number="24">For if civil war breaks out in a kingdom, nothing can make that kingdom last;</verse>
  <verse number="25">and if a family splits into parties, that family cannot continue.</verse>
  <verse number="26">So if Satan has risen in arms and has made war upon himself, stand he cannot, but meets his end.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Nay, no one can go into a strong man’s house and carry off his property, unless he first binds the strong man, and then he will plunder his house.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In solemn truth I tell you that all their sins may be pardoned to the sons of men, and all their blasphemies, however they may have blasphemed;</verse>
  <verse number="29">but whoever blasphemes against the Holy Spirit, he remains for ever unabsolved: he is guilty of a sin of the Ages.”</verse>
  <verse number="30">This was because they said, “He is possessed by a foul spirit.”</verse>
  <verse number="31">By this time His mother and His brothers arrive, and standing outside they send a message to Him to call Him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Now a crowd was sitting round Him; so they tell Him, “Your mother and your brothers and sisters are outside, inquiring for you.”</verse>
  <verse number="33">“Who are my mother and my brothers?” He replied.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And, fixing His eyes on the people who were sitting round Him in a circle, He said,</verse>
  <verse number="35">“Here are my mother and my brothers. For wherever there is one who has been obedient to God, there is my brother—my sister—and my mother.”</verse>
</chapter>