<chapter book="Mark" number="6" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Leaving that place He came into His own country, accompanied by His disciples.</verse>
  <verse number="2">On the Sabbath He proceeded to teach in the synagogue; and many, as they heard Him, were astonished. “Where did he acquire all this?” they asked. “What is this wisdom that has been given to him? And what are these marvellous miracles which his hands perform?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is not this the carpenter, Mary’s son, the brother of James and Joses, Jude and Simon? And do not his sisters live here among us?” So they turned angrily away.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But Jesus said to them, “There is no Prophet without honour except in his own country, and among his own relatives, and in his own home.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">And He could not do any miracle there, except that He laid His hands on a few who were out of health and cured them; and</verse>
  <verse number="6">He wondered at their unbelief. So He went round the adjacent villages, teaching.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Then summoning the Twelve to Him, He proceeded to send them out by twos, and gave them authority over the foul spirits.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He charged them to take nothing for the journey except a stick; no bread, no bag, and not a penny in their pockets,</verse>
  <verse number="9">but to go wearing sandals. “And do not,” He said, “put on an extra under garment.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Wherever you enter a house, make it your home till you leave that place.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But wherever they will not receive you or listen to you, when you leave shake off the very dust from under your feet to bear witness concerning them.”</verse>
  <verse number="12">So they set out, and preached in order that men might repent.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Many demons they expelled, and many invalids they anointed with oil and cured.</verse>
  <verse number="14">King Herod heard of all this (for the name of Jesus had become widely known)</verse>
  <verse number="15">Others asserted that He was Elijah. Others again said, “He is a Prophet, like one of the great Prophets.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">But when Herod heard of Him, he said, “The John, whom I beheaded, has come back to life.”</verse>
  <verse number="17">For Herod himself had sent and had had John arrested and had kept him in prison in chains, for the sake of Herodias, his brother Philip’s wife; because he had married her.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For John had repeatedly told Herod, “You have no right to be living with your brother’s wife.”</verse>
  <verse number="19">Therefore Herodias hated him and wished to take his life, but could not;</verse>
  <verse number="20">for Herod stood in awe of John, knowing him to be an upright and holy man, and he protected him. After listening to him he was in great perplexity, and yet he found a pleasure in listening.</verse>
  <verse number="21">At length Herodias found her opportunity. Herod on his birthday gave a banquet to the nobles of his court and to the tribunes and the principal people in Galilee,</verse>
  <verse number="22">at which Herodias’s own daughter came in and danced, and so charmed Herod and his guests that he said to her, “Ask me for anything you please, and I will give it to you.”</verse>
  <verse number="23">He even swore to her, “Whatever you ask me for I will give you, up to half my kingdom.”</verse>
  <verse number="24">She at once went out and said to her mother: “What shall I ask for?” “The head of John the Baptizer,” she replied.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The girl immediately came in, in haste, to the King and made her request. “My desire is,” she said, “that you will give me, here and now, on a dish, the head of John the Baptist.”</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then the King, though intensely sorry, yet for the sake of his oaths, and of his guests, would not break faith with her.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He at once sent a soldier of his guard with orders to bring John’s head. So he went and beheaded him in the prison,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and brought his head on a dish and gave it to the young girl, who gave it to her mother.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When John’s disciples heard of it, they came and took away his body and laid it in a tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="30">When the Apostles had re-assembled round Jesus, they reported to Him all they had done and all they had taught.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Then He said to them, “Come away, all of you, to a quiet place, and rest awhile.” For there were many coming and going, so that they had no time even for meals.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Accordingly they sailed away in the boat to a solitary place apart.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But the people saw them going, and many knew them; and coming by land they ran together there from all the neighbouring towns, and arrived before them.</verse>
  <verse number="34">So when Jesus landed, He saw a vast multitude; and His heart was moved with pity for them, because they were like sheep which have no shepherd, and He proceeded to teach them many things.</verse>
  <verse number="35">By this time it was late; so His disciples came to Him, and said, “This is a lonely place, and the hour is now late:</verse>
  <verse number="36">send them away that they may go to the farms and villages near here and buy themselves something to eat.”</verse>
  <verse number="37">“Give them food yourselves,” He replied. “Are we,” they asked, “to go and buy two hundred shillings’ worth of bread and give them food?”</verse>
  <verse number="38">“How many loaves have you?” He inquired; “go and see.” So they found out, and said, “Five; and a couple of fish.”</verse>
  <verse number="39">So He directed them to make all sit down in companies on the green grass.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And they sat down in rows of hundreds and of fifties.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Then He took the five loaves and the two fish, and lifting His eyes to Heaven He blessed the food. Then He broke the loaves into portions which He went on handing to the disciples to distribute; giving pieces also of the two fish to them all.</verse>
  <verse number="42">All ate and were fully satisfied.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And they carried away broken portions enough to fill twelve baskets, besides pieces of the fish.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Those who ate the bread were 5,000 adult men.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Immediately afterwards He made His disciples go on board the boat and cross over to Bethsaida, leaving Him behind to dismiss the crowd.</verse>
  <verse number="46">He then bade the people farewell, and went away up the hill to pray.</verse>
  <verse number="47">When evening was come, the boat was half way across the Lake, while he Himself was on shore alone.</verse>
  <verse number="48">But when He saw them distressed with rowing (for the wind was against them)</verse>
  <verse number="49">They saw Him walking on the water, and thinking that it was a spirit they cried out;</verse>
  <verse number="50">for they all saw Him and were terrified. He, however, immediately spoke to them. “There is no danger,” He said; “it is I; be not alarmed.”</verse>
  <verse number="51">Then He went up to them on board the boat, and the wind lulled; and they were beside themselves with silent amazement.</verse>
  <verse number="52">For they had not learned the lesson taught by the loaves, but their minds were dull.</verse>
  <verse number="53">Having crossed over they drew to land in Gennesaret and came to anchor.</verse>
  <verse number="54">But no sooner had they gone ashore than the people immediately recognized Him.</verse>
  <verse number="55">Then they scoured the whole district, and began to bring Him the sick on their mats wherever they heard He was.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And enter wherever He might—village or town or hamlet—they laid their sick in the open places, and entreated Him to let them touch were it but the tassel of His robe; and all, whoever touched Him, were restored to health.</verse>
</chapter>