<chapter book="Mark" number="7" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the Pharisees, with certain Scribes who had come from Jerusalem, came to Him in a body.</verse>
  <verse number="2">They had noticed that some of His disciples were eating their food with ‘unclean’ (that is to say, unwashed)</verse>
  <verse number="3"></verse>
  <verse number="4">and when they come from market they will not eat without bathing first; and they have a good many other customs which they have received traditionally and cling to, such as the rinsing of cups and pots and of bronze utensils, and the washing of beds.)</verse>
  <verse number="5">So the Pharisees and Scribes put the question to Him: “Why do your disciples transgress the traditions of the Elders, and eat their food with unclean hands?”</verse>
  <verse number="6">“Rightly did Isaiah prophesy of you hypocrites,” He replied; “as it is written, “’This People honour Me with their lips, while their hearts are far away from Me:</verse>
  <verse number="7">But idle is their devotion while they lay down precepts which are mere human rules.’</verse>
  <verse number="8">“You neglect God’s Commandment: you hold fast to men’s traditions.”</verse>
  <verse number="9">“Praiseworthy indeed!” He added, “to set at nought God’s Commandment in order to observe your own traditions!</verse>
  <verse number="10">For Moses said, ‘Honour thy father and thy mother’ and again, ‘He who curses father or mother, let him die the death.’</verse>
  <verse number="11">But *you* say, ‘If a man says to his father or mother, It is a Korban (that is, a thing devoted to God)</verse>
  <verse number="12">And so you no longer allow him to do anything for his father or mother,</verse>
  <verse number="13">thus nullifying God’s precept by your tradition which you have handed down. And many things of that kind you do.”</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then Jesus called the people to Him again. “Listen to me, all of you,” He said, “and understand.</verse>
  <verse number="15">There is nothing outside a man which entering him can make him unclean; but it is the things which come out of a man that make him unclean.”</verse>
  <verse number="16"></verse>
  <verse number="17">After He had left the crowd and gone indoors, His disciples began to ask Him about this figure of speech.</verse>
  <verse number="18">“Have *you* also so little understanding?” He replied; “do you not understand that anything whatever that enters a man from outside cannot make him unclean,</verse>
  <verse number="19">because it does not go into his heart, but into his stomach, and passes away ejected from him?” By these words Jesus pronounced all kinds of food clean.</verse>
  <verse number="20">“What comes out of a man,” He added, “that it is which makes him unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For from within, out of men’s hearts, their evil purposes proceed—fornication, theft, murder, adultery,</verse>
  <verse number="22">covetousness, wickedness, deceit, licentiousness, envy, reviling, pride, reckless folly:</verse>
  <verse number="23">all these wicked things come out from within and make a man unclean.”</verse>
  <verse number="24">Then He rose and left that place and went into the neighbourhood of Tyre and Sidon. Here He entered a house and wished no one to know it, but He could not escape observation.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Forthwith a woman whose little daughter was possessed by a foul spirit heard of Him, and came and flung herself at His feet.</verse>
  <verse number="26">She was a Gentile woman, a Syro-phoenician by nation: and again and again she begged Him to expel the demon from her daughter.</verse>
  <verse number="27">“Let the children first eat all they want,” He said; “it is not right to take the children’s bread and throw it to the dogs.”</verse>
  <verse number="28">“True, Sir,” she replied, “and yet the dogs under the table eat the children’s scraps.”</verse>
  <verse number="29">“For those words of yours, go home,” He replied; “the demon has gone out of your daughter.”</verse>
  <verse number="30">So she went home, and found the child lying on the bed, and the demon gone.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Returning from the neighbourhood of Tyre, He came by way of Sidon to the Lake of Galilee, passing through the district of the Ten Towns.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Here they brought to Him a deaf man that stammered, on whom they begged Him to lay His hands.</verse>
  <verse number="33">So Jesus taking him aside, apart from the crowd, put His fingers into his ears, and spat, and moistened his tongue;</verse>
  <verse number="34">and looking up to Heaven He sighed, and said to him, “Ephphatha!” (that is, “Open!”)</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the man’s ears were opened, and his tongue became untied, and he began to speak perfectly.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Then Jesus charged them to tell no one; but the more He charged them, all the more did they spread the news far and wide.</verse>
  <verse number="37">The amazement was extreme. “He succeeds in everything he attempts,” they exclaimed; “he even makes deaf men hear and dumb men speak!”</verse>
</chapter>