<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="1" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Adam, Sheth, Enosh,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Kenan, Mahalaleel, Jered,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Henoch, Methuselah, Lamech,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Noah, Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Sons of Japheth: Gomer and Magog, and Madai, and Javan, and Tubal, and Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And sons of Gomer: Ashchenaz, and Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And sons of Javan: Elisha, and Tarshishah, Kittim, and Dodanim.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Sons of Ham: Cush, and Mizraim, Put, and Canaan.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And sons of Cush: Seba and Havilah, and Sabta, and Raamah, and Sabtecka. And sons of Raamah: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Cush begat Nimrod: he began to be a mighty one in the land.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Mizraim begat the Ludim, and the Anamim, and the Lehabim, and the Naphtuhim,</verse>
  <verse number="12">and the Pathrusim, and the Casluhim (from whom came out the Philistim), and the Caphtorim.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Canaan begat Zidon his first born, and Heth,</verse>
  <verse number="14">and the Jebusite, and the Amorite, and the Girgashite,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and the Hivite, and the Arkite, and the Sinite,</verse>
  <verse number="16">and the Arvadite, and the Zemarite, and the Hamathite.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Sons of Shem: Elam and Asshur, and Arphaxad, and Lud, and Aram, and Uz, and Hul, and Gether, and Meshech.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Arphaxad begat Shelah, and Shelah begat Eber.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And to Eber have been born two sons, the name of the one is Peleg, for in his days hath the land been divided, and the name of his brother is Joktan.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Joktan begat Almodad, and Sheleph, and Hazarmaveth, and Jerah,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Hadoram, and Uzal, and Diklah,</verse>
  <verse number="22">and Ebal, and Abimael, and Sheba,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and Ophir, and Havilah, and Jobab; all these are sons of Joktan.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Shem, Arphaxad, Shelah,</verse>
  <verse number="25">Eber, Peleg, Reu,</verse>
  <verse number="26">Serug, Nahor, Terah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">Abram—he is Abraham.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Sons of Abraham: Isaac and Ishmael.</verse>
  <verse number="29">These are their generations: first-born of Ishmael, Nebaioth, and Kedar, and Adheel, and Mibsam,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Mishma, and Dumah, Massa, Hadad, and Tema,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Jetur, Naphish, and Kedema. These are sons of Ishmael.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And sons of Keturah, Abraham’s concubine: she bare Zimran, and Jokshan, and Medan, and Midian, and Ishbak, and Shuah. And sons of Jokshan: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And sons of Midian: Ephah and Epher, and Henoch, and Abida, and Eldaah; all these are sons of Keturah.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Abraham begetteth Isaac. Sons of Isaac: Esau and Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Sons of Esau: Eliphaz, Reuel, and Jeush, and Jaalam, and Korah.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Sons of Eliphaz: Teman, and Omar, Zephi, and Gatam, Kenaz, and Timna, and Amalek.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Sons of Reuel: Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And sons of Seir: Lotan, and Shobal, and Zibeon, and Anah, and Dishon, and Ezar, and Dishan.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And sons of Lotan: Hori and Homam, and sister of Lotan is Timna.</verse>
  <verse number="40">Sons of Shobal: Alian, and Manahath, and Ebal, Shephi, and Onam. And sons of Zideon: Aiah and Anah.</verse>
  <verse number="41">The sons of Anah: Dishon. and sons of Dishon: Amram, and Eshban, and Ithran, and Cheran.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Sons of Ezer: Bilhan, and Zavan, Jakan. Sons of Dishan: Uz and Aran.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And these are the kings who reigned in the land of Edom before the reigning of a king of the sons of Israel: Bela son of Beor, and the name of his city is Dinhabah.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And Bela dieth, and reign in his stead doth Jobab son of Zerah from Bozrali;</verse>
  <verse number="45">and Jobab dieth, and reign in his stead doth Husham from the land of the Temanite;</verse>
  <verse number="46">and Husham dieth, and reign in his stead doth Hadad, son of Bedad (who smiteth Midian in the field of Moab) and the name of his city is Avith;</verse>
  <verse number="47">and Hadad dieth, and reign in his stead doth Samlah from Masrekah;</verse>
  <verse number="48">and Samlah dieth, and reign in his stead doth Shaul from Rehoboth of the River;</verse>
  <verse number="49">and Shaul dieth, and reign in his stead doth Baal-Hanan son of Achbor;</verse>
  <verse number="50">and Baal-Hanan dieth, and reign in his stead doth Hadad, and the name of his city is Pai, and the name of his wife is Mehetabel daughter of Matred, daughter of Me-Zahab; Hadad also dieth.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And chiefs of Edom are: chief Timnah, chief Aliah, chief Jetheth,</verse>
  <verse number="52">chief Aholibamah, chief Elah, chief Pinon,</verse>
  <verse number="53">chief Kenaz, chief Teman, chief Mibzar,</verse>
  <verse number="54">chief Magdiel, chief Iram. These are chiefs of Edom.</verse>
</chapter>