<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="4" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Sons of Judah: Pharez, Hezron, and Carmi, and Hur, and Shobal.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Reaiah son of Shobal begat Jahath, and Jahath begat Ahumai and Lahad; these are families of the Zorathite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And these are of the father of Etam: Jezreel, and Ishma, and Idbash; and the name of their sister is Hazzelelponi,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and Penuel is father of Gedor, and Ezer father of Hushah. These are sons of Hur, first-born of Ephratah, father of Beth-Lehem.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And to Ashhur father of Tekoa were two wives, Helah and Naarah;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Naarah beareth to him Ahuzzam, and Hepher, and Temeni, and Haahashtari: these are sons of Naarah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And sons of Helah: Zereth, and Zohar, and Ethnan.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Coz begat Anub, and Zobebah, and the families of Aharhel son of Harum.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Jabez is honoured above his brethren, and his mother called his name Jabez, saying, ‘Because I have brought forth with grief.’</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jabez calleth to the God of Israel, saying, ‘If blessing Thou dost bless me, then Thou hast made great my border, and Thy hand hath been with me, and Thou hast kept me from evil—not to grieve me;’ and God bringeth in that which he asked.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Chelub brother of Shuah begat Mehir; he is father of Eshton.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Eshton begat Beth-Rapha, and Paseah, and Tehinnah father of Ir-Nahash; these are men of Rechah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And sons of Kenaz: Othniel, and Seraiah; and sons of Othniel: Hathath.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Meonothai begat Ophrah, and Seraiah begat Joab father of the valley of artificers, for they were artificers.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And sons of Caleb son of Jephunneh: Iru, Elah, and Naam; and sons of Elah, even Kenaz.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And sons of Jehaleleel: Ziph and Ziphah, Tiria, and Asareel.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And sons of Ezra are Jether, and Mered, and Epher, and Jalon: and she beareth Miriam, and Shammai, and Ishbah father of Eshtemoa.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And his wife Jehudijah bare Jered father of Gedor, and Heber father of Socho, and Jekuthiel father of Zanoah. And these are sons of Bithiah daughter of Pharaoh, whom Mered took,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and sons of the wife of Hodiah sister of Nahom: Abi-Keilah the Garmite, and Eshtemoa the Maachathite.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And sons of Shimon are Amnon, and Rinnah, Ben-Hanon, and Tilon; and sons of Ishi: Zoheth, and Ben-Zoheth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Sons of Shelah son of Judah: Er father of Lecah, and Laadah father of Mareshah, and the families of the house of the service of fine linen, of the house of Ashbea;</verse>
  <verse number="22">and Jokim, and the men of Chozeba, and Joash, and Saraph, who ruled over Moab and Jashubi-Lehem; and these things are ancient.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They are the potters and inhabitants of Netaim and Gedera; with the king in his work they dwelt there.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Sons of Simeon: Nemuel, and Jamin, Jarib, Zerah, Shaul;</verse>
  <verse number="25">Shallum his son, Mibsam his son, Mishma his son.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And sons of Mishma: Hammuel his son, Zacchur his son, Shimei his son.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And to Shimei are sixteen sons and six daughters, and to his brethren there are not many sons, and none of their families have multiplied as much as the sons of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they dwell in Beer-Sheba, and Moladah, and Hazar-Shaul,</verse>
  <verse number="29">and in Bilhah, and in Ezem, and in Tolad,</verse>
  <verse number="30">and in Bethuel, and in Hormah, and in Ziklag,</verse>
  <verse number="31">and in Beth-Marcaboth, and in Hazar-Susim, and in Beth-Birei, and in Shaarim; these are their cities till the reigning of David.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And their villages are Etam, and Ain, Rimmon, and Tochen, and Ashan, five cities,</verse>
  <verse number="33">and all their villages that are round about these cities unto Baal; these are their dwellings, and they have their genealogy:</verse>
  <verse number="34">even Meshobab, and Jamlech, and Joshah son of Amaziah,</verse>
  <verse number="35">and Joel, and Jehu son of Josibiah, son of Seraiah, son of Asiel,</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Elioenai, and Jaakobah, and Jeshohaiah, and Asaiah, and Adiel, and Jesimiel, and Benaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and Ziza son of Shiphi, son of Allon, son of Jedaiah, son of Shimri, son of Shemaiah.</verse>
  <verse number="38">These who are coming in by name are princes in their families, and the house of their fathers have broken forth into a multitude;</verse>
  <verse number="39">and they go to the entrance of Gedor, unto the east of the valley, to seek pasture for their flock,</verse>
  <verse number="40">and they find pasture, fat and good, and the land broad of sides, and quiet, and safe, for of Ham are those dwelling there before.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And these who are written by name come in the days of Hezekiah king of Judah, and smite their tents, and the habitations that have been found there, and devote them to destruction unto this day, and dwell in their stead, because pasture for their flock is there.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And of them, of the sons of Simeon, there have gone to mount Seir, five hundred men, and Pelatiah, and Neariah, and Rephaiah, and Uzziel, sons of Ishi, at their head,</verse>
  <verse number="43">and they smite the remnant of those escaped of Amalek, and dwell there unto this day.</verse>
</chapter>