<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="8" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Benjamin begat Bela his first-born, Ashbel the second, and Aharah the third,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Nohah the fourth, and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And there are sons to Bela: Addar, and Gera,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and Abihud, and Abishua, and Naaman, and Ahoah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Gera, and Shephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And these are sons of Ehud: they are heads of fathers to the inhabitants of Geba, and they remove them unto Manahath;</verse>
  <verse number="7">and Naaman, and Ahiah, and Gera, he removed them, and begat Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Shaharaim begat in the field of Moab, after his sending them away; Hushim and Baara are his wives.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he begetteth of Hodesh his wife, Jobab, and Zibia, and Mesha, and Malcham,</verse>
  <verse number="10">and Jeuz, and Shachiah, and Mirmah. These are his sons, heads of fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And of Hushim he begat Ahitub and Elpaal.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And sons of Elpaal: Eber, and Misheam, and Shamer, (he built Ono and Lod and its small towns),</verse>
  <verse number="13">and Beriah and Shema, (they are the heads of fathers to the inhabitants of Aijalon—they caused to flee the inhabitants of Gath),</verse>
  <verse number="14">and Ahio, Shashak, and Jeremoth,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Zebadiah, and Arad, and Ader,</verse>
  <verse number="16">and Michael, and Ispah, and Joha, sons of Beriah,</verse>
  <verse number="17">and Zebadiah, and Meshullam, and Hezeki, and Heber,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and Ishmerai, and Jezliah, and Jobab, sons of Elpaal;</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Jakim, and Zichri, and Zabdi,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and Elienai, and Zillethai, and Eliel,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Adaiah, and Beraiah, and Shimrath, sons of Shimei;</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Ishpan, and Heber, and Eliel,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and Abdon, and Zichri, and Hanan,</verse>
  <verse number="24">and Hananiah, and Elam, and Antothijah,</verse>
  <verse number="25">and Iphedeiah, and Penuel, sons of Shashak;</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Shamsherai, and Shehariah, and Athaliah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and Jaareshiah, and Eliah, and Zichri, sons of Jeroham.</verse>
  <verse number="28">These are heads of fathers, by their generations, heads; these dwelt in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And in Gibeon hath the father of Gibeon dwelt, and the name of his wife is Maachah;</verse>
  <verse number="30">and his son, the first-born, is Abdon, and Zur, and Kish, and Baal, and Nadab,</verse>
  <verse number="31">and Gedor, and Ahio, and Zacher;</verse>
  <verse number="32">and Mikloth begat Shimeah. And they also over-against their brethren dwelt in Jerusalem with their brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And Ner begat Kish, and Kish begat Saul, and Saul begat Jonathan, and Malchi-Shua, and Abinadab, and Esh-Baal.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And a son of Jonathan is Merib-Baal, and Merib-Baal begat Micah;</verse>
  <verse number="35">and sons of Micah: Pithon, and Melech, and Tarea, and Ahaz:</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Ahaz begat Jehoadah, and Jehoadah begat Alemeth, and Azmaveth, and Zimri; and Zimri begat Moza,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and Moza begat Binea, Raphah is his son, Eleasah his son, Azel his son.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And to Azel are six sons, and these are their names: Azrikam, Bocheru, and Ishmael, and Sheariah, and Obadiah, and Hanan. All these are sons of Azel.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And sons of Eshek his brother: Ulam his first-born, Jehush the second, and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the sons of Ulam are men mighty in valour, treading bow, and multiplying sons and son’s sons, a hundred and fifty. All these are of the sons of Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>