<chapter book="Titus" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And do thou speak what becomes sound doctrine:</verse>
  <verse number="2">The aged men to be sober, grave, of sound mind, sound in the faith, in love, in patience.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The aged women likewise, becoming holy in a serene state of mind, not accusers, not slaves to much wine, teachers of good;</verse>
  <verse number="4">That they render the young women discreet, to be lovers of the husband, lovers of the children,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Of sound mind chaste, remaining at home, good subordinates to their own husbands, that the word of God be not defamed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The younger men likewise beseech to be of sound mind.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Concerning all things hold thyself a type of good works: in doctrine, integrity, gravity, incorruptibility,</verse>
  <verse number="8">The word sound, not to be condemned; that he from the opposite may be changed, having nothing bad to say of you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Servants to be subordinate to their own masters, to be pleasing in all things; not contradicting;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Not purloining, but showing all good faith; that they may adorn the doctrine of the Saviour our God in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the grace of God who saves, was manifested to all men,</verse>
  <verse number="12">Teaching us that, denying ungodliness and eager worldly desires, we should live discreetly, and justly, and religiously, in the time now;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Expecting the blessed hope, and appearance of the glory of the great God and our Saviour Jesus Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who gave himself for us, that he might redeem us from all iniquity, and purify to himself a distinguished people, zealous of good works.</verse>
  <verse number="15">These things speak, and beseech, and reprove with all order. Let none despise thee.</verse>
</chapter>