<chapter book="Job" number="15" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Should a wise man make answer with vain knowledge, and fill his belly with the east wind?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Should he reason with unprofitable talk, or with speeches wherewith he can do no good?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Yea, thou doest away with fear, and restrainest devotion before God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For thine iniquity teacheth thy mouth, and thou choosest the tongue of the crafty.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thine own mouth condemneth thee, and not I; yea, thine own lips testify against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Art thou the first man that was born? or wast thou brought forth before the hills?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Hast thou heard the secret counsel of God? and dost thou restrain wisdom to thyself?</verse>
  <verse number="9">What knowest thou, that we know not? what understandest thou, which is not in us?</verse>
  <verse number="10">With us are both the grayheaded and the very aged men, much elder than thy father.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Are the consolations of God too small for thee, and the word that dealeth gently with thee?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why doth thine heart carry thee away? and why do thine eyes wink?</verse>
  <verse number="13">That thou turnest thy spirit against God, and lettest such words go out of thy mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">What is man, that he should be clean? and he which is born of a woman, that he should be righteous?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, he putteth no trust in his holy ones; yea, the heavens are not clean in his sight.</verse>
  <verse number="16">How much less one that is abominable and corrupt, a man that drinketh iniquity like water!</verse>
  <verse number="17">I will shew thee, hear thou me; and that which I have seen I will declare:</verse>
  <verse number="18">(Which wise men have told from their fathers, and have not hid it;</verse>
  <verse number="19">Unto whom alone the land was given, and no stranger passed among them:)</verse>
  <verse number="20">The wicked man travaileth with pain all his days, even the number of years that are laid up for the oppressor.</verse>
  <verse number="21">A sound of terrors is in his ears; in prosperity the spoiler shall come upon him:</verse>
  <verse number="22">He believeth not that he shall return out of darkness, and he is waited for of the sword:</verse>
  <verse number="23">He wandereth abroad for bread, saying, Where is it? he knoweth that the day of darkness is ready at his hand:</verse>
  <verse number="24">Distress and anguish make him afraid; they prevail against him, as a king ready to the battle:</verse>
  <verse number="25">Because he hath stretched out his hand against God, and behaveth himself proudly against the Almighty;</verse>
  <verse number="26">He runneth upon him with a stiff neck, with the thick bosses of his bucklers:</verse>
  <verse number="27">Because he hath covered his face with his fatness, and made collops of fat on his flanks;</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he hath dwelt in desolate cities, in houses which no man inhabited, which were ready to become heaps.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He shall not be rich, neither shall his substance continue, neither shall their produce bend to the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He shall not depart out of darkness; the flame shall dry up his branches, and by the breath of his mouth shall he go away.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Let him not trust in vanity, deceiving himself: for vanity shall be his recompence.</verse>
  <verse number="32">It shall be accomplished before his time, and his branch shall not be green.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He shall shake off his unripe grape as the vine, and shall cast off his flower as the olive.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For the company of the godless shall be barren, and fire shall consume the tents of bribery.</verse>
  <verse number="35">They conceive mischief, and bring forth iniquity, and their belly prepareth deceit.</verse>
</chapter>