<chapter book="Job" number="18" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Bildad the Shuhite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will ye lay snares for words? consider, and afterwards we will speak.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Wherefore are we counted as beasts, and are become unclean in your sight?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou that tearest thyself in thine anger, shall the earth be forsaken for thee? or shall the rock be removed out of its place?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Yea, the light of the wicked shall be put out, and the spark of his fire shall not shine.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The light shall be dark in his tent, and his lamp above him shall be put out.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The steps of his strength shall be straitened, and his own counsel shall cast him down.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For he is cast into a net by his own feet, and he walketh upon the toils.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A gin shall take him by the heel, and a snare shall lay hold on him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A noose is hid for him in the ground, and a trap for him in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Terrors shall make him afraid on every side, and shall chase him at his heels.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His strength shall be hunger-bitten and calamity shall be ready for his halting.</verse>
  <verse number="13">It shall devour the members of his body, yea, the firstborn of death shall devour his members.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He shall be rooted out of his tent wherein he trusteth; and he shall be brought to the king of terrors.</verse>
  <verse number="15">There shall dwell in his tent that which is none of his: brimstone shall be scattered upon his habitation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">His roots shall be dried up beneath, and above shall his branch be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His remembrance shall perish from the earth, and he shall have no name in the street.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He shall be driven from light into darkness, and chased out of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He shall have neither son nor son’s son among his people, nor any remaining where he sojourned.</verse>
  <verse number="20">They that come after shall be astonied at his day, as they that went before were affrighted.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Surely such are the dwellings of the unrighteous, and this is the place of him that knoweth not God.</verse>
</chapter>