<chapter book="Job" number="20" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Zophar the Naamathite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Therefore do my thoughts give answer to me, even by reason of my haste that is in me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I have heard the reproof which putteth me to shame, and the spirit of my understanding answereth me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Knowest thou not this of old time, since man was placed upon earth,</verse>
  <verse number="5">That the triumphing of the wicked is short, and the joy of the godless but for a moment?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Though his excellency mount up to the heavens, and his head reach unto the clouds;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Yet he shall perish for ever like his own dung: they which have seen him shall say, Where is he?</verse>
  <verse number="8">He shall fly away as a dream, and shall not be found: yea, he shall be chased away as a vision of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The eye which saw him shall see him no more; neither shall his place any more behold him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">His children shall seek the favour of the poor, and his hands shall give back his wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="11">His bones are full of his youth, but it shall lie down with him in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Though wickedness be sweet in his mouth, though he hide it under his tongue;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Though he spare it, and will not let it go, but keep it still within his mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Yet his meat in his bowels is turned, it is the gall of asps within him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He hath swallowed down riches, and he shall vomit them up again: God shall cast them out of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He shall suck the poison of asps: the viper’s tongue shall slay him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He shall not look upon the rivers, the flowing streams of honey and butter.</verse>
  <verse number="18">That which he laboured for shall he restore, and shall not swallow it down; according to the substance that he hath gotten, he shall not rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For he hath oppressed and forsaken the poor; he hath violently taken away an house, and he shall not build it up.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Because he knew no quietness within him, he shall not save aught of that wherein he delighteth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">There was nothing left that he devoured not; therefore his prosperity shall not endure.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In the fulness of his sufficiency he shall be in straits: the hand of every one that is in misery shall come upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">When he is about to fill his belly, God shall cast the fierceness of his wrath upon him, and shall rain it upon him while he is eating.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He shall flee from the iron weapon, and the bow of brass shall strike him through.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He draweth it forth, and it cometh out of his body: yea, the glittering point cometh out of his gall; terrors are upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">All darkness is laid up for his treasures: a fire not blown by man shall devour him; it shall consume that which is left in his tent.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The heavens shall reveal his iniquity, and the earth shall rise up against him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The increase of his house shall depart, his goods shall flow away in the day of his wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="29">This is the portion of a wicked man from God, and the heritage appointed unto him by God.</verse>
</chapter>