<chapter book="Job" number="21" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear diligently my speech; and let this be your consolations.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Suffer me, and I also will speak; and after that I have spoken, mock on.</verse>
  <verse number="4">As for me, is my complaint to man? and why should I not be impatient?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Mark me, and be astonished, and lay your hand upon your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Even when I remember I am troubled, and horror taketh hold on my flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Wherefore do the wicked live, become old, yea, wax mighty in power?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Their seed is established with them in their sight, and their offspring before their eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Their houses are safe from fear, neither is the rod of God upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Their bull gendereth, and faileth not; their cow calveth, and casteth not her calf.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They send forth their little ones like a flock, and their children dance.</verse>
  <verse number="12">They sing to the timbrel and harp, and rejoice at the sound of the pipe.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They spend their days in prosperity, and in a moment they go down to Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Yet they said unto God, Depart from us; for we desire not the knowledge of thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">What is the Almighty, that we should serve him? and what profit should we have, if we pray unto him?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo, their prosperity is not in their hand: the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">How oft is it that the lamp of the wicked is put out? that their calamity cometh upon them? that God distributeth sorrows in his anger?</verse>
  <verse number="18">That they are as stubble before the wind, and as chaff that the storm carrieth away?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Ye say, God layeth up his iniquity for his children. Let him recompense it unto himself, that he may know it.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Let his own eyes see his destruction, and let him drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For what pleasure hath he in his house after him, when the number of his months is cut off in the midst?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Shall any teach God knowledge? seeing he judgeth those that are high.</verse>
  <verse number="23">One dieth in his full strength, being wholly at ease and quiet:</verse>
  <verse number="24">His breasts are full of milk, and the marrow of his bones is moistened.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And another dieth in bitterness of soul, and never tasteth of good.</verse>
  <verse number="26">They lie down alike in the dust, and the worm covereth them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Behold, I know your thoughts, and the devices which ye wrongfully imagine against me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For ye say, Where is the house of the prince? and where is the tent wherein the wicked dwelt?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Have ye not asked them that go by the way? and do ye not know their tokens?</verse>
  <verse number="30">That the evil man is reserved to the day of calamity? that they are led forth to the day of wrath?</verse>
  <verse number="31">Who shall declare his way to his face? and who shall repay him what he hath done?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Yet shall he be borne to the grave, and shall keep watch over the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The clods of the valley shall be sweet unto him, and all men shall draw after him, as there were innumerable before him.</verse>
  <verse number="34">How then comfort ye me in vain, seeing in your answers there remaineth only falsehood?</verse>
</chapter>