<chapter book="Job" number="31" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I MADE a covenant with mine eyes; how then should I look upon a maid?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For what is the portion of God from above, and the heritage of the Almighty from on high?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it not calamity to the unrighteous, and disaster to the workers of iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Doth not he see my ways, and number all my steps?</verse>
  <verse number="5">If I have walked with vanity, and my foot hath hasted to deceit;</verse>
  <verse number="6">(Let me be weighed in an even balance, that God may know mine integrity;)</verse>
  <verse number="7">If my step hath turned out of the way, and mine heart walked after mine eyes, and if any spot hath cleaved to mine hands:</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then let me sow, and let another eat; yea, let the produce of my field be rooted out.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If mine heart have been enticed unto a woman, and I have laid wait at my neighbour’s door:</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then let my wife grind unto another, and let others bow down upon her.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For that were an heinous crime; yea, it were an iniquity to be punished by the judges:</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is a fire that consumeth unto Destruction, and would root out all mine increase.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I did despise the cause of my manservant or of my maidservant, when they contended with me:</verse>
  <verse number="14">What then shall I do when God riseth up? and when he visiteth, what shall I answer him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Did not he that made me in the womb make him? and did not one fashion us in the womb?</verse>
  <verse number="16">If I have withheld the poor from their desire, or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Or have eaten my morsel alone, and the fatherless hath not eaten thereof;</verse>
  <verse number="18">(Nay, from my youth he grew up with me as with a father, and I have been her guide from my mother’s womb;)</verse>
  <verse number="19">If I have seen any perish for want of clothing, or that the needy had no covering;</verse>
  <verse number="20">If his loins have not blessed me, and if he were not warmed with the fleece of my sheep;</verse>
  <verse number="21">If I have lifted up my hand against the fatherless, because I saw my help in the gate:</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then let my shoulder fall from the shoulder blade, and mine arm be broken from the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For calamity from God was a terror to me, and by reason of his excellency I could do nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If I have made gold my hope, and have said to the fine gold, Thou art my confidence;</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I rejoiced because my wealth was great, and because mine hand had gotten much;</verse>
  <verse number="26">If I beheld the sun when it shined, or the moon walking in brightness;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And my heart hath been secretly enticed, and my mouth hath kissed my hand:</verse>
  <verse number="28">This also were an iniquity to be punished by the judges: for I should have lied to God that is above.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If I rejoiced at the destruction of him that hated me, or lifted up myself when evil found him;</verse>
  <verse number="30">(Yea, I suffered not my mouth to sin by asking his life with a curse;)</verse>
  <verse number="31">If the men of my tent said not, Who can find one that hath not been satisfied with his flesh?</verse>
  <verse number="32">The stranger did not lodge in the street; but I opened my doors to the traveller;</verse>
  <verse number="33">If like Adam I covered my transgressions, by hiding mine iniquity in my bosom;</verse>
  <verse number="34">Because I feared the great multitude, and the contempt of families terrified me, so that I kept silence, and went not out of the door—</verse>
  <verse number="35">Oh that I had one to hear me! (lo, here is my signature, let the Almighty answer me;) and that I had the indictment which mine adversary hath written!</verse>
  <verse number="36">Surely I would carry it upon my shoulder; I would bind it unto me as a crown.</verse>
  <verse number="37">I would declare unto him the number of my steps; as a prince would I go near unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="38">If my land cry out against me, and the furrows thereof weep together;</verse>
  <verse number="39">If I have eaten the fruits thereof without money, or have caused the owners thereof to lose their life:</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let thistles grow instead of wheat, and cockle instead of barley. The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>