<chapter book="Job" number="34" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover Elihu answered and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear my words, ye wise men; and give ear unto me, ye that have knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the ear trieth words, as the palate tasteth meat.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Let us choose for us that which is right: let us know among ourselves what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For Job hath said, I am righteous, and God hath taken away my right:</verse>
  <verse number="6">Notwithstanding my right I am accounted a liar; my wound is incurable, though I am without transgression.</verse>
  <verse number="7">What man is like Job, who drinketh up scorning like water?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Which goeth in company with the workers of iniquity, and walketh with wicked men.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For he hath said, it profiteth a man nothing that he should delight himself with God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore hearken unto me, ye men of understanding: far be it from God, that he should do wickedness; and from the Almighty, that he should commit iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the work of a man shall he render unto him, and cause every man to find according to his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Yea, of a surety, God will not do wickedly, neither will the Almighty pervert judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who gave him a charge over the earth? or who hath disposed the whole world?</verse>
  <verse number="14">If he set his heart upon man, if he gather unto himself his spirit and his breath;</verse>
  <verse number="15">All flesh shall perish together, and man shall turn again unto dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If now thou hast understanding, hear this: hearken to the voice of my words.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Shall even one that hateth right govern? and wilt thou condemn him that is just and mighty?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Is it fit to say to a king, Thou art vile? or to nobles, Ye are wicked?</verse>
  <verse number="19">How much less to him that respecteth not the persons of princes, nor regardeth the rich more than the poor? for they all are the work of his hands.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In a moment they die, even at midnight; the people are shaken and pass away, and the mighty are taken away without hand.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For his eyes are upon the ways of a man, and he seeth all his goings.</verse>
  <verse number="22">There is no darkness, nor shadow of death, where the workers of iniquity may hide themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For he needeth not further to consider a man, that he should go before God in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He breaketh in pieces mighty men in ways past finding out, and setteth others in their stead.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Therefore he taketh knowledge of their works; and he overturneth them in the night, so that they are destroyed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He striketh them as wicked men in the open sight of others;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Because they turned aside from following him, and would not have regard to any of his ways:</verse>
  <verse number="28">So that they caused the cry of the poor to come unto him, and he heard the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When he giveth quietness, who then can condemn? and when he hideth his face, who then can behold him? whether it be done unto a nation, or unto a man, alike:</verse>
  <verse number="30">That the godless man reign not, that there be none to ensnare the people.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For hath any said unto God, I have borne chastisement, I will not offend any more:</verse>
  <verse number="32">That which I see not teach thou me: if I have done iniquity, I will do it no more?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Shall his recompence be as thou wilt, that thou refusest it? for thou must choose, and not I: therefore speak what thou knowest.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Men of understanding will say unto me, yea, every wise man that heareth me:</verse>
  <verse number="35">Job speaketh without knowledge, and his words are without wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Would that Job were tried unto the end, because of his answering like wicked men.</verse>
  <verse number="37">For he addeth rebellion unto his sin, he clappeth his hands among us, and multiplieth his words against God.</verse>
</chapter>