<chapter book="Job" number="36" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Elihu also proceeded, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Suffer me a little, and I will shew thee: for I have yet somewhat to say on God’s behalf.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I will fetch my knowledge from afar, and will ascribe righteousness to my Maker.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For truly my words are not false: one that is perfect in knowledge is with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Behold, God is mighty, and despiseth not any: he is mighty in strength of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He preserveth not the life of the wicked: but giveth to the afflicted their right.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He withdraweth not his eyes from the righteous: but with kings upon the throne he setteth them for ever, and they are exalted.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And if they be bound in fetters, and be taken in the cords of affliction;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then he sheweth them their work, and their transgressions, that they have behaved themselves proudly.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He openeth also their ear to instruction, and commandeth that they return from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they hearken and serve him, they shall spend their days in prosperity, and their years in pleasures.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But if they hearken not, they shall perish by the sword, and they shall die without knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">But they that are godless in heart lay up anger: they cry not for help when he bindeth them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They die in youth, and their life perisheth among the unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He delivereth the afflicted by his affliction, and openeth their ear in oppression.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Yea, he would have led thee away out of distress into a broad place, where there is no straitness; and that which is set on thy table should be full of fatness.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But thou art full of the judgment of the wicked: judgment and justice take hold on thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Because there is wrath, beware lest thou be led away by thy sufficiency; neither let the greatness of the ransom turn thee aside.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Will thy riches suffice, that thou be not in distress, or all the forces of thy strength?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Desire not the night, when peoples are cut off in their place.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Take heed, regard not iniquity: for this hast thou chosen rather than affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Behold, God doeth loftily in his power: who is a teacher like unto him?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Who hath enjoined him his way? or who can say, Thou hast wrought unrighteousness?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Remember that thou magnify his work, whereof men have sung.</verse>
  <verse number="25">All men have looked thereon; man beholdeth it afar off.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Behold, God is great, and we know him not; the number of his years is unsearchable.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For he draweth up the drops of water, which distil in rain from his vapour:</verse>
  <verse number="28">Which the skies pour down and drop upon man abundantly.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Yea, can any understand the spreadings of the clouds, the thunderings of his pavilion?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Behold, he spreadeth his light around him; and he covereth the bottom of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For by these he judgeth the peoples; he giveth meat in abundance.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He covereth his hands with the lightning; and giveth it a charge that it strike the mark.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The noise thereof telleth concerning him, the cattle also concerning the storm that cometh up.</verse>
</chapter>