<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Knowest thou the time when the wild goats of the rock bring forth? or canst thou mark when the hinds do calve?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Canst thou number the months that they fulfill? or knowest thou the time when they bring forth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">They bow themselves, they bring forth their young, they cast out their sorrows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Their young ones are in good liking, they grow up in the open field; they go forth, and return not again,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who hath sent out the wild ass free? or who hath loosed the bands of the wild ass?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whose house I have made the wilderness, and the salt land his dwelling place.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He scorneth the tumult of the city, neither heareth he the shoutings of the driver.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The range of the mountains is his pasture, and he searcheth after every green thing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will the wild-ox be content to serve thee? or will he abide by thy crib?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Canst thou bind the wild-ox with his band in the furrow? or will he harrow the valleys after thee?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wilt thou trust him, because his strength is great? or wilt thou leave to him thy labour?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wilt thou confide in him, that he will bring home thy seed, and gather the corn of thy threshingfloor?</verse>
  <verse number="13">The wing of the ostrich rejoiceth, but are her pinions and feathers kindly?</verse>
  <verse number="14">For she leaveth her eggs on the earth, and warmeth them in the dust,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And forgetteth that the foot may crush them, or that the wild beast may trample them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She is hardened against her young ones, as if they were not hers: though her labour be in vain, she is without fear;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Because God hath deprived her of wisdom, neither hath he imparted to her understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="18">What time she lifteth up herself on high, she scorneth the horse and his rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Hast thou given the horse his might? hast thou clothed his neck with the quivering mane?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Hast thou made him to leap as a locust? the glory of his snorting is terrible.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He paweth in the valley, and rejoiceth in his strength: he goeth out to meet the armed men.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He mocketh at fear, and is not dismayed; neither turneth he back from the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The quiver rattleth against him, the flashing spear and the javelin.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He swalloweth the ground with fierceness and rage; neither believeth he that it is the voice of the trumpet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">As oft as the trumpet soundeth he saith, Aha! and he smelleth the battle afar off, the thunder of the captains, and the shouting.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Doth the hawk soar by thy wisdom, and stretch her wings toward the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Doth the eagle mount up at thy command, and make her nest on high?</verse>
  <verse number="28">She dwelleth on the rock, and hath her lodging there, upon the crag of the rock, and the strong hold.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From thence she spieth out the prey; her eyes behold it afar off.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Her young ones also suck up blood: and where the slain are, there is she.</verse>
</chapter>