<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover the LORD answered Job, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shall he that cavilleth contend with the Almighty? he that argueth with God, let him answer it.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Job answered the LORD, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Behold, I am of small account; what shall I answer thee? I lay mine hand upon my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Once have I spoken, and I will not answer; yea twice, but I will proceed no further.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Gird up thy loins now like a man: I will demand of thee, and declare thou unto me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Wilt thou even disannul my judgment? wilt thou condemn me, that thou mayest be justified?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Or hast thou an arm like God? and canst thou thunder with a voice like him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Deck thyself now with excellency and dignity; and array thyself with honour and majesty.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Pour forth the overflowings of thine anger: and look upon every one that is proud, and abase him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Look on every one that is proud, and bring him low; and tread down the wicked where they stand.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hide them in the dust together; bind their faces in the hidden place.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then wilt I also confess of thee that thine own right hand can save thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold now behemoth, which I made with thee; he eateth grass as all ox.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo now, his strength is in his loins, and his force is in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He moveth his tail like a cedar: the sinews of his thighs are knit together.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are as tubes of brass; his limbs are like bars of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is the chief of the ways of God: he only that made him can make his sword to approach unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely the mountains bring him forth food; where all the beasts of the field do play.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He lieth under the lotus trees, in the covert of the reed, and the fen.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The lotus trees cover him with their shadow; the willows of the brook compass him about.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Behold, if a river overflow, he trembleth not: he is confident, though Jordan swell even to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Shall any take him when he is on the watch, or pierce through his nose with a snare?</verse>
</chapter>