<chapter book="1 John" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My children, these things I write to you in order that ye may not sin; and if any one sin, we have a patron with the Father, Jesus Christ [the] righteous;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and he is the propitiation for our sins; but not for ours alone, but also for the whole world.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And hereby we know that we know him, if we keep his commandments.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He that says, I know him, and does not keep his commandments, is a liar, and the truth is not in him;</verse>
  <verse number="5">but whoever keeps his word, in him verily the love of God is perfected. Hereby we know that we are in him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He that says he abides in him ought, even as he walked, himself also [so] to walk.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Beloved, I write no new commandment to you, but an old commandment, which ye have had from the beginning. The old commandment is the word which ye heard.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Again, I write a new commandment to you, which thing is true in him and in you, because the darkness is passing and the true light already shines.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He who says he is in the light, and hates his brother, is in the darkness until now.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He that loves his brother abides in light, and there is no occasion of stumbling in him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But he that hates his brother is in the darkness, and walks in the darkness, and knows not where he goes, because the darkness has blinded his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I write to you, children, because [your] sins are forgiven you for his name’s sake.</verse>
  <verse number="13">I write to you, fathers, because ye have known him [that is] from the beginning. I write to you, young men, because ye have overcome the wicked [one]. I write to you, little children, because ye have known the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I have written to you, fathers, because ye have known him [that is] from the beginning. I have written to you, young men, because ye are strong, and the word of God abides in you, and ye have overcome the wicked [one].</verse>
  <verse number="15">Love not the world, nor the things in the world. If any one love the world, the love of the Father is not in him;</verse>
  <verse number="16">because all that [is] in the world, the lust of the flesh, and the lust of the eyes, and the pride of life, is not of the Father, but is of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the world is passing, and its lust, but he that does the will of God abides for eternity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Little children, it is [the] last hour, and, according as ye have heard that antichrist comes, even now there have come many antichrists, whence we know that it is [the] last hour.</verse>
  <verse number="19">They went out from among us, but they were not of us; for if they had been of us, they would have surely remained with us, but that they might be made manifest that none are of us.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And ye have [the] unction from the holy [one], and ye know all things.</verse>
  <verse number="21">I have not written to you because ye do not know the truth, but because ye know it, and that no lie is of the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Who is the liar but he who denies that Jesus is the Christ? He is the antichrist who denies the Father and the Son.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Whoever denies the Son has not the Father either; he who confesses the Son has the Father also.</verse>
  <verse number="24">As for you let that which ye have heard from the beginning abide in you: if what ye have heard from the beginning abides in you, ye also shall abide in the Son and in the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And this is the promise which he has promised us, life eternal.</verse>
  <verse number="26">These things have I written to you concerning those who lead you astray:</verse>
  <verse number="27">and yourselves, the unction which ye have received from him abides in you, and ye have not need that any one should teach you; but as the same unction teaches you as to all things, and is true and is not a lie, and even as it has taught you, ye shall abide in him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And now, children, abide in him, that if he be manifested we may have boldness, and not be put to shame from before him at his coming.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If ye know that he is righteous, know that every one who practises righteousness is begotten of him.</verse>
</chapter>