<chapter book="Numbers" number="12" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Miriam speaketh—Aaron also—against Moses concerning the circumstance of the Cushite woman whom he had taken: for a Cushite woman he had taken;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and they say, ‘Only by Moses hath Jehovah spoken? also by us hath he not spoken?’ and Jehovah heareth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the man Moses is very humble, more than any of the men who are on the face of the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Jehovah saith suddenly unto Moses, and unto Aaron, and unto Miriam, ‘Come out ye three unto the tent of meeting;’ and they three come out.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jehovah cometh down in the pillar of the cloud, and standeth at the opening of the tent, and calleth Aaron and Miriam, and they come out both of them.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And He saith, ‘Hear, I pray you, My words: If your prophet is of Jehovah—in an appearance unto him I make Myself known; in a dream I speak with him;</verse>
  <verse number="7">not so My servant Moses; in all My house he is stedfast;</verse>
  <verse number="8">mouth unto mouth I speak with him, and by an appearance, and not in riddles; and the form of Jehovah he beholdeth attentively; and wherefore have ye not been afraid to speak against My servant—against Moses?’</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the anger of Jehovah burneth against them, and He goeth on,</verse>
  <verse number="10">and the cloud hath turned aside from off the tent, and lo, Miriam is leprous as snow; and Aaron turneth unto Miriam, and lo, leprous!</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Aaron saith unto Moses, ‘O, my lord, I pray thee, lay not upon us sin in which we have been foolish, and in which we have sinned;</verse>
  <verse number="12">let her not, I pray thee, be as one dead, when in his coming out from the womb of his mother—the half of his flesh is consumed.’</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Moses crieth unto Jehovah, saying, ‘O God, I pray Thee, give, I pray Thee, healing to her.’</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Jehovah saith unto Moses, ‘And her father had but spat in her face—is she not ashamed seven days? she is shut out seven days at the outside of the camp, and afterwards she is gathered.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Miriam is shut out at the outside of the camp seven days, and the people hath not journeyed till Miriam is gathered;</verse>
  <verse number="16">and afterwards have the people journeyed from Hazeroth, and they encamp in the wilderness of Paran.</verse>
</chapter>