<chapter book="Numbers" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah speaketh unto Moses, and unto Aaron, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">‘Each by his standard, with ensigns of the house of their fathers, do the sons of Israel encamp; over-against round about the tent of meeting they encamp.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">And those encamping eastward towards the sun-rising, are of the standard of the camp of Judah, by their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Judah is Nahshon, son of Amminadab;</verse>
  <verse number="4">and his host, and their numbered ones, are four and seventy thousand and six hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And those encamping by him are of the tribe of Issachar; and the prince of the sons of Issachar is Nethaneel son of Zuar;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and his host, and its numbered ones, are four and fifty thousand and four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The tribe of Zebulun; and the prince of the sons of Zebulun is Eliab son of Helon;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and his host, and its numbered ones, are seven and fifty thousand and four hundred;</verse>
  <verse number="9">all those numbered of the camp of Judah are a hundred thousand, and eighty thousand, and six thousand, and four hundred, by their hosts; they journey first.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The standard of the camp of Reuben is southward, by their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Reuben is Elizur son of Shedeur;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and his host, and its numbered ones, are six and forty thousand and five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And those encamping by him are of the tribe of Simeon; and the prince of the sons of Simeon is Shelumiel son of Zurishaddai;</verse>
  <verse number="13">and his host, and their numbered ones, are nine and fifty thousand and three hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the tribe of Gad; and the prince of the sons of Gad is Eliasaph son of Reuel;</verse>
  <verse number="15">and his host, and their numbered ones, are five and forty thousand and six hundred and fifty.</verse>
  <verse number="16">All those numbered of the camp of Reuben are a hundred thousand, and one and fifty thousand, and four hundred and fifty, by their hosts; and they journey second.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the tent of meeting—the camp of the Levites—hath journeyed in the midst of the camps; as they encamp so they journey, each at his station by their standards.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The standard of the camp of Ephraim, by their hosts, is westward; and the prince of the sons of Ephraim is Elishama son of Ammihud;</verse>
  <verse number="19">and his host, and their numbered ones, are forty thousand and five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And by him is the tribe of Manasseh; and the prince of the sons of Manasseh is Gamaliel son of Pedahzur;</verse>
  <verse number="21">and his host, and their numbered ones, are two and thirty thousand, and two hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the tribe of Benjamin; and the prince of the sons of Benjamin is Abidan son of Gideoni;</verse>
  <verse number="23">and his host, and their numbered ones, are five and thirty thousand and four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="24">All those numbered of the camp of Ephraim are a hundred thousand, and eight thousand, and a hundred, by their hosts; and they journey third.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The standard of the camp of Dan is northward, by their hosts; and the prince of the sons of Dan is Ahiezer son of Ammishaddai;</verse>
  <verse number="26">and his host, and their numbered ones, are two and sixty thousand and seven hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And those encamping by him are of the tribe of Asher; and the prince of the sons of Asher is Pagiel son of Ocran;</verse>
  <verse number="28">and his host, and their numbered ones, are one and forty thousand and five hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And the tribe of Naphtali; and the prince of the sons of Naphtali is Ahira son of Enan;</verse>
  <verse number="30">and his host, and their numbered ones, are three and fifty thousand and four hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="31">All those numbered of the camp of Dan are a hundred thousand, and seven and fifty thousand, and six hundred; at the rear they journey, by their standards.</verse>
  <verse number="32">These are those numbered of the sons of Israel by the house of their fathers; all those numbered of the camps by their hosts are six hundred thousand, and three thousand, and five hundred and fifty.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And the Levites have not numbered themselves in the midst of the sons of Israel, as Jehovah hath commanded Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the sons of Israel do according to all that Jehovah hath commanded Moses; so they have encamped by their standards, and so they have journeyed; each by his families, by the house of his fathers.</verse>
</chapter>