<chapter book="Hebrews" number="11" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And faith is the foundation of things hoped for, the proof of things not seen.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For by this were the elders testified of.</verse>
  <verse number="3">By faith we perceive that the times were adjusted by the word of God, so that things seen have been born not of things brought to light.</verse>
  <verse number="4">By faith Abel brought near a greater sacrifice to God than Cain, by which he was testified of to be just, God testifying of his gifts; and by it he being dead yet speaks.</verse>
  <verse number="5">By faith Enoch was transferred not to see death; and was not found, because God had transferred him: for before his transferring he had been testified of, to have pleased God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And without faith it is impossible to please: for he approaching to God must believe that he is, and is a remunerator to them seeking him out.</verse>
  <verse number="7">By faith Noah, having an intimation of the divine will of things not yet seen, being circumspect, prepared an ark for the salvation of his house; by which he condemned the world, and by faith became an heir of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="8">By faith Abraham, being called, listened, to go forth into the place which he was about to receive for an inheritance; and he came out, not knowing where he is coming.</verse>
  <verse number="9">By faith he dwelt in the land of promise, as a strange land, having dwelt in tents with Isaac and Jacob, co-heirs of the same promise:</verse>
  <verse number="10">For he awaited a city having foundations, whose artificer and maker is God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">By faith Sara also herself received power for the laying down of seed, and brought forth during the time of age, for she deemed him faithful having promised.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wherefore also from one were they born, and these of him having been dead, as the stars of heaven for multitude, and as the sand near the lip of the sea innumerable.</verse>
  <verse number="13">According to faith died all these, not having received the promises, but having seen them from afar, and been persuaded, and having embraced, and assented that they are strangers and newly arrived from a foreign country upon earth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For they saying such things show clearly that they seek a country.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And truly if they remembered that from which they came out, they had time to have returned.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And now they feel an ardent desire for a better, that is, a heavenly: wherefore God is not ashamed of them to be called their God: for he prepared for them a city.</verse>
  <verse number="17">By faith Abraham had brought near Isaac, being tried: and he having received the promises brought near the only born,</verse>
  <verse number="18">To whom it was spoken, That in Isaac shall seed be called to thee:</verse>
  <verse number="19">Reckoning that God was also able to raise from the dead; whence he also received him in a parable.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By faith concerning things about to be, Isaac blessed Jacob and Esau.</verse>
  <verse number="21">By faith Jacob, dying, blessed each of Joseph’s sons; and worshipped, upon the extremity of his rod.</verse>
  <verse number="22">By faith Joseph, dying, made mention of the departure of the sons of Israel: and charged concerning his bones.</verse>
  <verse number="23">By faith Moses, born, was hidden three months by his parents, because they saw a shrewd child; and they were not afraid of the edict of the king.</verse>
  <verse number="24">By faith Moses, having become great, refused to be reckoned the son of Pharaoh’s daughter;</verse>
  <verse number="25">Having chosen rather to be treated ill with the people of God, than to have the enjoyment of sin for a time;</verse>
  <verse number="26">Having deemed the reproach of Christ greater riches than treasures in Egypt: for he looked to the payment of reward.</verse>
  <verse number="27">By faith he forsook Egypt, not having feared the king’s wrath: for, as seeing the invisible, he was strong.</verse>
  <verse number="28">By faith he has kept the pascha, and the pouring out of blood, lest he destroying the first born should touch them.</verse>
  <verse number="29">By faith they passed through the Red sea as by dry land: which the Egyptians having tried were swallowed down.</verse>
  <verse number="30">By faith the walls of Jericho fell, having been surrounded for seven days.</verse>
  <verse number="31">By faith the harlot Rahab perished not with the unbelieving, having received the spies with peace.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And what more do I say? for the time will fail me recounting of Gedeon, Barak, and also Samson and Jephthae; David also, and Samuel, and the prophets:</verse>
  <verse number="33">Who by faith subdued kingdoms, wrought justice, attained the promises, shut up the mouths of lions,</verse>
  <verse number="34">Quenched the power of fire, escaped the mouth of the sword, were strengthened from weakness, were strong in war, turned away the armies of strangers.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Women received their dead from rising up: and others were beaten, not receiving redemption; that they might attain a better resurrection.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And others received trial of jestings and scourges, and further, of bonds and imprisonment:</verse>
  <verse number="37">They were stoned, they were cut by sawing, they were tried, they died by the slaughter of the sword: they wandered about in sheepskins and goatskins; being in want, pressed, treated ill;</verse>
  <verse number="38">(Of whom the world was not worthy:) wandering about in solitary places, and mountains, and caves, and holes of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And these all, having been testified of by faith, received not the promise:</verse>
  <verse number="40">God having foreseen something better for us, that without us they should not be completed.</verse>
</chapter>