<chapter book="Hebrews" number="13" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Let brotherly love remain.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Forget not hospitality: for by this some knew not having treated angels with friendship.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Remember them in bonds as bound together with them; them treated ill, as the same being in the body.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Marriage honoured in all, and the bed unpolluted: but fornicators and adulterers God will judge.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The disposition exempt from avarice; being contented with present circumstances: for he has said, I will not send thee back, nor forsake thee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">So that being confident, we say, The Lord aiding me, and I will not fear what man will do to me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Remember them guiding you, who spake to you the word of God: of whom, observing narrowly the issue of the mode of life, imitate the faith:</verse>
  <verse number="8">Jesus Christ, yesterday, and to day the same, and for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="9">With various and strange teachings be not carried about. For good the heart be rendered firm by grace; not by food, in which they having walked about were not profited.</verse>
  <verse number="10">We have an altar, of which they serving the tent have no power to eat.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For of whom the blood of the living ones is brought for sin into the holies by the chief priest, the bodies of these are burned without the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wherefore also Jesus, that he might consecrate the people by his own blood, suffered without the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Therefore we should come to him without the camp, bearing his reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For here have we no abiding city, but we seek that about to be.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By him therefore we should always bring up the sacrifice of praise to God, that is, the fruit of the lips assenting to his name.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the doing good and mutual participation forget not; for with such sacrifices God is well pleased.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Believe them guiding you, and yield: (for they watch vigilantly for your souls, as going to return the word.) that with joy they might do this, and not lamenting: for this unprofitable for you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Pray for us: for we have trusted that we have a good consciousness, in all things wishing to be well occupied.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And I beseech the more abundantly to do this, that I might the more speedily be restored to you.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the God of peace, having brought up from the dead, the great Shepherd of the sheep, in the blood of the eternal covenant, our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Put you in proper order in every good work for doing his will, doing in you the thing pleasing before him, by Jesus Christ; to whom glory for the time of times. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And I beseech you, brethren, hold up the word of entreaty: for I also sent to you in a few words.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Ye know the brother Timothy having been set at liberty; with whom, if he come more speedily, I shall see you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Greet all them guiding you, and all the holy.</verse>
  <verse number="25">They from Italy greet you. Grace with you all. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>