<chapter book="Hebrews" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the summary to the things spoken: We have such a chief priest, who sat on the throne of the Majesty in the heavens;</verse>
  <verse number="2">A workman of holy things, and of the true tent, which the Lord pitched, and not man.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For every chief priest is appointed to bring in gifts and sacrifices also: wherefore it is necessary also for this to have something which he might bring.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For if truly he were upon earth, he would not be a priest, there being priests bringing in gifts according to the law;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who serve the pattern and shadow of heavenly things, as Moses was given an intimation of the divine will, being about to complete the tent: for, See, says he, thou make all things according to the type shewed thee in the mount.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And now he has attained a more distinguished office, in how much also he is mediator of a better covenant, which was legislated upon better promises.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For if that first was faultless, then place was not to be sought for the second.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For rebuking them, he says, Behold, the days come, says the Lord, and I will complete for the house of Israel and for the house of Judah a new covenant:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Not according to the covenant which I made to their fathers in the day of my taking their hand to bring them out of the land of Egypt; for they remained not in my covenant, and I heeded them not, says the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this the covenant which I will set to the house of Israel after those days, says the Lord; giving my laws into their mind, and upon their hearts will I write them: and I will be to them for God, and they shall be to me for a people:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And they should not teach each his neighbor, and each his brother, saying, Know the Lord: for all shall know me, from their little even to their great ones.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I will be merciful to their iniquities, and their sins and their injustices will I remember no more.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In saying new, he has made the first old. And that made old and becoming weak is near destruction.</verse>
</chapter>