<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="12" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Indeed it is not profitable to me to boast. For I will come to visions and Revelation of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I knew a man in Christ before fourteen years, (whether in the body, I know not; whether out of the body, I know not: God knows;) such a one having been carried off even to the third heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I knew such a man, (whether in the body, whether out of the body, I know not: God knows;)</verse>
  <verse number="4">That he was carried off into paradise, and heard words not to be told, which it was not permitted man to speak.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Of such a one will I boast: and of myself I will not boast, except in my weakness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For if I be willing to boast, I shall not be mad; for the truth will I say: and I spare, lest any reckon for me above what he sees me, or what he hears of me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And lest I be lifted up by the eminence of Revelation, a thorn in the flesh was given me, a messenger of Satan, that he might cuff me, lest I be lifted up.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For this thrice besought I the Lord, that it remove away from me.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he said to me, My grace suffices thee: for my power is perfected in weakness. Therefore very willingly will I boast rather in my weaknesses, that Christ’s power may lodge upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore am I contented in weaknesses, in reproaches, in necessities in expulsions, in extremities for Christ: for when I am weak, then am I strong.</verse>
  <verse number="11">I have been mad boasting; ye forced me: for I ought to have been recommended by you: for I was not greatly inferior to the sent, if also I am nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Surely the signs of one sent was wrought in you in all patience, in signs, and wonders, and powers.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For what is it which ye were inferior to the rest of the churches, except that I myself acted not with negligence to you? favor me for this injustice.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Behold, I have prepared to come to you the third time; and I will not act with negligence to you: for I seek not your things, but you: for children ought not to treasure up for parents, but parents for children.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And I very willingly will expend and be expended for your souls; if also loving you more abundantly, the less I should be loved.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And let it be, I overloaded you not: but being dexterous, I took you by contrivance.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Not any of whom I have sent to you have I by him taken advantage of you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I called for Titus, and sent with a brother. Has Titus taken advantage of you? walked we not in the same spirit? not in the same steps?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Again, think ye that we excuse ourselves to you? before God in Christ we speak: and all things, beloved, for your building up.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I am afraid, lest somehow, having come, I find you not such; as I will, and I find you such as ye wish not: lest somehow, strifes, jealousies, wraths, intrigues, calumnies, whisperings, inflations, derangements:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Lest, coming again, my God should humble me with you, and I shall mourn for many of them having sinned before, and not having repented for uncleanness, and fornication, and licentiousness which they committed.</verse>
</chapter>