<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For this, having this service, as we were compassionated, we lose not courage;</verse>
  <verse number="2">But have renounced the hidden things of shame, not walking in craft, neither adulterating the word of God; but by manifestation of the truth recommending ourselves to every consciousness of man before God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And if also our good news is hid, in the lost is it hid:</verse>
  <verse number="4">In whom the God of this world blinded the minds of the unbelieving, so that the enlightening of the good news of the glory of Christ, who is the image of God, does not enlighten them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For we proclaim not ourselves, but Christ Jesus the Lord; and ourselves your servants for Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For God, having spoken light to shine out of darkness, who shone in our hearts, to the enlightening of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And we have this treasure in earthen vessels, that the eminence of power be of God, and not of us.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Being pressed in every thing, but not straightened; being at a loss, but not utterly perplexed;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Being driven out, but not forsaken; being cast down, but not destroyed;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Always bearing about in the body the death of the Lord Jesus, that also the life of Jesus be made manifest in our body.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For we, the living, are always delivered to death for Jesus, that also the life of Jesus be made manifest in our mortal flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="12">So that death is truly energetic in us, and life in you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And having the same spirit of faith, according to that written, I believed, therefore I spake: and we believe, and therefore we speak;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Knowing that he having raised the Lord Jesus will also raise us by Jesus, and present us with you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For all things for you, that grace, having abounded by the many, might abound in thanksgiving to the glory of God.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Wherefore we lose not courage; but if also our man without is destroyed, but he within is renewed day and day.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the present moment the lightness of our pressure works to us an eternal weight of glory, as eminence upon eminence;</verse>
  <verse number="18">We looking not at things seen, but at things not seen: for things seen, temporary; and things not seen, eternal.</verse>
</chapter>