<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="6" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And working together, we also beseech, lest also ye receive the grace of God in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="2">(For he says, In an acceptable time I listened to thee, and in the day of salvation have I run to succor thee: behold, now the acceptable time; behold; now the day of salvation.)</verse>
  <verse number="3">Giving no offence in any thing, that the service be not blamed:</verse>
  <verse number="4">But in every thing recommending ourselves as servants of God, in much patience, in pressures, in necessities, in extremities,</verse>
  <verse number="5">In blows, in imprisonments, in disorders, in fatigues, in watchings, in fastings;</verse>
  <verse number="6">In purity, in knowledge, in long suffering, in kindness, in the Holy Spirit, in love unfeigned.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In the word of truth, in the power of God, through the weapons of justice of the right hands and the left,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Through glory and ignominy, through slander and applause: as erring, and true;</verse>
  <verse number="9">As being ignorant, and knowing; as dying, and, behold, we live; as being disciplined, and not killed;</verse>
  <verse number="10">As being grieved, and always rejoicing; as poor, and making many rich; as having nothing, and possessing all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Our month stands open to you, O Corinthians, our heart has been enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Ye are not contracted in us, but ye are contracted in your bowels.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And for the same recompense, (I speak as to children,) be ye yourselves also enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Be not unequally yoked together with the unbelieving: for what participation to justice and iniquity and what communion to light with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And what conformity to Christ with Belial? and what part to the believing with the unbelieving?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And what agreement to the temple of God with images? for ye are the temple of the living God; as God said, That I will dwell in them, and will go round about; and will be their God, and they shall be a people to me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore come out from the midst of them, and be separated, says the Lord, and touch not the unclean; and I will receive you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And I will be to you for a Father, and ye shall be to me for sons and daughters, says the Lord Almighty.</verse>
</chapter>