<chapter book="Jeremiah" number="23" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Woe be to the pastors that destroy and scatter the sheep of my pasture! said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Therefore thus said the LORD God of Israel against the pastors that feed my people; You have scattered my flock, and driven them away, and have not visited them: behold, I will visit on you the evil of your doings, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will gather the remnant of my flock out of all countries where I have driven them, and will bring them again to their folds; and they shall be fruitful and increase.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I will set up shepherds over them which shall feed them: and they shall fear no more, nor be dismayed, neither shall they be lacking, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Behold, the days come, said the LORD, that I will raise to David a righteous Branch, and a King shall reign and prosper, and shall execute judgment and justice in the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In his days Judah shall be saved, and Israel shall dwell safely: and this is his name whereby he shall be called, THE LORD OUR RIGHTEOUSNESS.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Therefore, behold, the days come, said the LORD, that they shall no more say, The LORD lives, which brought up the children of Israel out of the land of Egypt;</verse>
  <verse number="8">But, The LORD lives, which brought up and which led the seed of the house of Israel out of the north country, and from all countries where I had driven them; and they shall dwell in their own land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My heart within me is broken because of the prophets; all my bones shake; I am like a drunken man, and like a man whom wine has overcome, because of the LORD, and because of the words of his holiness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For the land is full of adulterers; for because of swearing the land mourns; the pleasant places of the wilderness are dried up, and their course is evil, and their force is not right.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For both prophet and priest are profane; yes, in my house have I found their wickedness, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why their way shall be to them as slippery ways in the darkness: they shall be driven on, and fall therein: for I will bring evil on them, even the year of their visitation, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I have seen folly in the prophets of Samaria; they prophesied in Baal, and caused my people Israel to err.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I have seen also in the prophets of Jerusalem an horrible thing: they commit adultery, and walk in lies: they strengthen also the hands of evildoers, that none does return from his wickedness; they are all of them to me as Sodom, and the inhabitants thereof as Gomorrah.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore thus said the LORD of hosts concerning the prophets; Behold, I will feed them with wormwood, and make them drink the water of gall: for from the prophets of Jerusalem is profaneness gone forth into all the land.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Thus said the LORD of hosts, Listen not to the words of the prophets that prophesy to you: they make you vain: they speak a vision of their own heart, and not out of the mouth of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="17">They say still to them that despise me, The LORD has said, You shall have peace; and they say to every one that walks after the imagination of his own heart, No evil shall come on you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For who has stood in the counsel of the LORD, and has perceived and heard his word? who has marked his word, and heard it?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold, a whirlwind of the LORD is gone forth in fury, even a grievous whirlwind: it shall fall grievously on the head of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The anger of the LORD shall not return, until he have executed, and till he have performed the thoughts of his heart: in the latter days you shall consider it perfectly.</verse>
  <verse number="21">I have not sent these prophets, yet they ran: I have not spoken to them, yet they prophesied.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But if they had stood in my counsel, and had caused my people to hear my words, then they should have turned them from their evil way, and from the evil of their doings.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Am I a God at hand, said the LORD, and not a God afar off?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Can any hide himself in secret places that I shall not see him? said the LORD. Do not I fill heaven and earth? said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="25">I have heard what the prophets said, that prophesy lies in my name, saying, I have dreamed, I have dreamed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">How long shall this be in the heart of the prophets that prophesy lies? yes, they are prophets of the deceit of their own heart;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Which think to cause my people to forget my name by their dreams which they tell every man to his neighbor, as their fathers have forgotten my name for Baal.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The prophet that has a dream, let him tell a dream; and he that has my word, let him speak my word faithfully. What is the chaff to the wheat? said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Is not my word like as a fire? said the LORD; and like a hammer that breaks the rock in pieces?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Therefore, behold, I am against the prophets, said the LORD, that steal my words every one from his neighbor.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Behold, I am against the prophets, said the LORD, that use their tongues, and say, He said.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Behold, I am against them that prophesy false dreams, said the LORD, and do tell them, and cause my people to err by their lies, and by their lightness; yet I sent them not, nor commanded them: therefore they shall not profit this people at all, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And when this people, or the prophet, or a priest, shall ask you, saying, What is the burden of the LORD? you shall then say to them, What burden? I will even forsake you, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And as for the prophet, and the priest, and the people, that shall say, The burden of the LORD, I will even punish that man and his house.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Thus shall you say every one to his neighbor, and every one to his brother, What has the LORD answered? and, What has the LORD spoken?</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the burden of the LORD shall you mention no more: for every man’s word shall be his burden; for you have perverted the words of the living God, of the LORD of hosts our God.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Thus shall you say to the prophet, What has the LORD answered you? and, What has the LORD spoken?</verse>
  <verse number="38">But since you say, The burden of the LORD; therefore thus said the LORD; Because you say this word, The burden of the LORD, and I have sent to you, saying, You shall not say, The burden of the LORD;</verse>
  <verse number="39">Therefore, behold, I, even I, will utterly forget you, and I will forsake you, and the city that I gave you and your fathers, and cast you out of my presence:</verse>
  <verse number="40">And I will bring an everlasting reproach on you, and a perpetual shame, which shall not be forgotten.</verse>
</chapter>