<chapter book="Jeremiah" number="3" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">They say, If a man put away his wife, and she go from him, and become another man’s, shall he return to her again? shall not that land be greatly polluted? but you have played the harlot with many lovers; yet return again to me, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Lift up your eyes to the high places, and see where you have not been lien with. In the ways have you sat for them, as the Arabian in the wilderness; and you have polluted the land with your prostitutions and with your wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Therefore the showers have been withheld, and there has been no latter rain; and you had a whore’s forehead, you refused to be ashamed.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will you not from this time cry to me, My father, you are the guide of my youth?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Will he reserve his anger for ever? will he keep it to the end? Behold, you have spoken and done evil things as you could.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The LORD said also to me in the days of Josiah the king, Have you seen that which backsliding Israel has done? she is gone up on every high mountain and under every green tree, and there has played the harlot.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And I said after she had done all these things, Turn you to me. But she returned not. And her treacherous sister Judah saw it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And I saw, when for all the causes whereby backsliding Israel committed adultery I had put her away, and given her a bill of divorce; yet her treacherous sister Judah feared not, but went and played the harlot also.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And it came to pass through the lightness of her prostitution, that she defiled the land, and committed adultery with stones and with stocks.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And yet for all this her treacherous sister Judah has not turned to me with her whole heart, but feignedly, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the LORD said to me, The backsliding Israel has justified herself more than treacherous Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Go and proclaim these words toward the north, and say, Return, you backsliding Israel, said the LORD; and I will not cause my anger to fall on you: for I am merciful, said the LORD, and I will not keep anger for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Only acknowledge your iniquity, that you have transgressed against the LORD your God, and have scattered your ways to the strangers under every green tree, and you have not obeyed my voice, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Turn, O backsliding children, said the LORD; for I am married to you: and I will take you one of a city, and two of a family, and I will bring you to Zion:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And I will give you pastors according to my heart, which shall feed you with knowledge and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And it shall come to pass, when you be multiplied and increased in the land, in those days, said the LORD, they shall say no more, The ark of the covenant of the LORD: neither shall it come to mind: neither shall they remember it; neither shall they visit it; neither shall that be done any more.</verse>
  <verse number="17">At that time they shall call Jerusalem the throne of the LORD; and all the nations shall be gathered to it, to the name of the LORD, to Jerusalem: neither shall they walk any more after the imagination of their evil heart.</verse>
  <verse number="18">In those days the house of Judah shall walk with the house of Israel, and they shall come together out of the land of the north to the land that I have given for an inheritance to your fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But I said, How shall I put you among the children, and give you a pleasant land, a goodly heritage of the hosts of nations? and I said, You shall call me, My father; and shall not turn away from me.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely as a wife treacherously departs from her husband, so have you dealt treacherously with me, O house of Israel, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="21">A voice was heard on the high places, weeping and supplications of the children of Israel: for they have perverted their way, and they have forgotten the LORD their God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Return, you backsliding children, and I will heal your backslidings. Behold, we come to you; for you are the LORD our God.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Truly in vain is salvation hoped for from the hills, and from the multitude of mountains: truly in the LORD our God is the salvation of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For shame has devoured the labor of our fathers from our youth; their flocks and their herds, their sons and their daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="25">We lie down in our shame, and our confusion covers us: for we have sinned against the LORD our God, we and our fathers, from our youth even to this day, and have not obeyed the voice of the LORD our God.</verse>
</chapter>