<chapter book="Hebrews" number="3" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Therefore, holy brothers, sharers in the heavenly calling, consider the Apostle and High Priest of our confession: Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He is faithful to the One who made him, just as Moses also was, with his entire house.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For this Jesus was considered worthy of greater glory than Moses, so much so that the house which he has built holds a greater honor than the former one.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For every house is built by someone, but God is the One who has created all things.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And certainly Moses was faithful, with his entire house, like any servant, as a testimony to those things that would soon be said.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Yet truly, Christ is like a Son in his own house. We are that house, if we firmly retain the faithfulness and the glory of hope, even unto the end.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Because of this, it is just as the Holy Spirit says: “If today you hear his voice,</verse>
  <verse number="8">harden not your hearts, as in the provocation, the very day of temptation, in the desert,</verse>
  <verse number="9">where your fathers tested me, even though they had seen and examined my works for forty years.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this reason, I was enraged against this generation, and I said: They always wander astray in heart. For they have not known my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="11">So it is as I swore in my wrath: They shall not enter into my rest!”</verse>
  <verse number="12">Be cautious, brothers, lest perhaps there may be, in any of you, an evil heart of unbelief, turning aside from the living God.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Instead, exhort one another every day, while it is still called ‘today,’ so that none of you may become hardened through the falseness of sin.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For we have been made participants in Christ. This is only so, if we firmly retain the beginning of his substance, even unto the end.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For it has been said: “If today you hear his voice, harden not your hearts, in the same manner as in the former provocation.”</verse>
  <verse number="16">For some of those listening did provoke him. But not all of these had set forth from Egypt through Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="17">So against whom was he angry for forty years? Was it not those who had sinned, whose dead bodies lay prostrate in the desert?</verse>
  <verse number="18">But to whom did he swear that they would not enter into his rest, except to those who were incredulous?</verse>
  <verse number="19">And so, we perceive that they were not able to enter because of unbelief.</verse>
</chapter>