<chapter book="Job" number="12" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job, answering, said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Are you, therefore, alone among men, and will wisdom die with you?</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I have a heart just as you also do, and I am not inferior to you. For who is ignorant of these things, which you know?</verse>
  <verse number="4">He who is mocked by his friends as I am, will call upon God, and he will listen to him because it is the sincerity of the just that is being mocked.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The lamp that is despised in the thoughts of the rich is ready for the appointed time.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The tabernacles of robbers are numerous, and they provoke God boldly; whereas, it is he who has given all things into their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In truth, ask the mules, and they will teach you, and the birds of the sky, and they will reveal to you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Speak with the earth, and it will respond to you, and the fish of the sea will explain.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who is ignorant that the hand of the Lord has made all these things?</verse>
  <verse number="10">In his hand is the soul of all the living and the spirit of all the flesh of mankind.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Does not the ear perceive words, and the palate, when eating, perceive flavor?</verse>
  <verse number="12">In old age is wisdom, and in length of days is prudence.</verse>
  <verse number="13">With him is wisdom and strength, he has counsel and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If he tears down, there is no one who can build up; if he encloses a man, there is no one who can open.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If he restrains the waters, everything will dry up; and if he sends them forth, they will subdue the land.</verse>
  <verse number="16">With him is strength and wisdom; he knows both the deceiver and he who is deceived.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He leads advisors to a foolish end and judges to stupidity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He removes the belt of kings and encircles their waist with a rope.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He leads away priests in dishonor and displaces nobles,</verse>
  <verse number="20">altering the lips of those who speak the truth and sweeping away the teaching of the aged.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He pours distain upon the leaders, relieving those who had been oppressed.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He reveals the depths of the darkness, and he brings the shadow of death into the light.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He multiplies peoples, and destroys them, and, having been overthrown, he restores them anew.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He transforms the heart of the leaders of the people on earth, and misleads those who in vain advance upon the inviolable.</verse>
  <verse number="25">They will grope as in the darkness, not the light, and he will make them stagger like drunkards.</verse>
</chapter>