<chapter book="Job" number="18" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But Baldad the Suhite responded by saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will you throw around words? Understand first, and then let us speak.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Why have we been treated like mules, as if we were unworthy before you?</verse>
  <verse number="4">You, who ruins your own soul in your fury, will the earth be forsaken because of you, and will the cliffs be moved from their place?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Will not the light of the impious be put out, and the flame of his fire refuse to shine?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Light will become darkness in his tabernacle, and the lamp that is over him will be extinguished.</verse>
  <verse number="7">His strong steps will be constrained, and his own counsel will cast him down uncontrollably.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For he has caused his own feet to go into a net, and he has walked into its web.</verse>
  <verse number="9">His heel will be held in a snare, and thirst will rage against him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A trap has been hidden for him in the earth, and a decoy, along his path.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Horrifying things will terrify him everywhere and will entangle his feet.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let his strength be diminished by famine, and let starvation invade his ribs.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Let it devour the beauty of his skin; let the ancient death consume his arms.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Let his confidence be torn away from his tabernacle, and let ruin trample over him like a king.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Let the companions of he who is not, dwell in his tabernacle; let brimstone rain down upon his tabernacle.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Let his roots be dried up from beneath him, and his harvest be crushed from above.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let the memory of him perish from the earth, and let not his name be celebrated in the streets.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He will expel him from light into darkness, and he will remove him from the world.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Neither his offspring, nor his descendents, will exist among his people, nor will there be any remnants in his country.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The last will be astonished at his day, and the first will be overcome with horror.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And so, these are the tabernacles of the sinful, and this the place of he who does not know God.</verse>
</chapter>