<chapter book="Job" number="21" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job responded by saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">I beseech you to hear my words and to do penance.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Permit me, and I will speak, and afterwards, if you see fit, you can laugh at my words.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Is my dispute against man, so that I would have no reason to be discouraged?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Listen to me and be astonished, and place a finger over your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">As for me, when I think it over, I am afraid, and trembling convulses my body.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Why then do the impious live, having been lifted up and strengthened with riches?</verse>
  <verse number="8">They see their offspring continue before them: a commotion of close relatives and of children’s children in their sight.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Their houses have been secure and peaceable, and there is no staff of God over them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Their cattle have conceived and have not miscarried; their cow has given birth and is not deprived of her newborn.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Their little ones go out like a flock, and their children jump around playfully.</verse>
  <verse number="12">They take up the timbrel and the lyre, and they rejoice at the sound of the organ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Their days are prolonged in wealth, yet, in an instant, they descend into hell.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who has said to God, “Depart from us, for we do not want the knowledge of your ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Who is the Almighty that we should serve him? And how is it helpful to us if we pray to him?”</verse>
  <verse number="16">It is true that their good things are not in their power. May the counsel of the impious be far from me!</verse>
  <verse number="17">How often will the lamp of the wicked be extinguished, and a deluge overtake them, and how often will he distribute the afflictions of his wrath?</verse>
  <verse number="18">They will be like chaff before the face of the wind, and like ashes that the whirlwind scatters.</verse>
  <verse number="19">God will preserve the grief of the father for his sons, and, when he repays, then he will understand.</verse>
  <verse number="20">His eyes will see his own destruction, and he will drink from the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For what does he care what happens to his house after him, or if the number of its months are reduced by half?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Can anyone teach holy knowledge to God, who judges the exalted?</verse>
  <verse number="23">This one dies strong and healthy, rich and happy.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His gut is full of fat and his bones are moistened with marrow.</verse>
  <verse number="25">In truth, another dies in bitterness of soul, without any resources.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And yet they will sleep together in the dust, and worms will cover them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Surely, I know your thoughts and your sinful judgments against me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For you say, “Where is the house of the ruler, and where are the tabernacles of the impious?”</verse>
  <verse number="29">Ask any passerby whom you wish, and you will realize that he understands these same things:</verse>
  <verse number="30">that the evil-doer is reserved for the day of destruction, and he will be led to the day of wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Who will reprove his way to his face, and who will repay him for what he has done?</verse>
  <verse number="32">He will be led to the tomb, and he will remain awake in the chaos of the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He has been found acceptable to the banks of the River of Lamentation, and he will draw any man towards him, and there are countless before him.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Therefore, how long will you console me in vain, when your answer is shown to be repugnant to truth?</verse>
</chapter>