<chapter book="Job" number="22" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Eliphaz the Themanite responded by saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can man be compared with God, even if he were perfect in knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="3">What advantage is it to God, if you were just? Or what do you provide for him, if your way should be immaculate?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will he reprove you and take you to judgment for being afraid,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and not because of your many evil deeds and your infinite unfairness?</verse>
  <verse number="6">For you have taken away the collateral of your brothers without cause, and stripped them naked of their clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="7">You have not given water to the weary; you have taken bread away from the hungry.</verse>
  <verse number="8">By the strength of your arm, you took possession of the land, and you retain it by being the strongest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">You have sent widows away empty, and you have crushed the shoulders of orphans.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Because of this, you are surrounded by traps, and unexpected fears will disturb you.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And did you think that you would not see darkness and that you were not to be overwhelmed by the on-rush of overflowing waters?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Have you not considered that God is higher than the heavens and is lifted above the height of the stars?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And you say: “Well, what does God know?” and, “He judges, as if through a fog,”</verse>
  <verse number="14">and, “The clouds are his hiding-place,” and, “He does not examine us closely,” and, “He makes his rounds at the limits of the heavens.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">Do you not want to tend the path of the ages, which wicked men have spurned?</verse>
  <verse number="16">These were taken away before their time, and a flood overthrew their foundation.</verse>
  <verse number="17">They said to God, “Withdraw from us,” and they treated the Almighty as if he could do nothing,</verse>
  <verse number="18">though he had filled their houses with good things. May their way of thinking be far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The just will see and will rejoice, and the innocent will mock them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Has not their haughtiness been cut down, and has not fire devoured the remnants of them?</verse>
  <verse number="21">So, repose yourself with him and be at peace, and, in this way, you will have the best fruits.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Accept the law from his mouth, and place his words in your heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If you will return to the Almighty, you will be rebuilt, and you will put sinfulness far from your tabernacle.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He will give you stone in place of dirt, and torrents of gold in place of stone.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the Almighty will be against your enemies, and silver will be gathered together for you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then will you flock together in delight over the Almighty, and you will lift up your face to God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">You will plead with him, and he will listen to you, and you will pay your vows.</verse>
  <verse number="28">You will decide on something, and it will come to you, and the light will shine in your ways.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For he who had been humbled, will be in glory; and he who will lower his eyes, will be the one saved.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The innocent will be saved, and he will be saved with purity in his hands.</verse>
</chapter>