<chapter book="Job" number="23" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered by saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Now again my conversation is in bitterness, and the force of my scourging weighs more heavily on me because of my mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Who will grant me that I might know and find him, and that I may approach even to his throne?</verse>
  <verse number="4">I would place judgment before his eye, and my mouth would fill with criticism,</verse>
  <verse number="5">so that I may know the words that he will answer me and understand what he will say to me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I do not want him to contend with me with much strength, nor to overwhelm me with the bulk of his greatness.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Let him show fairness in response to me, and let my judgment reach to victory.</verse>
  <verse number="8">If I go to the east, he does not appear; if I go to the west, I will not understand him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If I turn to the left, what can I do? I will not take hold of him. If I turn myself to the right, I will not see him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Truly, he knows my way and has tested me like gold that passes through fire.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My feet have been following his footsteps; I have kept to his way and have not strayed from it.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I have not withdrawn from the commands of his lips, and the words of his mouth I have hidden in my sinews.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For he is alone, and no one is able to disturb his intention; and whatever his spirit wills, that he accomplishes.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And when he fulfills his will in me, many other similar ones will also be present with him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And, for this reason, I have been troubled at his presence, and, when I consider him, I am approached by fear.</verse>
  <verse number="16">God has weakened my heart, and the Almighty has confused me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Yet I have not perished because of the threatening darkness, nor has gloom covered my face.</verse>
</chapter>