<chapter book="Job" number="3" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After this, Job opened his mouth and cursed his day,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and this is what he said:</verse>
  <verse number="3">May the day perish on which I was born, and the night, in which it was said, “A man has been conceived.”</verse>
  <verse number="4">May that day be turned into darkness, may God not seek it from above, and may light not illuminate it.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Let darkness and the shadow of death obscure it, let a fog overtake it, and let it be enveloped in bitterness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let a whirlwind of darkness take hold of that night, let it not be counted in the days of the year, nor numbered in the months.</verse>
  <verse number="7">May that night be alone and unworthy of praise.</verse>
  <verse number="8">May they curse it, who curse the day, who are prepared to awaken a leviathan.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Let the stars be concealed with its darkness. Let it expect light, and not see it, nor the rising of the dawn in the East.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For it did not close the doors of the womb that bore me, nor take away evils from my eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Why did I not die in the womb? Having left the womb, why did I not immediately perish?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why was I received upon the knees? Why was I suckled at the breasts?</verse>
  <verse number="13">For by now, I should have been sleeping silently, and taking rest in my sleep</verse>
  <verse number="14">with the kings and consuls of the earth, who build themselves solitudes,</verse>
  <verse number="15">either with princes, who possess gold and fill their houses with silver,</verse>
  <verse number="16">or, like a hidden miscarriage, I should not have continued, just like those who, being conceived, have not seen the light.</verse>
  <verse number="17">There the impious cease from rebellion, and there the wearied in strength take rest.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And at such times, having been bound together without difficulty, they have not heard the voice of the bailiff.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The small and great are there, and the servant is free from his master.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why is light given to the miserable, and life to those who are in bitterness of soul,</verse>
  <verse number="21">who expect death, and it does not arrive, like those who dig for treasure</verse>
  <verse number="22">and who rejoice greatly when they have found the grave,</verse>
  <verse number="23">to a man whose way is hidden and whom God has surrounded with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Before I eat, I sigh; and like overflowing waters, so is my howl,</verse>
  <verse number="25">for the terror that I feared has happened to me, and so has the dread befallen me.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Have I not remained hidden? Have I not kept silence? Have I not remained calm? Yet indignation has overcome me.</verse>
</chapter>