<chapter book="Job" number="30" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But now, those younger in years scorn me, whose fathers I would not have seen fit to place with the dogs of my flock,</verse>
  <verse number="2">the strength of whose hands was nothing to me, and they were considered unworthy of life itself.</verse>
  <verse number="3">They were barren from poverty and hunger; they gnawed in solitude, layered with misfortune and misery.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they chewed grass and the bark from trees, and the root of junipers was their food.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They took these things from the steep valleys, and when they discovered one of these things, they rushed to the others with a cry.</verse>
  <verse number="6">They lived in the parched desert and in caves underground or above the rocks.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They rejoiced among these kinds of things, and they considered it delightful to be under thorns.</verse>
  <verse number="8">These are the sons of foolish and base men, not even paying any attention to the land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Now I become their song, and I have been made into their proverb.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They loathe me, and so they flee far from me, and they are not reluctant to spit in my face.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he has opened his quiver and has afflicted me, and he has placed a bridle in my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Immediately, upon rising, my calamities rise up to the right. They have overturned my feet and have pressed me down along their way like waves.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They have diverted my journeys; they have waited to ambush me, and they have prevailed, and there was no one who might bring help.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They have rushed upon me, as when a wall is broken or a gate opened, and they have been pulled down into my miseries.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I have been reduced to nothing. You have taken away my desire like a wind, and my health has passed by like a cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But now my soul withers within myself, and the days of affliction take hold of me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">At night, my bone is pierced with sorrows, and those who feed on me, do not sleep.</verse>
  <verse number="18">By the sheer number of them my clothing is worn away, and they have closed in on me like the collar of my coat.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I have been treated like dirt, and I have been turned into embers and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I cry to you, and you do not heed me. I stand up, and you do not look back at me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">You have changed me into hardness, and, with the hardness of your hand, you oppose me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">You have lifted me up, and, placing me as if on the wind, you have thrown me down powerfully.</verse>
  <verse number="23">I know that you will hand me over to death, where a home has been established for all the living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Truly, then, you do not extend your hand in order to consume them, and if they fall down, you will save them.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Once, I wept over him who was afflicted, and my soul had compassion on the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I expected good things, but evil things have come to me. I stood ready for light, yet darkness burst forth.</verse>
  <verse number="27">My insides have seethed, without any rest, for the days of affliction have prevented it.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I went forth mourning, without anger, and rising up, I cried out in confusion.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I was the brother of snakes, and the companion of ostriches.</verse>
  <verse number="30">My skin has become blackened over me, and my bones have dried up because of the heat.</verse>
  <verse number="31">My harp has been turned into mourning, and my pipes have been turned into a voice of weeping.</verse>
</chapter>