<chapter book="Job" number="36" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Continuing in a similar manner, Eliu had this to say:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Bear with me for a little while and I will show you; for I have still more to say in favor of God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I will review my knowledge from the beginning, and I will prove my Maker to be just.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For truly my words are without any falsehood and perfect knowledge will be proven to you.</verse>
  <verse number="5">God does not abandon the powerful, for he himself is also powerful.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But he does not save the impious, though he grants judgment to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He will not take his eyes away from the just, and he continually establishes kings on their throne, and they are exalted.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And, if they are in captivity, or are bound with the chains of poverty,</verse>
  <verse number="9">he will reveal to them their works, as well as their sinfulness, in that they were violent.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Likewise, he will open their ears to his correction, and he will speak to them, so that they may return from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they listen and obey, they will fill their days with goodness and complete their years in glory.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But if they will not listen, they will pass away by the sword and will be consumed by foolishness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The false and the crafty provoke the wrath of God, yet they do not cry out to him when they are chained.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Their soul will die in a storm, and their life, among the unmanly.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He will rescue the poor from his anguish, and he will open his ear during tribulation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Therefore, he will save you from the narrow mouth very widely, even though it has no foundation under it. Moreover, your respite at table will be full of fatness.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Your case has been judged like that of the impious; you will withdraw your plea and your judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Therefore, do not let anger overwhelm you so that you oppress another; neither should you allow a multitude of gifts to influence you.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Lay down your greatness without distress, and put aside all of your power with courage.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Do not prolong the night, even if people rise on their behalf.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Be careful that you do not turn to iniquity; for, after your misery, you have begun to follow this.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Behold, God is exalted in his strength, and there is no one like him among the law-givers.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Who is able to investigate his ways? And who can say, “You have done iniquity,” to him?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Remember that you are ignorant of his work, yet men have sung its praises.</verse>
  <verse number="25">All men consider him; and each one ponders from a distance.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Behold, God is great, defeating our knowledge; the number of his years is inestimable.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He carries away the drops of rain, and he sends forth showers like a raging whirlpool;</verse>
  <verse number="28">they flow from the clouds that are woven above everything.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If he wills it, he extends the clouds as his tent</verse>
  <verse number="30">and shines with his light from above; likewise, he covers the oceans within his tent.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For he judges the people by these things, and he gives food to a multitude of mortals.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Within his hands, he hides the light, and he commands it to come forth again.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He announces it to his friend, for it is his possession and he is able to reach out to it.</verse>
</chapter>