<chapter book="Job" number="37" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">At this, my heart became frightened, and it has been moved from its place.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Pay close attention to the alarm of his voice and to the sound that proceeds from his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He beholds everything under the heavens, and his light reaches beyond the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">After this, a noise will sound; he will thunder with the voice of his greatness, and it will not be tracked down, yet his voice will be obeyed.</verse>
  <verse number="5">God will thunder with his voice miraculously, for he performs great and unsearchable things.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He commands the snow to descend on earth, and the winter rains, and the shower of his strength.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He signs the hand of all men, so that each one may know his works.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The beast will enter his hiding-place, and he will remain in his cave.</verse>
  <verse number="9">From the interior, a storm will come forth, and a cold winter from the north.</verse>
  <verse number="10">As God breathes out, frost forms, and the waters are poured forth very widely again.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Crops desire clouds, and the clouds scatter their light.</verse>
  <verse number="12">It shines all around, wherever the will of him that governs them will lead, to anywhere he will command, over the whole face of the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="13">whether in one tribe, or in his own region, or in whatever place of his mercy that he will order them to be found.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Listen to these things, Job. Stand up and consider the wonders of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Do you know when God ordered the rains, so as to show the light of his clouds?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Do you know the great paths of the clouds, and the perfect sciences?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Are not your garments hot, when the south wind blows across the land?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Perhaps you have made the heavens with him, which are very solid, as if they had been cast from brass.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Reveal to us what we should say to him, for, of course, we are wrapped in darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Who will explain to him the things that I am saying? Even while a man is still speaking, he will be devoured.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Although they do not see the light, the air will be thickened suddenly into clouds, and the wind, passing by, will drive them away.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Riches arrive from the north, and fearful praise reaches out to God.</verse>
  <verse number="23">We are not worthy to be able to find him. Great in strength, great in judgment, great in justice: he is indescribable.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Therefore, men will fear him, and all those who seem to themselves to be wise, will not dare to contemplate him.</verse>
</chapter>