<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Do you know at what time the wild goats have given birth among the rocks, or do you observe the deer when they go into labor?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Have you numbered the months since their conception, and do you know at what time they gave birth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">They bend themselves for their offspring, and they give birth, and they emit roars.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Their young are weaned and go out to feed; they depart and do not return to them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who has set the wild ass free, and who has released his bonds?</verse>
  <verse number="6">I have given a house in solitude to him, and his tabernacle is in the salted land.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He despises the crowded city; he does not pay attention to the bellow of the tax collector.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He looks around the mountains of his pasture, and he searches everywhere for green plants.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will the rhinoceros be willing to serve you, and will he remain in your stall?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Can you detain the rhinoceros with your harness to plough for you, and will he loosen the soil of the furrows behind you?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Will you put your faith in his great strength, and delegate your labors to him?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Will you trust him to return to you the seed, and to gather it on your drying floor?</verse>
  <verse number="13">The wing of the ostrich is like the wings of the heron, and of the hawk.</verse>
  <verse number="14">When she leaves eggs behind in the earth, will you perhaps warm them in the dust?</verse>
  <verse number="15">She forgets that feet may trample them, or that the beasts of the field may shatter them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She is hardened against her young, as if they were not hers; she has labored in vain, with no fear compelling her.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For God has deprived her of wisdom; neither has he given her understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Yet, when the time is right, she raises her wings on high; she ridicules the horse and his rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Will you supply strength to the horse, or envelope his throat with neighing?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Will you alarm him as the locusts do? His panic is revealed by the display of his nostrils.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He digs at the earth with his hoof; he jumps around boldly; he advances to meet armed men.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He despises fear; he does not turn away from the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Above him, the quiver rattles, the spear and the shield shake.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Seething and raging, he drinks up the earth; neither does he pause when the blast of the trumpet sounds.</verse>
  <verse number="25">When he hears the bugle, he says, “Ha!” He smells the battle from a distance, the exhortation of the officers, and the battle cry of the soldiers.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Does the hawk grow feathers by means of your wisdom, spreading her wings towards the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Will the eagle lift herself up at your command and make her nest in steep places?</verse>
  <verse number="28">She dwells among the rocks, and she lingers among broken boulders and inaccessible cliffs.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From there, she looks for food, and her eyes catch sight of it from far away.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Her young will drink blood, and wherever the carcass will be, she is there immediately.</verse>
</chapter>