<chapter book="Ezra" number="10" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And at Ezra’s praying, and at his making confession, weeping and casting himself down before the house of God, there have been gathered unto him out of Israel an assembly very great—men and women and children—for the people have wept, multiplying weeping.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Shechaniah son of Jehiel, of the sons of Elam, answereth and saith to Ezra, ‘We—we have trespassed against our God, and we settle strange women of the peoples of the land; and now there is hope for Israel concerning this,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and now, let us make a covenant with our God, to cause all the women to go out, and that which is born of them, by the counsel of the Lord, and of those trembling at the command of our God, and according to law it is done;</verse>
  <verse number="4">rise, for on thee is the matter, and we are with thee; be strong, and do.’</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Ezra riseth, and causeth the heads of the priests, the Levites, and all Israel, to swear to do according to this word—and they swear.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Ezra riseth from before the house of God, and goeth unto the chamber of Jehohanan son of Eliashib; yea, he goeth there, bread he hath not eaten, and water he hath not drunk, for he is mourning because of the trespass of the removal.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they cause a voice to pass over into Judah and Jerusalem, to all sons of the removal, to be gathered to Jerusalem,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and every one who cometh not in by the third day, according to the counsel of the heads and of the elders, all his substance is devoted, and himself separated from the assembly of the removal.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And gathered are all the men of Judah and Benjamin to Jerusalem by the third day, it is the ninth month, on the twentieth of the month, and all the people sit in the broad place of the house of God, trembling on account of the matter and of the showers.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Ezra the priest riseth, and saith unto them, ‘Ye—ye have trespassed, and ye settle strange women, to add to the guilt of Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and, now, make confession to Jehovah, God of your fathers, and do His good pleasure, and be separated from the peoples of the land, and from the strange women.’</verse>
  <verse number="12">And all the assembly answer and say with a great voice, ‘Right; according to thy word—on us to do;</verse>
  <verse number="13">but the people are many, and it is the time of showers, and there is no power to stand without, and the work is not for one day, nor for two, for we have multiplied to transgress in this thing.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Let, we pray thee, our heads of all the assembly stand, and all who are in our cities, who have settled strange wives, do come in at the times appointed, and with them the elders of city and city, and its judges, till the turning back of the fury of the wrath of our God from us, for this thing.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">Only Jonathan son of Asahel, and Jahaziah son of Tikvah, stood against this, and Meshullam, and Shabbethai the Levite, helped them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the sons of the removal do so, and Ezra the priest, and men, heads of the fathers, for the house of their fathers, are separated, even all of them by name, and they sit on the first day of the tenth month, to examine the matter;</verse>
  <verse number="17">and they finish with all the men who have settled strange women unto the first day of the first month.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And there are found of the sons of the priests that have settled strange women: of the sons of Jeshua son of Jozadak, and his brethren, Maaseiah, and Eliezer, and Jarib, and Gedaliah;</verse>
  <verse number="19">and they give their hand to send out their wives, and, being guilty, a ram of the flock, for their guilt.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And of the sons of Immer: Hanani and Zebadiah;</verse>
  <verse number="21">and of the sons of Harim: Masseiah, and Elijah, and Shemaiah, and Jehiel, and Uzziah;</verse>
  <verse number="22">and of the sons of Pashhur: Elioenai, Maaseiah, Ishmael, Nethaneel, Jozabad, and Elasah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And of the Levites: Jozabad, and Shimei, and Kelaiah—he is Kelita,—Pethahiah, Judah, and Eliezer.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And of the singers: Eliashib. And of the gatekeepers: Shallum, and Telem, and Uri.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And of Israel: of the sons of Parosh: Ramiah, and Jeziah, and Malchijah, and Miamin, and Eleazar, and Malchijah, and Benaiah.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And of the sons of Elam: Mattaniah, Zechariah, and Jehiel, and Abdi, and Jeremoth, and Elijah.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And of the sons of Zattu: Elioenai, Eliashib, Mattaniah, and Jeremoth, and Zabad, and Aziza.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And of the sons of Bebai: Jehohanan, Hananiah, Zabbai, Athlai.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And of the sons of Bani: Meshullam, Malluch, and Adaiah, Jashub, and Sheal, and Ramoth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And of the sons of Pahath-Moab: Adna, and Chelal, Benaiah, Maaseiah, Mattaniah, Bezaleel, and Binnui, and Manasseh.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And of the sons of Harim: Eliezer, Ishijah, Malchiah, Shemaiah, Shimeon,</verse>
  <verse number="32">Benjamin, Malluch, Shemariah.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Of the sons of Hashum: Mattenai, Mattathah, Zabad, Eliphelet, Jeremai, Manasseh, Shimei.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Of the sons of Bani: Maadai, Amram, and Uel,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Benaiah, Bedeiah, Cheluhu,</verse>
  <verse number="36">Vaniah, Meremoth, Eliashib,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Mattaniah, Mattenai, and Jaasau,</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Bani, and Binnui, Shimei,</verse>
  <verse number="39">and Shelemiah, and Nathan, and Adaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="40">Machnadbai, Shashai, Sharai,</verse>
  <verse number="41">Azareel, and Shelemiah, Shemariah,</verse>
  <verse number="42">Shallum, Amariah, Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Of the sons of Nebo: Jeiel, Mattithiah, Zabad, Zebina, Jadau, and Joel, Benaiah;</verse>
  <verse number="44">all these have taken strange women, and there are of them women—who adopt sons.</verse>
</chapter>