<chapter book="Ezra" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these are sons of the province who are going up—of the captives of the removal that Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon removed to Babylon, and they turn back to Jerusalem and Judah, each to his city—</verse>
  <verse number="2">who have come in with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, Baanah: The number of the men of the people of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Sons of Parosh, two thousand a hundred seventy and two.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Sons of Shephatiah, three hundred seventy and two.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Sons of Arah, seven hundred five and seventy.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Sons of Pahath-Moab, of the sons of Jeshua, Joab, two thousand eight hundred and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Sons of Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Sons of Zattu, nine hundred and forty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Sons of Zaccai, seven hundred and sixty.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Sons of Bani, six hundred forty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Sons of Bebai, six hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Sons of Azgad, a thousand two hundred twenty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Sons of Adonikam, six hundred sixty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Sons of Bigvai, two thousand fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Sons of Adin, four hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Sons of Ater of Hezekiah, ninety and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Sons of Bezai, three hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Sons of Jorah, a hundred and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Sons of Hashum, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Sons of Gibbar, ninety and five.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Sons of Beth-Lehem, a hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Men of Netophah, fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Men of Anathoth, a hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Sons of Azmaveth, forty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Sons of Kirjath-Arim, Chephirah, and Beeroth, seven hundred and forty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Sons of Ramah and Gaba, six hundred twenty and one.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Men of Michmas, a hundred twenty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Men of Beth-El and Ai, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Sons of Nebo, fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Sons of Magbish, a hundred fifty and six.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Sons of another Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Sons of Harim, three hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Sons of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, seven hundred twenty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Sons of Jericho, three hundred forty and five.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Sons of Senaah, three thousand and six hundred and thirty.</verse>
  <verse number="36">The Priests: sons of Jedaiah, of the house of Jeshua, nine hundred seventy and three.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Sons of Imner, a thousand fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Sons of Pashhur, a thousand two hundred forty and seven.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Sons of Harim, a thousand and seventeen.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The Levites; sons of Jeshua and Kadmiel, of the sons of Hodaviah, seventy and four.</verse>
  <verse number="41">The singers: sons of Asaph, a hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Sons of the gatekeepers; sons of Shallum, sons of Ater, sons of Talmon, sons of Akkub, sons of Hatita, sons of Shobai, the whole are a hundred thirty and nine.</verse>
  <verse number="43">The Nethinim: sons of Ziha, sons of Hasupha, sons of Tabbaoth,</verse>
  <verse number="44">Sons of Keros, sons of Siaha, sons of Padon,</verse>
  <verse number="45">Sons of Lebanah, sons of Hagabah, sons of Akkub,</verse>
  <verse number="46">Sons of Hagab, sons of Shalmai, sons of Hanan,</verse>
  <verse number="47">Sons of Giddel, sons of Gahar, sons of Reaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="48">Sons of Rezin, sons of Nekoda, sons of Gazzam,</verse>
  <verse number="49">Sons of Uzza, sons of Paseah, sons of Besai,</verse>
  <verse number="50">Sons of Asnah, sons of Mehunim, sons of Nephusim,</verse>
  <verse number="51">Sons of Bakbuk, sons of Hakupha, sons of Harhur,</verse>
  <verse number="52">Sons of Bazluth, sons of Mehida, sons of Harsha,</verse>
  <verse number="53">Sons of Barkos, sons of Sisera, sons of Thamah,</verse>
  <verse number="54">Sons of Neziah, sons of Hatipha.</verse>
  <verse number="55">Sons of the servants of Solomon: sons of Sotai, sons of Sophereth, sons of Peruda,</verse>
  <verse number="56">Sons of Jaalah, sons of Darkon, sons of Giddel,</verse>
  <verse number="57">Sons of Shephatiah, sons of Hattil, sons of Pochereth of Zebaim, sons of Ami.</verse>
  <verse number="58">All the Nethinim, and the sons of the servants of Solomon are three hundred ninety and two.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And these are those going up from Tel-Melah, Tel-Harsa, Cherub, Addan, Immer, and they have not been able to declare the house of their fathers, and their seed, whether they are of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="60">sons of Delaiah, sons of Tobiah, sons of Nekoda, six hundred fifty and two.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And of the sons of the priests: sons of Habaiah, sons of Koz, sons of Barzillai (who took from the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite a wife, and is called by their name;)</verse>
  <verse number="62">these have sought their register among those reckoning themselves by genealogy, and they have not been found, and they are redeemed from the priesthood,</verse>
  <verse number="63">and the Tirshatha saith to them, that they eat not of the most holy things till the standing up of a priest with Urim and with Thummim.</verse>
  <verse number="64">All the assembly together is four myriad two thousand three hundred sixty,</verse>
  <verse number="65">apart from their servants and their handmaids; these are seven thousand three hundred thirty and seven: and of them are singers and songstresses two hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="66">Their horses are seven hundred thirty and six, their mules, two hundred forty and five,</verse>
  <verse number="67">their camels, four hundred thirty and five, asses, six thousand seven hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="68">And some of the heads of the fathers in their coming in to the house of Jehovah that is in Jerusalem, have offered willingly for the house of God, to establish it on its base;</verse>
  <verse number="69">according to their power they have given to the treasure of the work; of gold, drams six myriads and a thousand, and of silver, pounds five thousand, and of priests’ coats, a hundred.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And the priests dwell, and the Levites, and of the people, and the singers, and the gatekeepers, and the Nethinim, in their cities; even all Israel in their cities.</verse>
</chapter>