<chapter book="1 Samuel" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it will be when Samuel was old, he set his sons judges to Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the name of his son the firstborn will be Joel; and the name of his second, Abiah: judges at the Well of the Oath.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And his sons went not in his way, and they will incline after plunder, and they will take a gift, and they will turn away from judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And all the old men of Israel will gather together and will come to Samuel to Ramah;</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they will say to him, Behold, thou wert old, and thy sons went not in thy ways: now set up for us a king to judge us as all the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the word will be evil in the eyes of Samuel when they said, Give to us a king to judge us: and Samuel will pray to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Jehovah will say to Samuel, Hear to the voice of the people to all which they will say to thee: for not thee did they reject, but me they rejected from reigning over them.</verse>
  <verse number="8">According to all the works which they did from the day I brought them up out of Egypt, and even to this day, and they will forsake me and serve other gods, so they do also to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And now hear to their voice: but protesting, thou shalt protest to them, and announce to them the judgment of the king who shall reign over them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Samuel will say all the words of Jehovah to the people asking from him a king.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he will say, This shall be the judgment of the king who shall reign over you: your sons he will take and set for himself, for his chariots and for his horsemen; and running before his chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And to set to himself captains of thousands and captains of fifties; and to plough his ploughing and to reap his harvest, and to do all his fighting and all his chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And your daughters he will take for perfumers, and for cooks, and for bakers.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And your fields and your vineyards, and your olive trees, the good he will take and give to his servants.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And of your seeds and of your vineyards he will take the tenth and give to his eunuchs and to his servants.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And your servants and your maids, and your good young men, and your asses, he will take and make for his services.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And of your sheep he will take the tenth: and ye shall be to him for servants.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And ye cried out in that day from before your king which ye chose to yourselves; and Jehovah will not answer you in that day.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the people will refuse to hear to the voice of Samuel; and they will say, Nay; but a king shall be over us.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And we were as all the nations; and our king judged us and went out before us, and fought our battles.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Samuel will hear all the words of the people, and he will speak them in the ears of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Jehovah will say to Samuel, Hear to their voice, and make a king for them. And Samuel will say to them, Go ye a man to his city.</verse>
</chapter>