<chapter book="Hebrews" number="13" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Let the charity of the brotherhood abide in you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And hospitality do not forget; for by this some, being not aware of it, have entertained angels.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Remember them that are in bands, as if you were bound with them; and them that labour, as being yourselves also in the body.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Marriage honourable in all, and the bed undefiled. For fornicators and adulterers God will judge.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Let your manners be without covetousness, contented with such things as you have; for he hath said: I will not leave thee, neither will I forsake thee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">So that we may confidently say: The Lord is my helper: I will not fear what man shall do to me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Remember your prelates who have spoken the word of God to you; whose faith follow, considering the end of their conversation,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Jesus Christ, yesterday, and to day; and the same for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be not led away with various and strange doctrines. For it is best that the heart be established with grace, not with meats; which have not profited those that walk in them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">We have an altar, whereof they have no power to eat who serve the tabernacle.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the bodies of those beasts, whose blood is brought into the holies by the high priest for sin, are burned without the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Wherefore Jesus also, that he might sanctify the people by his own blood, suffered without the gate.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Let us go forth therefore to him without the camp, bearing his reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For we have not here a lasting city, but we seek one that is to come.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By him therefore let us offer the sacrifice of praise always to God, that is to say, the fruit of lips confessing to his name.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And do not forget to do good, and to impart; for by such sacrifices God’s favour is obtained.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Obey your prelates, and be subject to them. For they watch as being to render an account of your souls; that they may do this with joy, and not with grief. For this is not expedient for you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Pray for us. For we trust we have a good conscience, being willing to behave ourselves well in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And I beseech you the more to do this, that I may be restored to you the sooner.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And may the God of peace, who brought again from the dead the great pastor of the sheep, our Lord Jesus Christ, in the blood of the everlasting testament,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Fit you in all goodness, that you may do his will; doing in you that which is well pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom is glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And I beseech you, brethren, that you suffer this word of consolation. For I have written to you in a few words.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Know ye that our brother Timothy is set at liberty: with whom (if he come shortly) I will see you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Salute all your prelates, and all the saints. The brethren from Italy salute you.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Grace be with you all. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>