<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The song of songs which is to Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He shall kiss me from the kisses of his mouth: for thy good breasts are above wine.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To the odor of the good ointments thy name shall be poured forth an ointment; for this, the maidens loved thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Draw me, we will run after thee: the king brought me to his chambers: we will exult and rejoice in thee, we will remember thy breasts above wine: the upright loved thee.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I am black and beautiful, O daughters of Jerusalem, as the tents of Kedar, as the curtains of Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Thou shalt not see me, I am black; the sun searched me: my mother’s sons were angry with me; they set me to watch the vineyards; my vineyard I watched not for me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Announce to me, thou whom my soul loved, where thou wilt feed, where thou wilt lie down at noon: wherefore shall I be as he covered by the herds of thy companions.</verse>
  <verse number="8">If thou shalt not know for thyself, O fair one among women, come forth for thyself at the heels of the flock, and feed thy kids by the shepherds tents.</verse>
  <verse number="9">To my mares in Pharaoh’s chariots I likened thee, O my neighbor.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thy cheeks were beautiful with with rows, thy neck with strings of pearls.</verse>
  <verse number="11">We will make for thee rows of gold, with marks of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The king yet in his divan, my spikenard gave its odor.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A bundle of myrrh my beloved to me; he shall lodge between my breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A cluster of cypress my beloved to me in the vineyards of the kids fountain.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold thee fair, my friend; behold thee beautiful; thine eyes are doves’.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold thee beautiful, my beloved, also pleasant: also our bed is green.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The walls of our houses cedars, our carved ceilings, cypresses.</verse>
</chapter>