<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am the flower of the plain, the lily of the valleys.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As the lily between thorns, so is my friend between the daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="3">As the apple among the trees of the forest, so my beloved between the sons. In his shadow I delighted, and I sat down, and his fruit was sweet to my palate.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He brought me to the house of wine, and his banner over me was love.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Sustain me with cakes, and refresh me with apples, for I am pierced of love.</verse>
  <verse number="6">His left hand is under my head, and his right shall embrace me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I adjured you, O daughters of Jerusalem, by the roes, or by the hinds of the field, if ye shall awake and if ye shall arouse love till he shall desire.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The voice of my beloved I behold him coming leaping upon the mountains, springing upon the hills.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My beloved is like to the roe or to the fawn of the hinds: behold him standing behind our wall looking forth from the windows, glancing from the lattices.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My beloved answered and said to me, Rise up for thyself, my friend, my beautiful one, and go for thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For behold, the winter passed away, the rain glided away; it went for itself.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The flowers were seen in the earth; the time of pruning came, and the voice of the turtle-dove was heard in our land.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fig tree ripened its unripe figs, and the vines are in blossom; they gave an odor. Rise up, my friend, my beautiful one, and go for thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My dove in the refuges of the rock, in the biding of the steep mountain: cause me to see thy form, cause me to hear thy voice; for thy voice is sweet and thy form becoming.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Seize for us the foxes, the little foxes destroying the vineyards: and our vineyards are in blossom.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My beloved to me, and I to him: he feeding among the lilies.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Until the day shall breathe and the shadows fled away, turn, thou, it being likened to thee, my beloved, to the roe, or to the fawn of the hind upon the mountains of section.</verse>
</chapter>