<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Behold thee beautiful, my friend, behold thee beautiful; thine eyes doves from behind to thy veil: thy hair as a herd of goats which lay down from mount Gilead.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thy teeth as a herd of the shorn which came up from the washing; all of them bearing twins, and none barren among them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">As a scarlet thread thy lips, and thy speech becoming: as a piece of pomegranate, thy temples from behind thy veil.</verse>
  <verse number="4">As the tower of David thy neck, built for the weapons; a thousand shields hung upon it, all shields of the powerful.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thy two breasts as two fawns, twins of the roe deer feeding among the lilies.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Till the day shall breathe, and the shadows fled away, I will go for myself to the mountain of myrrh, and to the hill of Lebanon.</verse>
  <verse number="7">All of thee beautiful, my friend, and no blemish in thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thou shalt come with me from Lebanon, O bride, with me from Lebanon: thou shalt go round about from the head of faith, from the head of Shenir and Hermon, from the dwellings of lions, from the mountains of panthers.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou didst rob me of the heart, my sister, O bride; thou didst rob me of the heart with one of thine eyes, with one necklace of thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">How beautiful were thy breasts, my sister, O bride! how good were thy breasts above wine, and the odor of thine ointments above all spices.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thy lips will drop honey droppings, O bride: honey and milk under thy tongue, and the odor of thy garments as the odor of Lebanon.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A garden shut up, my sister, O bride; a reservoir shut up, a fountain sealed.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Thy sendings forth a park of pomegranates, with most precious fruits, cypresses with spikenards,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Spikenard and saffron; the reed and cinnamon, with all the woods of Lebanon; myrrh and aloes, with all the heads of spices.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A fountain of gardens, a well of living waters and flowings from Lebanon.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Awake, O north wind; and come, thou south, blow upon my garden; its spices shall flow out. My beloved shall come to his garden, and he shall eat his most precious fruits.</verse>
</chapter>