<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I Came to my garden, my sister, O spouse: I gathered my myrrh with my spices; I ate my droppings with my honey; I drank my wine with my milk: Eat, O friends; drink ye, and drink to the full, O beloved ones.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I slept and my heart waked: the voice of my beloved knocks at the door; Open to me, my sister, my friend, my dove, my perfect one: my head was filled with dew, my locks with the drops of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I put off my tunic, and how shall I put it on? I washed my feet; how shall I defile them?</verse>
  <verse number="4">My beloved sent his hand from the hole, and my bowels were disquieted for him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I arose to open to my beloved, and my hands dropped myrrh, and my fingers, myrrh overflowing upon the hands of the bolt.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I opened to my beloved, and my beloved turned about, he passed away: my soul went forth in his speaking: I sought and I found him not; I called him and he answered me not.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They watching going round about in the city, found me; they struck me, they wounded me: they watching the wall took away my veil from me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">I adjured you, O daughters of Jerusalem, if ye shall find my beloved, what ye shall announce to him: I am pierced by love.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What is thy beloved above the beloved, O beautiful one among women? What thy beloved above the beloved, that thou didst thus adjure us?</verse>
  <verse number="10">My beloved is white and ruddy, bearing the standard of ten thousand.</verse>
  <verse number="11">His head purified gold, his locks waving branches, black as a raven.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His eyes as doves upon channels of waters washed with milk, sitting upon fulness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">His cheeks as beds of spices, towers of aromatic herbs: his lips lilies, dropping overflowing myrrh.</verse>
  <verse number="14">His hands rings of gold completed in Tarshish: his bowels wrought ivory covered over with sapphires.</verse>
  <verse number="15">His legs bases of white marble, founded upon of pure gold: his aspect as Lebanon, choice as the cedars.</verse>
  <verse number="16">His palate, sweetness: he is all loveliness. This my beloved, and this my friend, O daughters of Jerusalem.</verse>
</chapter>