<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Who will give thee as a brother to me, sucking the breasts of my mother? I shall find thee without, I shall kiss thee; also they shall not despise me.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will lead thee, I will bring thee to the house of my mother; thou wilt teach me: I will give thee to drink from spiced wine from the new wine of my pomegranate.</verse>
  <verse number="3">His left hand under my head, and his right shall embrace me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">I adjured you, O daughters of Jerusalem, why will ye awake, and why will ye rouse love till he shall desire?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who this coming up from the desert, leaning herself upon her beloved? Under the apple tree I aroused thee: there thy mother brought thee forth: there she bearing thee, brought forth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Set me as a seal upon thy heart, as a seal upon thine arm: for love was strong as death; jealousy hard as hades: its flames, flames of fire, flames of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Many waters shall not be able to quench love, and rivers shall not overwhelm it: if a man shall give all the riches of his house for love, despising, they shall be despised for him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A little sister to us, and no breasts to her: what shall we do for our sister in the day it shall be spoken for her?</verse>
  <verse number="9">If she be a wall, we will build upon her a fortress of silver: and if she is a door we will bind upon her a tablet of cedar.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I am a wall, and my breasts as towers: then was I in his eyes as finding peace.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A vineyard was to Solomon in the place of a multitude; he gave the vineyards to those watching; each shall bring in its fruit a thousand of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">My vineyard to me before me: a thousand to thee, O Solomon, and two hundred to those watching its fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Thou sitting in the gardens, the companions attending to thy voice: cause thou me to hear.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Flee, my beloved, and be it likened to thee to the roe or to the fawn of the hinds upon the mountains of spices.</verse>
</chapter>