<chapter book="1 Timothy" number="1" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, apostle of Jesus Christ, according to [the] command of God our Saviour, and of Christ Jesus our hope,</verse>
  <verse number="2">to Timotheus, [my] true child in faith: grace, mercy, peace, from God our Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Even as I begged thee to remain in Ephesus, [when I was] going to Macedonia, that thou mightest enjoin some not to teach other doctrines,</verse>
  <verse number="4">nor to turn their minds to fables and interminable genealogies, which bring questionings rather than [further] God’s dispensation, which [is] in faith.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But the end of what is enjoined is love out of a pure heart and a good conscience and unfeigned faith;</verse>
  <verse number="6">which [things] some having missed, have turned aside to vain discourse,</verse>
  <verse number="7">desiring to be law-teachers, not understanding either what they say or concerning what they [so] strenuously affirm.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Now we know that the law [is] good if any one uses it lawfully,</verse>
  <verse number="9">knowing this, that law has not its application to a righteous person, but to [the] lawless and insubordinate, to [the] impious and sinful, to [the] unholy and profane, to smiters of fathers and smiters of mothers; to murderers,</verse>
  <verse number="10">fornicators, sodomites, kidnappers, liars, perjurers; and if any other thing is opposed to sound teaching,</verse>
  <verse number="11">according to the glad tidings of the glory of the blessed God, with which I have been entrusted.</verse>
  <verse number="12">[And] I thank Christ Jesus our Lord, who has given me power, that he has counted me faithful, appointing to ministry him</verse>
  <verse number="13">who before was a blasphemer and persecutor, and an insolent overbearing [man]: but mercy was shewn me because I did it ignorantly, in unbelief.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But the grace of our Lord surpassingly over-abounded with faith and love, which [is] in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Faithful [is] the word, and worthy of all acceptation, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am [the] first.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But for this reason mercy was shewn me, that in me, [the] first, Jesus Christ might display the whole long-suffering, for a delineation of those about to believe on him to life eternal.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Now to the King of the ages, [the] incorruptible, invisible, only God, honour and glory to the ages of ages. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="18">This charge, [my] child Timotheus, I commit to thee, according to the prophecies as to thee preceding, in order that thou mightest war by them the good warfare,</verse>
  <verse number="19">maintaining faith and a good conscience; which [last] some, having put away, have made shipwreck as to faith;</verse>
  <verse number="20">of whom is Hymenaeus and Alexander, whom I have delivered to Satan, that they may be taught by discipline not to blaspheme.</verse>
</chapter>