<chapter book="1 Timothy" number="5" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Rebuke not an elder sharply, but exhort [him] as a father, younger [men] as brethren,</verse>
  <verse number="2">elder women as mothers, younger women as sisters, with all purity.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Honour widows who are really widows;</verse>
  <verse number="4">but if any widow have children or descendants, let them learn first to be pious as regards their own house, and to render a return on their side to [their] parents; for this is acceptable in the sight of God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Now she who [is] a widow indeed, and is left alone, has put [her] hope in God, and continues in supplications and prayers night and day.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But she that lives in habits of self-indulgence is dead [while] living.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And these things enjoin, that they may be irreproachable.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But if any one does not provide for his own, and specially for those of [his] house, he has denied the faith, and is worse than the unbeliever.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Let a widow be put upon the list, being of not less than sixty years, [having been] wife of one man,</verse>
  <verse number="10">borne witness to in good works, if she have brought up children, if she have exercised hospitality, if she have washed saints’ feet, if she have imparted relief to the distressed, if she have diligently followed every good work.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But younger widows decline; for when they grow wanton against Christ, they desire to marry,</verse>
  <verse number="12">being guilty, because they have cast off their first faith.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And, at the same time, they learn also [to be] idle, going about to people’s houses; and not only idle, but also gossipers and meddlers, speaking things not becoming.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I will therefore that the younger marry, bear children, rule the house, give no occasion to the adversary in respect of reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For already some have turned aside after Satan.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If any believing man or woman have widows, let them impart relief to them, and let not the assembly be charged, that it may impart relief to those [that are] widows indeed.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let the elders who take the lead [among the saints] well be esteemed worthy of double honour, specially those labouring in word and teaching;</verse>
  <verse number="18">for the scripture says, Thou shalt not muzzle an ox that treadeth out corn, and, The workman [is] worthy of his hire.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Against an elder receive not an accusation unless where there are two or three witnesses.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Those that sin convict before all, that the rest also may have fear.</verse>
  <verse number="21">I testify before God and Christ Jesus and the elect angels, that thou keep these things without prejudice, doing nothing by favour.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Lay hands quickly on no man, nor partake in others’ sins. Keep thyself pure.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Drink no longer only water, but use a little wine on account of thy stomach and thy frequent illnesses.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Of some men the sins are manifest beforehand, going before to judgment, and some also they follow after.</verse>
  <verse number="25">In like manner good works also are manifest beforehand, and those that are otherwise cannot be hid.</verse>
</chapter>