<chapter book="Titus" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And thou—be speaking what doth become the sound teaching;</verse>
  <verse number="2">aged men to be temperate, grave, sober, sound in the faith, in the love, in the endurance;</verse>
  <verse number="3">aged women, in like manner, in deportment as doth become sacred persons, not false accusers, to much wine not enslaved, of good things teachers,</verse>
  <verse number="4">that they may make the young women sober-minded, to be lovers of their husbands, lovers of their children,</verse>
  <verse number="5">sober, pure, keepers of their own houses, good, subject to their own husbands, that the word of God may not be evil spoken of.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The younger men, in like manner, be exhorting to be sober-minded;</verse>
  <verse number="7">concerning all things thyself showing a pattern of good works; in the teaching uncorruptedness, gravity, incorruptibility,</verse>
  <verse number="8">discourse sound, irreprehensible, that he who is of the contrary part may be ashamed, having nothing evil to say concerning you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Servants—to their own masters are to be subject, in all things to be well-pleasing, not gainsaying,</verse>
  <verse number="10">not purloining, but showing all good stedfastness, that the teaching of God our Saviour they may adorn in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the saving grace of God was manifested to all men,</verse>
  <verse number="12">teaching us, that denying the impiety and the worldly desires, soberly and righteously and piously we may live in the present age,</verse>
  <verse number="13">waiting for the blessed hope and manifestation of the glory of our great God and Saviour Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="14">who did give himself for us, that he might ransom us from all lawlessness, and might purify to himself a peculiar people, zealous of good works;</verse>
  <verse number="15">these things be speaking, and exhorting, and convicting, with all charge; let no one despise thee!</verse>
</chapter>