<chapter book="Matthew" number="5" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And seeing the multitudes, he went up into the mountain: and when he had sat down, his disciples came unto him:</verse>
  <verse number="2">and he opened his mouth and taught them, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Blessed are the poor in spirit: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Blessed are they that mourn: for they shall be comforted.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Blessed are the meek: for they shall inherit the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Blessed are they that hunger and thirst after righteousness: for they shall be filled.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Blessed are the merciful: for they shall obtain mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Blessed are the pure in heart: for they shall see God.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called sons of God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Blessed are they that have been persecuted for righteousness’ sake: for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Blessed are ye when men shall reproach you, and persecute you, and say all manner of evil against you falsely, for my sake.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Rejoice, and be exceeding glad: for great is your reward in heaven: for so persecuted they the prophets that were before you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Ye are the salt of the earth: but if the salt have lost its savor, wherewith shall it be salted? it is thenceforth good for nothing, but to be cast out and trodden under foot of men.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Ye are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hid.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Neither do men light a lamp, and put it under the bushel, but on the stand; and it shineth unto all that are in the house.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Even so let your light shine before men; that they may see your good works, and glorify your Father who is in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Think not that I came to destroy the law or the prophets: I came not to destroy, but to fulfil.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For verily I say unto you, Till heaven and earth pass away, one jot or one tittle shall in no wise pass away from the law, till all things be accomplished.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Whosoever therefore shall break one of these least commandments, and shall teach men so, shall be called least in the kingdom of heaven: but whosoever shall do and teach them, he shall be called great in the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I say unto you, that except your righteousness shall exceed the righteousness of the scribes and Pharisees, ye shall in no wise enter into the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Ye have heard that it was said to them of old time, Thou shalt not kill; and whosoever shall kill shall be in danger of the judgment:</verse>
  <verse number="22">but I say unto you, that every one who is angry with his brother shall be in danger of the judgment; and whosoever shall say to his brother, Raca, shall be in danger of the council; and whosoever shall say, Thou fool, shall be in danger of the hell of fire.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If therefore thou art offering thy gift at the altar, and there rememberest that thy brother hath aught against thee,</verse>
  <verse number="24">leave there thy gift before the altar, and go thy way, first be reconciled to thy brother, and then come and offer thy gift.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Agree with thine adversary quickly, while thou art with him in the way; lest haply the adversary deliver thee to the judge, and the judge deliver thee to the officer, and thou be cast into prison.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Verily I say unto thee, Thou shalt by no means come out thence, till thou have paid the last farthing.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Ye have heard that it was said, Thou shalt not commit adultery :</verse>
  <verse number="28">but I say unto you, that every one that looketh on a woman to lust after her hath committed adultery with her already in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And if thy right eye causeth thee to stumble, pluck it out, and cast it from thee: for it is profitable for thee that one of thy members should perish, and not thy whole body be cast into hell.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And if thy right hand causeth thee to stumble, cut it off, and cast it from thee: for it is profitable for thee that one of thy members should perish, and not thy whole body go into hell.</verse>
  <verse number="31">It was said also, Whosoever shall put away his wife, let him give her a writing of divorcement :</verse>
  <verse number="32">but I say unto you, that every one that putteth away his wife, saving for the cause of fornication, maketh her an adulteress: and whosoever shall marry her when she is put away committeth adultery.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Again, ye have heard that it was said to them of old time, Thou shalt not forswear thyself, but shalt perform unto the Lord thine oaths:</verse>
  <verse number="34">but I say unto you, Swear not at all; neither by the heaven, for it is the throne of God;</verse>
  <verse number="35">nor by the earth, for it is the footstool of his feet; nor by Jerusalem, for it is the city of the great King.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Neither shalt thou swear by thy head, for thou canst not make one hair white or black.</verse>
  <verse number="37">But let your speech be, Yea, yea; Nay, nay: and whatsoever is more than these is of the evil one.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Ye have heard that it was said, An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a tooth:</verse>
  <verse number="39">but I say unto you, Resist not him that is evil: but whosoever smiteth thee on thy right cheek, turn to him the other also.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And if any man would go to law with thee, and take away thy coat, let him have thy cloak also.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And whosoever shall compel thee to go one mile, go with him two.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Give to him that asketh thee, and from him that would borrow of thee turn not thou away.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Ye have heard that it was said, Thou shalt love thy neighbor, and hate thine enemy :</verse>
  <verse number="44">but I say unto you, Love your enemies, and pray for them that persecute you;</verse>
  <verse number="45">that ye may be sons of your Father who is in heaven: for he maketh his sun to rise on the evil and the good, and sendeth rain on the just and the unjust.</verse>
  <verse number="46">For if ye love them that love you, what reward have ye? do not even the publicans the same ?</verse>
  <verse number="47">And if ye salute your brethren only, what do ye more than others? do not even the Gentiles the same ?</verse>
  <verse number="48">Ye therefore shall be perfect, as your heavenly Father is perfect.</verse>
</chapter>