<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The proverbs of Solomon, the son of David, king of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="2">to know wisdom and instruction; to discern the words of understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">to receive instruction in wise dealing, in righteousness, justice, and equity;</verse>
  <verse number="4">to give prudence to the simple, knowledge and discretion to the young man:</verse>
  <verse number="5">that the wise man may hear, and increase in learning; that the man of understanding may attain to sound counsel:</verse>
  <verse number="6">to understand a proverb, and parables, the words and riddles of the wise.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The fear of Yahweh is the beginning of knowledge; but the foolish despise wisdom and instruction.</verse>
  <verse number="8">My son, listen to your father’s instruction, and don’t forsake your mother’s teaching:</verse>
  <verse number="9">for they will be a garland to grace your head, and chains around your neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if sinners entice you, don’t consent.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they say, “Come with us, Let’s lay in wait for blood; let’s lurk secretly for the innocent without cause;</verse>
  <verse number="12">let’s swallow them up alive like Sheol, and whole, like those who go down into the pit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">We’ll find all valuable wealth. We’ll fill our houses with spoil.</verse>
  <verse number="14">You shall cast your lot among us. We’ll all have one purse.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, don’t walk in the way with them. Keep your foot from their path,</verse>
  <verse number="16">for their feet run to evil. They hurry to shed blood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For in vain is the net spread in the sight of any bird:</verse>
  <verse number="18">but these lay wait for their own blood. They lurk secretly for their own lives.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So are the ways of everyone who is greedy for gain. It takes away the life of its owners.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom calls aloud in the street. She utters her voice in the public squares.</verse>
  <verse number="21">She calls at the head of noisy places. At the entrance of the city gates, she utters her words:</verse>
  <verse number="22">“How long, you simple ones, will you love simplicity? How long will mockers delight themselves in mockery, and fools hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn at my reproof. Behold, I will pour out my spirit on you. I will make known my words to you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I have called, and you have refused; I have stretched out my hand, and no one has paid attention;</verse>
  <verse number="25">but you have ignored all my counsel, and wanted none of my reproof;</verse>
  <verse number="26">I also will laugh at your disaster. I will mock when calamity overtakes you;</verse>
  <verse number="27">when calamity overtakes you like a storm, when your disaster comes on like a whirlwind; when distress and anguish come on you.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then will they call on me, but I will not answer. They will seek me diligently, but they will not find me;</verse>
  <verse number="29">because they hated knowledge, and didn’t choose the fear of Yahweh.</verse>
  <verse number="30">They wanted none of my counsel. They despised all my reproof.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Therefore they will eat of the fruit of their own way, and be filled with their own schemes.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the backsliding of the simple will kill them. The careless ease of fools will destroy them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But whoever listens to me will dwell securely, and will be at ease, without fear of harm.”</verse>
</chapter>