<chapter book="Proverbs" number="17" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Better is a dry morsel with quietness, than a house full of feasting with strife.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A servant who deals wisely will rule over a son who causes shame, and shall have a part in the inheritance among the brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The refining pot is for silver, and the furnace for gold, but Yahweh tests the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="4">An evildoer heeds wicked lips. A liar gives ear to a mischievous tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whoever mocks the poor reproaches his Maker. He who is glad at calamity shall not be unpunished.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Children’s children are the crown of old men; the glory of children are their parents.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Arrogant speech isn’t fitting for a fool, much less do lying lips fit a prince.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A bribe is a precious stone in the eyes of him who gives it; wherever he turns, he prospers.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He who covers an offense promotes love; but he who repeats a matter separates best friends.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A rebuke enters deeper into one who has understanding than a hundred lashes into a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="11">An evil man seeks only rebellion; therefore a cruel messenger shall be sent against him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let a bear robbed of her cubs meet a man, rather than a fool in his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoever rewards evil for good, evil shall not depart from his house.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The beginning of strife is like breaching a dam, therefore stop contention before quarreling breaks out.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He who justifies the wicked, and he who condemns the righteous, both of them alike are an abomination to Yahweh.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Why is there money in the hand of a fool to buy wisdom, since he has no understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="17">A friend loves at all times; and a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A man void of understanding strikes hands, and becomes collateral in the presence of his neighbor.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He who loves disobedience loves strife. One who builds a high gate seeks destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="20">One who has a perverse heart doesn’t find prosperity, and one who has a deceitful tongue falls into trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He who becomes the father of a fool grieves. The father of a fool has no joy.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A cheerful heart makes good medicine, but a crushed spirit dries up the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A wicked man receives a bribe in secret, to pervert the ways of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Wisdom is before the face of one who has understanding, but the eyes of a fool wander to the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A foolish son brings grief to his father, and bitterness to her who bore him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Also to punish the righteous is not good, nor to flog officials for their integrity.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He who spares his words has knowledge. He who is even tempered is a man of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Even a fool, when he keeps silent, is counted wise. When he shuts his lips, he is thought to be discerning.</verse>
</chapter>