<chapter book="Proverbs" number="2" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if you will receive my words, and store up my commandments within you;</verse>
  <verse number="2">So as to turn your ear to wisdom, and apply your heart to understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Yes, if you call out for discernment, and lift up your voice for understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="4">If you seek her as silver, and search for her as for hidden treasures:</verse>
  <verse number="5">then you will understand the fear of Yahweh, and find the knowledge of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For Yahweh gives wisdom. Out of his mouth comes knowledge and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He lays up sound wisdom for the upright. He is a shield to those who walk in integrity;</verse>
  <verse number="8">that he may guard the paths of justice, and preserve the way of his saints.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then you will understand righteousness and justice, equity and every good path.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For wisdom will enter into your heart. Knowledge will be pleasant to your soul.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Discretion will watch over you. Understanding will keep you,</verse>
  <verse number="12">to deliver you from the way of evil, from the men who speak perverse things;</verse>
  <verse number="13">who forsake the paths of uprightness, to walk in the ways of darkness;</verse>
  <verse number="14">who rejoice to do evil, and delight in the perverseness of evil;</verse>
  <verse number="15">who are crooked in their ways, and wayward in their paths:</verse>
  <verse number="16">To deliver you from the strange woman, even from the foreigner who flatters with her words;</verse>
  <verse number="17">who forsakes the friend of her youth, and forgets the covenant of her God:</verse>
  <verse number="18">for her house leads down to death, her paths to the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="19">None who go to her return again, neither do they attain to the paths of life:</verse>
  <verse number="20">that you may walk in the way of good men, and keep the paths of the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the upright will dwell in the land. The perfect will remain in it.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But the wicked will be cut off from the land. The treacherous will be rooted out of it.</verse>
</chapter>