<chapter book="Proverbs" number="23" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When you sit to eat with a ruler, consider diligently what is before you;</verse>
  <verse number="2">put a knife to your throat, if you are a man given to appetite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Don’t be desirous of his dainties, since they are deceitful food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Don’t weary yourself to be rich. In your wisdom, show restraint.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Why do you set your eyes on that which is not? For it certainly sprouts wings like an eagle and flies in the sky.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Don’t eat the food of him who has a stingy eye, and don’t crave his delicacies:</verse>
  <verse number="7">for as he thinks about the cost, so he is. “Eat and drink!” he says to you, but his heart is not with you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The morsel which you have eaten you shall vomit up, and lose your good words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Don’t speak in the ears of a fool, for he will despise the wisdom of your words.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Don’t move the ancient boundary stone. Don’t encroach on the fields of the fatherless:</verse>
  <verse number="11">for their Defender is strong. He will plead their case against you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Apply your heart to instruction, and your ears to the words of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Don’t withhold correction from a child. If you punish him with the rod, he will not die.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Punish him with the rod, and save his soul from Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, if your heart is wise, then my heart will be glad, even mine:</verse>
  <verse number="16">yes, my heart will rejoice, when your lips speak what is right.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Don’t let your heart envy sinners; but rather fear Yahweh all the day long.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Indeed surely there is a future hope, and your hope will not be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Listen, my son, and be wise, and keep your heart on the right path!</verse>
  <verse number="20">Don’t be among ones drinking too much wine, or those who gorge themselves on meat:</verse>
  <verse number="21">for the drunkard and the glutton shall become poor; and drowsiness clothes them in rags.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Listen to your father who gave you life, and don’t despise your mother when she is old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Buy the truth, and don’t sell it. Get wisdom, discipline, and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The father of the righteous has great joy. Whoever fathers a wise child delights in him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let your father and your mother be glad! Let her who bore you rejoice!</verse>
  <verse number="26">My son, give me your heart; and let your eyes keep in my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For a prostitute is a deep pit; and a wayward wife is a narrow well.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Yes, she lies in wait like a robber, and increases the unfaithful among men.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Who has woe? Who has sorrow? Who has strife? Who has complaints? Who has needless bruises? Who has bloodshot eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Those who stay long at the wine; those who go to seek out mixed wine.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Don’t look at the wine when it is red, when it sparkles in the cup, when it goes down smoothly.</verse>
  <verse number="32">In the end, it bites like a snake, and poisons like a viper.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Your eyes will see strange things, and your mind will imagine confusing things.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Yes, you will be as he who lies down in the midst of the sea, or as he who lies on top of the rigging:</verse>
  <verse number="35">“They hit me, and I was not hurt! They beat me, and I don’t feel it! When will I wake up? I can do it again. I can find another.”</verse>
</chapter>