<chapter book="Proverbs" number="5" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, pay attention to my wisdom. Turn your ear to my understanding:</verse>
  <verse number="2">that you may maintain discretion, that your lips may preserve knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the lips of an adulteress drip honey. Her mouth is smoother than oil,</verse>
  <verse number="4">But in the end she is as bitter as wormwood, and as sharp as a two-edged sword.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Her feet go down to death. Her steps lead straight to Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="6">She gives no thought to the way of life. Her ways are crooked, and she doesn’t know it.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Now therefore, my sons, listen to me. Don’t depart from the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Remove your way far from her. Don’t come near the door of her house,</verse>
  <verse number="9">lest you give your honor to others, and your years to the cruel one;</verse>
  <verse number="10">lest strangers feast on your wealth, and your labors enrich another man’s house.</verse>
  <verse number="11">You will groan at your latter end, when your flesh and your body are consumed,</verse>
  <verse number="12">and say, “How I have hated instruction, and my heart despised reproof;</verse>
  <verse number="13">neither have I obeyed the voice of my teachers, nor turned my ear to those who instructed me!</verse>
  <verse number="14">I have come to the brink of utter ruin, in the midst of the gathered assembly.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">Drink water out of your own cistern, running water out of your own well.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Should your springs overflow in the streets, streams of water in the public squares?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let them be for yourself alone, not for strangers with you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Let your spring be blessed. Rejoice in the wife of your youth.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A loving doe and a graceful deer—let her breasts satisfy you at all times. Be captivated always with her love.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For why should you, my son, be captivated with an adulteress? Why embrace the bosom of another?</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the ways of man are before the eyes of Yahweh. He examines all his paths.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The evil deeds of the wicked ensnare him. The cords of his sin hold him firmly.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He will die for lack of instruction. In the greatness of his folly, he will go astray.</verse>
</chapter>