<chapter book="Philippians" number="1" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul and Timothy, servants of Christ Jesus, to all the saints in Christ Jesus which are at Philippi, with the bishops and deacons:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Grace to you and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I thank my God upon all my remembrance of you,</verse>
  <verse number="4">always in every supplication of mine on behalf of you all making my supplication with joy,</verse>
  <verse number="5">for your fellowship in furtherance of the gospel from the first day until now;</verse>
  <verse number="6">being confident of this very thing, that he which began a good work in you will perfect it until the day of Jesus Christ:</verse>
  <verse number="7">even as it is right for me to be thus minded on behalf of you all, because I have you in my heart, inasmuch as, both in my bonds and in the defence and confirmation of the gospel, ye all are partakers with me of grace.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For God is my witness, how I long after you all in the tender mercies of Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And this I pray, that your love may abound yet more and more in knowledge and all discernment;</verse>
  <verse number="10">so that ye may approve the things that are excellent; that ye may be sincere and void of offence unto the day of Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="11">being filled with the fruits of righteousness, which are through Jesus Christ, unto the glory and praise of God.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now I would have you know, brethren, that the things which happened unto me have fallen out rather unto the progress of the gospel;</verse>
  <verse number="13">so that my bonds became manifest in Christ throughout the whole praetorian guard, and to all the rest;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and that most of the brethren in the Lord, being confident through my bonds, are more abundantly bold to speak the word of God without fear.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Some indeed preach Christ even of envy and strife; and some also of good will:</verse>
  <verse number="16">the one do it of love, knowing that I am set for the defence of the gospel:</verse>
  <verse number="17">but the other proclaim Christ of faction, not sincerely, thinking to raise up affliction for me in my bonds.</verse>
  <verse number="18">What then? only that in every way, whether in pretence or in truth, Christ is proclaimed; and therein I rejoice, yea, and will rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For I know that this shall turn to my salvation, through your supplication and the supply of the Spirit of Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="20">according to my earnest expectation and hope, that in nothing shall I be put to shame, but that with all boldness, as always, so now also Christ shall be magnified in my body, whether by life, or by death.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For to me to live is Christ, and to die is gain.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But if to live in the flesh,—if this is the fruit of my work, then what I shall choose I wot not.</verse>
  <verse number="23">But I am in a strait betwixt the two, having the desire to depart and be with Christ; for it is very far better:</verse>
  <verse number="24">yet to abide in the flesh is more needful for your sake.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And having this confidence, I know that I shall abide, yea, and abide with you all, for your progress and joy in the faith;</verse>
  <verse number="26">that your glorying may abound in Christ Jesus in me through my presence with you again.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Only let your manner of life be worthy of the gospel of Christ: that, whether I come and see you or be absent, I may hear of your state, that ye stand fast in one spirit, with one soul striving for the faith of the gospel;</verse>
  <verse number="28">and in nothing affrighted by the adversaries: which is for them an evident token of perdition, but of your salvation, and that from God;</verse>
  <verse number="29">because to you it hath been granted in the behalf of Christ, not only to believe on him, but also to suffer in his behalf:</verse>
  <verse number="30">having the same conflict which ye saw in me, and now hear to be in me.</verse>
</chapter>