<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am the man who has seen affliction under the rod of God’s wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He has driven me away and made me walk in darkness instead of light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Indeed, He keeps turning His hand against me all day long.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He has worn away my flesh and skin; He has shattered my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He has besieged me and surrounded me with bitterness and hardship.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He has made me dwell in darkness like those dead for ages.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He has walled me in so I cannot escape; He has weighed me down with chains.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Even when I cry out and plead for help, He shuts out my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He has barred my ways with cut stones; He has made my paths crooked.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He is a bear lying in wait, a lion hiding in ambush.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He forced me off my path and tore me to pieces; He left me without help.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He bent His bow and set me as the target for His arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He pierced my kidneys with His arrows.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I am a laughingstock to all my people; they mock me in song all day long.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He has filled me with bitterness; He has intoxicated me with wormwood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He has ground my teeth with gravel and trampled me in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="17">My soul has been deprived of peace; I have forgotten what prosperity is.</verse>
  <verse number="18">So I say, “My strength has perished, along with my hope from the LORD.”</verse>
  <verse number="19">Remember my affliction and wandering, the wormwood and the gall.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely my soul remembers and is humbled within me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Yet I call this to mind, and therefore I have hope:</verse>
  <verse number="22">Because of the loving devotion of the LORD we are not consumed, for His mercies never fail.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They are new every morning; great is Your faithfulness!</verse>
  <verse number="24">“The LORD is my portion,” says my soul, “therefore I will hope in Him.”</verse>
  <verse number="25">The LORD is good to those who wait for Him, to the soul who seeks Him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">It is good to wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is good for a man to bear the yoke while he is still young.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Let him sit alone in silence, for the LORD has laid it upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Let him bury his face in the dust—perhaps there is still hope.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Let him offer his cheek to the one who would strike him; let him be filled with reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For the Lord will not cast us off forever.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Even if He causes grief, He will show compassion according to His abundant loving devotion.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For He does not willingly afflict or grieve the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="34">To crush underfoot all the prisoners of the land,</verse>
  <verse number="35">to deny a man justice before the Most High,</verse>
  <verse number="36">to subvert a man in his lawsuit—of these the Lord does not approve.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who has spoken and it came to pass, unless the Lord has ordained it?</verse>
  <verse number="38">Do not both adversity and good come from the mouth of the Most High?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Why should any mortal man complain, in view of his sins?</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let us examine and test our ways, and turn back to the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Let us lift up our hearts and hands to God in heaven:</verse>
  <verse number="42">“We have sinned and rebelled; You have not forgiven.”</verse>
  <verse number="43">You have covered Yourself in anger and pursued us; You have killed without pity.</verse>
  <verse number="44">You have covered Yourself with a cloud that no prayer can pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">You have made us scum and refuse among the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All our enemies open their mouths against us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Panic and pitfall have come upon us—devastation and destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Streams of tears flow from my eyes over the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">My eyes overflow unceasingly, without relief,</verse>
  <verse number="50">until the LORD looks down from heaven and sees.</verse>
  <verse number="51">My eyes bring grief to my soul because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Without cause my enemies hunted me like a bird.</verse>
  <verse number="53">They dropped me alive into a pit and cast stones upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">The waters flowed over my head, and I thought I was going to die.</verse>
  <verse number="55">I called on Your name, O LORD, out of the depths of the Pit.</verse>
  <verse number="56">You heard my plea: “Do not ignore my cry for relief.”</verse>
  <verse number="57">You drew near when I called on You; You said, “Do not be afraid.”</verse>
  <verse number="58">You defend my cause, O Lord; You redeem my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">You have seen, O LORD, the wrong done to me; vindicate my cause!</verse>
  <verse number="60">You have seen all their malice, all their plots against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">O LORD, You have heard their insults, all their plots against me—</verse>
  <verse number="62">the slander and murmuring of my assailants against me all day long.</verse>
  <verse number="63">When they sit and when they rise, see how they mock me in song.</verse>
  <verse number="64">You will pay them back what they deserve, O LORD, according to the work of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="65">Put a veil of anguish over their hearts; may Your curse be upon them!</verse>
  <verse number="66">You will pursue them in anger and exterminate them from under Your heavens, O LORD.</verse>
</chapter>