<chapter book="Hosea" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hear this ye priests, and attend, ye house of Israel, and give ear, ye house of the king; for the judgment is to you, because ye were a snare to the watch tower and a net stretched out upon Tabor.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the rowers made deep the slaughter, and I a correction to them all.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I knew Ephraim and Israel were not hid from me: for now thou didst commit fornication, O Ephraim; Israel was deified.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They will not give their doings to turn back to their God, for the spirit of fornication is in the midst of them, and they knew not Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the pride of Israel was humbled in his face, and Israel and Ephraim shall be weak in their iniquity; Judah also being weak with them.</verse>
  <verse number="6">With their sheep and with their oxen they will go to seek Jehovah; and they shall not find; he withdrew himself from them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Against Jehovah they acted faithlessly: for they begat strange sons: now shall the new moon consume them with their portions.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Strike the horn upon the hill, and the trumpet upon the height: make a loud noise at the house of vanity after thee, O Benjamin.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Ephraim shall be for desolation in the day of chastisement: in the tribes of Israel I made known the faithful thing.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The princes of Judah were as they removing the bound: upon them will I pour out my wrath as water.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Ephraim was oppressed, he was broken in judgment because he was willing to go after the command.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I as a moth to Ephraim, and as rottenness to the house of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Ephraim will see his disease and Judah his wound, and Ephraim will go to Assur, and he will send to king Jareb: and he will not be able to heal for you, and he will not remove from you the wound.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For I as the lion to Ephraim, and as the young lion to the house of Judah I, I will rend and go away; I will take away and none delivering.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I will go and turn back to my place, even till when they shall be guilty, and they sought my face: in straitness to them they will turn to me.</verse>
</chapter>