<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="11" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Followers of me become ye, as I also am of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I praise you, brethren, that in all things ye remember me, and according as I did deliver to you, the deliverances ye keep,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and I wish you to know that of every man the head is the Christ, and the head of a woman is the husband, and the head of Christ is God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Every man praying or prophesying, having the head covered, doth dishonour his head,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and every woman praying or prophesying with the head uncovered, doth dishonour her own head, for it is one and the same thing with her being shaven,</verse>
  <verse number="6">for if a woman is not covered—then let her be shorn, and if it is a shame for a woman to be shorn or shaven—let her be covered;</verse>
  <verse number="7">for a man, indeed, ought not to cover the head, being the image and glory of God, and a woman is the glory of a man,</verse>
  <verse number="8">for a man is not of a woman, but a woman is of a man,</verse>
  <verse number="9">for a man also was not created because of the woman, but a woman because of the man;</verse>
  <verse number="10">because of this the woman ought to have a token of authority upon the head, because of the messengers;</verse>
  <verse number="11">but neither is a man apart from a woman, nor a woman apart from a man, in the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="12">for as the woman is of the man, so also the man is through the woman, and the all things are of God.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In your own selves judge ye; is it seemly for a woman uncovered to pray to God?</verse>
  <verse number="14">doth not even nature itself teach you, that if a man indeed have long hair, a dishonour it is to him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">and a woman, if she have long hair, a glory it is to her, because the hair instead of a covering hath been given to her;</verse>
  <verse number="16">and if any one doth think to be contentious, we have no such custom, neither the assemblies of God.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And this declaring, I give no praise, because not for the better, but for the worse ye come together;</verse>
  <verse number="18">for first, indeed, ye coming together in an assembly, I hear of divisions being among you, and partly I believe it,</verse>
  <verse number="19">for it behoveth sects also to be among you, that those approved may become manifest among you;</verse>
  <verse number="20">ye, then, coming together at the same place—it is not to eat the Lord’s supper;</verse>
  <verse number="21">for each his own supper doth take before in the eating, and one is hungry, and another is drunk;</verse>
  <verse number="22">why, have ye not houses to eat and to drink in? or the assembly of God do ye despise, and shame those not having? what may I say to you? shall I praise you in this? I do not praise!</verse>
  <verse number="23">For I—I received from the Lord that which also I did deliver to you, that the Lord Jesus in the night in which he was delivered up, took bread,</verse>
  <verse number="24">and having given thanks, he brake, and said, ‘Take ye, eat ye, this is my body, that for you is being broken; this do ye—to the remembrance of me.’</verse>
  <verse number="25">In like manner also the cup after the supping, saying, ‘This cup is the new covenant in my blood; this do ye, as often as ye may drink it—to the remembrance of me;’</verse>
  <verse number="26">for as often as ye may eat this bread, and this cup may drink, the death of the Lord ye do shew forth—till he may come;</verse>
  <verse number="27">so that whoever may eat this bread or may drink the cup of the Lord unworthily, guilty he shall be of the body and blood of the Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="28">and let a man be proving himself, and so of the bread let him eat, and of the cup let him drink;</verse>
  <verse number="29">for he who is eating and drinking unworthily, judgment to himself he doth eat and drink—not discerning the body of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Because of this, among you many are weak and sickly, and sleep do many;</verse>
  <verse number="31">for if ourselves we were discerning, we would not be being judged,</verse>
  <verse number="32">and being judged by the Lord, we are chastened, that with the world we may not be condemned;</verse>
  <verse number="33">so then, my brethren, coming together to eat, for one another wait ye;</verse>
  <verse number="34">and if any one is hungry, at home let him eat, that to judgment ye may not come together; and the rest, whenever I may come, I shall arrange.</verse>
</chapter>