<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="3" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I, brethren, was not able to speak to you as to spiritual, but as to fleshly—as to babes in Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="2">with milk I fed you, and not with meat, for ye were not yet able, but not even yet are ye now able,</verse>
  <verse number="3">for yet ye are fleshly, for where there is among you envying, and strife, and divisions, are ye not fleshly, and in the manner of men do walk?</verse>
  <verse number="4">for when one may say, ‘I, indeed, am of Paul;’ and another, ‘I—of Apollos;’ are ye not fleshly?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who, then, is Paul, and who Apollos, but ministrants through whom ye did believe, and to each as the Lord gave?</verse>
  <verse number="6">I planted, Apollos watered, but God was giving growth;</verse>
  <verse number="7">so that neither is he who is planting anything, nor he who is watering, but He who is giving growth—God;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and he who is planting and he who is watering are one, and each his own reward shall receive, according to his own labour,</verse>
  <verse number="9">for of God we are fellow-workmen; God’s tillage, God’s building ye are.</verse>
  <verse number="10">According to the grace of God that was given to me, as a wise master-builder, a foundation I have laid, and another doth build on it,</verse>
  <verse number="11">for other foundation no one is able to lay except that which is laid, which is Jesus the Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="12">and if any one doth build upon this foundation gold, silver, precious stones, wood, hay, straw—</verse>
  <verse number="13">of each the work shall become manifest, for the day shall declare it, because in fire it is revealed, and the work of each, what kind it is, the fire shall prove;</verse>
  <verse number="14">if of any one the work doth remain that he built on it, a wage he shall receive;</verse>
  <verse number="15">if of any the work is burned up, he shall suffer loss; and himself shall be saved, but so as through fire.</verse>
  <verse number="16">have ye not known that ye are a sanctuary of God, and the Spirit of God doth dwell in you?</verse>
  <verse number="17">if any one the sanctuary of God doth waste, him shall God waste; for the sanctuary of God is holy, the which ye are.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Let no one deceive himself; if any one doth seem to be wise among you in this age—let him become a fool, that he may become wise,</verse>
  <verse number="19">for the wisdom of this world is foolishness with God, for it hath been written, ‘Who is taking the wise in their craftiness;’</verse>
  <verse number="20">and again, ‘The Lord doth know the reasonings of the wise, that they are vain.’</verse>
  <verse number="21">So then, let no one glory in men, for all things are yours,</verse>
  <verse number="22">whether Paul, or Apollos, or Cephas, or the world, or life, or death, or things present, or things about to be—all are yours,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and ye are Christ’s, and Christ is God’s.</verse>
</chapter>