<chapter book="Job" number="15" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Should a wise man utter vain knowledge, and fill his belly with the east wind?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Should he reason with unprofitable talk? or with speeches with which he can do no good?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Yes, you cast off fear, and restrain prayer before God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For your mouth utters your iniquity, and you choose the tongue of the crafty.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Your own mouth comdemns you, and not I: yes, your own lips testify against you.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Are you the first man that was born? or were you made before the hills?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Have you heard the secret of God? and do you restrain wisdom to yourself?</verse>
  <verse number="9">What know you, that we know not? what understand you, which is not in us?</verse>
  <verse number="10">With us are both the gray headed and very aged men, much elder than your father.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Are the consolations of God small with you? is there any secret thing with you?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Why does your heart carry you away? and what do your eyes wink at,</verse>
  <verse number="13">That you turn your spirit against God, and let such words go out of your mouth?</verse>
  <verse number="14">What is man, that he should be clean? and he which is born of a woman, that he should be righteous?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, he puts no trust in his saints; yes, the heavens are not clean in his sight.</verse>
  <verse number="16">How much more abominable and filthy is man, which drinks iniquity like water?</verse>
  <verse number="17">I will show you, hear me; and that which I have seen I will declare;</verse>
  <verse number="18">Which wise men have told from their fathers, and have not hid it:</verse>
  <verse number="19">To whom alone the earth was given, and no stranger passed among them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The wicked man travails with pain all his days, and the number of years is hidden to the oppressor.</verse>
  <verse number="21">A dreadful sound is in his ears: in prosperity the destroyer shall come on him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He believes not that he shall return out of darkness, and he is waited for of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He wanders abroad for bread, saying, Where is it? he knows that the day of darkness is ready at his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Trouble and anguish shall make him afraid; they shall prevail against him, as a king ready to the battle.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For he stretches out his hand against God, and strengthens himself against the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He runs on him, even on his neck, on the thick bosses of his bucklers:</verse>
  <verse number="27">Because he covers his face with his fatness, and makes bulges of fat on his flanks.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he dwells in desolate cities, and in houses which no man inhabits, which are ready to become heaps.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He shall not be rich, neither shall his substance continue, neither shall he prolong the perfection thereof on the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He shall not depart out of darkness; the flame shall dry up his branches, and by the breath of his mouth shall he go away.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Let not him that is deceived trust in vanity: for vanity shall be his recompense.</verse>
  <verse number="32">It shall be accomplished before his time, and his branch shall not be green.</verse>
  <verse number="33">He shall shake off his unripe grape as the vine, and shall cast off his flower as the olive.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For the congregation of hypocrites shall be desolate, and fire shall consume the tabernacles of bribery.</verse>
  <verse number="35">They conceive mischief, and bring forth vanity, and their belly prepares deceit.</verse>
</chapter>