<chapter book="Job" number="31" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I made a covenant with my eyes; why then should I think on a maid?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For what portion of God is there from above? and what inheritance of the Almighty from on high?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is not destruction to the wicked? and a strange punishment to the workers of iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Does not he see my ways, and count all my steps?</verse>
  <verse number="5">If I have walked with vanity, or if my foot has hurried to deceit;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let me be weighed in an even balance that God may know my integrity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">If my step has turned out of the way, and my heart walked after my eyes, and if any blot has stuck to my hands;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then let me sow, and let another eat; yes, let my offspring be rooted out.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If my heart have been deceived by a woman, or if I have laid wait at my neighbor’s door;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then let my wife grind to another, and let others bow down on her.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For this is an heinous crime; yes, it is an iniquity to be punished by the judges.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is a fire that consumes to destruction, and would root out all my increase.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I did despise the cause of my manservant or of my maidservant, when they contended with me;</verse>
  <verse number="14">What then shall I do when God rises up? and when he visits, what shall I answer him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Did not he that made me in the womb make him? and did not one fashion us in the womb?</verse>
  <verse number="16">If I have withheld the poor from their desire, or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Or have eaten my morsel myself alone, and the fatherless has not eaten thereof;</verse>
  <verse number="18">(For from my youth he was brought up with me, as with a father, and I have guided her from my mother’s womb;)</verse>
  <verse number="19">If I have seen any perish for want of clothing, or any poor without covering;</verse>
  <verse number="20">If his loins have not blessed me, and if he were not warmed with the fleece of my sheep;</verse>
  <verse number="21">If I have lifted up my hand against the fatherless, when I saw my help in the gate:</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then let my arm fall from my shoulder blade, and my arm be broken from the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For destruction from God was a terror to me, and by reason of his highness I could not endure.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If I have made gold my hope, or have said to the fine gold, You are my confidence;</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I rejoice because my wealth was great, and because my hand had gotten much;</verse>
  <verse number="26">If I beheld the sun when it shined, or the moon walking in brightness;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And my heart has been secretly enticed, or my mouth has kissed my hand:</verse>
  <verse number="28">This also were an iniquity to be punished by the judge: for I should have denied the God that is above.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If I rejoice at the destruction of him that hated me, or lifted up myself when evil found him:</verse>
  <verse number="30">Neither have I suffered my mouth to sin by wishing a curse to his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If the men of my tabernacle said not, Oh that we had of his flesh! we cannot be satisfied.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The stranger did not lodge in the street: but I opened my doors to the travelers.</verse>
  <verse number="33">If I covered my transgressions as Adam, by hiding my iniquity in my bosom:</verse>
  <verse number="34">Did I fear a great multitude, or did the contempt of families terrify me, that I kept silence, and went not out of the door?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Oh that one would hear me! behold, my desire is, that the Almighty would answer me, and that my adversary had written a book.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Surely I would take it on my shoulder, and bind it as a crown to me.</verse>
  <verse number="37">I would declare to him the number of my steps; as a prince would I go near to him.</verse>
  <verse number="38">If my land cry against me, or that the furrows likewise thereof complain;</verse>
  <verse number="39">If I have eaten the fruits thereof without money, or have caused the owners thereof to lose their life:</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let thistles grow instead of wheat, and cockle instead of barley. The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>