<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Know you the time when the wild goats of the rock bring forth? or can you mark when the hinds do calve?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can you number the months that they fulfill? or know you the time when they bring forth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">They bow themselves, they bring forth their young ones, they cast out their sorrows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Their young ones are in good liking, they grow up with corn; they go forth, and return not to them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who has sent out the wild ass free? or who has loosed the bands of the wild ass?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whose house I have made the wilderness, and the barren land his dwellings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He scorns the multitude of the city, neither regards he the crying of the driver.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The range of the mountains is his pasture, and he searches after every green thing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will the unicorn be willing to serve you, or abide by your crib?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Can you bind the unicorn with his band in the furrow? or will he harrow the valleys after you?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Will you trust him, because his strength is great? or will you leave your labor to him?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Will you believe him, that he will bring home your seed, and gather it into your barn?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Gave you the goodly wings to the peacocks? or wings and feathers to the ostrich?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Which leaves her eggs in the earth, and warms them in dust,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And forgets that the foot may crush them, or that the wild beast may break them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She is hardened against her young ones, as though they were not her’s: her labor is in vain without fear;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Because God has deprived her of wisdom, neither has he imparted to her understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="18">What time she lifts up herself on high, she scorns the horse and his rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Have you given the horse strength? have you clothed his neck with thunder?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Can you make him afraid as a grasshopper? the glory of his nostrils is terrible.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He paws in the valley, and rejoices in his strength: he goes on to meet the armed men.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He mocks at fear, and is not affrighted; neither turns he back from the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The quiver rattles against him, the glittering spear and the shield.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He swallows the ground with fierceness and rage: neither believes he that it is the sound of the trumpet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He said among the trumpets, Ha, ha; and he smells the battle afar off, the thunder of the captains, and the shouting.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Does the hawk fly by your wisdom, and stretch her wings toward the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Does the eagle mount up at your command, and make her nest on high?</verse>
  <verse number="28">She dwells and stays on the rock, on the crag of the rock, and the strong place.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From there she seeks the prey, and her eyes behold afar off.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Her young ones also suck up blood: and where the slain are, there is she.</verse>
</chapter>