<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover the LORD answered Job, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shall he that contends with the Almighty instruct him? he that reproves God, let him answer it.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Job answered the LORD, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Behold, I am vile; what shall I answer you? I will lay my hand on my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Once have I spoken; but I will not answer: yes, twice; but I will proceed no further.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then answered the LORD to Job out of the whirlwind, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Gird up your loins now like a man: I will demand of you, and declare you to me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Will you also cancel my judgment? will you condemn me, that you may be righteous?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Have you an arm like God? or can you thunder with a voice like him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Deck yourself now with majesty and excellency; and array yourself with glory and beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Cast abroad the rage of your wrath: and behold every one that is proud, and abase him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Look on every one that is proud, and bring him low; and tread down the wicked in their place.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hide them in the dust together; and bind their faces in secret.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then will I also confess to you that your own right hand can save you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold now behemoth, which I made with you; he eats grass as an ox.</verse>
  <verse number="16">See now, his strength is in his loins, and his force is in the navel of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He moves his tail like a cedar: the sinews of his stones are wrapped together.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are as strong pieces of brass; his bones are like bars of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is the chief of the ways of God: he that made him can make his sword to approach to him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely the mountains bring him forth food, where all the beasts of the field play.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He lies under the shady trees, in the covert of the reed, and fens.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The shady trees cover him with their shadow; the willows of the brook compass him about.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Behold, he drinks up a river, and hastens not: he trusts that he can draw up Jordan into his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He takes it with his eyes: his nose pierces through snares.</verse>
</chapter>