<chapter book="Job" number="41" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Can you draw out leviathan with an hook? or his tongue with a cord which you let down?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can you put an hook into his nose? or bore his jaw through with a thorn?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Will he make many supplications to you? will he speak soft words to you?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Will he make a covenant with you? will you take him for a servant for ever?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Will you play with him as with a bird? or will you bind him for your maidens?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Shall the companions make a banquet of him? shall they part him among the merchants?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Can you fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish spears?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Lay your hand on him, remember the battle, do no more.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Behold, the hope of him is in vain: shall not one be cast down even at the sight of him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">None is so fierce that dare stir him up: who then is able to stand before me?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Who has prevented me, that I should repay him? whatever is under the whole heaven is mine.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I will not conceal his parts, nor his power, nor his comely proportion.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who can discover the face of his garment? or who can come to him with his double bridle?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who can open the doors of his face? his teeth are terrible round about.</verse>
  <verse number="15">His scales are his pride, shut up together as with a close seal.</verse>
  <verse number="16">One is so near to another, that no air can come between them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">They are joined one to another, they stick together, that they cannot be sundered.</verse>
  <verse number="18">By his neesings a light does shine, and his eyes are like the eyelids of the morning.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Out of his mouth go burning lamps, and sparks of fire leap out.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Out of his nostrils goes smoke, as out of a seething pot or caldron.</verse>
  <verse number="21">His breath kindles coals, and a flame goes out of his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In his neck remains strength, and sorrow is turned into joy before him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The flakes of his flesh are joined together: they are firm in themselves; they cannot be moved.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His heart is as firm as a stone; yes, as hard as a piece of the nether millstone.</verse>
  <verse number="25">When he raises up himself, the mighty are afraid: by reason of breakings they purify themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sword of him that lays at him cannot hold: the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He esteems iron as straw, and brass as rotten wood.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The arrow cannot make him flee: sling stones are turned with him into stubble.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Darts are counted as stubble: he laughs at the shaking of a spear.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Sharp stones are under him: he spreads sharp pointed things on the mire.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He makes the deep to boil like a pot: he makes the sea like a pot of ointment.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He makes a path to shine after him; one would think the deep to be hoary.</verse>
  <verse number="33">On earth there is not his like, who is made without fear.</verse>
  <verse number="34">He beholds all high things: he is a king over all the children of pride.</verse>
</chapter>