<chapter book="Job" number="5" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Call now, if there be any that will answer you; and to which of the saints will you turn?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For wrath kills the foolish man, and envy slays the silly one.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I have seen the foolish taking root: but suddenly I cursed his habitation.</verse>
  <verse number="4">His children are far from safety, and they are crushed in the gate, neither is there any to deliver them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whose harvest the hungry eats up, and takes it even out of the thorns, and the robber swallows up their substance.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Although affliction comes not forth of the dust, neither does trouble spring out of the ground;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Yet man is born to trouble, as the sparks fly upward.</verse>
  <verse number="8">I would seek to God, and to God would I commit my cause:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Which does great things and unsearchable; marvelous things without number:</verse>
  <verse number="10">Who gives rain on the earth, and sends waters on the fields:</verse>
  <verse number="11">To set up on high those that be low; that those which mourn may be exalted to safety.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He disappoints the devices of the crafty, so that their hands cannot perform their enterprise.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He takes the wise in their own craftiness: and the counsel of the fraudulent is carried headlong.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They meet with darkness in the day time, and grope in the noonday as in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But he saves the poor from the sword, from their mouth, and from the hand of the mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="16">So the poor has hope, and iniquity stops her mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Behold, happy is the man whom God corrects: therefore despise not you the chastening of the Almighty:</verse>
  <verse number="18">For he makes sore, and binds up: he wounds, and his hands make whole.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He shall deliver you in six troubles: yes, in seven there shall no evil touch you.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In famine he shall redeem you from death: and in war from the power of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="21">You shall be hid from the whip of the tongue: neither shall you be afraid of destruction when it comes.</verse>
  <verse number="22">At destruction and famine you shall laugh: neither shall you be afraid of the beasts of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For you shall be in league with the stones of the field: and the beasts of the field shall be at peace with you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And you shall know that your tabernacle shall be in peace; and you shall visit your habitation, and shall not sin.</verse>
  <verse number="25">You shall know also that your seed shall be great, and your offspring as the grass of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">You shall come to your grave in a full age, like as a shock of corn comes in in his season.</verse>
  <verse number="27">See this, we have searched it, so it is; hear it, and know you it for your good.</verse>
</chapter>