<chapter book="Job" number="7" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Is there not an appointed time to man on earth? are not his days also like the days of an hireling?</verse>
  <verse number="2">As a servant earnestly desires the shadow, and as an hireling looks for the reward of his work:</verse>
  <verse number="3">So am I made to possess months of vanity, and wearisome nights are appointed to me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">When I lie down, I say, When shall I arise, and the night be gone? and I am full of tossings to and fro to the dawning of the day.</verse>
  <verse number="5">My flesh is clothed with worms and clods of dust; my skin is broken, and become loathsome.</verse>
  <verse number="6">My days are swifter than a weaver’s shuttle, and are spent without hope.</verse>
  <verse number="7">O remember that my life is wind: my eye shall no more see good.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The eye of him that has seen me shall see me no more: your eyes are on me, and I am not.</verse>
  <verse number="9">As the cloud is consumed and vanishes away: so he that goes down to the grave shall come up no more.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He shall return no more to his house, neither shall his place know him any more.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore I will not refrain my mouth; I will speak in the anguish of my spirit; I will complain in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Am I a sea, or a whale, that you set a watch over me?</verse>
  <verse number="13">When I say, My bed shall comfort me, my couch shall ease my complaints;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then you scare me with dreams, and terrify me through visions:</verse>
  <verse number="15">So that my soul chooses strangling, and death rather than my life.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I loathe it; I would not live always: let me alone; for my days are vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="17">What is man, that you should magnify him? and that you should set your heart on him?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And that you should visit him every morning, and try him every moment?</verse>
  <verse number="19">How long will you not depart from me, nor let me alone till I swallow down my spittle?</verse>
  <verse number="20">I have sinned; what shall I do to you, O you preserver of men? why have you set me as a mark against you, so that I am a burden to myself?</verse>
  <verse number="21">And why do you not pardon my transgression, and take away my iniquity? for now shall I sleep in the dust; and you shall seek me in the morning, but I shall not be.</verse>
</chapter>