<chapter book="Job" number="8" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Bildad the Shuhite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will you speak these things? and how long shall the words of your mouth be like a strong wind?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Does God pervert judgment? or does the Almighty pervert justice?</verse>
  <verse number="4">If your children have sinned against him, and he have cast them away for their transgression;</verse>
  <verse number="5">If you would seek to God betimes, and make your supplication to the Almighty;</verse>
  <verse number="6">If you were pure and upright; surely now he would awake for you, and make the habitation of your righteousness prosperous.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Though your beginning was small, yet your latter end should greatly increase.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For inquire, I pray you, of the former age, and prepare yourself to the search of their fathers:</verse>
  <verse number="9">(For we are but of yesterday, and know nothing, because our days on earth are a shadow:)</verse>
  <verse number="10">Shall not they teach you, and tell you, and utter words out of their heart?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Can the rush grow up without mire? can the flag grow without water?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Whilst it is yet in his greenness, and not cut down, it wither before any other herb.</verse>
  <verse number="13">So are the paths of all that forget God; and the hypocrite’s hope shall perish:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Whose hope shall be cut off, and whose trust shall be a spider’s web.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He shall lean on his house, but it shall not stand: he shall hold it fast, but it shall not endure.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He is green before the sun, and his branch shoots forth in his garden.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His roots are wrapped about the heap, and sees the place of stones.</verse>
  <verse number="18">If he destroy him from his place, then it shall deny him, saying, I have not seen you.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold, this is the joy of his way, and out of the earth shall others grow.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Behold, God will not cast away a perfect man, neither will he help the evil doers:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Till he fill your mouth with laughing, and your lips with rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="22">They that hate you shall be clothed with shame; and the dwelling place of the wicked shall come to nothing.</verse>
</chapter>