<chapter book="Joshua" number="19" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the second lot came forth to Simeon, for the tribe of the children of Simeon according to their families; and their inheritance was within the inheritance of the children of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And they had in their inheritance Beer-sheba, and Sheba, and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and Hazar-Shual, and Balah, and Ezem,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and Eltolad, and Bethul, and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Ziklag, and Beth-marcaboth, and Hazar-susah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Beth-lebaoth, and Sharuhen: thirteen cities and their hamlets;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ain, Rimmon, and Ether, and Ashan: four cities and their hamlets;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and all the hamlets that are round these cities to Baalath-beer, [that is] Ramah of the south. This is the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Simeon according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Out of the lot of the children of Judah was the inheritance of the children of Simeon; for the portion of the children of Judah was too great for them, and the children of Simeon inherited within their inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the third lot came up for the children of Zebulun according to their families. And the border of their inheritance was unto Sarid;</verse>
  <verse number="11">and their border went up westwards, and [to] Marealah, and reached to Dabbesheth, and reached to the torrent that is before Jokneam;</verse>
  <verse number="12">and turned from Sarid eastward, toward the sun-rising, to the border of Chisloth-Tabor, and went out to Dabrath, and went up to Japhia;</verse>
  <verse number="13">and from thence it passed eastward toward the sun-rising to Gath-Hepher, to Eth-kazin, and went out to Rimmon which reaches to Neah;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and the border turned round it northwards to Hannathon: and ended in the valley of Jiphthah-el;...</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Kattath, and Nahalal, and Shimron, and Jidalah, and Beth-lehem: twelve cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This was the inheritance of the children of Zebulun according to their families, these cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The fourth lot came forth to Issachar, for the children of Issachar according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And their territory was toward Jizreel, and Chesulloth, and Shunem,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and Hapharaim, and Shion, and Anaharath,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and Rabbith, and Kishion, and Ebez,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Remeth, and En-gannim, and En-haddah, and Beth-pazzez;</verse>
  <verse number="22">and the border reached to Tabor, and Shahazimah, and Beth-shemesh; and their border ended at the Jordan: sixteen cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This was the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Issachar according to their families, the cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the fifth lot came forth for the tribe of the children of Asher according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And their territory was Helkath, and Hali, and Beten, and Acshaph,</verse>
  <verse number="26">and Allammelech, and Amead, and Mishal; and [the border] reached to Carmel westwards, and to Shihor-libnath,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and turned towards the sun-rising to Beth-Dagon, and reached to Zebulun, and to the valley of Jiphthah-el northward [to] Beth-emek and Neiel, and went out to Cabul on the left,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and Ebron, and Rehob, and Hammon, and Kanah, as far as great Zidon;</verse>
  <verse number="29">and the border turned to Ramah, and as far as the fortified city of Tyre; and the border turned to Hosah; and ended at the sea by the tract of country of Achzib;</verse>
  <verse number="30">and Ummah, and Aphek, and Rehob: twenty-two cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="31">This was the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Asher according to their families, these cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The sixth lot came forth to the children of Naphtali, for the children of Naphtali according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And their border was from Heleph, from the oak of Zaanannim; and Adami-nekeb and Jabneel to Lakkum; and ended at the Jordan;</verse>
  <verse number="34">and the border turned westwards to Aznoth-Tabor, and went out from thence to Hukkok, and reached to Zebulun on the south, and reached to Asher on the west, and to Judah upon Jordan towards the sun-rising.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the fortified cities were Ziddim, Zer, and Hammath, Rakkath, and Chinnereth,</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Adamah, and Ramah, and Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and Kedesh, and Edrei, and En-Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Jiron, and Migdal-el, Horem, and Beth-anath, and Beth-shemesh: nineteen cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="39">This was the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Naphtali according to their families, the cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The seventh lot came forth for the tribe of the children of Dan according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And the territory of their inheritance was Zoreah, and Eshtaol, and Ir-shemesh,</verse>
  <verse number="42">and Shaalabbin, and Ajalon, and Jithlah,</verse>
  <verse number="43">and Elon, and Timnathah, and Ekron,</verse>
  <verse number="44">and El-tekeh, and Gibbethon, and Baalath,</verse>
  <verse number="45">and Jehud, and Beneberak, and Gath-Rimmon,</verse>
  <verse number="46">and Me-jarkon, and Rakkon, with the border over against Japho.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And the border of the children of Dan ended with these; and the children of Dan went up and fought against Leshem, and took it, and smote it with the edge of the sword, and took possession of it, and dwelt in it, and called Leshem, Dan, after the name of Dan their father.</verse>
  <verse number="48">This was the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Dan according to their families, these cities and their hamlets.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And they ended dividing the land for inheritance according to its borders. And the children of Israel gave an inheritance to Joshua the son of Nun among them.</verse>
  <verse number="50">According to the word of Jehovah they gave him the city that he asked, Timnath-serah in the hill-country of Ephraim; and he built the city, and dwelt in it.</verse>
  <verse number="51">These were the inheritances, which Eleazar the priest, and Joshua the son of Nun, and the chief fathers of the tribes of the children of Israel, distributed by lot in Shiloh before Jehovah, at the entrance of the tent of meeting. And they ended dividing the land.</verse>
</chapter>