<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="1" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">- - -</verse>
  <verse number="2">Bride: May he kiss me with the kiss of his mouth. Groom to Bride: So much better than wine are your breasts, fragranced with the finest perfumes.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Bride to Groom: Your name is oil that has been poured out; therefore, the maidens have loved you. Draw me forward.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Chorus to Bride: We will run after you in the odor of your perfumes. Bride to Chorus: The king has led me into his storerooms. Chorus to Bride: We will exult and rejoice in you, remembering your breasts above wine. Groom to Bride: The righteous love you.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Bride to Chorus: O daughters of Jerusalem: I am black, but shapely, like the tabernacles of Kedar, like the tents of Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Do not be concerned that I am dark, for the sun has changed my color. The sons of my mother have fought against me. They have made me the keeper of the vineyards. My own vineyard I have not kept.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Bride to Groom: Reveal to me, you whom my soul loves, where you pasture, where you recline at midday, lest I begin to wander after the flocks of your companions.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Groom to Bride: If you yourself do not know, O most beautiful among women, then go out and follow after the steps of the flocks, and pasture your young goats beside the tabernacles of the shepherds.</verse>
  <verse number="9">O my love, I have compared you to my company of horsemen against the chariots of Pharaoh.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Your cheeks are beautiful, like those of a turtledove. Your neck is like a bejeweled collar.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Chorus to Bride: We will fashion for you chains of gold, accented with reddened silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Bride to Chorus: While the king was taking his rest, my aromatic ointment sent forth its odor.</verse>
  <verse number="13">My beloved is a bundle of myrrh to me. He shall abide between my breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My beloved is a cluster of Cyprus grapes to me, in the vineyards of Engaddi.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Groom to Bride: Behold, you are beautiful, O my love. Behold, you are beautiful. Your eyes are those of a dove.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Bride to Groom: Behold, you are handsome, O my beloved, and graceful. Our bed is flourishing.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Groom to Bride: The timbers of our houses are of cedar; our ceilings are of cypress.</verse>
</chapter>