<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="7" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Chorus to Groom: What will you see in the Sulamitess, other than choruses of encampments? Chorus to Bride: How beautiful are your footsteps in shoes, O daughter of a ruler! The joints of your thighs are like jewels, which have been fabricated by the hand of an artist.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Your navel is a round bowl, never lacking in curvature. Your abdomen is like a bundle of wheat, surrounded with lilies.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Your two breasts are like two young twin does.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Your neck is like a tower of ivory. Your eyes like the fish ponds at Heshbon, which are at the entrance to the daughter of the multitude. Your nose is like the tower of Lebanon, which looks out toward Damascus.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Your head is like Carmel, and the hairs of your head are like the purple of the king, bound into pleats.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Most beloved one, how beautiful you are, and how graceful in delights!</verse>
  <verse number="7">Your stature is comparable to the palm tree, and your breasts to clusters of grapes.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Groom: I said, I will ascend to the palm tree, and take hold of its fruit. And your breasts will be like clusters of grapes on the vine. And the fragrance of your mouth will be like apples.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Bride: Your throat is like the finest wine: wine worthy for my beloved to drink, and for his lips and teeth to contemplate.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I am for my beloved, and his turning is to me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Approach, my beloved. Let us go out into the field; let us linger in the villages.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let us go up in the morning to the vineyards; let us see if the vineyard has flourished, if the flowers are ready to bear fruit, if the pomegranates have flourished. There I will give my breasts to you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The mandrakes yield their fragrance. At our gates is every fruit. The new and the old, my beloved, I have kept for you.</verse>
</chapter>