<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="8" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Bride to Groom: Who will give you to me as my brother, feeding from the breasts of my mother, so that I may discover you outside, and may kiss you, and so that now no one may despise me?</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will take hold of you and lead you into my mother’s house. There you will teach me, and I will give you a cup of spiced wine, and of new wine from my pomegranates.</verse>
  <verse number="3">His left hand is under my head, and his right hand shall embrace me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Groom to Chorus: I bind you by oath, O daughters of Jerusalem, not to disturb or awaken the beloved, until she wills.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Chorus to Groom: Who is she, who ascends from the desert, flowing with delights, leaning upon her beloved? Groom to Bride: Under the apple tree, I awakened you. There your mother was corrupted. There she who bore you was violated.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Set me like a seal upon your heart, like a seal upon your arm. For love is strong, like death, and envy is enduring, like hell: their lamps are made of fire and flames.</verse>
  <verse number="7">A multitude of waters cannot extinguish love, nor can a river overwhelm it. If a man were to give all the substance of his house in exchange for love, he would despise it as nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Chorus: Our sister is little and has no breasts. What shall we do for our sister on the day when she is called upon?</verse>
  <verse number="9">If she is a wall, let us build a rampart of silver upon it. If she is a door, let us join it together with boards of cedar.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Bride to Chorus: I am a wall, and my breasts are like towers, since, in his presence, I have become like one who has discovered peace.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The peaceful one had a vineyard, in that which held the peoples. He handed it on to the caretakers; a man brought, in exchange for its fruit, a thousand pieces of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Groom: My vineyard is before me. The thousand is for your peacefulness, and two hundred is for those who care for its fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Bride to Groom: Your friends are attentive to those who have been dwelling in the gardens. Cause me to heed your voice.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Flee away, my beloved, and become like the doe and the young stag upon the mountains of aromatic plants.</verse>
</chapter>