<chapter book="Job" number="10" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“I loathe my own life; I will express my complaint and speak in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will say to God: Do not condemn me! Let me know why You prosecute me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Does it please You to oppress me, to reject the work of Your hands and favor the schemes of the wicked?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Do You have eyes of flesh? Do You see as man sees?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Are Your days like those of a mortal, or Your years like those of a man,</verse>
  <verse number="6">that You should seek my iniquity and search out my sin—</verse>
  <verse number="7">though You know that I am not guilty, and there is no deliverance from Your hand?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Your hands shaped me and altogether formed me. Would You now turn and destroy me?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Please remember that You molded me like clay. Would You now return me to dust?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Did You not pour me out like milk, and curdle me like cheese?</verse>
  <verse number="11">You clothed me with skin and flesh, and knit me together with bones and sinews.</verse>
  <verse number="12">You have granted me life and loving devotion, and Your care has preserved my spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Yet You concealed these things in Your heart, and I know that this was in Your mind:</verse>
  <verse number="14">If I sinned, You would take note, and would not acquit me of my iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If I am guilty, woe to me! And even if I am righteous, I cannot lift my head. I am full of shame and aware of my affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Should I hold my head high, You would hunt me like a lion, and again display Your power against me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">You produce new witnesses against me and multiply Your anger toward me. Hardships assault me in wave after wave.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Why then did You bring me from the womb? Oh, that I had died, and no eye had seen me!</verse>
  <verse number="19">If only I had never come to be, but had been carried from the womb to the grave.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Are my days not few? Withdraw from me, that I may have a little comfort,</verse>
  <verse number="21">before I go—never to return—to a land of darkness and gloom,</verse>
  <verse number="22">to a land of utter darkness, of deep shadow and disorder, where even the light is like darkness.”</verse>
</chapter>