<chapter book="Job" number="20" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Zophar the Naamathite replied:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“So my anxious thoughts compel me to answer, because of the turmoil within me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I have heard a rebuke that insults me, and my understanding prompts a reply.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Do you not know that from antiquity, since man was placed on the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="5">the triumph of the wicked has been brief and the joy of the godless momentary?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Though his arrogance reaches the heavens, and his head touches the clouds,</verse>
  <verse number="7">he will perish forever, like his own dung; those who had seen him will ask, ‘Where is he?’</verse>
  <verse number="8">He will fly away like a dream, never to be found; he will be chased away like a vision in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The eye that saw him will see him no more, and his place will no longer behold him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">His sons will seek the favor of the poor, for his own hands must return his wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The youthful vigor that fills his bones will lie down with him in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Though evil is sweet in his mouth and he conceals it under his tongue,</verse>
  <verse number="13">though he cannot bear to let it go and keeps it in his mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="14">yet in his stomach his food sours into the venom of cobras within him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He swallows wealth but vomits it out; God will force it from his stomach.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He will suck the poison of cobras; the fangs of a viper will kill him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He will not enjoy the streams, the rivers flowing with honey and cream.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He must return the fruit of his labor without consuming it; he cannot enjoy the profits of his trading.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For he has oppressed and forsaken the poor; he has seized houses he did not build.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Because his appetite is never satisfied, he cannot escape with his treasure.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Nothing is left for him to consume; thus his prosperity will not endure.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In the midst of his plenty, he will be distressed; the full force of misery will come upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">When he has filled his stomach, God will vent His fury upon him, raining it down on him as he eats.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Though he flees from an iron weapon, a bronze-tipped arrow will pierce him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">It is drawn out of his back, the gleaming point from his liver. Terrors come over him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Total darkness is reserved for his treasures. A fire unfanned will consume him and devour what is left in his tent.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The heavens will expose his iniquity, and the earth will rise up against him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The possessions of his house will be removed, flowing away on the day of God’s wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="29">This is the wicked man’s portion from God, the inheritance God has appointed him.”</verse>
</chapter>