<chapter book="Job" number="22" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Eliphaz the Temanite replied:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Can a man be of use to God? Can even a wise man benefit Him?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Does it delight the Almighty that you are righteous? Does He profit if your ways are blameless?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Is it for your reverence that He rebukes you and enters into judgment against you?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Is not your wickedness great? Are not your iniquities endless?</verse>
  <verse number="6">For you needlessly demanded security from your brothers and deprived the naked of their clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="7">You gave no water to the weary and withheld food from the famished,</verse>
  <verse number="8">while the land belonged to a mighty man, and a man of honor lived on it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">You sent widows away empty-handed, and the strength of the fatherless was crushed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore snares surround you, and sudden peril terrifies you;</verse>
  <verse number="11">it is so dark you cannot see, and a flood of water covers you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is not God as high as the heavens? Look at the highest stars, how lofty they are!</verse>
  <verse number="13">Yet you say: ‘What does God know? Does He judge through thick darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thick clouds veil Him so He does not see us as He traverses the vault of heaven.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">Will you stay on the ancient path that wicked men have trod?</verse>
  <verse number="16">They were snatched away before their time, and their foundations were swept away by a flood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">They said to God, ‘Depart from us. What can the Almighty do to us?’</verse>
  <verse number="18">But it was He who filled their houses with good things; so I stay far from the counsel of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The righteous see it and are glad; the innocent mock them:</verse>
  <verse number="20">‘Surely our foes are destroyed, and fire has consumed their excess.’</verse>
  <verse number="21">Reconcile now and be at peace with Him; thereby good will come to you.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Receive instruction from His mouth, and lay up His words in your heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If you return to the Almighty, you will be restored. If you remove injustice from your tents</verse>
  <verse number="24">and consign your gold to the dust and the gold of Ophir to the stones of the ravines,</verse>
  <verse number="25">then the Almighty will be your gold and the finest silver for you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Surely then you will delight in the Almighty and lift up your face to God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">You will pray to Him, and He will hear you, and you will fulfill your vows.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Your decisions will be carried out, and light will shine on your ways.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When men are brought low and you say, ‘Lift them up!’ then He will save the lowly.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He will deliver even one who is not innocent, rescuing him through the cleanness of your hands.”</verse>
</chapter>