<chapter book="Job" number="28" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“Surely there is a mine for silver and a place where gold is refined.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Iron is taken from the earth, and copper is smelted from ore.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Man puts an end to the darkness; he probes the farthest recesses for ore in deepest darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Far from human habitation he cuts a shaft in places forgotten by the foot of man. Far from men he dangles and sways.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Food may come from the earth, but from below it is transformed as by fire.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Its rocks are the source of sapphires, containing flecks of gold.</verse>
  <verse number="7">No bird of prey knows that path; no falcon’s eye has seen it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Proud beasts have never trodden it; no lion has ever prowled over it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The miner strikes the flint; he overturns mountains at their base.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He hews out channels in the rocks, and his eyes spot every treasure.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He stops up the sources of the streams to bring what is hidden to light.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But where can wisdom be found, and where does understanding dwell?</verse>
  <verse number="13">No man can know its value, nor is it found in the land of the living.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The ocean depths say, ‘It is not in me,’ while the sea declares, ‘It is not with me.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">It cannot be bought with gold, nor can its price be weighed out in silver.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It cannot be valued in the gold of Ophir, in precious onyx or sapphire.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Neither gold nor crystal can compare to it, nor jewels of fine gold be exchanged for it.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Coral and quartz are unworthy of mention; the price of wisdom is beyond rubies.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Topaz from Cush cannot compare to it, nor can it be valued in pure gold.</verse>
  <verse number="20">From where, then, does wisdom come, and where does understanding dwell?</verse>
  <verse number="21">It is hidden from the eyes of every living thing and concealed from the birds of the air.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Abaddon and Death say, ‘We have heard a rumor about it.’</verse>
  <verse number="23">But God understands its way, and He knows its place.</verse>
  <verse number="24">For He looks to the ends of the earth and sees everything under the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="25">When God fixed the weight of the wind and measured out the waters,</verse>
  <verse number="26">when He set a limit for the rain and a path for the thunderbolt,</verse>
  <verse number="27">then He looked at wisdom and appraised it; He established it and searched it out.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And He said to man, ‘Behold, the fear of the Lord, that is wisdom, and to turn away from evil is understanding.’”</verse>
</chapter>