<chapter book="Job" number="30" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“But now they mock me, men younger than I am, whose fathers I would have refused to put with my sheep dogs.</verse>
  <verse number="2">What use to me was the strength of their hands, since their vigor had left them?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Gaunt from poverty and hunger, they gnawed the dry land, and the desolate wasteland by night.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They plucked mallow among the shrubs, and the roots of the broom tree were their food.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They were banished from among men, shouted at like thieves,</verse>
  <verse number="6">so that they lived on the slopes of the wadis, among the rocks and in holes in the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They cried out among the shrubs and huddled beneath the nettles.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A senseless and nameless brood, they were driven off the land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And now they mock me in song; I have become a byword among them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They abhor me and keep far from me; they do not hesitate to spit in my face.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Because God has unstrung my bow and afflicted me, they have cast off restraint in my presence.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The rabble arises at my right; they lay snares for my feet and build siege ramps against me.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They tear up my path; they profit from my destruction, with no one to restrain them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They advance as through a wide breach; through the ruins they keep rolling in.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Terrors are turned loose against me; they drive away my dignity as by the wind, and my prosperity has passed like a cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And now my soul is poured out within me; days of affliction grip me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Night pierces my bones, and my gnawing pains never rest.</verse>
  <verse number="18">With great force He grasps my garment; He seizes me by the collar of my tunic.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He throws me into the mud, and I have become like dust and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I cry out to You for help, but You do not answer; when I stand up, You merely look at me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">You have ruthlessly turned on me; You oppose me with Your strong hand.</verse>
  <verse number="22">You snatch me up into the wind and drive me before it; You toss me about in the storm.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Yes, I know that You will bring me down to death, to the place appointed for all the living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Yet no one stretches out his hand against a ruined man when he cries for help in his distress.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Have I not wept for those in trouble? Has my soul not grieved for the needy?</verse>
  <verse number="26">But when I hoped for good, evil came; when I looked for light, darkness fell.</verse>
  <verse number="27">I am churning within and cannot rest; days of affliction confront me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I go about blackened, but not by the sun. I stand up in the assembly and cry for help.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I have become a brother of jackals, a companion of ostriches.</verse>
  <verse number="30">My skin grows black and peels, and my bones burn with fever.</verse>
  <verse number="31">My harp is tuned to mourning and my flute to the sound of weeping.</verse>
</chapter>