<chapter book="Job" number="31" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“I have made a covenant with my eyes. How then could I gaze with desire at a virgin?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For what is the allotment of God from above, or the heritage from the Almighty on high?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Does not disaster come to the unjust and calamity to the workers of iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Does He not see my ways and count my every step?</verse>
  <verse number="5">If I have walked in falsehood or my foot has rushed to deceit,</verse>
  <verse number="6">let God weigh me with honest scales, that He may know my integrity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">If my steps have turned from the path, if my heart has followed my eyes, or if impurity has stuck to my hands,</verse>
  <verse number="8">then may another eat what I have sown, and may my crops be uprooted.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If my heart has been enticed by my neighbor’s wife, or I have lurked at his door,</verse>
  <verse number="10">then may my own wife grind grain for another, and may other men sleep with her.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For that would be a heinous crime, an iniquity to be judged.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is a fire that burns down to Abaddon; it would root out my entire harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I have rejected the cause of my manservant or maidservant when they made a complaint against me,</verse>
  <verse number="14">what will I do when God rises to judge? How will I answer when called to account?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Did not He who made me in the womb also make them? Did not the same One form us in the womb?</verse>
  <verse number="16">If I have denied the desires of the poor or allowed the widow’s eyes to fail,</verse>
  <verse number="17">if I have eaten my morsel alone, not sharing it with the fatherless—</verse>
  <verse number="18">though from my youth I reared him as would a father, and from my mother’s womb I guided the widow—</verse>
  <verse number="19">if I have seen one perish for lack of clothing, or a needy man without a cloak,</verse>
  <verse number="20">if his heart has not blessed me for warming him with the fleece of my sheep,</verse>
  <verse number="21">if I have lifted up my hand against the fatherless because I saw that I had support in the gate,</verse>
  <verse number="22">then may my arm fall from my shoulder and be torn from its socket.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For calamity from God terrifies me, and His splendor I cannot overpower.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If I have put my trust in gold or called pure gold my security,</verse>
  <verse number="25">if I have rejoiced in my great wealth because my hand had gained so much,</verse>
  <verse number="26">if I have beheld the sun in its radiance or the moon moving in splendor,</verse>
  <verse number="27">so that my heart was secretly enticed and my hand threw a kiss from my mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="28">this would also be an iniquity to be judged, for I would have denied God on high.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If I have rejoiced in my enemy’s ruin, or exulted when evil befell him—</verse>
  <verse number="30">I have not allowed my mouth to sin by asking for his life with a curse—</verse>
  <verse number="31">if the men of my house have not said, ‘Who is there who has not had his fill?’—</verse>
  <verse number="32">but no stranger had to lodge on the street, for my door has been open to the traveler—</verse>
  <verse number="33">if I have covered my transgressions like Adam by hiding my guilt in my heart,</verse>
  <verse number="34">because I greatly feared the crowds and the contempt of the clans terrified me, so that I kept silent and would not go outside—</verse>
  <verse number="35">(Oh, that I had one to hear me! Here is my signature. Let the Almighty answer me; let my accuser compose an indictment.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Surely I would carry it on my shoulder and wear it like a crown.</verse>
  <verse number="37">I would give account of all my steps; I would approach Him like a prince.)—</verse>
  <verse number="38">if my land cries out against me and its furrows weep together,</verse>
  <verse number="39">if I have devoured its produce without payment or broken the spirit of its tenants,</verse>
  <verse number="40">then let briers grow instead of wheat and stinkweed instead of barley.” Thus conclude the words of Job.</verse>
</chapter>