<chapter book="Job" number="38" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Who is this who obscures My counsel by words without knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Now brace yourself like a man; I will question you, and you shall inform Me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where were you when I laid the foundations of the earth? Tell Me, if you have understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who fixed its measurements? Surely you know! Or who stretched a measuring line across it?</verse>
  <verse number="6">On what were its foundations set, or who laid its cornerstone,</verse>
  <verse number="7">while the morning stars sang together and all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Who enclosed the sea behind doors when it burst forth from the womb,</verse>
  <verse number="9">when I made the clouds its garment and thick darkness its blanket,</verse>
  <verse number="10">when I fixed its boundaries and set in place its bars and doors,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and I declared: ‘You may come this far, but no farther; here your proud waves must stop’?</verse>
  <verse number="12">In your days, have you commanded the morning or assigned the dawn its place,</verse>
  <verse number="13">that it might spread to the ends of the earth and shake the wicked out of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">The earth takes shape like clay under a seal; its hills stand out like the folds of a garment.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Light is withheld from the wicked, and their upraised arm is broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Have you journeyed to the vents of the sea or walked in the trenches of the deep?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Have the gates of death been revealed to you? Have you seen the gates of the shadow of death?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Have you surveyed the extent of the earth? Tell Me, if you know all this.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Where is the way to the home of light? Do you know where darkness resides,</verse>
  <verse number="20">so you can lead it back to its border? Do you know the paths to its home?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Surely you know, for you were already born! And the number of your days is great!</verse>
  <verse number="22">Have you entered the storehouses of snow or observed the storehouses of hail,</verse>
  <verse number="23">which I hold in reserve for times of trouble, for the day of war and battle?</verse>
  <verse number="24">In which direction is the lightning dispersed, or the east wind scattered over the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who cuts a channel for the flood or clears a path for the thunderbolt,</verse>
  <verse number="26">to bring rain on a barren land, on a desert where no man lives,</verse>
  <verse number="27">to satisfy the parched wasteland and make it sprout with tender grass?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Does the rain have a father? Who has begotten the drops of dew?</verse>
  <verse number="29">From whose womb does the ice emerge? Who gives birth to the frost from heaven,</verse>
  <verse number="30">when the waters become hard as stone and the surface of the deep is frozen?</verse>
  <verse number="31">Can you bind the chains of the Pleiades or loosen the belt of Orion?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Can you bring forth the constellations in their seasons or lead out the Bear and her cubs?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Do you know the laws of the heavens? Can you set their dominion over the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="34">Can you command the clouds so that a flood of water covers you?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Can you send the lightning bolts on their way? Do they report to you, ‘Here we are’?</verse>
  <verse number="36">Who has put wisdom in the heart or given understanding to the mind?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who has the wisdom to count the clouds? Or who can tilt the water jars of the heavens</verse>
  <verse number="38">when the dust hardens into a mass and the clods of earth stick together?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Can you hunt the prey for a lioness or satisfy the hunger of young lions</verse>
  <verse number="40">when they crouch in their dens and lie in wait in the thicket?</verse>
  <verse number="41">Who provides food for the raven when its young cry out to God as they wander about for lack of food?</verse>
</chapter>