<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“Do you know when mountain goats give birth? Have you watched the doe bear her fawn?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can you count the months they are pregnant? Do you know the time they give birth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">They crouch down and bring forth their young; they deliver their newborn.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Their young ones thrive and grow up in the open field; they leave and do not return.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who set the wild donkey free? Who released the swift donkey from the harness?</verse>
  <verse number="6">I made the wilderness his home and the salt flats his dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He scorns the tumult of the city and never hears the shouts of a driver.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He roams the mountains for pasture, searching for any green thing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will the wild ox consent to serve you? Will he stay by your manger at night?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Can you hold him to the furrow with a harness? Will he plow the valleys behind you?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Can you rely on his great strength? Will you leave your hard work to him?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Can you trust him to bring in your grain and gather it to your threshing floor?</verse>
  <verse number="13">The wings of the ostrich flap joyfully, but cannot match the pinions and feathers of the stork.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For she leaves her eggs on the ground and lets them warm in the sand.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She forgets that a foot may crush them, or a wild animal may trample them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She treats her young harshly, as if not her own, with no concern that her labor was in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For God has deprived her of wisdom; He has not endowed her with understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Yet when she proudly spreads her wings, she laughs at the horse and its rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Do you give strength to the horse or adorn his neck with a mane?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Do you make him leap like a locust, striking terror with his proud snorting?</verse>
  <verse number="21">He paws in the valley and rejoices in his strength; he charges into battle.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He laughs at fear, frightened of nothing; he does not turn back from the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A quiver rattles at his side, along with a flashing spear and lance.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Trembling with excitement, he devours the distance; he cannot stand still when the ram’s horn sounds.</verse>
  <verse number="25">At the blast of the horn, he snorts with fervor. He catches the scent of battle from afar, the shouts of captains and the cry of war.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Does the hawk take flight by your understanding and spread his wings toward the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Does the eagle soar at your command and make his nest on high?</verse>
  <verse number="28">He dwells on a cliff and lodges there; his stronghold is on a rocky crag.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From there he spies out food; his eyes see it from afar.</verse>
  <verse number="30">His young ones feast on blood; and where the slain are, there he is.”</verse>
</chapter>