<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the LORD said to Job:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Will the faultfinder contend with the Almighty? Let him who argues with God give an answer.”</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Job answered the LORD:</verse>
  <verse number="4">“Behold, I am insignificant. How can I reply to You? I place my hand over my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I have spoken once, but I have no answer—twice, but I have nothing to add.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind and said:</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Now brace yourself like a man; I will question you, and you shall inform Me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Would you really annul My justice? Would you condemn Me to justify yourself?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Do you have an arm like God’s? Can you thunder with a voice like His?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then adorn yourself with majesty and splendor, and clothe yourself with honor and glory.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Unleash the fury of your wrath; look on every proud man and bring him low.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Look on every proud man and humble him; trample the wicked where they stand.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Bury them together in the dust; imprison them in the grave.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then I will confess to you that your own right hand can save you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Look at Behemoth, which I made along with you. He feeds on grass like an ox.</verse>
  <verse number="16">See the strength of his loins and the power in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">His tail sways like a cedar; the sinews of his thighs are tightly knit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are tubes of bronze; his limbs are rods of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is the foremost of God’s works; only his Maker can draw the sword against him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The hills yield him their produce, while all the beasts of the field play nearby.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He lies under the lotus plants, hidden among the reeds of the marsh.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The lotus plants conceal him in their shade; the willows of the brook surround him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Though the river rages, Behemoth is unafraid; he remains secure, though the Jordan surges to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Can anyone capture him as he looks on, or pierce his nose with a snare?</verse>
</chapter>