<chapter book="Job" number="5" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“Call out if you please, but who will answer? To which of the holy ones will you turn?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For resentment kills a fool, and envy slays the simple.</verse>
  <verse number="3">I have seen a fool taking root, but suddenly his house was cursed.</verse>
  <verse number="4">His sons are far from safety, crushed in court without a defender.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The hungry consume his harvest, taking it even from the thorns, and the thirsty pant after his wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For distress does not spring from the dust, and trouble does not sprout from the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Yet man is born to trouble as surely as sparks fly upward.</verse>
  <verse number="8">However, if I were you, I would appeal to God and lay my cause before Him—</verse>
  <verse number="9">the One who does great and unsearchable things, wonders without number.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He gives rain to the earth and sends water upon the fields.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He sets the lowly on high, so that mourners are lifted to safety.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He thwarts the schemes of the crafty, so that their hands find no success.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He catches the wise in their craftiness, and sweeps away the plans of the cunning.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They encounter darkness by day and grope at noon as in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He saves the needy from the sword in their mouth and from the clutches of the powerful.</verse>
  <verse number="16">So the poor have hope, and injustice shuts its mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Blessed indeed is the man whom God corrects; so do not despise the discipline of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For He wounds, but He also binds; He strikes, but His hands also heal.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He will rescue you from six calamities; no harm will touch you in seven.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In famine He will redeem you from death, and in battle from the stroke of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="21">You will be hidden from the scourge of the tongue, and will not fear havoc when it comes.</verse>
  <verse number="22">You will laugh at destruction and famine, and need not fear the beasts of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For you will have a covenant with the stones of the field, and the wild animals will be at peace with you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">You will know that your tent is secure, and find nothing amiss when inspecting your home.</verse>
  <verse number="25">You will know that your offspring will be many, your descendants like the grass of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">You will come to the grave in full vigor, like a sheaf of grain gathered in season.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Indeed, we have investigated, and it is true! So hear it and know for yourself.”</verse>
</chapter>