<chapter book="Job" number="6" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job replied:</verse>
  <verse number="2">“If only my grief could be weighed and placed with my calamity on the scales.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For then it would outweigh the sand of the seas—no wonder my words have been rash.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For the arrows of the Almighty have pierced me; my spirit drinks in their poison; the terrors of God are arrayed against me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Does a wild donkey bray over fresh grass, or an ox low over its fodder?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Is tasteless food eaten without salt, or is there flavor in the white of an egg?</verse>
  <verse number="7">My soul refuses to touch them; they are loathsome food to me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">If only my request were granted and God would fulfill my hope:</verse>
  <verse number="9">that God would be willing to crush me, to unleash His hand and cut me off!</verse>
  <verse number="10">It still brings me comfort, and joy through unrelenting pain, that I have not denied the words of the Holy One.</verse>
  <verse number="11">What strength do I have, that I should still hope? What is my future, that I should be patient?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is my strength like that of stone, or my flesh made of bronze?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Is there any help within me now that success is driven from me?</verse>
  <verse number="14">A despairing man should have the kindness of his friend, even if he forsakes the fear of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But my brothers are as faithless as wadis, as seasonal streams that overflow,</verse>
  <verse number="16">darkened because of the ice and the inflow of melting snow,</verse>
  <verse number="17">but ceasing in the dry season and vanishing from their channels in the heat.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Caravans turn aside from their routes; they go into the wasteland and perish.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The caravans of Tema look for water; the travelers of Sheba hope to find it.</verse>
  <verse number="20">They are confounded because they had hoped; their arrival brings disappointment.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For now you are of no help; you see terror, and you are afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Have I ever said, ‘Give me something; offer me a bribe from your wealth;</verse>
  <verse number="23">deliver me from the hand of the enemy; redeem me from the grasp of the ruthless’?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Teach me, and I will be silent. Help me understand how I have erred.</verse>
  <verse number="25">How painful are honest words! But what does your argument prove?</verse>
  <verse number="26">Do you intend to correct my words, and treat as wind my cry of despair?</verse>
  <verse number="27">You would even cast lots for an orphan and barter away your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But now, please look at me. Would I lie to your face?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Reconsider; do not be unjust. Reconsider, for my righteousness is at stake.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Is there iniquity on my tongue? Can my mouth not discern malice?</verse>
</chapter>