<chapter book="Esther" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the king will go in and Haman to drink with Esther the queen.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the king will say to Esther also in the second day at the drinking of wine, What thy asking, queen Esther? and it shall be given to thee: and what thy seeking? even to the half of the kingdom and it shall be done.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Esther the queen will answer and say, If I found grace in thine eyes, O king, and if good to the king, my soul shall be given to me in my asking, and my people in my seeking.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For we were sold, I and my people, to cut off, to kill and to destroy. And if for servants and for maids we were sold, I was silent, but the enemy made not even for the loss of the king.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the king Ahasuerus will say, and he will say to Esther the queen, Who is he, and where is he, whom his heart filled him to do thus?</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Esther will say, The man, the adversary and enemy, this evil Haman. And Haman was terrified from before the king and the queen.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the king rose up in his wrath from the drinking of wine, to the garden of the palace: and Haman stood up to seek out for his soul from Esther the queen; for he saw that evil was completed for him from the king.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the king turned back from the garden of the palace to the house of the drinking of wine; and Haman fell upon the bed which Esther was upon And the king will say, Also is he to force the queen with me in the house? The word went forth from the king’s mouth, and they covered Haman’s face.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Harbonah, one of the eunuchs, will say before the king, Also behold the tree which Haman made for Mordecai who spake good for the king, standing in Haman’s house, high fifty cubits: And the king will say, Ye shall hang him upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they will hang Haman upon the tree that he preps for Mordecai. And the wrath of the king subsided.</verse>
</chapter>