<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="16" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And they brought in the ark of God, and set it in the midst of the tent that David had pitched for it: and they offered burnt offerings and peace offerings before God.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And when David had made an end of offering the burnt offering and the peace offerings, he blessed the people in the name of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he dealt to every one of Israel, both man and woman, to every one a loaf of bread, and a portion of flesh, and a cake of raisins.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he appointed certain of the Levites to minister before the ark of the LORD, and to celebrate and to thank and praise the LORD, the God of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Asaph the chief, and second to him Zechariah, Jeiel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehiel, and Mattithiah, and Eliab, and Benaiah, and Obed-edom, and Jeiel, with psalteries and with harps; and Asaph with cymbals, sounding aloud;</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Benaiah and Jahaziel the priests with trumpets continually, before the ark of the covenant of God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Then on that day did David first ordain to give thanks unto the LORD, by the hand of Asaph and his brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="8">O give thanks unto the LORD, call upon his name; make known his doings among the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Sing unto him, sing praises unto him; talk ye of all his marvelous works.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Glory ye in his holy name: let the heart of them rejoice that seek the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Seek ye the LORD and his strength; seek his face evermore.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Remember his marvelous works that he hath done; his wonders, and the judgments of his mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="13">O ye seed of Israel his servant, ye children of Jacob, his chosen ones.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He is the LORD our God: his judgments are in all the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Remember his covenant for ever, the word which he commanded to a thousand generations;</verse>
  <verse number="16">The covenant which he made with Abraham, and his oath unto Isaac;</verse>
  <verse number="17">And confirmed the same unto Jacob for a statute, to Israel for an everlasting covenant:</verse>
  <verse number="18">Saying, Unto thee will I give the land of Canaan, the lot of your inheritance:</verse>
  <verse number="19">When ye were but a few men in number; yea, very few, and sojourners in it;</verse>
  <verse number="20">And they went about from nation to nation, and from one kingdom to another people.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He suffered no man to do them wrong; yea, he reproved kings for their sakes;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Saying, Touch not mine anointed ones, and do my prophets no harm.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Sing unto the LORD, all the earth; shew forth his salvation from day to day.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Declare his glory among the nations, his marvelous works among all the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For great is the LORD, and highly to be praised: he also is to be feared above all gods.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For all the gods of the peoples are idols: but the LORD made the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Honour and majesty are before him: strength and gladness are in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Give unto the LORD, ye kindreds of the peoples, give unto the LORD glory and strength.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Give unto the LORD the glory due unto his name: bring an offering, and come before him: worship the LORD in the beauty of holiness.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Tremble before him, all the earth: the world also is stablished that it cannot be moved.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Let the heavens be glad, and let the earth rejoice; and let them say among the nations, The LORD reigneth.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Let the sea roar and the fulness thereof; let the field exult, and all that is therein;</verse>
  <verse number="33">Then shall the trees of the wood sing for joy before the LORD, for he cometh to judge the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="34">O give thanks unto the LORD; for he is good: for his mercy endureth for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And say ye, Save us, O God of our salvation, and gather us together and deliver us from the nations, to give thanks unto thy holy name, and to triumph in thy praise.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Blessed be the LORD, the God of Israel, from everlasting even to everlasting. And all the people said, Amen, and praised the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="37">So he left there, before the ark of the covenant of the LORD, Asaph and his brethren, to minister before the ark continually, as every day’s work required:</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Obed-edom with their brethren, threescore and eight; Obed-edom also the son of Jeduthun and Hosah to be doorkeepers:</verse>
  <verse number="39">and Zadok the priest, and his brethren the priests, before the tabernacle of the LORD in the high place that was at Gibeon,</verse>
  <verse number="40">to offer burnt offerings unto the LORD upon the altar of burnt offering continually morning and evening, even according to all that is written in the law of the LORD, which he commanded unto Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="41">and with them Heman and Jeduthun, and the rest that were chosen, who were expressed by name, to give thanks to the LORD, because his mercy endureth for ever;</verse>
  <verse number="42">and with them Heman and Jeduthun with trumpets and cymbals for those that should sound aloud, and with instruments for the songs of God: and the sons of Jeduthun to be at the gate.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And all the people departed every man to his house: and David returned to bless his house.</verse>
</chapter>