<chapter book="Luke" number="23" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the entire multitude of them, rising up, led him to Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Then they began to accuse him, saying, “We found this one subverting our nation, and prohibiting giving tribute to Caesar, and saying that he is Christ the king.”</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Pilate questioned him, saying: “You are the king of the Jews?” But in response, he said: “You are saying it.”</verse>
  <verse number="4">Then Pilate said to the leaders of the priests and to the crowds, “I find no case against this man.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">But they continued more intensely, saying: “He has stirred up the people, teaching throughout all of Judea, beginning from Galilee, even to this place.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">But Pilate, upon hearing Galilee, asked if the man were of Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And when he realized that he was under Herod’s jurisdiction, he sent him away to Herod, who was himself also at Jerusalem in those days.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then Herod, upon seeing Jesus, was very glad. For he had been wanting to see him for a long time, because he had heard so many things about him, and he was hoping to see some kind of sign wrought by him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then he questioned him with many words. But he gave him no response at all.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the leaders of the priests, and the scribes, stood firm in persistently accusing him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Then Herod, with his soldiers, scorned him. And he ridiculed him, clothing him in a white garment. And he sent him back to Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Herod and Pilate became friends on that day. For previously they were enemies to one another.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Pilate, calling together the leaders of the priests, and the magistrates, and the people,</verse>
  <verse number="14">said to them: “You have brought before me this man, as one who disturbs the people. And behold, having questioned him before you, I find no case against this man, in those things about which you accuse him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And neither did Herod. For I sent you all to him, and behold, nothing deserving of death was recorded about him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Therefore, I will chastise him and release him.”</verse>
  <verse number="17">Now he was required to release one person for them on the feast day.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But the entire crowd exclaimed together, saying: “Take this one, and release to us Barabbas!”</verse>
  <verse number="19">Now he had been cast into prison because of a certain sedition that occurred in the city and for murder.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Then Pilate spoke to them again, wanting to release Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But they shouted in response, saying: “Crucify him! Crucify him!”</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then he said to them a third time: “Why? What evil has he done? I find no case against him for death. Therefore, I will chastise him and release him.”</verse>
  <verse number="23">But they persisted, with loud voices, in demanding that he be crucified. And their voices increased in intensity.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And so Pilate issued a judgment granting their petition.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Then he released for them the one who had been cast into prison for murder and sedition, whom they were requesting. Yet truly, Jesus he handed over to their will.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And as they were leading him away, they apprehended a certain one, Simon of Cyrene, as he was returning from the countryside. And they imposed the cross on him to carry after Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Then a great crowd of people followed him, with women who were mourning and lamenting him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But Jesus, turning to them, said: “Daughters of Jerusalem, do not weep over me. Instead, weep over yourselves and over your children.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For behold, the days will arrive in which they will say, ‘Blessed are the barren, and the wombs that have not borne, and the breasts that have not nursed.’</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then they will begin to say to the mountains, ‘Fall over us,’ and to the hills, ‘Cover us.’</verse>
  <verse number="31">For if they do these things with green wood, what will be done with the dry?”</verse>
  <verse number="32">Now they also led out two other criminals with him, in order to execute them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And when they arrived at the place that is called Calvary, they crucified him there, with the robbers, one to the right and the other to the left.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Then Jesus said, “Father, forgive them. For they know not what they do.” And truly, dividing his garments, they cast lots.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And people were standing near, watching. And the leaders among them derided him, saying: “He saved others. Let him save himself, if this one is the Christ, the elect of God.”</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the soldiers also ridiculed him, approaching him and offering him vinegar,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and saying, “If you are the king of the Jews, save yourself.”</verse>
  <verse number="38">Now there was also an inscription written over him in letters of Greek, and Latin, and Hebrew: THIS IS THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And one of those robbers who were hanging blasphemed him, saying, “If you are the Christ, save yourself and us.”</verse>
  <verse number="40">But the other responded by rebuking him, saying: “Do you have no fear of God, since you are under the same condemnation?</verse>
  <verse number="41">And indeed, it is just for us. For we are receiving what our deeds deserve. But truly, this one has done nothing wrong.”</verse>
  <verse number="42">And he said to Jesus, “Lord, remember me when you come into your kingdom.”</verse>
  <verse number="43">And Jesus said to him, “Amen I say to you, this day you shall be with me in Paradise.”</verse>
  <verse number="44">Now it was nearly the sixth hour, and a darkness occurred over the entire earth, until the ninth hour.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And the sun was obscured. And the veil of the temple was torn down the middle.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And Jesus, crying out with a loud voice, said: “Father, into your hands I commend my spirit.” And upon saying this, he expired.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Now, the centurion, seeing what had happened, glorified God, saying, “Truly, this man was the Just One.”</verse>
  <verse number="48">And the entire crowd of those who came together to see this spectacle also saw what had happened, and they returned, striking their breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="49">Now all those who knew him, and the women who had followed him from Galilee, were standing at a distance, watching these things.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And behold, there was a man named Joseph, who was a councilman, a good and just man,</verse>
  <verse number="51">(for he had not consented to their decision or their actions). He was from Arimathea, a city of Judea. And he was himself also anticipating the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="52">This man approached Pilate and petitioned for the body of Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And taking him down, he wrapped him in a fine linen cloth, and he placed him in a tomb hewn from rock, in which no one had ever been placed.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And it was the day of Preparation, and the Sabbath was drawing near.</verse>
  <verse number="55">Now the women who had come with him from Galilee, by following, saw the tomb and the manner in which his body was placed.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And upon returning, they prepared aromatic spices and ointments. But on the Sabbath, indeed, they rested, according to the commandment.</verse>
</chapter>