<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="16" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">So they brought the ark of God, and set it in the middle of the tent that David had pitched for it: and they offered burnt sacrifices and peace offerings before God.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And when David had made an end of offering the burnt offerings and the peace offerings, he blessed the people in the name of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he dealt to every one of Israel, both man and woman, to every one a loaf of bread, and a good piece of flesh, and a flagon of wine.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he appointed certain of the Levites to minister before the ark of the LORD, and to record, and to thank and praise the LORD God of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Asaph the chief, and next to him Zechariah, Jeiel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehiel, and Mattithiah, and Eliab, and Benaiah, and Obededom: and Jeiel with psalteries and with harps; but Asaph made a sound with cymbals;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Benaiah also and Jahaziel the priests with trumpets continually before the ark of the covenant of God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Then on that day David delivered first this psalm to thank the LORD into the hand of Asaph and his brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Give thanks to the LORD, call on his name, make known his deeds among the people.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Sing to him, sing psalms to him, talk you of all his wondrous works.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Glory you in his holy name: let the heart of them rejoice that seek the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Seek the LORD and his strength, seek his face continually.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Remember his marvelous works that he has done, his wonders, and the judgments of his mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="13">O you seed of Israel his servant, you children of Jacob, his chosen ones.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He is the LORD our God; his judgments are in all the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Be you mindful always of his covenant; the word which he commanded to a thousand generations;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Even of the covenant which he made with Abraham, and of his oath to Isaac;</verse>
  <verse number="17">And has confirmed the same to Jacob for a law, and to Israel for an everlasting covenant,</verse>
  <verse number="18">Saying, To you will I give the land of Canaan, the lot of your inheritance;</verse>
  <verse number="19">When you were but few, even a few, and strangers in it.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And when they went from nation to nation, and from one kingdom to another people;</verse>
  <verse number="21">He suffered no man to do them wrong: yes, he reproved kings for their sakes,</verse>
  <verse number="22">Saying, Touch not my anointed, and do my prophets no harm.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Sing to the LORD, all the earth; show forth from day to day his salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Declare his glory among the heathen; his marvelous works among all nations.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For great is the LORD, and greatly to be praised: he also is to be feared above all gods.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For all the gods of the people are idols: but the LORD made the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Glory and honor are in his presence; strength and gladness are in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Give to the LORD, you kindreds of the people, give to the LORD glory and strength.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Give to the LORD the glory due to his name: bring an offering, and come before him: worship the LORD in the beauty of holiness.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Fear before him, all the earth: the world also shall be stable, that it be not moved.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Let the heavens be glad, and let the earth rejoice: and let men say among the nations, The LORD reigns.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Let the sea roar, and the fullness thereof: let the fields rejoice, and all that is therein.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Then shall the trees of the wood sing out at the presence of the LORD, because he comes to judge the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="34">O give thanks to the LORD; for he is good; for his mercy endures for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And say you, Save us, O God of our salvation, and gather us together, and deliver us from the heathen, that we may give thanks to your holy name, and glory in your praise.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Blessed be the LORD God of Israel for ever and ever. And all the people said, Amen, and praised the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="37">So he left there before the ark of the covenant of the LORD Asaph and his brothers, to minister before the ark continually, as every day’s work required:</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Obededom with their brothers, three score and eight; Obededom also the son of Jeduthun and Hosah to be porters:</verse>
  <verse number="39">And Zadok the priest, and his brothers the priests, before the tabernacle of the LORD in the high place that was at Gibeon,</verse>
  <verse number="40">To offer burnt offerings to the LORD on the altar of the burnt offering continually morning and evening, and to do according to all that is written in the law of the LORD, which he commanded Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="41">And with them Heman and Jeduthun, and the rest that were chosen, who were expressed by name, to give thanks to the LORD, because his mercy endures for ever;</verse>
  <verse number="42">And with them Heman and Jeduthun with trumpets and cymbals for those that should make a sound, and with musical instruments of God. And the sons of Jeduthun were porters.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And all the people departed every man to his house: and David returned to bless his house.</verse>
</chapter>