<chapter book="Numbers" number="12" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Miriam and Aaron spoke against Moses, because of his wife, an Ethiopian,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and they said: “Has the Lord spoken only through Moses? Has he not also spoken similarly to us?” And when the Lord had heard this,</verse>
  <verse number="3">(for Moses was a man exceedingly meek, beyond all the men who were living upon the earth)</verse>
  <verse number="4">immediately he spoke to him, and to Aaron and Miriam, “Go out, you three only, to the tabernacle of the covenant.” And when they had gone out,</verse>
  <verse number="5">the Lord descended in a column of cloud, and he stood at the entrance of the tabernacle, calling to Aaron and Miriam. And when they had advanced,</verse>
  <verse number="6">he said to them: “Listen to my words. If there will be among you a prophet of the Lord, I will appear to him in a vision, or I will speak to him through a dream.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But it is not so with my servant Moses, who is the most faithful in all my house.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For I speak with him mouth to mouth, and plainly. And not through enigmas and figures does he perceive the Lord. Therefore, why were you not afraid to disparage my servant Moses?”</verse>
  <verse number="9">And being angry against them, he went away.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Likewise, the cloud which was over the tabernacle withdrew. And behold, Miriam appeared to be white with a leprosy, like snow. And when Aaron had looked upon her, and he had seen the spreading of the leprosy,</verse>
  <verse number="11">he said to Moses: “I beg you, my lord, not to impose upon us this sin, which we have committed foolishly.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Do not let this one be like one who is dead, or like an abortion that has been cast from the womb of her mother. Behold, half of her flesh is already consumed by leprosy.”</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Moses cried out to the Lord, saying, “O God, I beg you: heal her.”</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the Lord answered him: “If her father had spit on her face, should she not have been filled with shame for at least seven days? Let her be separated, outside the camp, for seven days, and after that, she will be called back.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">And so Miriam was excluded from the camp for seven days. And the people did not move from that place, until Miriam was called back.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the people set out from Hazeroth, and they pitched their tents in the desert of Paran.</verse>
</chapter>