<chapter book="Ezekiel" number="33" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Again the word of the LORD came to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Son of man, speak to the children of your people, and say to them, When I bring the sword on a land, if the people of the land take a man of their coasts, and set him for their watchman:</verse>
  <verse number="3">If when he sees the sword come on the land, he blow the trumpet, and warn the people;</verse>
  <verse number="4">Then whoever hears the sound of the trumpet, and takes not warning; if the sword come, and take him away, his blood shall be on his own head.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He heard the sound of the trumpet, and took not warning; his blood shall be on him. But he that takes warning shall deliver his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But if the watchman see the sword come, and blow not the trumpet, and the people be not warned; if the sword come, and take any person from among them, he is taken away in his iniquity; but his blood will I require at the watchman’s hand.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So you, O son of man, I have set you a watchman to the house of Israel; therefore you shall hear the word at my mouth, and warn them from me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">When I say to the wicked, O wicked man, you shall surely die; if you do not speak to warn the wicked from his way, that wicked man shall die in his iniquity; but his blood will I require at your hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Nevertheless, if you warn the wicked of his way to turn from it; if he do not turn from his way, he shall die in his iniquity; but you have delivered your soul.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore, O you son of man, speak to the house of Israel; Thus you speak, saying, If our transgressions and our sins be on us, and we pine away in them, how should we then live?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Say to them, As I live, said the Lord GOD, I have no pleasure in the death of the wicked; but that the wicked turn from his way and live: turn you, turn you from your evil ways; for why will you die, O house of Israel?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Therefore, you son of man, say to the children of your people, The righteousness of the righteous shall not deliver him in the day of his transgression: as for the wickedness of the wicked, he shall not fall thereby in the day that he turns from his wickedness; neither shall the righteous be able to live for his righteousness in the day that he sins.</verse>
  <verse number="13">When I shall say to the righteous, that he shall surely live; if he trust to his own righteousness, and commit iniquity, all his righteousnesses shall not be remembered; but for his iniquity that he has committed, he shall die for it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Again, when I say to the wicked, You shall surely die; if he turn from his sin, and do that which is lawful and right;</verse>
  <verse number="15">If the wicked restore the pledge, give again that he had robbed, walk in the statutes of life, without committing iniquity; he shall surely live, he shall not die.</verse>
  <verse number="16">None of his sins that he has committed shall be mentioned to him: he has done that which is lawful and right; he shall surely live.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Yet the children of your people say, The way of the Lord is not equal: but as for them, their way is not equal.</verse>
  <verse number="18">When the righteous turns from his righteousness, and commits iniquity, he shall even die thereby.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But if the wicked turn from his wickedness, and do that which is lawful and right, he shall live thereby.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Yet you say, The way of the Lord is not equal. O you house of Israel, I will judge you every one after his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And it came to pass in the twelfth year of our captivity, in the tenth month, in the fifth day of the month, that one that had escaped out of Jerusalem came to me, saying, The city is smitten.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Now the hand of the LORD was on me in the evening, before he that was escaped came; and had opened my mouth, until he came to me in the morning; and my mouth was opened, and I was no more dumb.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then the word of the LORD came to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Son of man, they that inhabit those wastes of the land of Israel speak, saying, Abraham was one, and he inherited the land: but we are many; the land is given us for inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Why say to them, Thus said the Lord GOD; You eat with the blood, and lift up your eyes toward your idols, and shed blood: and shall you possess the land?</verse>
  <verse number="26">You stand on your sword, you work abomination, and you defile every one his neighbor’s wife: and shall you possess the land?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Say you thus to them, Thus said the Lord GOD; As I live, surely they that are in the wastes shall fall by the sword, and him that is in the open field will I give to the beasts to be devoured, and they that be in the forts and in the caves shall die of the pestilence.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For I will lay the land most desolate, and the pomp of her strength shall cease; and the mountains of Israel shall be desolate, that none shall pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Then shall they know that I am the LORD, when I have laid the land most desolate because of all their abominations which they have committed.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Also, you son of man, the children of your people still are talking against you by the walls and in the doors of the houses, and speak one to another, every one to his brother, saying, Come, I pray you, and hear what is the word that comes forth from the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they come to you as the people comes, and they sit before you as my people, and they hear your words, but they will not do them: for with their mouth they show much love, but their heart goes after their covetousness.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And, see, you are to them as a very lovely song of one that has a pleasant voice, and can play well on an instrument: for they hear your words, but they do them not.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And when this comes to pass, (see, it will come,) then shall they know that a prophet has been among them.</verse>
</chapter>