<chapter book="Ezekiel" number="37" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The hand of the LORD was on me, and carried me out in the spirit of the LORD, and set me down in the middle of the valley which was full of bones,</verse>
  <verse number="2">And caused me to pass by them round about: and, behold, there were very many in the open valley; and, see, they were very dry.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he said to me, Son of man, can these bones live? And I answered, O Lord GOD, you know.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Again he said to me, Prophesy on these bones, and say to them, O you dry bones, hear the word of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thus said the Lord GOD to these bones; Behold, I will cause breath to enter into you, and you shall live:</verse>
  <verse number="6">And I will lay sinews on you, and will bring up flesh on you, and cover you with skin, and put breath in you, and you shall live; and you shall know that I am the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So I prophesied as I was commanded: and as I prophesied, there was a noise, and behold a shaking, and the bones came together, bone to his bone.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And when I beheld, see, the sinews and the flesh came up on them, and the skin covered them above: but there was no breath in them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then said he to me, Prophesy to the wind, prophesy, son of man, and say to the wind, Thus said the Lord GOD; Come from the four winds, O breath, and breathe on these slain, that they may live.</verse>
  <verse number="10">So I prophesied as he commanded me, and the breath came into them, and they lived, and stood up on their feet, an exceeding great army.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Then he said to me, Son of man, these bones are the whole house of Israel: behold, they say, Our bones are dried, and our hope is lost: we are cut off for our parts.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Therefore prophesy and say to them, Thus said the Lord GOD; Behold, O my people, I will open your graves, and cause you to come up out of your graves, and bring you into the land of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And you shall know that I am the LORD, when I have opened your graves, O my people, and brought you up out of your graves,</verse>
  <verse number="14">And shall put my spirit in you, and you shall live, and I shall place you in your own land: then shall you know that I the LORD have spoken it, and performed it, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The word of the LORD came again to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="16">Moreover, you son of man, take you one stick, and write on it, For Judah, and for the children of Israel his companions: then take another stick, and write on it, For Joseph, the stick of Ephraim and for all the house of Israel his companions:</verse>
  <verse number="17">And join them one to another into one stick; and they shall become one in your hand.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And when the children of your people shall speak to you, saying, Will you not show us what you mean by these?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Say to them, Thus said the Lord GOD; Behold, I will take the stick of Joseph, which is in the hand of Ephraim, and the tribes of Israel his fellows, and will put them with him, even with the stick of Judah, and make them one stick, and they shall be one in my hand.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the sticks where on you write shall be in your hand before their eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And say to them, Thus said the Lord GOD; Behold, I will take the children of Israel from among the heathen, where they be gone, and will gather them on every side, and bring them into their own land:</verse>
  <verse number="22">And I will make them one nation in the land on the mountains of Israel; and one king shall be king to them all: and they shall be no more two nations, neither shall they be divided into two kingdoms any more at all.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Neither shall they defile themselves any more with their idols, nor with their detestable things, nor with any of their transgressions: but I will save them out of all their dwelling places, wherein they have sinned, and will cleanse them: so shall they be my people, and I will be their God.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And David my servant shall be king over them; and they all shall have one shepherd: they shall also walk in my judgments, and observe my statutes, and do them.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And they shall dwell in the land that I have given to Jacob my servant, wherein your fathers have dwelled; and they shall dwell therein, even they, and their children, and their children’s children for ever: and my servant David shall be their prince for ever.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Moreover I will make a covenant of peace with them; it shall be an everlasting covenant with them: and I will place them, and multiply them, and will set my sanctuary in the middle of them for ever more.</verse>
  <verse number="27">My tabernacle also shall be with them: yes, I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the heathen shall know that I the LORD do sanctify Israel, when my sanctuary shall be in the middle of them for ever more.</verse>
</chapter>