<chapter book="Proverbs" number="12" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Whoso loveth correction loveth knowledge; But he that hateth reproof is brutish.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A good man shall obtain favor of Jehovah; But a man of wicked devices will he condemn.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A man shall not be established by wickedness; But the root of the righteous shall not be moved.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A worthy woman is the crown of her husband; But she that maketh ashamed is as rottenness in his bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the righteous are just; But the counsels of the wicked are deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The words of the wicked are of lying in wait for blood; But the mouth of the upright shall deliver them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The wicked are overthrown, and are not; But the house of the righteous shall stand.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A man shall be commended according to his wisdom; But he that is of a perverse heart shall be despised.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Better is he that is lightly esteemed, and hath a servant, Than he that honoreth himself, and lacketh bread.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A righteous man regardeth the life of his beast; But the tender mercies of the wicked are cruel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He that tilleth his land shall have plenty of bread; But he that followeth after vain persons is void of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The wicked desireth the net of evil men; But the root of the righteous yieldeth fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In the transgression of the lips is a snare to the evil man; But the righteous shall come out of trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A man shall be satisfied with good by the fruit of his mouth; And the doings of a man’s hands shall be rendered unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The way of a fool is right in his own eyes; But he that is wise hearkeneth unto counsel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A fool’s vexation is presently known; But a prudent man concealeth shame.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that uttereth truth showeth forth righteousness; But a false witness, deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">There is that speaketh rashly like the piercings of a sword; But the tongue of the wise is health.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The lip of truth shall be established for ever; But a lying tongue is but for a moment.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Deceit is in the heart of them that devise evil; But to the counsellors of peace is joy.</verse>
  <verse number="21">There shall no mischief happen to the righteous; But the wicked shall be filled with evil.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Lying lips are an abomination to Jehovah; But they that deal truly are his delight.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A prudent man concealeth knowledge; But the heart of fools proclaimeth foolishness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The hand of the diligent shall bear rule; But the slothful shall be put under taskwork.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Heaviness in the heart of a man maketh it stoop; But a good word maketh it glad.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The righteous is a guide to his neighbor; But the way of the wicked causeth them to err.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The slothful man roasteth not that which he took in hunting; But the precious substance of men is to the diligent.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the way of righteousness is life; And in the pathway thereof there is no death.</verse>
</chapter>