<chapter book="Proverbs" number="17" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Better is a dry morsel, and quietness therewith, Than a house full of feasting with strife.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A servant that dealeth wisely shall have rule over a son that causeth shame, And shall have part in the inheritance among the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The refining pot is for silver, and the furnace for gold; But Jehovah trieth the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="4">An evil-doer giveth heed to wicked lips; And a liar giveth ear to a mischievous tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whoso mocketh the poor reproacheth his Maker; And he that is glad at calamity shall not be unpunished.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Children’s children are the crown of old men; And the glory of children are their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Excellent speech becometh not a fool; Much less do lying lips a prince.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A bribe is as a precious stone in the eyes of him that hath it; Whithersoever it turneth, it prospereth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He that covereth a transgression seeketh love; But he that harpeth on a matter separateth chief friends.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A rebuke entereth deeper into one that hath understanding Than a hundred stripes into a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="11">An evil man seeketh only rebellion; Therefore a cruel messenger shall be sent against him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let a bear robbed of her whelps meet a man, Rather than a fool in his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso rewardeth evil for good, Evil shall not depart from his house.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The beginning of strife is as when one letteth out water: Therefore leave off contention, before there is quarrelling.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He that justifieth the wicked, and he that condemneth the righteous, Both of them alike are an abomination to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Wherefore is there a price in the hand of a fool to buy wisdom, Seeing he hath no understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="17">A friend loveth at all times; And a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A man void of understanding striketh hands, And becometh surety in the presence of his neighbor.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He loveth transgression that loveth strife: He that raiseth high his gate seeketh destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He that hath a wayward heart findeth no good; And he that hath a perverse tongue falleth into mischief.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that begetteth a fool doeth it to his sorrow; And the father of a fool hath no joy.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A cheerful heart is a good medicine; But a broken spirit drieth up the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A wicked man receiveth a bribe out of the bosom, To pervert the ways of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Wisdom is before the face of him that hath understanding; But the eyes of a fool are in the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A foolish son is a grief to his father, And bitterness to her that bare him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Also to punish the righteous is not good, Nor to smite the noble for their uprightness.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He that spareth his words hath knowledge; And he that is of a cool spirit is a man of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Even a fool, when he holdeth his peace, is counted wise; When he shutteth his lips, he is esteemed as prudent.</verse>
</chapter>