<chapter book="Proverbs" number="21" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The king’s heart is in the hand of Jehovah as the watercourses: He turneth it whithersoever he will.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Every way of a man is right in his own eyes; But Jehovah weighteth the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To do righteousness and justice Is more acceptable to Jehovah than sacrifice.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A high look, and a proud heart, Even the lamp of the wicked, is sin.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the diligent tend only to plenteousness; But every one that is hasty hasteth only to want.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The getting of treasures by a lying tongue Is a vapor driven to and fro by them that seek death.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The violence of the wicked shall sweep them away, Because they refuse to do justice.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The way of him that is laden with guilt is exceeding crooked; But as for the pure, his work is right.</verse>
  <verse number="9">It is better to dwell in the corner of the housetop, Than with a contentious woman in a wide house.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The soul of the wicked desireth evil: His neighbor findeth no favor in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">When the scoffer is punished, the simple is made wise; And when the wise is instructed, he receiveth knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The righteous man considereth the house of the wicked, How the wicked are overthrown to their ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso stoppeth his ears at the cry of the poor, He also shall cry, but shall not be heard.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A gift in secret pacifieth anger; And a present in the bosom, strong wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It is joy to the righteous to do justice; But it is a destruction to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The man that wandereth out of the way of understanding Shall rest in the assembly of the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that loveth pleasure shall be a poor man: He that loveth wine and oil shall not be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The wicked is a ransom for the righteous; And the treacherous cometh in the stead of the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="19">It is better to dwell in a desert land, Than with a contentious and fretful woman.</verse>
  <verse number="20">There is precious treasure and oil in the dwelling of the wise; But a foolish man swalloweth it up.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that followeth after righteousness and kindness Findeth life, righteousness, and honor.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A wise man scaleth the city of the mighty, And bringeth down the strength of the confidence thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue Keepeth his soul from troubles.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The proud and haughty man, scoffer is his name; He worketh in the arrogance of pride.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The desire of the sluggard killeth him; For his hands refuse to labor.</verse>
  <verse number="26">There is that coveteth greedily all the day long; But the righteous giveth and withholdeth not.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sacrifice of the wicked is an abomination: How much more, when he bringeth it with a wicked mind!</verse>
  <verse number="28">A false witness shall perish; But the man that heareth shall speak so as to endure.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A wicked man hardeneth his face; But as for the upright, he establisheth his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="30">There is no wisdom nor understanding Nor counsel against Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The horse is prepared against the day of battle; But victory is of Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>