<chapter book="Proverbs" number="7" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, keep my words, And lay up my commandments with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Keep my commandments and live; And my law as the apple of thine eye.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Bind them upon thy fingers; Write them upon the tablet of thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Say unto wisdom, Thou art my sister; And call understanding thy kinswoman:</verse>
  <verse number="5">That they may keep thee from the strange woman, From the foreigner that flattereth with her words.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For at the window of my house I looked forth through my lattice;</verse>
  <verse number="7">And I beheld among the simple ones, I discerned among the youths, A young man void of understanding,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Passing through the street near her corner; And he went the way to her house,</verse>
  <verse number="9">In the twilight, in the evening of the day, In the middle of the night and in the darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And, behold, there met him a woman With the attire of a harlot, and wily of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="11">(She is clamorous and wilful; Her feet abide not in her house:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now she is in the streets, now in the broad places, And lieth in wait at every corner.)</verse>
  <verse number="13">So she caught him, and kissed him, And with an impudent face she said unto him:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Sacrifices of peace-offerings are with me; This day have I paid my vows.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore came I forth to meet thee, Diligently to seek thy face, and I have found thee.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I have spread my couch with carpets of tapestry, With striped cloths of the yarn of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I have perfumed my bed With myrrh, aloes, and cinnamon.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Come, let us take our fill of love until the morning; Let us solace ourselves with loves.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For the man is not at home; He is gone a long journey:</verse>
  <verse number="20">He hath taken a bag of money with him; He will come home at the full moon.</verse>
  <verse number="21">With her much fair speech she causeth him to yield; With the flattering of her lips she forceth him along.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He goeth after her straightway, As an ox goeth to the slaughter, Or as one in fetters to the correction of the fool;</verse>
  <verse number="23">Till an arrow strike through his liver; As a bird hasteth to the snare, And knoweth not that it is for his life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Now therefore, my sons, hearken unto me, And attend to the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let not thy heart decline to her ways; Go not astray in her paths.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For she hath cast down many wounded: Yea, all her slain are a mighty host.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Her house is the way to Sheol, Going down to the chambers of death.</verse>
</chapter>