<chapter book="Proverbs" number="8" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Doth not wisdom cry, And understanding put forth her voice?</verse>
  <verse number="2">On the top of high places by the way, Where the paths meet, she standeth;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Beside the gates, at the entry of the city, At the coming in at the doors, she crieth aloud:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Unto you, O men, I call; And my voice is to the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="5">O ye simple, understand prudence; And, ye fools, be of an understanding heart.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Hear, for I will speak excellent things; And the opening of my lips shall be right things.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For my mouth shall utter truth; And wickedness is an abomination to my lips.</verse>
  <verse number="8">All the words of my mouth are in righteousness; There is nothing crooked or perverse in them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They are all plain to him that understandeth, And right to them that find knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Receive my instruction, and not silver; And knowledge rather than choice gold.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For wisdom is better than rubies; And all the things that may be desired are not to be compared unto it.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I wisdom have made prudence my dwelling, And find out knowledge and discretion.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fear of Jehovah is to hate evil: Pride, and arrogancy, and the evil way, And the perverse mouth, do I hate.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Counsel is mine, and sound knowledge: I am understanding; I have might.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By me kings reign, And princes decree justice.</verse>
  <verse number="16">By me princes rule, And nobles, even all the judges of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I love them that love me; And those that seek me diligently shall find me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Riches and honor are with me; Yea, durable wealth and righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="19">My fruit is better than gold, yea, than fine gold; And my revenue than choice silver.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I walk in the way of righteousness, In the midst of the paths of justice;</verse>
  <verse number="21">That I may cause those that love me to inherit substance, And that I may fill their treasuries.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Jehovah possessed me in the beginning of his way, Before his works of old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">I was set up from everlasting, from the beginning, Before the earth was.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When there were no depths, I was brought forth, When there were no fountains abounding with water.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Before the mountains were settled, Before the hills was I brought forth;</verse>
  <verse number="26">While as yet he had not made the earth, nor the fields, Nor the beginning of the dust of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When he established the heavens, I was there: When he set a circle upon the face of the deep,</verse>
  <verse number="28">When he made firm the skies above, When the fountains of the deep became strong,</verse>
  <verse number="29">When he gave to the sea its bound, That the waters should not transgress his commandment, When he marked out the foundations of the earth;</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then I was by him, as a master workman; And I was daily his delight, Rejoicing always before him,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Rejoicing in his habitable earth; And my delight was with the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Now therefore, my sons, hearken unto me; For blessed are they that keep my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Hear instruction, and be wise, And refuse it not.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Blessed is the man that heareth me, Watching daily at my gates, Waiting at the posts of my doors.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For whoso findeth me findeth life, And shall obtain favor of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="36">But he that sinneth against me wrongeth his own soul: All they that hate me love death.</verse>
</chapter>