<chapter book="John" number="7" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then, after these things, Jesus was walking in Galilee. For he was not willing to walk in Judea, because the Jews were seeking to kill him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Now the feast day of the Jews, the Feast of Tabernacles, was near.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And his brothers said to him: “Move away from here and go into Judea, so that your disciples there may also see your works that you do.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Of course, no one does anything in secret, but he himself seeks to be in the public view. Since you do these things, manifest yourself to the world.”</verse>
  <verse number="5">For neither did his brothers believe in him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Therefore, Jesus said to them: “My time has not yet come; but your time is always at hand.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The world cannot hate you. But it hates me, because I offer testimony about it, that its works are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">You may go up to this feast day. But I am not going up to this feast day, because my time has not yet been fulfilled.”</verse>
  <verse number="9">When he had said these things, he himself remained in Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">But after his brothers went up, then he also went up to the feast day, not openly, but as if in secret.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore, the Jews were seeking him on the feast day, and they were saying, “Where is he?”</verse>
  <verse number="12">And there was much murmuring in the crowd concerning him. For certain ones were saying, “He is good.” But others were saying, “No, for he seduces the crowds.”</verse>
  <verse number="13">Yet no one was speaking openly about him, out of fear of the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then, about the middle of the feast, Jesus ascended into the temple, and he was teaching.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the Jews wondered, saying: “How does this one know letters, though he has not been taught?”</verse>
  <verse number="16">Jesus responded to them and said: “My doctrine is not of me, but of him who sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">If anyone has chosen to do his will, then he will realize, about the doctrine, whether it is from God, or whether I am speaking from myself.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Whoever speaks from himself seeks his own glory. But whoever seeks the glory of him who sent him, this one is true, and injustice is not in him.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Did not Moses give you the law? And yet not one among you keeps the law!</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why are you seeking to kill me?” The crowd responded and said: “You must have a demon. Who is seeking to kill you?”</verse>
  <verse number="21">Jesus responded and said to them: “One work have I done, and you all wonder.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For Moses gave you circumcision, (not that it is of Moses, but of the fathers) and on the Sabbath you circumcise a man.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If a man can receive circumcision on the Sabbath, so that the law of Moses may not be broken, why are you indignant toward me, because I have made a man whole on the Sabbath?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Do not judge according to appearances, but instead judge a just judgment.”</verse>
  <verse number="25">Therefore, some of those from Jerusalem said: “Is he not the one whom they are seeking to kill?</verse>
  <verse number="26">And behold, he is speaking openly, and they say nothing to him. Could the leaders have decided that it is true this one is the Christ?</verse>
  <verse number="27">But we know him and where he is from. And when the Christ has arrived, no one will know where he is from.”</verse>
  <verse number="28">Therefore, Jesus cried out in the temple, teaching and saying: “You know me, and you also know where I am from. And I have not arrived of myself, but he who sent me is true, and him you do not know.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I know him. For I am from him, and he has sent me.”</verse>
  <verse number="30">Therefore, they were seeking to apprehend him, and yet no one laid hands on him, because his hour had not yet come.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But many among the crowd believed in him, and they were saying, “When the Christ arrives, will he perform more signs than this man does?”</verse>
  <verse number="32">The Pharisees heard the crowd murmuring these things about him. And the leaders and the Pharisees sent attendants to apprehend him.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Therefore, Jesus said to them: “For a brief time, I am still with you, and then I am going to him who sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="34">You shall seek me, and you will not find me. And where I am, you are not able to go.”</verse>
  <verse number="35">And so the Jews said among themselves: “Where is this place to which he will go, such that we will not find him? Will he go to those dispersed among the Gentiles and teach the Gentiles?</verse>
  <verse number="36">What is this word that he spoke, ‘You will seek me and you will not find me; and where I am, you are not able to go?’ ”</verse>
  <verse number="37">Then, on the last great day of the feast, Jesus was standing and crying out, saying: “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink:</verse>
  <verse number="38">whoever believes in me, just as Scripture says, ‘From his chest shall flow rivers of living water.’ ”</verse>
  <verse number="39">Now he said this about the Spirit, which those who believe in him would soon be receiving. For the Spirit had not yet been given, because Jesus had not yet been glorified.</verse>
  <verse number="40">Therefore, some from that crowd, when they had heard these words of his, were saying, “This one truly is the Prophet.”</verse>
  <verse number="41">Others were saying, “He is the Christ.” Yet certain ones were saying: “Does the Christ come from Galilee?</verse>
  <verse number="42">Does Scripture not say that the Christ comes from the offspring of David and from Bethlehem, the town where David was?”</verse>
  <verse number="43">And so there arose a dissension among the multitude because of him.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Now certain ones among them wanted to apprehended him, but no one laid hands upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Therefore, the attendants went to the high priests and the Pharisees. And they said to them, “Why have you not brought him?”</verse>
  <verse number="46">The attendants responded, “Never has a man spoken like this man.”</verse>
  <verse number="47">And so the Pharisees answered them: “Have you also been seduced?</verse>
  <verse number="48">Have any of the leaders believed in him, or any of the Pharisees?</verse>
  <verse number="49">But this crowd, which does not know the law, they are accursed.”</verse>
  <verse number="50">Nicodemus, the one who came to him by night and who was one of them, said to them,</verse>
  <verse number="51">“Does our law judge a man, unless it has first heard him and has known what he has done?”</verse>
  <verse number="52">They responded and said to him: “Are you also a Galilean? Study the Scriptures, and see that a prophet does not arise from Galilee.”</verse>
  <verse number="53">And each one returned to his own house.</verse>
</chapter>