<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="22" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And David spoke unto the LORD the words of this song in the day that the LORD delivered him out of the hand of all his enemies, and out of the hand of Saul;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and he said: The LORD is my rock, and my fortress, and my deliverer;</verse>
  <verse number="3">The God who is my rock, in Him I take refuge; My shield, and my horn of salvation, my high tower, and my refuge; My saviour, Thou savest me from violence.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Praised, I cry, is the LORD, And I am saved from mine enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For the waves of Death compassed me. The floods of Belial assailed me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The cords of Sheol surrounded me; The snares of Death confronted me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In my distress I called upon the LORD, Yea, I called unto my God; And out of His temple He heard my voice, And my cry did enter into His ears.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then the earth did shake and quake, The foundations of heaven did tremble; They were shaken, because He was wroth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Smoke arose up in His nostrils, And fire out of His mouth did devour; Coals flamed forth from Him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He bowed the heavens also, and came down; And thick darkness was under His feet.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And He rode upon a cherub, and did fly; Yea, He was seen upon the wings of the wind.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And He made darkness pavilions round about Him, Gathering of waters, thick clouds of the skies.</verse>
  <verse number="13">At the brightness before Him Coals of fire flamed forth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The LORD thundered from heaven, And the Most High gave forth His voice.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And He sent out arrows, and scattered them; Lightning, and discomfited them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the channels of the sea appeared, The foundations of the world were laid bare By the rebuke of the LORD, At the blast of the breath of His nostrils.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He sent from on high, He took me; He drew me out of many waters;</verse>
  <verse number="18">He delivered me from mine enemy most strong, From them that hated me, for they were too mighty for me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">They confronted me in the day of my calamity; But the LORD was a stay unto me.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He brought me forth also into a large place; He delivered me, because He delighted in me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The LORD rewarded me according to my righteousness; According to the cleanness of my hands hath He recompensed me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For I have kept the ways of the LORD, And have not wickedly departed from my God.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For all His ordinances were before me; And as for His statutes, I did not depart from them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And I was single-hearted toward Him, And I kept myself from mine iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Therefore hath the LORD recompensed me according to my righteousness, According to my cleanness in His eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="26">With the merciful Thou dost show Thyself merciful, With the upright man Thou dost show Thyself upright,</verse>
  <verse number="27">With the pure Thou dost show Thyself pure; And with the crooked Thou dost show Thyself subtle.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the afflicted people Thou dost save; But Thine eyes are upon the haughty, that Thou mayest humble them.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For Thou art my lamp, O LORD; And the LORD doth lighten my darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="30">For by Thee I run upon a troop; By my God do I scale a wall.</verse>
  <verse number="31">As for God, His way is perfect; The word of the LORD is tried; He is a shield unto all them that take refuge in Him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For who is God, save the LORD? And who is a Rock, save our God?</verse>
  <verse number="33">The God who is my strong fortress, And who letteth my way go forth straight;</verse>
  <verse number="34">Who maketh my feet like hinds’, And setteth me upon my high places;</verse>
  <verse number="35">Who traineth my hands for war, So that mine arms do bend a bow of brass.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Thou hast also given me Thy shield of salvation; And Thy condescension hath made me great.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Thou hast enlarged my steps under me, And my feet have not slipped.</verse>
  <verse number="38">I have pursued mine enemies, and destroyed them; Neither did I turn back till they were consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And I have consumed them, and smitten them through, that they cannot arise; Yea, they are fallen under my feet.</verse>
  <verse number="40">For Thou hast girded me with strength unto the battle; Thou hast subdued under me those that rose up against me.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Thou hast also made mine enemies turn their backs unto me; Yea, them that hate me, that I might cut them off.</verse>
  <verse number="42">They looked, but there was none to save; Even unto the LORD, but He answered them not.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Then did I beat them small as the dust of the earth, I did stamp them as the mire of the streets, and did tread them down.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Thou also hast delivered me from the contentions of my people; Thou hast kept me to be the head of the nations; A people whom I have not known serve me.</verse>
  <verse number="45">The sons of the stranger dwindle away before me; As soon as they hear of me, they obey me.</verse>
  <verse number="46">The sons of the stranger fade away, And come halting out of their close places.</verse>
  <verse number="47">The LORD liveth, and blessed be my Rock; And exalted be the God, my Rock of salvation;</verse>
  <verse number="48">Even the God that executeth vengeance for me, And bringeth down peoples under me,</verse>
  <verse number="49">And that bringeth me forth from mine enemies; Yea, Thou liftest me up above them that rise up against me; Thou deliverest me from the violent man.</verse>
  <verse number="50">Therefore I will give thanks unto Thee, O LORD, among the nations, And will sing praises unto Thy name.</verse>
  <verse number="51">A tower of salvation is He to His king; And showeth mercy to His anointed, To David and to his seed, for evermore.</verse>
</chapter>