<chapter book="Philippians" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">If then [there be] any comfort in Christ, if any consolation of love, if any fellowship of [the] Spirit, if any bowels and compassions,</verse>
  <verse number="2">fulfil my joy, that ye may think the same thing, having the same love, joined in soul, thinking one thing;</verse>
  <verse number="3">[let] nothing [be] in the spirit of strife or vain glory, but, in lowliness of mind, each esteeming the other as more excellent than themselves;</verse>
  <verse number="4">regarding not each his own [qualities], but each those of others also.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For let this mind be in you which [was] also in Christ Jesus;</verse>
  <verse number="6">who, subsisting in the form of God, did not esteem it an object of rapine to be on an equality with God;</verse>
  <verse number="7">but emptied himself, taking a bondman’s form, taking his place in [the] likeness of men;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and having been found in figure as a man, humbled himself, becoming obedient even unto death, and [that the] death of [the] cross.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Wherefore also God highly exalted him, and granted him a name, that which is above every name,</verse>
  <verse number="10">that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, of heavenly and earthly and infernal [beings],</verse>
  <verse number="11">and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ [is] Lord to God [the] Father’s glory.</verse>
  <verse number="12">So that, my beloved, even as ye have always obeyed, not as in my presence only, but now much rather in my absence, work out your own salvation with fear and trembling,</verse>
  <verse number="13">for it is God who works in you both the willing and the working according to [his] good pleasure.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Do all things without murmurings and reasonings,</verse>
  <verse number="15">that ye may be harmless and simple, irreproachable children of God in the midst of a crooked and perverted generation; among whom ye appear as lights in [the] world,</verse>
  <verse number="16">holding forth [the] word of life, so as to be a boast for me in Christ’s day, that I have not run in vain nor laboured in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But if also I am poured out as a libation on the sacrifice and ministration of your faith, I rejoice, and rejoice in common with you all.</verse>
  <verse number="18">In like manner do ye also rejoice, and rejoice with me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But I hope in [the] Lord Jesus to send Timotheus to you shortly, that I also may be refreshed, knowing how ye get on.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I have no one like-minded who will care with genuine feeling how ye get on.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For all seek their own things, not the things of Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But ye know the proof of him, that, as a child a father, he has served with me in the work of the glad tidings.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Him therefore I hope to send immediately, as soon as I shall see how it goes with me:</verse>
  <verse number="24">but I trust in [the] Lord that I myself also shall soon come;</verse>
  <verse number="25">but I have thought it necessary to send to you Epaphroditus, my brother and fellow-workman and fellow-soldier, but your messenger and minister to my need,</verse>
  <verse number="26">since he had a longing desire after you all, and was distressed because ye had heard that he was sick;</verse>
  <verse number="27">for he was also sick close to death, but God had mercy on him, and not indeed on him alone, but also on me, that I might not have sorrow upon sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I have sent him therefore the more diligently, that seeing him ye might again rejoice, and that I might be the less sorrowful.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Receive him therefore in [the] Lord with all joy, and hold such in honour;</verse>
  <verse number="30">because for the sake of the work he drew near even to death, venturing his life that he might fill up what lacked in your ministration toward me.</verse>
</chapter>