<chapter book="Philippians" number="3" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For the rest, my brethren, rejoice in [the] Lord: to write the same things to you, to me [is] not irksome, and for you safe.</verse>
  <verse number="2">See to dogs, see to evil workmen, see to the concision.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For we are the circumcision, who worship by [the] Spirit of God, and boast in Christ Jesus, and do not trust in flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Though I have [my] trust even in flesh; if any other think to trust in flesh, I rather:</verse>
  <verse number="5">as to circumcision, [I received it] the eighth day; of [the] race of Israel, of [the] tribe of Benjamin, Hebrew of Hebrews; as to [the] law, a Pharisee;</verse>
  <verse number="6">as to zeal, persecuting the assembly; as to righteousness which [is] in [the] law, found blameless;</verse>
  <verse number="7">but what things were gain to me these I counted, on account of Christ, loss.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But surely I count also all things to be loss on account of the excellency of the knowledge of Christ Jesus my Lord, on account of whom I have suffered the loss of all, and count them to be filth, that I may gain Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and that I may be found in him, not having my righteousness, which [would be] on the principle of law, but that which is by faith of Christ, the righteousness which [is] of God through faith,</verse>
  <verse number="10">to know him, and the power of his resurrection, and the fellowship of his sufferings, being conformed to his death,</verse>
  <verse number="11">if any way I arrive at the resurrection from among [the] dead.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Not that I have already obtained [the prize], or am already perfected; but I pursue, if also I may get possession [of it], seeing that also I have been taken possession of by Christ [Jesus].</verse>
  <verse number="13">Brethren, I do not count to have got possession myself; but one thing—forgetting the things behind, and stretching out to the things before,</verse>
  <verse number="14">I pursue, [looking] towards [the] goal, for the prize of the calling on high of God in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="15">As many therefore as [are] perfect, let us be thus minded; and if ye are any otherwise minded, this also God shall reveal to you.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But whereto we have attained, [let us] walk in the same steps.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Be imitators [all] together of me, brethren, and fix your eyes on those walking thus as you have us for a model;</verse>
  <verse number="18">(for many walk of whom I have told you often, and now tell you even weeping, that they [are] the enemies of the cross of Christ:</verse>
  <verse number="19">whose end [is] destruction, whose god [is] the belly, and [their] glory in their shame, who mind earthly things:)</verse>
  <verse number="20">for our commonwealth has its existence in [the] heavens, from which also we await the Lord Jesus Christ [as] Saviour,</verse>
  <verse number="21">who shall transform our body of humiliation into conformity to his body of glory, according to the working of [the] power which he has even to subdue all things to himself.</verse>
</chapter>