<chapter book="Mark" number="2" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A few days later Jesus went back to Capernaum. And when the people heard that He was home,</verse>
  <verse number="2">they gathered in such large numbers that there was no more room, not even outside the door, as Jesus spoke the word to them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then a paralytic was brought to Him, carried by four men.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Since they were unable to get to Jesus through the crowd, they uncovered the roof above Him, made an opening, and lowered the paralytic on his mat.</verse>
  <verse number="5">When Jesus saw their faith, He said to the paralytic, “Son, your sins are forgiven.”</verse>
  <verse number="6">But some of the scribes were sitting there and thinking in their hearts,</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Why does this man speak like this? He is blaspheming! Who can forgive sins but God alone?”</verse>
  <verse number="8">At once Jesus knew in His spirit that they were thinking this way within themselves. “Why are you thinking these things in your hearts?” He asked.</verse>
  <verse number="9">“Which is easier: to say to a paralytic, ‘Your sins are forgiven,’ or to say, ‘Get up, pick up your mat, and walk’?</verse>
  <verse number="10">But so that you may know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgive sins...” He said to the paralytic,</verse>
  <verse number="11">“I tell you, get up, pick up your mat, and go home.”</verse>
  <verse number="12">And immediately the man got up, picked up his mat, and walked out in front of them all. As a result, they were all astounded and glorified God, saying, “We have never seen anything like this!”</verse>
  <verse number="13">Once again Jesus went out beside the sea. All the people came to Him, and He taught them there.</verse>
  <verse number="14">As He was walking along, He saw Levi son of Alphaeus sitting at the tax booth. “Follow Me,” He told him, and Levi got up and followed Him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">While Jesus was dining at Levi’s house, many tax collectors and sinners were eating with Him and His disciples—for there were many who followed Him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">When the scribes who were Pharisees saw Jesus eating with these people, they asked His disciples, “Why does He eat with tax collectors and sinners?”</verse>
  <verse number="17">On hearing this, Jesus told them, “It is not the healthy who need a doctor, but the sick. I have not come to call the righteous, but sinners.”</verse>
  <verse number="18">Now John’s disciples and the Pharisees were often fasting. So people came to Jesus and asked, “Why don’t Your disciples fast like John’s disciples and those of the Pharisees?”</verse>
  <verse number="19">Jesus replied, “How can the guests of the bridegroom fast while He is with them? As long as He is with them, they cannot fast.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But the time will come when the bridegroom will be taken from them; then they will fast.</verse>
  <verse number="21">No one sews a patch of unshrunk cloth on an old garment. If he does, the new piece will pull away from the old, and a worse tear will result.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And no one pours new wine into old wineskins. If he does, the wine will burst the skins, and both the wine and the wineskins will be ruined. Instead, new wine is poured into new wineskins.”</verse>
  <verse number="23">One Sabbath Jesus was passing through the grainfields, and His disciples began to pick the heads of grain as they walked along.</verse>
  <verse number="24">So the Pharisees said to Him, “Look, why are they doing what is unlawful on the Sabbath?”</verse>
  <verse number="25">Jesus replied, “Have you never read what David did when he and his companions were hungry and in need?</verse>
  <verse number="26">During the high priesthood of Abiathar, he entered the house of God and ate the consecrated bread, which was lawful only for the priests. And he gave some to his companions as well.”</verse>
  <verse number="27">Then Jesus declared, “The Sabbath was made for man, not man for the Sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Therefore, the Son of Man is Lord even of the Sabbath.”</verse>
</chapter>