<chapter book="Joel" number="2" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Blow you the trumpet in Zion, and sound an alarm in my holy mountain: let all the inhabitants of the land tremble: for the day of the LORD comes, for it is near at hand;</verse>
  <verse number="2">A day of darkness and of gloominess, a day of clouds and of thick darkness, as the morning spread on the mountains: a great people and a strong; there has not been ever the like, neither shall be any more after it, even to the years of many generations.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A fire devours before them; and behind them a flame burns: the land is as the garden of Eden before them, and behind them a desolate wilderness; yes, and nothing shall escape them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The appearance of them is as the appearance of horses; and as horsemen, so shall they run.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Like the noise of chariots on the tops of mountains shall they leap, like the noise of a flame of fire that devours the stubble, as a strong people set in battle array.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Before their face the people shall be much pained: all faces shall gather blackness.</verse>
  <verse number="7">They shall run like mighty men; they shall climb the wall like men of war; and they shall march every one on his ways, and they shall not break their ranks:</verse>
  <verse number="8">Neither shall one thrust another; they shall walk every one in his path: and when they fall on the sword, they shall not be wounded.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They shall run to and fro in the city; they shall run on the wall, they shall climb up on the houses; they shall enter in at the windows like a thief.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The earth shall quake before them; the heavens shall tremble: the sun and the moon shall be dark, and the stars shall withdraw their shining:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the LORD shall utter his voice before his army: for his camp is very great: for he is strong that executes his word: for the day of the LORD is great and very terrible; and who can abide it?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Therefore also now, said the LORD, turn you even to me with all your heart, and with fasting, and with weeping, and with mourning:</verse>
  <verse number="13">And rend your heart, and not your garments, and turn to the LORD your God: for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and of great kindness, and repents him of the evil.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who knows if he will return and repent, and leave a blessing behind him; even a meat offering and a drink offering to the LORD your God?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Blow the trumpet in Zion, sanctify a fast, call a solemn assembly:</verse>
  <verse number="16">Gather the people, sanctify the congregation, assemble the elders, gather the children, and those that suck the breasts: let the bridegroom go forth of his chamber, and the bride out of her closet.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let the priests, the ministers of the LORD, weep between the porch and the altar, and let them say, Spare your people, O LORD, and give not your heritage to reproach, that the heathen should rule over them: why should they say among the people, Where is their God?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then will the LORD be jealous for his land, and pity his people.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Yes, the LORD will answer and say to his people, Behold, I will send you corn, and wine, and oil, and you shall be satisfied therewith: and I will no more make you a reproach among the heathen:</verse>
  <verse number="20">But I will remove far off from you the northern army, and will drive him into a land barren and desolate, with his face toward the east sea, and his hinder part toward the utmost sea, and his stink shall come up, and his ill smell shall come up, because he has done great things.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Fear not, O land; be glad and rejoice: for the LORD will do great things.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Be not afraid, you beasts of the field: for the pastures of the wilderness do spring, for the tree bears her fruit, the fig tree and the vine do yield their strength.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Be glad then, you children of Zion, and rejoice in the LORD your God: for he has given you the former rain moderately, and he will cause to come down for you the rain, the former rain, and the latter rain in the first month.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the floors shall be full of wheat, and the vats shall overflow with wine and oil.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And I will restore to you the years that the locust has eaten, the cankerworm, and the caterpillar, and the palmerworm, my great army which I sent among you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And you shall eat in plenty, and be satisfied, and praise the name of the LORD your God, that has dealt wondrously with you: and my people shall never be ashamed.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And you shall know that I am in the middle of Israel, and that I am the LORD your God, and none else: and my people shall never be ashamed.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out my spirit on all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, your old men shall dream dreams, your young men shall see visions:</verse>
  <verse number="29">And also on the servants and on the handmaids in those days will I pour out my spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And I will show wonders in the heavens and in the earth, blood, and fire, and pillars of smoke.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The sun shall be turned into darkness, and the moon into blood, before the great and terrible day of the LORD come.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And it shall come to pass, that whoever shall call on the name of the LORD shall be delivered: for in mount Zion and in Jerusalem shall be deliverance, as the LORD has said, and in the remnant whom the LORD shall call.</verse>
</chapter>