<chapter book="John" number="14" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Let not your heart be troubled: believe in God, and believe in me.</verse>
  <verse number="2">In my Father’s house are many dwellings: and if not, I had said to you. I go to prepare a place for you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And if I go and prepare a place for you, again I come, and I will receive you to myself; that where I am, ye might be also.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And where I retire ye know, and the way ye know.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thomas says to him, Lord, we know not where thou retirest; and how can we know the way?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Jesus says to him, I am the way, and the truth, and the life: no one comes to the Father, except by me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">If ye had known me, ye had also known my Father: and from now ye know, and have seen him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Philip says to him, Lord, show us the Father, and it suffices us.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Jesus says, to him, So long time am I with you, and hast thou not known me, Philip? he having seen me has seen the Father; and how sayest thou, Show us the Father?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Believest thou not that I in the Father, and the Father is in me? the words which I speak to you, I speak not of myself: and the Father remaining in me does the works.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Believe ye me that I in the Father, and the Father in me: and if not, for these works believe me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Truly, truly, I say to you, He believing in me, the works which I do shall he do also; and greater than these shall he do; for I go to my Father.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And whatever ye ask in my name, this will I do, that the Father might be honoured by the Son.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If ye ask anything in my name, I will do.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If ye love me, keep my commands.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And I will ask the Father, and he will give you another Intercessor, that should remain with you forever;</verse>
  <verse number="17">The Spirit of truth; which the world cannot receive, for it sees it not, neither knows: and ye know it; for it shall remain with you, and shall be in you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I will not leave you orphans; I come to you.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Yet a little, and the world sees me no more; and ye see me: because I live, ye shall live also.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In that day shall ye know that I am in my Father, and ye in me, and I in you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He having my commands, and keeping them, the same is he loving me: and he loving me shall be loved by my Father, and I will love him, and manifest myself to him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Judas says to him, not Iscariot, Lord, how has it been that thou art about to make thyself manifest to us, and not to the world?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Jesus answered and said to him, If any one love me, he will keep my word: and my Father will love him, and we will come to him, and we will make our stay with him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He not loving me will not keep my words: and the word which ye hear is not of me, but of the Father having sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="25">These have I spoken to you, remaining with you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">But the Intercessor, the Holy Spirit, which the Father will send in my name, the same shall teach you all things, and he shall remind you of all things which I spake to you.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Peace I leave to you, my peace I give to you: not as the world gives, give I to you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be timid.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Ye have heard that I said to you, I retire, and I am coming to you. If ye loved me, ye would rejoice because I said, I go to the Father: for my Father is greater than I.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And now have I told you before it shall be, that when it should be, ye might believe.</verse>
  <verse number="30">I will no more speak much with you: for the ruler of this world comes, and has nothing in me.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But that the world might know that I love the Father, and as the Father commanded me, so I do. Arise ye, let us go thence.</verse>
</chapter>