<chapter book="John" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the third day was a marriage in Cana of Galilee; and the mother of Jesus was there:</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Jesus was also called, and his disciples, to the wedding.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And wine having failed, the mother of Jesus says to him, They have no wine.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Jesus says to her, What to me and thee, woman mine hour comes not yet.</verse>
  <verse number="5">His mother says to the servants, Whatever he says to you, do.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And six stone water buckets were placed there, according to the purification of the Jews, containing each two or three measures.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Jesus says to them, Fill the water buckets with water. And they filled them even up over.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he says to them, Draw now, and carry to the superintendent of the feast. And they carried.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And when the superintendent of the feast tasted the wine having been water, and knew not whence it is: (and the servants knew, having drawn the water;) the superintendent calls the bridegroom,</verse>
  <verse number="10">And says to him, Every man sets good wine first; and when they be intoxicated, then inferior: thou hast kept the good wine till now.</verse>
  <verse number="11">This beginning of signs did Jesus in Cana of Galilee, and manifested his glory; and his disciples believed on him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">After this he went down to Capernaum, he, and his mother, and his brethren, and his disciples: and they remained there not many days.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the pascha of the Jews was near, and Jesus went up to Jerusalem,</verse>
  <verse number="14">And found in the temple those selling oxen and sheep and doves, and money-changers sitting;</verse>
  <verse number="15">And having made a scourge of ropes, he cast all out of the temple, also sheep, and oxen; and poured out the small coin of money-changers, and overturned the tables;</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he said to those selling doves, Take away these things hence; make not the house of my Father a house of merchandise.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And his disciples remembered that it is written, The zeal of thine house has eaten me up.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then answered the Jews and said to him, What sign shewest thou, that thou doest these things?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Jesus answered and said to them, Loose this temple, and in three days will I raise it up.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Then said the Jews, In forty-six years was this temple built, and wilt thou raise it up in three days?</verse>
  <verse number="21">But he spake concerning the temple of his body.</verse>
  <verse number="22">When therefore he was risen from the dead, his disciples remembered that he said this to them; and they believed the writing, and the word which Jesus spake.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And when he was in Jerusalem at the pascha, in the festival, many believed in his name, beholding his signs which he did.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Jesus himself trusted not himself to them, for he knew all,</verse>
  <verse number="25">For also he had no need that any should testify concerning man: for he knew what was in man.</verse>
</chapter>