<chapter book="John" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After these was the festival of the Jews; and Jesus went up to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And there is in Jerusalem, at the sheep place a pool, in Hebrew called Bethesda, having five porches.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In these lay a great multitude of weak, blind, lame, withered, expecting the moving of the water.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For a messenger at a time went down into the pool, and troubled the water: then he having first stepped in after the troubling of the water became healthy, by whatever malady a long while since he was laid.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And a certain man was there, being in weakness thirty-eight years.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Jesus having seen the same lying down, and having known that it was already much time, says to him, Wilt thou be well?</verse>
  <verse number="7">He being sick answered him, Lord, I have no man, that, when the water was troubled, he might cast me into the pool: and in which I am coming, another steps down before me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Jesus says to him, Arise, take up thy couch, and walk.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And quickly the man was well, and he took up his couch, and walked: and the sabbath was in that day.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then said the Jews to him healed, It is the sabbath: it is not lawful for thee to take up thy couch.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He answered them, He having made me well, the same said to me, Lift up thy couch, and walk.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Then they asked him, Who is the man having said to thee, Lift up thy couch, and walk?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he healed knew not who he is: for Jesus escaped, a crowd being in the place.</verse>
  <verse number="14">After these, Jesus finds him in the temple, and he said to him, Behold, thou hast become well: sin no more, lest something worse be to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The man departed, and announced to the Jews that it is Jesus having made him well.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And therefore the Jews drove out Jesus, and sought to kill him, because he did these in the sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Jesus answered, My Father works till now, and I work.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For this therefore the Jews sought the more to kill him, for not only did he loose the sabbath, but also he called God his own Father, making himself equal to God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Then answered Jesus and said to them, Truly, truly, I say to you, The Son can of himself do nothing, except what he sees the Father doing: for whatever he should do, also these does the Son likewise.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For the Father loves the Son, and shows him all which himself does: and he will show him greater than these, that ye might wonder.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For as the Father arouses the dead, and makes alive; so also the Son makes alive whom he will.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For the Father judges no one, but he has given all judgment to the Son:</verse>
  <verse number="23">That all should honour the Son, as they honour the Father. He honouring not the Son, honours not the Father having sent him.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Truly, truly, I say to you, That he hearing my word, and believing him having sent me, has eternal life, and comes not into judgment; but has passed from death to life.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Truly, truly, I say to you, That the hour comes, and now is, when the dead shall hear the voice of the Son of God: and they hearing shall live.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For as the Father has life in himself, so also gave he to the Son to have life in himself;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And gave him authority also to do judgment, because he is the Son of man.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Wonder not at this: for the hour comes, in which all they in the tombs shall hear his voice, and shall go forth;</verse>
  <verse number="29">They having done good, to rising up of life; and they having done bad, to rising up of judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="30">I can do nothing of myself: as I hear, I judge: and my judgment is just; for I seek not my will, but the will of the Father having sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If I testify of myself, my testimony is not true.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Another is testifying of me, and I know that the testimony which he testifies of me is true.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Ye have sent to John, and he has testified to the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="34">But I receive not testimony from man: but these I say that ye might be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He was a burning and manifest light: and ye wished to rejoice for a time in his light.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And I have greater testimony than of John: for the works that the Father gave me that I might finish them, the same works that I do, testify of me, that the Father has sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And the Father having sent me, he has testified of me. Nor have ye at any time heard his voice, or seen his form.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And his word ye have not remaining in you: for whom he sent, him ye believe not.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Search the writings; for ye think in them to have eternal life: and these are they testifying of me.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And ye wish not to come to me, that ye might have life.</verse>
  <verse number="41">I receive not glory from man.</verse>
  <verse number="42">But I know you, that ye have not the love of God in you.</verse>
  <verse number="43">I have come in the name of my Father, and ye receive me not: if another should come in his own name, him will ye receive.</verse>
  <verse number="44">How can ye believe, receiving glory from one another, and ye seek not the glory that from God alone?</verse>
  <verse number="45">Think not that I shall accuse you to the Father: he accusing you is Moses, in whom ye have hoped.</verse>
  <verse number="46">For if ye had believed Moses, ye had believed me: for he himself wrote of me.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And if ye believe not his writings, how shall ye believe my words?</verse>
</chapter>