<chapter book="John" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jesus walked after these in Galilee: for he wished not to walk in Judea, because the Jews sought to kill him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the festival of the Jews was near, the Pitching of tents.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then said his brethren to him, Go away thence, and retire to Judea, that also thy disciples might see thy works which thou doest.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For none does any thing in secret, and seeks himself to be in freedom of speech. If thou do these, make thyself manifest to the world.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For neither believed his brethren in him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then says Jesus to them, My time is not yet present: and your time is always ready.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The world cannot hate you: but me it hates, for I testify of it, that its works are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Go ye up to this festival: I go not yet up to the festival; for my time has not yet been completed.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And speaking to them these things, he remained in Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And when his brethren went up, then he went up to the festival, not openly, but as in secret.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Then the Jews sought him in the festival, and said, Where is he.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And much murmuring was for him in the crowds: some truly said, That he is good: and others said, No; but he deceives the crowd.</verse>
  <verse number="13">However none spake of him with freedom of speech, for fear of the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And now the festival being in the midst, Jesus went up to the temple, and taught.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the Jews wondered, saying, How knows he letters, not having learned.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Jesus answered them, and said, My teaching is not mine, but his having sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">If any desire to do his will, he shall know of the teaching, whether it is of God, or I speak from myself.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He speaking from himself, seeks his own glory: but he seeking the glory of him having sent him, he is true, and no injustice is in him.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Has not Moses given you the law, and none of you does the law? Why seek ye to kill me?</verse>
  <verse number="20">The crowd answered and said, Thou hast a demon: who seeks to kill thee?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Jesus answered and said to them, I did one work, and ye all marvel for this.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Moses has given you circumcision; (not that it is of Moses, but of the fathers;) and in the sabbath ye circumcise a man.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If a man receive circumcision in the sabbath, that the law of Moses be not loosed; rage not at me, because I made a man wholly well on the Sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Judge not according to sight, but judge just judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Then said some of the Jerusalemites, Is not this he, whom they seek to kill?</verse>
  <verse number="26">And, behold, he speaks in freedom of speech, and they say nothing to him. Not at any time knew the rulers truly, that this is truly Christ?</verse>
  <verse number="27">But we know this whence he is: and Christ, when he should come, none knows whence he is.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then cried Jesus in the temple, teaching, and saying, And ye know me, and ye know whence I am: and I have not come of myself, but he having sent me is true, whom ye know not.</verse>
  <verse number="29">But I know him; for I am from him, and he sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then sought they to seize him: and none put the hand upon him, for his hour had not yet come.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And many of the crowd believed on him, and said, That Christ, when he should come, will he do more signs than these which he did?</verse>
  <verse number="32">The Pharisees heard the crowd murmuring these things of him; and the Pharisees and chief priests sent servants that they might seize him.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Then said Jesus to them, Yet a little time am I with you, and I retire to him having sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And ye shall seek me and shall not find: and where I am, ye cannot come.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Then said the Jews among themselves, Where is he about to go, that we shall not find him? is he not about to go to the dispersion of the Greeks, and teach the Greeks?</verse>
  <verse number="36">What is the word which he spake, Ye shall seek me, and shall not find: and where I am, ye cannot come?</verse>
  <verse number="37">In the last day, the great one of the festival, Jesus stood and cried, saying, If any thirst, let him come to me, and drink.</verse>
  <verse number="38">He believing in me, as said the writing, from his belly shall flow rivers of living waters.</verse>
  <verse number="39">(This spake he of the Spirit which they believing in him were about to receive: for the Holy Spirit was not yet; for Jesus was not yet honoured.)</verse>
  <verse number="40">Then many of the crowd, having heard the word, said, This is truly a prophet.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Others said, This is Christ: and others said, Yet Christ comes not out of Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Said not the writing, That of the seed of David, and from Bethlehem, the town where David was, Christ comes?</verse>
  <verse number="43">Then was there a division in the crowd on his account.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And some of them wished to seize him; but none put hands upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then came the servants to the chief priests and Pharisees; and they said to them, Why did ye not bring him.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And the servants answered, Never spake man as this man.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Then the Pharisees answered them, Have ye not also been deceived.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Have any of the rulers or of the Pharisees believed in him?</verse>
  <verse number="49">But the crowd, not knowing the law, are cursed.</verse>
  <verse number="50">Nicodemus says to them, (he having come to him by night, being one of them,)</verse>
  <verse number="51">Our law judges not a man, except it first hear from him, and know what he does.</verse>
  <verse number="52">They answered and said to him, And art thou not of Galilee? Search, and see: for a prophet has not risen out of Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And each man went to his house.</verse>
</chapter>