<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="22" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And David sang this song to the LORD on the day the LORD had delivered him from the hand of all his enemies and from the hand of Saul.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He said: “The LORD is my rock, my fortress, and my deliverer.</verse>
  <verse number="3">My God is my rock, in whom I take refuge, my shield, and the horn of my salvation. My stronghold, my refuge, and my Savior, You save me from violence.</verse>
  <verse number="4">I will call upon the LORD, who is worthy to be praised; so shall I be saved from my enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For the waves of death engulfed me; the torrents of chaos overwhelmed me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The cords of Sheol entangled me; the snares of death confronted me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In my distress I called upon the LORD; I cried out to my God. And from His temple He heard my voice, and my cry for help reached His ears.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then the earth shook and quaked; the foundations of the heavens trembled; they were shaken because He burned with anger.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Smoke rose from His nostrils, and consuming fire came from His mouth; glowing coals blazed forth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He parted the heavens and came down with dark clouds beneath His feet.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He mounted a cherub and flew; He soared on the wings of the wind.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He made darkness a canopy around Him, a gathering of water and thick clouds.</verse>
  <verse number="13">From the brightness of His presence coals of fire blazed forth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The LORD thundered from heaven; the voice of the Most High resounded.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He shot His arrows and scattered the foes; He hurled lightning and routed them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The channels of the sea appeared, and the foundations of the world were exposed at the rebuke of the LORD, at the blast of the breath of His nostrils.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He reached down from on high and took hold of me; He drew me out of deep waters.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He rescued me from my powerful enemy, from foes too mighty for me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">They confronted me in my day of calamity, but the LORD was my support.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He brought me out into the open; He rescued me because He delighted in me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The LORD has rewarded me according to my righteousness; He has repaid me according to the cleanness of my hands.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For I have kept the ways of the LORD and have not wickedly departed from my God.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For all His ordinances are before me; I have not disregarded His statutes.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And I have been blameless before Him and kept myself from iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="25">So the LORD has repaid me according to my righteousness, according to my cleanness in His sight.</verse>
  <verse number="26">To the faithful You show Yourself faithful, to the blameless You show Yourself blameless;</verse>
  <verse number="27">to the pure You show Yourself pure, but to the crooked You show Yourself shrewd.</verse>
  <verse number="28">You save an afflicted people, but Your eyes are on the haughty to bring them down.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For You, O LORD, are my lamp; the LORD lights up my darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="30">For in You I can charge an army; with my God I can scale a wall.</verse>
  <verse number="31">As for God, His way is perfect; the word of the LORD is flawless. He is a shield to all who take refuge in Him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For who is God besides the LORD? And who is the Rock except our God?</verse>
  <verse number="33">God is my strong fortress, and He makes my way clear.</verse>
  <verse number="34">He makes my feet like those of a deer and stations me upon the heights.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He trains my hands for battle; my arms can bend a bow of bronze.</verse>
  <verse number="36">You have given me Your shield of salvation, and Your gentleness exalts me.</verse>
  <verse number="37">You broaden the path beneath me so that my ankles do not give way.</verse>
  <verse number="38">I pursued my enemies and destroyed them; I did not turn back until they were consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="39">I devoured and crushed them so they could not rise; they have fallen under my feet.</verse>
  <verse number="40">You have armed me with strength for battle; You have subdued my foes beneath me.</verse>
  <verse number="41">You have made my enemies retreat before me; I destroyed those who hated me.</verse>
  <verse number="42">They looked, but there was no one to save them—to the LORD, but He did not answer.</verse>
  <verse number="43">I ground them as the dust of the earth; I crushed and trampled them like mud in the streets.</verse>
  <verse number="44">You have delivered me from the strife of my people; You have preserved me as the head of nations; a people I had not known shall serve me.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Foreigners cower before me; when they hear me, they obey me.</verse>
  <verse number="46">Foreigners lose heart and come trembling from their strongholds.</verse>
  <verse number="47">The LORD lives, and blessed be my Rock! And may God, the Rock of my salvation, be exalted—</verse>
  <verse number="48">the God who avenges me and brings down nations beneath me,</verse>
  <verse number="49">who frees me from my enemies. You exalt me above my foes; You rescue me from violent men.</verse>
  <verse number="50">Therefore I will praise You, O LORD, among the nations; I will sing praises to Your name.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Great salvation He brings to His king. He shows loving devotion to His anointed, to David and his descendants forever.”</verse>
</chapter>