<chapter book="Joshua" number="19" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the second lot went out, for the sons of Simeon by their families. And their inheritance was,</verse>
  <verse number="2">in the midst of the possession of the sons of Judah: Beersheba, and Sheba, and Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and Hazar-shual, Balah, and Ezem,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and Eltolad, Bethul, and Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Ziklag, and Beth-marcaboth, and Hazar-susah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Bethlebaoth, and Sharuhen: thirteen cities, and their villages;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ain and Enrimmon, and Ether and Ashan: four cities, and their villages;</verse>
  <verse number="8">all villages around these cities, as far as Baalath-beer, the high place facing the southern region. This is the inheritance of the sons of Simeon, according to their families,</verse>
  <verse number="9">within the possession and lot of the sons of Judah, which was greater. And for this reason, the sons of Simeon had a possession in the midst of their inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the third lot fell to the sons of Zebulun, by their families; and the limit of their possession was set as far as Sarid.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And it ascends from the sea and from Mareal. And it passes on to Dabbesheth, as far as the torrent, which is opposite Jokneam.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And it turns back from Sarid, to the east, to the end of Chisloth-tabor. And it goes out to Daberath, and it ascends opposite Japhia.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And from there, it continues to the eastern region of Gathhepher and Ethkazin. And goes out to Rimmon, Amthar, and Neah.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And it circles to the north at Hannathon. And its exits are at the Valley of Iphtahel;</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Kattath and Nahalal, and Shimron and Idalah, and Bethlehem: twelve cities, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This is the inheritance of the tribe of the sons of Zebulun, by their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The fourth lot went out to Issachar, by their families.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And his inheritance was: Jezreel, and Chesulloth, and Shunem,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and Hapharaim, and Shion, and Anaharath,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and Rabbith and Kishion, Ebez</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Remeth, and Engannim, and Enhaddah, and Bethpazzez.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And its limit reaches to Tabor and Shahazumah and Beth-shemesh; and its exits shall be at the Jordan: sixteen cities, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This is the possession of the sons of Issachar by their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the fifth lot fell to the tribe of the sons of Asher, by their families.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And their border was: Helkath, and Hali, and Beten, and Achshaph,</verse>
  <verse number="26">and Allammelech, and Amad, and Mishal. And it extends even to Carmel by the sea, and Shihor, and Libnath.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And it turns back toward the east at Bethdagon. And it continues on as far as Zebulun and the Valley of Iphtahel, toward the north, at Beth-emek and Neiel. And it goes out to the left of Cabul,</verse>
  <verse number="28">and to Ebron, and Rehob, and Hammon, and Kanah, as far as the great Sidon.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And it turns back at Ramah, even to the very fortified city of Tyre, and even to Hosah. And its exits shall be at the sea, from the lot of Achzib;</verse>
  <verse number="30">and Ummah, and Aphek, and Rehob: twenty-two cities, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="31">This is the possession of the sons of Asher, by their families, and the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The sixth lot fell to the sons of Naphtali, by their families.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And its border begins from Heleph and Elon, into Zaanannim, and Adami, which is Nekeb, and Jabneel, as far as Lakkum. And its exits are as far as the Jordan.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the border turns back to the west at Aznoth-tabor, and it goes out from there to Hukkok. And continues on to Zebulun, in the south, and to Asher, in the west, and to Judah, at the Jordan, toward the rising of the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the most fortified cities are Ziddim, Zer and Hammath, and Rakkath, and Chinnereth,</verse>
  <verse number="36">and Adamah and Ramah, Hazor</verse>
  <verse number="37">and Kedesh and Edrei, Enhazor</verse>
  <verse number="38">and Yiron and Migdalel, Horem and Bethanath, and Beth-shemesh: nineteen cities, and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="39">This is the possession of the tribe of the sons of Naphtali, by their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The seventh lot went out to the tribe of the sons of Dan, by their families.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And the border of their possession was Zorah, and Eshtaol, and Ir-shemesh, that is, the City of the Sun,</verse>
  <verse number="42">Sha-alabbin, and Aijalon, and Ithlah,</verse>
  <verse number="43">Elon, and Timnah, and Ekron,</verse>
  <verse number="44">Eltekeh, Gibbethon and Baalath,</verse>
  <verse number="45">and Jehud, and Bene and Berak, and Gath-Rimmon,</verse>
  <verse number="46">and Mejarkon and Rakkon, with a border that looks toward Joppa,</verse>
  <verse number="47">and there the last part is concluded. And the sons of Dan ascended and fought against Leshem, and they seized it. And they struck it with the mouth of the sword, and they possessed it, and they lived in it, calling it by the name of Leshem-Dan, according to the name of their father Dan.</verse>
  <verse number="48">This is the possession of the tribe of the sons of Dan, by their families, the cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And when he had completed dividing the land by lot to each one by their tribes, the sons of Israel gave a possession to Joshua, the son of Nun, in their midst,</verse>
  <verse number="50">in accord with the precept of the Lord, the city he requested, Timnath-Serah, on mount Ephraim. And he built up the city, and he lived in it.</verse>
  <verse number="51">These are the possessions which Eleazar, the priest, and Joshua, the son of Nun, and the leaders of the families and tribes of the sons of Israel divided by lot at Shiloh, before the Lord, at the door of the Tabernacle of the Testimony. And so did they divide the land.</verse>
</chapter>