<chapter book="Ezra" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these are the children of the province, that went up out of the captivity of those that had been carried away, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, and who came again to Jerusalem and to Judah, every one to his city,</verse>
  <verse number="2">who came with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Saraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, Baanah. The number of the men of the people of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="3">The children of Parosh, two thousand one hundred and seventy-two.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The children of Shephatiah, three hundred and seventy-two.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The children of Arah, seven hundred and seventy-five.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The children of Pahath-Moab, of the children of Jeshua [and] Joab, two thousand eight hundred and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The children of Elam, a thousand two hundred and fifty-four.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The children of Zattu, nine hundred and forty-five.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The children of Zaccai, seven hundred and sixty.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The children of Bani, six hundred and forty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The children of Bebai, six hundred and twenty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The children of Azgad, a thousand two hundred and twenty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The children of Adonikam, six hundred and sixty-six.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The children of Bigvai, two thousand and fifty-six.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The children of Adin, four hundred and fifty-four.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The children of Ater of [the family of] Hezekiah, ninety-eight.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The children of Bezai, three hundred and twenty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The children of Jorah, a hundred and twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The children of Hashum, two hundred and twenty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The children of Gibbar, ninety-five.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The children of Bethlehem, a hundred and twenty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The men of Netophah, fifty-six.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The men of Anathoth, a hundred and twenty-eight.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The children of Azmaveth, forty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The children of Kirjath-arim, Chephirah, and Beeroth, seven hundred and forty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The children of Ramah and Geba, six hundred and twenty-one.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The men of Michmas, a hundred and twenty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The men of Bethel and Ai, two hundred and twenty-three.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The children of Nebo, fifty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The children of Magbish, a hundred and fifty-six.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The children of the other Elam, a thousand two hundred and fifty-four.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The children of Harim, three hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The children of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, seven hundred and twenty-five.</verse>
  <verse number="34">The children of Jericho, three hundred and forty-five.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The children of Senaah, three thousand six hundred and thirty.</verse>
  <verse number="36">The priests: the children of Jedaiah, of the house of Jeshua, nine hundred and seventy-three.</verse>
  <verse number="37">The children of Immer, a thousand and fifty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="38">The children of Pashhur, a thousand two hundred and forty-seven.</verse>
  <verse number="39">The children of Harim, a thousand and seventeen.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The Levites: the children of Jeshua and of Kadmiel, of the children of Hodaviah, seventy-four.</verse>
  <verse number="41">The singers: the children of Asaph, a hundred and twenty-eight.</verse>
  <verse number="42">The children of the doorkeepers: the children of Shallum, the children of Ater, the children of Talmon, the children of Akkub, the children of Hatita, the children of Shobai, in all a hundred and thirty-nine.</verse>
  <verse number="43">The Nethinim: the children of Ziha, the children of Hasupha, the children of Tabbaoth,</verse>
  <verse number="44">the children of Keros, the children of Siaha, the children of Padon,</verse>
  <verse number="45">the children of Lebanah, the children of Hagabah, the children of Akkub,</verse>
  <verse number="46">the children of Hagab, the children of Shamlai, the children of Hanan,</verse>
  <verse number="47">the children of Giddel, the children of Gahar, the children of Reaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="48">the children of Rezin, the children of Nekoda, the children of Gazzam,</verse>
  <verse number="49">the children of Uzza, the children of Phaseah, the children of Besai,</verse>
  <verse number="50">the children of Asnah, the children of Meunim, the children of Nephusim,</verse>
  <verse number="51">the children of Bakbuk, the children of Hakupha, the children of Harhur,</verse>
  <verse number="52">the children of Bazluth, the children of Mehida, the children of Harsha,</verse>
  <verse number="53">the children of Barkos, the children of Sisera, the children of Thamah,</verse>
  <verse number="54">the children of Neziah, the children of Hatipha.</verse>
  <verse number="55">The children of Solomon’s servants: the children of Sotai, the children of Sophereth, the children of Peruda,</verse>
  <verse number="56">the children of Jaalah, the children of Darkon, the children of Giddel,</verse>
  <verse number="57">the children of Shephatiah, the children of Hattil, the children of Pochereth-Hazzebaim, the children of Ami.</verse>
  <verse number="58">All the Nethinim and the children of Solomon’s servants, three hundred and ninety-two.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And these are they that went up from Tel-melah, Tel-harsha, Cherub-Addan, Immer; but they could not shew their fathers’ house, nor their seed, whether they were of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="60">The children of Delaiah, the children of Tobijah, the children of Nekoda, six hundred and fifty-two.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And of the children of the priests: the children of Habaiah, the children of Koz, the children of Barzillai; who took a wife of the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and was called after their name.</verse>
  <verse number="62">These sought their genealogical register, but they were not found; therefore were they, as polluted, removed from the priesthood.</verse>
  <verse number="63">And the Tirshatha said to them that they should not eat of the most holy things, till there stood up a priest with Urim and with Thummim.</verse>
  <verse number="64">The whole congregation together was forty-two thousand three hundred and sixty,</verse>
  <verse number="65">besides their servants and their maids, of whom there were seven thousand three hundred and thirty-seven; and they had two hundred singing men and singing women.</verse>
  <verse number="66">Their horses were seven hundred and thirty-six; their mules two hundred and forty-five;</verse>
  <verse number="67">their camels four hundred and thirty-five; the asses six thousand seven hundred and twenty.</verse>
  <verse number="68">And some of the chief fathers, when they came to the house of Jehovah which is at Jerusalem, offered freely for the house of God to set it up in its place.</verse>
  <verse number="69">They gave after their ability to the treasure of the work sixty-one thousand darics of gold, and five thousand pounds of silver, and one hundred priests’ coats.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And the priests, and the Levites, and [some] of the people, and the singers, and the doorkeepers, and the Nethinim dwelt in their cities, and all Israel in their cities.</verse>
</chapter>