<chapter book="Job" number="11" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Zophar, the Naamathite, answered,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Shouldn’t the multitude of words be answered? Should a man full of talk be justified?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Should your boastings make men hold their peace? When you mock, shall no man make you ashamed?</verse>
  <verse number="4">For you say, ‘My doctrine is pure. I am clean in your eyes.’</verse>
  <verse number="5">But oh that God would speak, and open his lips against you,</verse>
  <verse number="6">that he would show you the secrets of wisdom! For true wisdom has two sides. Know therefore that God exacts of you less than your iniquity deserves.</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Can you fathom the mystery of God? Or can you probe the limits of the Almighty?</verse>
  <verse number="8">They are high as heaven. What can you do? They are deeper than Sheol. What can you know?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Its measure is longer than the earth, and broader than the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If he passes by, or confines, or convenes a court, then who can oppose him?</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he knows false men. He sees iniquity also, even though he doesn’t consider it.</verse>
  <verse number="12">An empty-headed man becomes wise when a man is born as a wild donkey’s colt.</verse>
  <verse number="13">“If you set your heart aright, stretch out your hands toward him.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If iniquity is in your hand, put it far away. Don’t let unrighteousness dwell in your tents.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Surely then you shall lift up your face without spot; Yes, you shall be steadfast, and shall not fear:</verse>
  <verse number="16">for you shall forget your misery. You shall remember it as waters that are passed away.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Life shall be clearer than the noonday. Though there is darkness, it shall be as the morning.</verse>
  <verse number="18">You shall be secure, because there is hope. Yes, you shall search, and shall take your rest in safety.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Also you shall lie down, and none shall make you afraid. Yes, many shall court your favor.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But the eyes of the wicked shall fail. They shall have no way to flee. Their hope shall be the giving up of the spirit.”</verse>
</chapter>