<chapter book="Job" number="16" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“I have heard many such things. You are all miserable comforters!</verse>
  <verse number="3">Shall vain words have an end? Or what provokes you that you answer?</verse>
  <verse number="4">I also could speak as you do. If your soul were in my soul’s place, I could join words together against you, and shake my head at you,</verse>
  <verse number="5">but I would strengthen you with my mouth. The solace of my lips would relieve you.</verse>
  <verse number="6">“Though I speak, my grief is not subsided. Though I forbear, what am I eased?</verse>
  <verse number="7">But now, God, you have surely worn me out. You have made desolate all my company.</verse>
  <verse number="8">You have shriveled me up. This is a witness against me. My leanness rises up against me. It testifies to my face.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He has torn me in his wrath, and persecuted me. He has gnashed on me with his teeth. My adversary sharpens his eyes on me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They have gaped on me with their mouth. They have struck me on the cheek reproachfully. They gather themselves together against me.</verse>
  <verse number="11">God delivers me to the ungodly, and casts me into the hands of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I was at ease, and he broke me apart. Yes, he has taken me by the neck, and dashed me to pieces. He has also set me up for his target.</verse>
  <verse number="13">His archers surround me. He splits my kidneys apart, and does not spare. He pours out my gall on the ground.</verse>
  <verse number="14">He breaks me with breach on breach. He runs on me like a giant.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I have sewed sackcloth on my skin, and have thrust my horn in the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My face is red with weeping. Deep darkness is on my eyelids.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Although there is no violence in my hands, and my prayer is pure.</verse>
  <verse number="18">“Earth, don’t cover my blood. Let my cry have no place to rest.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Even now, behold, my witness is in heaven. He who vouches for me is on high.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My friends scoff at me. My eyes pour out tears to God,</verse>
  <verse number="21">that he would maintain the right of a man with God, of a son of man with his neighbor!</verse>
  <verse number="22">For when a few years have come, I shall go the way of no return.</verse>
</chapter>