<chapter book="Job" number="21" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Listen diligently to my speech. Let this be your consolation.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Allow me, and I also will speak; After I have spoken, mock on.</verse>
  <verse number="4">As for me, is my complaint to man? Why shouldn’t I be impatient?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Look at me, and be astonished. Lay your hand on your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">When I remember, I am troubled. Horror takes hold of my flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Why do the wicked live, become old, yes, and grow mighty in power?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Their child is established with them in their sight, their offspring before their eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Their houses are safe from fear, neither is the rod of God upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Their bulls breed without fail. Their cows calve, and don’t miscarry.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They send forth their little ones like a flock. Their children dance.</verse>
  <verse number="12">They sing to the tambourine and harp, and rejoice at the sound of the pipe.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They spend their days in prosperity. In an instant they go down to Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They tell God, ‘Depart from us, for we don’t want to know about your ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">What is the Almighty, that we should serve him? What profit should we have, if we pray to him?’</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, their prosperity is not in their hand. The counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">“How often is it that the lamp of the wicked is put out, that their calamity comes on them, that God distributes sorrows in his anger?</verse>
  <verse number="18">How often is it that they are as stubble before the wind, as chaff that the storm carries away?</verse>
  <verse number="19">You say, ‘God lays up his iniquity for his children.’ Let him recompense it to himself, that he may know it.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Let his own eyes see his destruction. Let him drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For what does he care for his house after him, when the number of his months is cut off?</verse>
  <verse number="22">“Shall any teach God knowledge, since he judges those who are high?</verse>
  <verse number="23">One dies in his full strength, being wholly at ease and quiet.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His pails are full of milk. The marrow of his bones is moistened.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Another dies in bitterness of soul, and never tastes of good.</verse>
  <verse number="26">They lie down alike in the dust. The worm covers them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">“Behold, I know your thoughts, the devices with which you would wrong me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For you say, ‘Where is the house of the prince? Where is the tent in which the wicked lived?’</verse>
  <verse number="29">Haven’t you asked wayfaring men? Don’t you know their evidences,</verse>
  <verse number="30">that the evil man is reserved to the day of calamity, That they are led forth to the day of wrath?</verse>
  <verse number="31">Who shall declare his way to his face? Who shall repay him what he has done?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Yet he will be borne to the grave. Men shall keep watch over the tomb.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The clods of the valley shall be sweet to him. All men shall draw after him, as there were innumerable before him.</verse>
  <verse number="34">So how can you comfort me with nonsense, because in your answers there remains only falsehood?”</verse>
</chapter>