<chapter book="Job" number="27" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Job again took up his parable, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“As God lives, who has taken away my right, the Almighty, who has made my soul bitter.</verse>
  <verse number="3">(For the length of my life is still in me, and the spirit of God is in my nostrils);</verse>
  <verse number="4">surely my lips shall not speak unrighteousness, neither shall my tongue utter deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Far be it from me that I should justify you. Until I die I will not put away my integrity from me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I hold fast to my righteousness, and will not let it go. My heart shall not reproach me so long as I live.</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Let my enemy be as the wicked. Let him who rises up against me be as the unrighteous.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For what is the hope of the godless, when he is cut off, when God takes away his life?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Will God hear his cry when trouble comes on him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Will he delight himself in the Almighty, and call on God at all times?</verse>
  <verse number="11">I will teach you about the hand of God. That which is with the Almighty will I not conceal.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Behold, all of you have seen it yourselves; why then have you become altogether vain?</verse>
  <verse number="13">“This is the portion of a wicked man with God, the heritage of oppressors, which they receive from the Almighty.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If his children are multiplied, it is for the sword. His offspring shall not be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Those who remain of him shall be buried in death. His widows shall make no lamentation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Though he heap up silver as the dust, and prepare clothing as the clay;</verse>
  <verse number="17">he may prepare it, but the just shall put it on, and the innocent shall divide the silver.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He builds his house as the moth, as a booth which the watchman makes.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He lies down rich, but he shall not do so again. He opens his eyes, and he is not.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Terrors overtake him like waters. A storm steals him away in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The east wind carries him away, and he departs. It sweeps him out of his place.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For it hurls at him, and does not spare, as he flees away from his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Men shall clap their hands at him, and shall hiss him out of his place.</verse>
</chapter>