<chapter book="Job" number="37" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“Yes, at this my heart trembles, and is moved out of its place.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear, oh, hear the noise of his voice, the sound that goes out of his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He sends it forth under the whole sky, and his lightning to the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">After it a voice roars. He thunders with the voice of his majesty. He doesn’t hold back anything when his voice is heard.</verse>
  <verse number="5">God thunders marvelously with his voice. He does great things, which we can’t comprehend.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For he says to the snow, ‘Fall on the earth;’ likewise to the shower of rain, and to the showers of his mighty rain.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He seals up the hand of every man, that all men whom he has made may know it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then the animals take cover, and remain in their dens.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Out of its room comes the storm, and cold out of the north.</verse>
  <verse number="10">By the breath of God, ice is given, and the breadth of the waters is frozen.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Yes, he loads the thick cloud with moisture. He spreads abroad the cloud of his lightning.</verse>
  <verse number="12">It is turned around by his guidance, that they may do whatever he commands them on the surface of the habitable world,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whether it is for correction, or for his land, or for loving kindness, that he causes it to come.</verse>
  <verse number="14">“Listen to this, Job. Stand still, and consider the wondrous works of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Do you know how God controls them, and causes the lightning of his cloud to shine?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Do you know the workings of the clouds, the wondrous works of him who is perfect in knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="17">You whose clothing is warm, when the earth is still by reason of the south wind?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Can you, with him, spread out the sky, which is strong as a cast metal mirror?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Teach us what we shall tell him, for we can’t make our case by reason of darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Shall it be told him that I would speak? Or should a man wish that he were swallowed up?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Now men don’t see the light which is bright in the skies, but the wind passes, and clears them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Out of the north comes golden splendor. With God is awesome majesty.</verse>
  <verse number="23">We can’t reach the Almighty. He is exalted in power. In justice and great righteousness, he will not oppress.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Therefore men revere him. He doesn’t regard any who are wise of heart.”</verse>
</chapter>