<chapter book="Job" number="38" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Yahweh answered Job out of the whirlwind,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“Who is this who darkens counsel by words without knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Brace yourself like a man, for I will question you, then you answer me!</verse>
  <verse number="4">“Where were you when I laid the foundations of the earth? Declare, if you have understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who determined its measures, if you know? Or who stretched the line on it?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whereupon were its foundations fastened? Or who laid its cornerstone,</verse>
  <verse number="7">when the morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
  <verse number="8">“Or who shut up the sea with doors, when it broke forth from the womb,</verse>
  <verse number="9">when I made clouds its garment, and wrapped it in thick darkness,</verse>
  <verse number="10">marked out for it my bound, set bars and doors,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and said, ‘Here you may come, but no further. Here your proud waves shall be stayed?’</verse>
  <verse number="12">“Have you commanded the morning in your days, and caused the dawn to know its place;</verse>
  <verse number="13">that it might take hold of the ends of the earth, and shake the wicked out of it?</verse>
  <verse number="14">It is changed as clay under the seal, and stands forth as a garment.</verse>
  <verse number="15">From the wicked, their light is withheld. The high arm is broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">“Have you entered into the springs of the sea? Or have you walked in the recesses of the deep?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Have the gates of death been revealed to you? Or have you seen the gates of the shadow of death?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Have you comprehended the earth in its breadth? Declare, if you know it all.</verse>
  <verse number="19">“What is the way to the dwelling of light? As for darkness, where is its place,</verse>
  <verse number="20">that you should take it to its bound, that you should discern the paths to its house?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Surely you know, for you were born then, and the number of your days is great!</verse>
  <verse number="22">Have you entered the treasuries of the snow, or have you seen the treasures of the hail,</verse>
  <verse number="23">which I have reserved against the time of trouble, against the day of battle and war?</verse>
  <verse number="24">By what way is the lightning distributed, or the east wind scattered on the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who has cut a channel for the flood water, or the path for the thunderstorm;</verse>
  <verse number="26">To cause it to rain on a land where no man is; on the wilderness, in which there is no man;</verse>
  <verse number="27">to satisfy the waste and desolate ground, to cause the tender grass to spring forth?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Does the rain have a father? Or who fathers the drops of dew?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Out of whose womb came the ice? The gray frost of the sky, who has given birth to it?</verse>
  <verse number="30">The waters become hard like stone, when the surface of the deep is frozen.</verse>
  <verse number="31">“Can you bind the cluster of the Pleiades, or loosen the cords of Orion?</verse>
  <verse number="32">Can you lead forth the constellations in their season? Or can you guide the Bear with her cubs?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Do you know the laws of the heavens? Can you establish its dominion over the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="34">“Can you lift up your voice to the clouds, That abundance of waters may cover you?</verse>
  <verse number="35">Can you send forth lightnings, that they may go? Do they report to you, ‘Here we are?’</verse>
  <verse number="36">Who has put wisdom in the inward parts? Or who has given understanding to the mind?</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who can number the clouds by wisdom? Or who can pour out the bottles of the sky,</verse>
  <verse number="38">when the dust runs into a mass, and the clods of earth stick together?</verse>
  <verse number="39">“Can you hunt the prey for the lioness, or satisfy the appetite of the young lions,</verse>
  <verse number="40">when they crouch in their dens, and lie in wait in the thicket?</verse>
  <verse number="41">Who provides for the raven his prey, when his young ones cry to God, and wander for lack of food?</verse>
</chapter>