<chapter book="Job" number="4" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Eliphaz the Temanite answered,</verse>
  <verse number="2">“If someone ventures to talk with you, will you be grieved? But who can withhold himself from speaking?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Behold, you have instructed many, you have strengthened the weak hands.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Your words have supported him who was falling, You have made firm the feeble knees.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But now it has come to you, and you faint. It touches you, and you are troubled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Isn’t your piety your confidence? Isn’t the integrity of your ways your hope?</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Remember, now, whoever perished, being innocent? Or where were the upright cut off?</verse>
  <verse number="8">According to what I have seen, those who plow iniquity, and sow trouble, reap the same.</verse>
  <verse number="9">By the breath of God they perish. By the blast of his anger are they consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The roaring of the lion, and the voice of the fierce lion, the teeth of the young lions, are broken.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The old lion perishes for lack of prey. The cubs of the lioness are scattered abroad.</verse>
  <verse number="12">“Now a thing was secretly brought to me. My ear received a whisper of it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In thoughts from the visions of the night, when deep sleep falls on men,</verse>
  <verse number="14">fear came on me, and trembling, which made all my bones shake.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Then a spirit passed before my face. The hair of my flesh stood up.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It stood still, but I couldn’t discern its appearance. A form was before my eyes. Silence, then I heard a voice, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="17">‘Shall mortal man be more just than God? Shall a man be more pure than his Maker?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Behold, he puts no trust in his servants. He charges his angels with error.</verse>
  <verse number="19">How much more, those who dwell in houses of clay, whose foundation is in the dust, who are crushed before the moth!</verse>
  <verse number="20">Between morning and evening they are destroyed. They perish forever without any regarding it.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Isn’t their tent cord plucked up within them? They die, and that without wisdom.’</verse>
</chapter>