<chapter book="Matthew" number="7" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">“Judge not, that you may not be judged;</verse>
  <verse number="2">for your own judgement will be dealt—and your own measure meted—to yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And why do you look at the splinter in your brother’s eye, and not notice the beam which is in your own eye?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Or how say to your brother, ‘Allow me to take the splinter out of your eye,’ while the beam is in your own eye?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Hypocrite, first take the beam out of your own eye, and then you will see clearly how to remove the splinter from your brother’s eye.</verse>
  <verse number="6">“Give not that which is holy to the dogs, nor throw your pearls to the swine; otherwise they will trample them under their feet and then turn and attack you.</verse>
  <verse number="7">“Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and the door will be opened to you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For it is always he who asks that receives, he who seeks that finds, and he who knocks that has the door opened to him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What man is there among you, who if his son shall ask him for bread will offer him a stone?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Or if the son shall ask him for a fish will offer him a snake?</verse>
  <verse number="11">If you then, imperfect as you are, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father in Heaven give good things to those who ask Him!</verse>
  <verse number="12">Everything, therefore, be it what it may, that you would have men do to you, do you also the same to them; for in this the Law and the Prophets are summed up.</verse>
  <verse number="13">“Enter by the narrow gate; for wide is the gate and broad the road which leads to ruin, and many there are who enter by it;</verse>
  <verse number="14">because narrow is the gate and contracted the road which leads to Life, and few are those who find it.</verse>
  <verse number="15">“Beware of the false teachers—men who come to you in sheep’s fleeces, but beneath that disguise they are ravenous wolves.</verse>
  <verse number="16">By their fruits you will easily recognize them. Are grapes gathered from thorns or figs from brambles?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Just so every good tree produces good fruit, but a poisonous tree produces bad fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A good tree cannot bear bad fruit, nor a poisonous tree good fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Every tree which does not yield good fruit is cut down and thrown aside for burning.</verse>
  <verse number="20">So by their fruits at any rate, you will easily recognize them.</verse>
  <verse number="21">“Not every one who says to me, ‘Master, Master,’ will enter the Kingdom of the Heavens, but only those who are obedient to my Father who is in Heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Many will say to me on that day, “’Master, Master, have we not prophesied in Thy name, and in Thy name expelled demons, and in Thy name performed many mighty works?’</verse>
  <verse number="23">“And then I will tell them plainly, “’I never knew you: begone from me, you doers of wickedness.’</verse>
  <verse number="24">“Every one who hears these my teachings and acts upon them will be found to resemble a wise man who builds his house upon rock;</verse>
  <verse number="25">and the heavy rain falls, the swollen torrents come, and the winds blow and beat against the house; yet it does not fall, for its foundation is on rock.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And every one who hears these my teachings and does not act upon them will be found to resemble a fool who builds his house upon sand.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The heavy rain descends, the swollen torrents come, and the winds blow and burst upon the house, and it falls; and disastrous is the fall.”</verse>
  <verse number="28">When Jesus had concluded this discourse, the crowds were filled with amazement at His teaching,</verse>
  <verse number="29">for He had been teaching them as one who had authority, and not as their Scribes taught.</verse>
</chapter>