<chapter book="Romans" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, servant of Jesus Christ, called sent, separated to the good news of God,</verse>
  <verse number="2">(Which he before promised by his prophets in the holy writings,)</verse>
  <verse number="3">Concerning his Son born of the seed of David according to the flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Determined the Son of God in power, according to the spirit of holiness, by the rising up of the dead of Jesus Christ our Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="5">By whom we received grace and sending forth, to the obedience of faith in all nations for his name:</verse>
  <verse number="6">In whom are ye also, the called of Jesus Christ:</verse>
  <verse number="7">To all being in Rome, beloved of God, called holy: Grace to you and peace from God our Father, and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="8">First, I return thanks to my God by Jesus Christ for you all, that your faith is announced in the whole world.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For my witness is God, whom I serve in my spirit in the good news of his Son, so that continually I make mention of you, always supplicating in my prayers;</verse>
  <verse number="10">If in any way I shall be prospered on my way in the will of God to come to you.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For I long to see you, That I might impart to you some spiritual grace, in order for you to be firm;</verse>
  <verse number="12">And this is, to be comforted together in you by the faith in one another both of you and of me.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I would not ye should be ignorant, brethren, that many times I proposed to come to you, (and I was hindered till this time,) that I might have some fruit also in you, and in the rest of the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Both to Greeks, and foreigners; both to wise and unwise, I am debtor.</verse>
  <verse number="15">So that for my part being zealous, also to you that in Rome, to announce the good news.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For I am not ashamed of the good news of Christ: for it is the power of God to salvation to all believing; both to the Jew first, and the Greek.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the justice of God in it is revealed from faith to faith: as has been written, And the just shall live by faith.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the wrath of God is revealed from heaven upon all profanation and injustice of men, of those detaining the truth in injustice;</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wherefore that known of God is manifest in them; for God manifested to them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For the invisible things of him from the creation of the world, being understood by things made, are inspected, truly both his eternal power and divinity; so that they are inexcusable:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Wherefore having known God, not as God did they honour or return thanks; but were rendered vain in their conversations, and their heart without understanding was darkened.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Declaring themselves to be wise, they were fools,</verse>
  <verse number="23">And they changed the glory of the incorruptible God into the likeness of an image of corruptible man, and of flying things, and of creeping things, and of quadrupeds.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Wherefore God delivered them in the eager desire of their hearts to uncleanness, to dishonour their bodies in themselves:</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who changed the truth of God into a falsehood, and reverenced and served the creation above him creating, who is praised forever. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Therefore God delivered them to the suffering of ignominy: for also their females changed the natural use into that against generation:</verse>
  <verse number="27">Likewise also males, leaving the natural use of the female, were set on fire in their longing for one another; males with males working deformity, and the retribution which was needed receiving in themselves for their erring.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And as they chose not to have God in knowledge, God delivered them to an adulterated purpose, to do things not fitting;</verse>
  <verse number="29">Having been filled with all injustice, fornication, wickedness, covetousness, badness; full of envy, slaughter, strife, deceit, malignity,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Whisperers, slanderers, odious to God, abusers of power, proud, tumultuous, inventors of injuries, disobedient to parents,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Destitute of understanding, unsteady, devoid of natural affection, implacable, merciless:</verse>
  <verse number="32">Who knowing the justice of God, that they doing such things are worthy of death, not only do them, but also approve those doing.</verse>
</chapter>