<chapter book="Romans" number="16" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I place with you Phebe our sister, being servant of the church in Cenchrea:</verse>
  <verse number="2">That ye receive her in the Lord, worthy of the holy ones, and encourage her in whatever thing she have need of you: for she also has been the rule of many, and of myself.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Embrace Priscilla and Aquila my helpers in Christ Jesus:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who for my soul have laid down their own necks: to whom not only I give thanks, but also all the churches of the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the church in their house. Embrace my beloved Epenetus, who is the first fruits of Achaia to Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Embrace Mary, who wearied for us.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Embrace Andronicus and Junia, my kinsmen, and my fellowprisoners, who are distinguished among the sent, who also have been in Christ before me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Embrace ye Amplias my beloved in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Embrace Urban, our helper in Christ, and Stachys my beloved.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Embrace Apelles acceptable in Christ. Embrace them of Aristobulus.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Embrace Herodion my kinsman. Embrace them of Narcissus, them being in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Embrace Tryphen a and Tryphosa, wearied in the Lord. Embrace Persis the beloved, who was much wearied in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Embrace Rufus chosen in the Lord, and his mother and mine.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Embrace Asyncritus, Phlegon, Hermas, Patrobas, Hermes, and the brethren with them.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Embrace Philologus, and Julia, Nereus, and his sister, and Olympas, and all the holy ones with them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Embrace one another with a holy kiss. The churches of Christ embrace you.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I beseech you, brethren, to observe narrowly them having made divisions and scandals against the teaching which ye learned; and bend away from them.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For such serve not our Lord Jesus Christ, but their own belly; and by specious language and praise completely deceive the hearts of the innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For your obedience has come to all. Therefore I rejoice for you: and I wish you truly to be wise to good, and pure to evil.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the God of peace will rub together Satan under your feet swiftly. The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ with you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Timotheus my helper, and Lucius, and Jason, and Sosipater, my kinsmen, embrace you.</verse>
  <verse number="22">I Tertius embrace you, having written the epistle in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Gains my guest, and of the whole church, embraces you. Erastus steward of the city embraces you, and Quartus the brother.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ with you all. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And to him being able to support you according to my good news, and the proclamation of Jesus Christ, according to the revelation of the mystery kept silent from eternal times,</verse>
  <verse number="26">And now made manifest, also by the prophetic writings according to the command of the eternal God, for the obedience of faith made known to all nations:</verse>
  <verse number="27">To the only wise God, by Jesus Christ, to whom glory forever. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>