<chapter book="Romans" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">What then shall we say Abraham our father to have found, according to the flesh?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For if Abraham was justified by works, he has boasting; but not toward God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For what says the writing? And Abraham believed God, and it was reckoned to him for justice.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And to him working, the reward is not reckoned according to favor, but according to debt.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And to him not working, and believing upon him justifying the impious, his faith is reckoned for justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">As also David speaks the happiness of the man, to whom God reckons justice without works,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Happy they whose iniquities were remitted, and whose sins were covered.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A happy man to whom the Lord should not reckon sin.</verse>
  <verse number="9">This happiness then upon circumcision, or upon uncircumcision? for we say that faith was reckoned to Abraham for justice.</verse>
  <verse number="10">How then was it reckoned? to him being in circumcision, or in uncircumcision? Not in circumcision, but in uncircumcision.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he received the sign of circumcision, a seal of the justice of the faith which in uncircumcision: for him to be father of all believing through uncircumcision; for justice also to be reckoned to them:</verse>
  <verse number="12">And father of circumcision to them not of circumcision only, but also to them, walking in order in the tracks of the uncircumcision, of the faith of our father Abraham.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For not by the law, the promise to Abraham, or to his seed, for him to be heir of the world, but by the justice of faith.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For if they of the law, heirs, faith was made void, and the promise left inactive:</verse>
  <verse number="15">For the law works wrath: for where is no law, no transgression.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Therefore of faith, that according to grace; the promise to be firm to all the seed; not to that of the law only, but also to that of the faith of Abraham; who is father of us all,</verse>
  <verse number="17">(As it has been written, That have set thee father of many nations,) over against him who believed God, making alive the dead, and calling things not being as being.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Who against hope believed upon hope, for him to become father of many nations, according to that said, So shall thy seed be.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And not having been weak in faith, he observed not his own body already having been dead, being about a hundred years, and the death of Sarah’s womb:</verse>
  <verse number="20">And for the promise of God he was not separated by unbelief; but was strengthened in faith, having given glory to God;</verse>
  <verse number="21">And made perfectly certain that, what was promised, he is able to do.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And therefore it was reckoned to him for justice.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And it was not written for him alone, that it was reckoned to him;</verse>
  <verse number="24">But also for us, to whom it is about to be reckoned, to them believing upon him having raised up Jesus our Lord from the dead;</verse>
  <verse number="25">Who was delivered up for our faults, and raised up for our justification.</verse>
</chapter>