<chapter book="Romans" number="9" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I Speak truth in Christ, I lie not, my consciousness bearing witness to me in the Holy Spirit,</verse>
  <verse number="2">That there is great grief to me and continued pain in my heart.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For I myself was praying to be anathema from Christ for my brethren, my kinsmen according to the flesh:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who are Israelites; whose the adoption as a son, and the glory, and covenants, and legislation, and divine worship, and solemn promises;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whose the fathers, and from whom Christ according to the flesh, who being God over all, praised forever. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And not as that the word of God has fallen through. For not they all of Israel, they which of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Neither that the seed of Abraham, are all children: but, In Isaac shall the seed be called to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">That is, The children of the flesh, these not the children of God: but the children of the solemn promise are reckoned for seed.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For this the word of solemn promise, According to this time will I come, and there shall be a son to Sarah.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And not only; but also Rebecca, having coition of one, Isaac our father;</verse>
  <verse number="11">(For not yet born, neither having done any good or evil, that according to choice the purpose of God might remain, not of works, but of him calling;)</verse>
  <verse number="12">It was said to her, That the greater shall serve the less.</verse>
  <verse number="13">As has been written, Jacob have I loved, and Esau have I hated.</verse>
  <verse number="14">What then shall we say is injustice with God? It may not be.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I will commiserate whomsoever I commiserate, and I will have compassion upon whomsoever I have compassion.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Surely then, not of him willing, nor of him running, but of God commiserating.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the writing says to Pharaoh, That for this same have I raised thee up, so that I might show in thee my power, and so that my name might be announced in all the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Surely then, whom he will he commiserates, and whom he will he hardens.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou wilt then say to me, Why does he yet blame For who has withstood his will?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely, O man, who art thou replying against God? Shall the formation say to him having formed, Why hast thou made me so.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Or has not the potter power over the clay, of the same mixture truly to make one vessel for honour, and one for dishonour.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And if God, willing anger to be shown, and his power to be made known, endured in much long suffering the vessels of anger put in proper order for destruction:</verse>
  <verse number="23">And that he might make known the riches of his glory upon the vessels of mercy, which he before prepared for glory.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Whom he also called us, not only from the Jews, but also of the nations?</verse>
  <verse number="25">As also he says in Hosea, I will call not my people my people; and the not loved, loved.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And it shall be, in the place where it was said to them, Ye not my people; there shall they be called the sons of the living God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Esaias cries for Israel, If the number of the sons of Israel as the sand of the sea, the remnant shall be saved:</verse>
  <verse number="28">For finishing and cutting short the word in justice: for the Lord will make the word cut short upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And as Esaias said before, Except the Lord of Sabaoth had left us seed, as Sodom had we been, and as Gomorrha had we been likened.</verse>
  <verse number="30">What then shall we say? That the nations, not following justice, overtook justice, and the justice of faith.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Israel following the law of justice, reached not the law of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Wherefore? Because not of faith, but as of the works of the law. For they stumbled at the stumblingstone;</verse>
  <verse number="33">As has been written, Behold I set in Zion a stone of stumbling and rock of offence: and every one believing on him shall not be ashamed.</verse>
</chapter>