<chapter book="Luke" number="24" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But on the morrow of the sabbath, very early indeed in the morning, they came to the tomb, bringing the aromatic spices which they had prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And they found the stone rolled away from the sepulchre.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And when they had entered they found not the body of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And it came to pass as they were in perplexity about it, that behold, two men suddenly stood by them in shining raiment.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And as they were filled with fear and bowed their faces to the ground, they said to them, Why seek ye the living one among the dead?</verse>
  <verse number="6">He is not here, but is risen: remember how he spoke to you, being yet in Galilee,</verse>
  <verse number="7">saying, The Son of man must be delivered up into the hands of sinners, and be crucified, and rise the third day.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they remembered his words;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and, returning from the sepulchre, related all these things to the eleven and to all the rest.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now it was Mary of Magdala, and Johanna, and Mary the [mother] of James, and the others with them, who told these things to the apostles.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And their words appeared in their eyes as an idle tale, and they disbelieved them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But Peter, rising up, ran to the sepulchre, and stooping down he sees the linen clothes lying there alone, and went away home, wondering at what had happened.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And behold, two of them were going on the same day to a village distant sixty stadia from Jerusalem, called Emmaus;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and they conversed with one another about all these things which had taken place.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And it came to pass as they conversed and reasoned, that Jesus himself drawing nigh, went with them;</verse>
  <verse number="16">but their eyes were holden so as not to know him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he said to them, What discourses are these which pass between you as ye walk, and are downcast?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And one [of them], named Cleopas, answering said to him, Thou sojournest alone in Jerusalem, and dost not know what has taken place in it in these days?</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he said to them, What things? And they said to him, The things concerning Jesus the Nazaraean, who was a prophet mighty in deed and word before God and all the people;</verse>
  <verse number="20">and how the chief priests and our rulers delivered him up to [the] judgment of death and crucified him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But we had hoped that he was [the one] who is about to redeem Israel. But then, besides all these things, it is now, to-day, the third day since these things took place.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And withal, certain women from amongst us astonished us, having been very early at the sepulchre,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and, not having found his body, came, saying that they also had seen a vision of angels, who say that he is living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And some of those with us went to the sepulchre, and found it so, as the women also had said, but him they saw not.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he said to them, O senseless and slow of heart to believe in all that the prophets have spoken!</verse>
  <verse number="26">Ought not the Christ to have suffered these things and to enter into his glory?</verse>
  <verse number="27">And having begun from Moses and from all the prophets, he interpreted to them in all the scriptures the things concerning himself.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they drew near to the village where they were going, and he made as though he would go farther.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And they constrained him, saying, Stay with us, for it is toward evening and the day is declining. And he entered in to stay with them.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And it came to pass as he was at table with them, having taken the bread, he blessed, and having broken it, gave it to them.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And their eyes were opened, and they recognised him. And he disappeared from them.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they said to one another, Was not our heart burning in us as he spoke to us on the way, [and] as he opened the scriptures to us?</verse>
  <verse number="33">And rising up the same hour, they returned to Jerusalem. And they found the eleven, and those with them, gathered together,</verse>
  <verse number="34">saying, The Lord is indeed risen and has appeared to Simon.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And they related what [had happened] on the way, and how he was made known to them in the breaking of bread.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And as they were saying these things, he himself stood in their midst, and says to them, Peace [be] unto you.</verse>
  <verse number="37">But they, being confounded and being frightened, supposed they beheld a spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And he said to them, Why are ye troubled? and why are thoughts rising in your hearts?</verse>
  <verse number="39">behold my hands and my feet, that it is I myself. Handle me and see, for a spirit has not flesh and bones as ye see me having.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And having said this he shewed them his hands and his feet.</verse>
  <verse number="41">But while they yet did not believe for joy, and were wondering, he said to them, Have ye anything here to eat?</verse>
  <verse number="42">And they gave him part of a broiled fish and of a honeycomb;</verse>
  <verse number="43">and he took it and ate before them.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And he said to them, These [are] the words which I spoke to you while I was yet with you, that all that is written concerning me in the law of Moses and prophets and psalms must be fulfilled.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then he opened their understanding to understand the scriptures,</verse>
  <verse number="46">and said to them, Thus it is written, and thus it behoved the Christ to suffer, and to rise from among the dead the third day;</verse>
  <verse number="47">and that repentance and remission of sins should be preached in his name to all the nations beginning at Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And ye are witnesses of these things.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And behold, I send the promise of my Father upon you; but do ye remain in the city till ye be clothed with power from on high.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And he led them out as far as Bethany, and having lifted up his hands, he blessed them.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And it came to pass as he was blessing them, he was separated from them and was carried up into heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And they, having done him homage, returned to Jerusalem with great joy,</verse>
  <verse number="53">and were continually in the temple praising and blessing God.</verse>
</chapter>