<chapter book="Ephesians" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For this, I Paul, the imprisoned of Christ Jesus for you the nations,</verse>
  <verse number="2">If ye have heard of the distribution of the grace of God given to me for you:</verse>
  <verse number="3">That by revelation he made Known to me the mystery; (as I before wrote briefly,</verse>
  <verse number="4">By which ye, reading, can perceive My understanding in the mystery of Christ,)</verse>
  <verse number="5">Which in other generations was not made known to the sons of men, as now has been revealed to his holy sent and to the prophets by the Spirit:</verse>
  <verse number="6">For the nations to be co-heirs, and united in one body, and, participators of his solemn promise in Christ by the good news:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Of which I Became a servant, according to the gift of the grace of God given to me according to the energy of his power.</verse>
  <verse number="8">To me, the least of all the holy ones, was this grace given, to announce the good news in the nations, the untraceable riches of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And to enlighten all what the distribution of the mystery, concealed from times immemorial in God, having created all things by Jesus Christ:</verse>
  <verse number="10">That it might now be made known to beginnings and powers in the heavenlies by the church the manifold wisdom of God,</verse>
  <verse number="11">According to the purpose of times immemorial which he made in Christ Jesus our Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="12">In whom we have freedom of speech and access with confidence by his faith.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore I desire not to lose courage in my pressures for you, which is your glory.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For this I bend my knees to the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="15">Of whom all the family in the heavens and upon earth is named,</verse>
  <verse number="16">That he might give to you, according to the riches of his glory, to be strengthened with power by his Spirit in the interior man;</verse>
  <verse number="17">For Christ to dwell by faith in your hearts; in love being rendered firm, and the foundation laid,</verse>
  <verse number="18">That ye might be fully able to comprehend with all the holy what the length, and breadth, and depth, and height;</verse>
  <verse number="19">To know also the love of Christ, surpassing knowledge, that ye might be filled in all the fulness of God.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And to him being able to do above all things more abundantly above what we ask or think, according to the power being energetic in us,</verse>
  <verse number="21">To him the glory in the church in Christ Jesus to all generations of the times of times. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>