<chapter book="Ephesians" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Be ye therefore imitators of God, as dearly beloved children;</verse>
  <verse number="2">And walk ye in love, as also Christ loved us, and gave himself for us a gift and sacrifice to God for a smell of sweet odor.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And fornication, and all uncleanness, or overreaching, let it not be named with you, as becomes the holy;</verse>
  <verse number="4">And obscenity, and silly discourse, or wit, which things concern not; but rather thankfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For this ye are knowing, that every fornicator, or unclean, or covetous person, who is an idolater, has no inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let none lead you astray with vain words: for by these things comes the anger of God upon the sons of disobedience.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be ye not therefore partakers with them.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For ye were then darkness, and now light in the Lord: walk ye as children of light:</verse>
  <verse number="9">(For the fruit of the Spirit in all goodness and justice and truth;)</verse>
  <verse number="10">Trying what is pleasing to the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And participate not with the unfruitful works of darkness, and rather also confute.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For the things done secretly by them it is also shameful to speak.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And all things refuted, by light are made manifest: for everything made manifest is light.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Wherefore he says, Awake, who sleeping, and arise from the dead, and Christ will enlighten thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">See therefore how ye walk accurately, not as unwise, but as wise,</verse>
  <verse number="16">Making purchase of time, for the days are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For this be not foolish, but understanding what the will of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And be not drunk with wine, in which is debauchery; but be filled with the Spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="19">Speaking to yourselves on harps, and songs, and spiritual odes, singing and playing on the harp in your heart to the Lord;</verse>
  <verse number="20">Giving thanks always for all things, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, to God and the Father;</verse>
  <verse number="21">Yielding obedience to one another in the fear of God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Women, yield ye obedience to your own husbands, as to the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the husband is the head of the wife, as also Christ the head of the church: and he is the saviour of the body.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But as the church is subjected to Christ, so also wives to their own husbands in everything.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Husbands, love your own wives, as also Christ loved the church, and delivered himself up for it;</verse>
  <verse number="26">That he might consecrate it, having cleansed by the washing of water in the word,</verse>
  <verse number="27">That he might present it to himself a glorious church, not having spot, or wrinkle, or any such thing: but that it be holy and blameless.</verse>
  <verse number="28">So ought men to love their own wives as their own bodies. He loving his wife, loves himself.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For none at any time hates his own flesh; but brings it up and cherishes it, as also the Lord the church:</verse>
  <verse number="30">For we are members of his body, of his flesh, and of his bones.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For this a man shall leave his father and mother, and be joined to his wife, and they two shall be one flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="32">This is a great mystery: but I speak to Christ and to the church.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But ye also altogether, let each so love his own wife as himself: and the wife that she fear her husband.</verse>
</chapter>