<chapter book="James" number="4" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">From where come wars and fights among you? come they not hence, even of your lusts that war in your members?</verse>
  <verse number="2">You lust, and have not: you kill, and desire to have, and cannot obtain: you fight and war, yet you have not, because you ask not.</verse>
  <verse number="3">You ask, and receive not, because you ask amiss, that you may consume it on your lusts.</verse>
  <verse number="4">You adulterers and adulteresses, know you not that the friendship of the world is enmity with God? whoever therefore will be a friend of the world is the enemy of God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Do you think that the scripture said in vain, The spirit that dwells in us lusts to envy?</verse>
  <verse number="6">But he gives more grace. Why he said, God resists the proud, but gives grace to the humble.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Draw near to God, and he will draw near to you. Cleanse your hands, you sinners; and purify your hearts, you double minded.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be afflicted, and mourn, and weep: let your laughter be turned to mourning, and your joy to heaviness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Humble yourselves in the sight of the Lord, and he shall lift you up.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Speak not evil one of another, brothers. He that speaks evil of his brother, and judges his brother, speaks evil of the law, and judges the law: but if you judge the law, you are not a doer of the law, but a judge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">There is one lawgiver, who is able to save and to destroy: who are you that judge another?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Go to now, you that say, To day or to morrow we will go into such a city, and continue there a year, and buy and sell, and get gain:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Whereas you know not what shall be on the morrow. For what is your life? It is even a vapor, that appears for a little time, and then vanishes away.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For that you ought to say, If the Lord will, we shall live, and do this, or that.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But now you rejoice in your boastings: all such rejoicing is evil.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore to him that knows to do good, and does it not, to him it is sin.</verse>
</chapter>