<chapter book="James" number="5" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Go to now, you rich men, weep and howl for your miseries that shall come on you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Your riches are corrupted, and your garments are moth-eaten.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Your gold and silver is corroded; and the rust of them shall be a witness against you, and shall eat your flesh as it were fire. You have heaped treasure together for the last days.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Behold, the hire of the laborers who have reaped down your fields, which is of you kept back by fraud, cries: and the cries of them which have reaped are entered into the ears of the Lord of sabaoth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">You have lived in pleasure on the earth, and been wanton; you have nourished your hearts, as in a day of slaughter.</verse>
  <verse number="6">You have condemned and killed the just; and he does not resist you.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be patient therefore, brothers, to the coming of the Lord. Behold, the farmer waits for the precious fruit of the earth, and has long patience for it, until he receive the early and latter rain.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Be you also patient; establish your hearts: for the coming of the Lord draws near.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Grudge not one against another, brothers, lest you be condemned: behold, the judge stands before the door.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Take, my brothers, the prophets, who have spoken in the name of the Lord, for an example of suffering affliction, and of patience.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Behold, we count them happy which endure. You have heard of the patience of Job, and have seen the end of the Lord; that the Lord is very pitiful, and of tender mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But above all things, my brothers, swear not, neither by heaven, neither by the earth, neither by any other oath: but let your yes be yes; and your no, no; lest you fall into condemnation.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Is any among you afflicted? let him pray. Is any merry? let him sing psalms.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Is any sick among you? let him call for the elders of the church; and let them pray over him, anointing him with oil in the name of the Lord:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the prayer of faith shall save the sick, and the Lord shall raise him up; and if he have committed sins, they shall be forgiven him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Confess your faults one to another, and pray one for another, that you may be healed. The effectual fervent prayer of a righteous man avails much.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Elias was a man subject to like passions as we are, and he prayed earnestly that it might not rain: and it rained not on the earth by the space of three years and six months.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he prayed again, and the heaven gave rain, and the earth brought forth her fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Brothers, if any of you do err from the truth, and one convert him;</verse>
  <verse number="20">Let him know, that he which converts the sinner from the error of his way shall save a soul from death, and shall hide a multitude of sins.</verse>
</chapter>