<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="1" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The Song of Songs, that is Solomon’s.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Let him kiss me with kisses of his mouth, For better are thy loves than wine.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For fragrance are thy perfumes good. Perfume emptied out—thy name, Therefore have virgins loved thee!</verse>
  <verse number="4">Draw me: after thee we run, The king hath brought me into his inner chambers, We do joy and rejoice in thee, We mention thy loves more than wine, Uprightly they have loved thee!</verse>
  <verse number="5">Dark am I, and comely, daughters of Jerusalem, As tents of Kedar, as curtains of Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Fear me not, because I am very dark, Because the sun hath scorched me, The sons of my mother were angry with me, They made me keeper of the vineyards, My vineyard—my own—I have not kept.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Declare to me, thou whom my soul hath loved, Where thou delightest, Where thou liest down at noon, For why am I as one veiled, By the ranks of thy companions?</verse>
  <verse number="8">If thou knowest not, O fair among women, Get thee forth by the traces of the flock, And feed thy kids by the shepherds’ dwellings!</verse>
  <verse number="9">To my joyous one in chariots of Pharaoh, I have compared thee, my friend,</verse>
  <verse number="10">Comely have been thy cheeks with garlands, Thy neck with chains.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Garlands of gold we do make for thee, With studs of silver!</verse>
  <verse number="12">While the king is in his circle, My spikenard hath given its fragrance.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A bundle of myrrh is my beloved to me, Between my breasts it lodgeth.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A cluster of cypress is my beloved to me, In the vineyards of En-Gedi!</verse>
  <verse number="15">Lo, thou art fair, my friend, Lo, thou art fair, thine eyes are doves!</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo, thou art fair, my love, yea, pleasant, Yea, our couch is green,</verse>
  <verse number="17">The beams of our houses are cedars, Our rafters are firs, I am a rose of Sharon, a lily of the valleys!</verse>
</chapter>