<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As a lily among the thorns,</verse>
  <verse number="2">So is my friend among the daughters!</verse>
  <verse number="3">As a citron among trees of the forest, So is my beloved among the sons, In his shade I delighted, and sat down, And his fruit is sweet to my palate.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He hath brought me in unto a house of wine, And his banner over me is love,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Sustain me with grape-cakes, Support me with citrons, for I am sick with love.</verse>
  <verse number="6">His left hand is under my head, And his right doth embrace me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I have adjured you, daughters of Jerusalem, By the roes or by the hinds of the field, Stir not up nor wake the love till she please!</verse>
  <verse number="8">The voice of my beloved! lo, this—he is coming, Leaping on the mountains, skipping on the hills.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My beloved is like to a roe, Or to a young one of the harts. Lo, this—he is standing behind our wall, Looking from the windows, Blooming from the lattice.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My beloved hath answered and said to me, ‘Rise up, my friend, my fair one, and come away,</verse>
  <verse number="11">For lo, the winter hath passed by, The rain hath passed away—it hath gone.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The flowers have appeared in the earth, The time of the singing hath come, And the voice of the turtle was heard in our land,</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fig-tree hath ripened her green figs, And the sweet-smelling vines have given forth fragrance, Rise, come, my friend, my fair one, yea, come away.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My dove, in clefts of the rock, In a secret place of the ascent, Cause me to see thine appearance, Cause me to hear thy voice, For thy voice is sweet, and thy appearance comely.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Seize ye for us foxes, Little foxes—destroyers of vineyards, Even our sweet-smelling vineyards.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My beloved is mine, and I am his, Who is delighting among the lilies,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Till the day doth break forth, And the shadows have fled away, Turn, be like, my beloved, To a roe, or to a young one of the harts, On the mountains of separation!</verse>
</chapter>