<chapter book="Job" number="11" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Zophar the Naamathite answereth and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">Is a multitude of words not answered? And is a man of lips justified?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Thy devices make men keep silent, Thou scornest, and none is causing blushing!</verse>
  <verse number="4">And thou sayest, ‘Pure is my discourse, And clean I have been in Thine eyes.’</verse>
  <verse number="5">And yet, O that God had spoken! And doth open His lips with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And declare to thee secrets of wisdom, For counsel hath foldings. And know thou that God forgetteth for thee, Some of thine iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">By searching dost thou find out God? Unto perfection find out the Mighty One?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Heights of the heavens!—what dost thou? Deeper than Sheol!—what knowest thou?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Longer than earth is its measure, And broader than the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If He pass on, and shut up, and assemble, Who then dost reverse it?</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he hath known men of vanity, And He seeth iniquity, And one doth not consider it!</verse>
  <verse number="12">And empty man is bold, And the colt of a wild ass man is born.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If thou—thou hast prepared thy heart, And hast spread out unto Him thy hands,</verse>
  <verse number="14">If iniquity is in thy hand, put it far off, And let not perverseness dwell in thy tents.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For then thou liftest up thy face from blemish, And thou hast been firm, and fearest not.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For thou dost forget misery, As waters passed away thou rememberest.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And above the noon doth age rise, Thou fliest—as the morning thou art.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And thou hast trusted because their is hope, And searched—in confidence thou liest down,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And thou hast rested, And none is causing trembling, And many have entreated thy face;</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the eyes of the wicked are consumed, And refuge hath perished from them, And their hope is a breathing out of soul!</verse>
</chapter>