<chapter book="Job" number="29" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job addeth to lift up his simile, and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who doth make me as in months past, As in the days of God’s preserving me?</verse>
  <verse number="3">In His causing His lamp to shine on my head, By His light I walk through darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="4">As I have been in days of my maturity, And the counsel of God upon my tent.</verse>
  <verse number="5">When yet the Mighty One is with me. Round about me—my young ones,</verse>
  <verse number="6">When washing my goings with butter, And the firm rock is with me rivulets of oil.</verse>
  <verse number="7">When I go out to the gate by the city, In a broad place I prepare my seat.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Seen me have youths, and they, been hidden, And the aged have risen—they stood up.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Princes have kept in words, And a hand they place on their mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The voice of leaders hath been hidden, And their tongue to the palate hath cleaved.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the ear heard, and declareth me happy, And the eye hath seen, and testifieth to me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I deliver the afflicted who is crying, And the fatherless who hath no helper.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The blessing of the perishing cometh on me, And the heart of the widow I cause to sing.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Righteousness I have put on, and it clotheth me, As a robe and a diadem my justice.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Eyes I have been to the blind, And feet to the lame am I.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A father I am to the needy, And the cause I have not known I search out.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I break the jaw-teeth of the perverse, And from his teeth I cast away prey.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And I say, ‘With my nest I expire, And as the sand I multiply days.’</verse>
  <verse number="19">My root is open unto the waters, And dew doth lodge on my branch.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My honour is fresh with me, And my bow in my hand is renewed.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To me they have hearkened, Yea, they wait, and are silent for my counsel.</verse>
  <verse number="22">After my word they change not, And on them doth my speech drop,</verse>
  <verse number="23">And they wait as for rain for me, And their mouth they have opened wide As for the latter rain.</verse>
  <verse number="24">I laugh unto them—they give no credence, And the light of my face cause not to fall.</verse>
  <verse number="25">I choose their way, and sit head, And I dwell as a king in a troop, When mourners he doth comfort.</verse>
</chapter>