<chapter book="Job" number="33" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And yet, I pray thee, O Job, Hear my speech and to all my words give ear.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Lo, I pray thee, I have opened my mouth, My tongue hath spoken in the palate.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Of the uprightness of my heart are my sayings, And knowledge have my lips clearly spoken.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The Spirit of God hath made me, And the breath of the Mighty doth quicken me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">If thou art able—answer me, Set in array before me—station thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Lo, I am, according to thy word, for God, From the clay I—I also, have been formed.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Lo, my terror doth not frighten thee, And my burden on thee is not heavy.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Surely—thou hast said in mine ears, And the sounds of words I hear:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Pure am I, without transgression, Innocent am I, and I have no iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Lo, occasions against me He doth find, He doth reckon me for an enemy to Him,</verse>
  <verse number="11">He doth put in the stocks my feet, He doth watch all my paths.’</verse>
  <verse number="12">Lo, in this thou hast not been righteous, I answer thee, that greater is God than man.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore against Him hast thou striven, When for all His matters He answereth not?</verse>
  <verse number="14">For once doth God speak, and twice, (He doth not behold it.)</verse>
  <verse number="15">In a dream—a vision of night, In the falling of deep sleep on men, In slumberings on a bed.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Then He uncovereth the ear of men, And for their instruction sealeth:</verse>
  <verse number="17">To turn aside man from doing, And pride from man He concealeth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He keepeth back his soul from corruption, And his life from passing away by a dart.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And he hath been reproved With pain on his bed, And the strife of his bones is enduring.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And his life hath nauseated bread, And his soul desirable food.</verse>
  <verse number="21">His flesh is consumed from being seen, And high are his bones, they were not seen!</verse>
  <verse number="22">And draw near to the pit doth his soul, And his life to those causing death.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If there is by him a messenger, An interpreter—one of a thousand, To declare for man his uprightness:</verse>
  <verse number="24">Then He doth favour him and saith, ‘Ransom him from going down to the pit, I have found an atonement.’</verse>
  <verse number="25">Fresher is his flesh than a child’s, He returneth to the days of his youth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He maketh supplication unto God, And He accepteth him. And he seeth His face with shouting, And He returneth to man His righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He looketh on men, and saith, ‘I sinned, And uprightness I have perverted, And it hath not been profitable to me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">He hath ransomed my soul From going over into the pit, And my life on the light looketh.’</verse>
  <verse number="29">Lo, all these doth God work, Twice—thrice with man,</verse>
  <verse number="30">To bring back his soul from the pit, To be enlightened with the light of the living.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Attend, O Job, hearken to me, Keep silent, and I—I do speak.</verse>
  <verse number="32">If there are words—answer me, Speak, for I have a desire to justify thee.</verse>
  <verse number="33">If there are not—hearken thou to me, Keep silent, and I teach thee wisdom.</verse>
</chapter>