<chapter book="Job" number="37" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Also, at this my heart trembleth, And it moveth from its place.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hearken diligently to the trembling of His voice, Yea, the sound from His mouth goeth forth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Under the whole heavens He directeth it, And its light is over the skirts of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">After it roar doth a voice—He thundereth with the voice of His excellency, And He doth not hold them back, When His voice is heard.</verse>
  <verse number="5">God thundereth with His voice wonderfully, Doing great things and we know not.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For to snow He saith, ‘Be on the earth.’ And the small rain and great rain of His power.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Into the hand of every man he sealeth, For the knowledge by all men of His work.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And enter doth the beast into covert, And in its habitations it doth continue.</verse>
  <verse number="9">From the inner chamber cometh a hurricane, And from scatterings winds—cold,</verse>
  <verse number="10">From the breath of God is frost given, And the breadth of waters is straitened,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Yea, by filling He doth press out a cloud, Scatter a cloud doth His light.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And it is turning itself round by His counsels, For their doing all He commandeth them, On the face of the habitable earth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whether for a rod, or for His land, Or for kindness—He doth cause it to come.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Hear this, O Job, Stand and consider the wonders of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Dost thou know when God doth place them, And caused to shine the light of His cloud?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Dost thou know the balancings of a cloud? The wonders of the Perfect in knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="17">How thy garments are warm, In the quieting of the earth from the south?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Thou hast made an expanse with Him For the clouds—strong as a hard mirror!</verse>
  <verse number="19">Let us know what we say to Him, We set not in array because of darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Is it declared to Him that I speak? If a man hath spoken, surely he is swallowed up.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And now, they have not seen the light, Bright it is in the clouds, And the wind hath passed by and cleanseth them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">From the golden north it cometh, Beside God is fearful honour.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The Mighty! we have not found Him out, High in power and judgment, He doth not answer! And abundant in righteousness,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Therefore do men fear Him, He seeth not any of the wise of heart.</verse>
</chapter>