<chapter book="Job" number="39" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hast thou known the time of The bearing of the wild goats of the rock? The bringing forth of hinds thou dost mark!</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thou dost number the months they fulfil? And thou hast known the time of their bringing forth!</verse>
  <verse number="3">They bow down, Their young ones they bring forth safely, Their pangs they cast forth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Safe are their young ones, They grow up in the field, they have gone out, And have not returned to them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who hath sent forth the wild ass free? Yea, the bands of the wild ass who opened?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Whose house I have made the wilderness, And his dwellings the barren land,</verse>
  <verse number="7">He doth laugh at the multitude of a city, The cries of an exactor he heareth not.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The range of mountains is his pasture, And after every green thing he seeketh.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Is a Reem willing to serve thee? Doth he lodge by thy crib?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Dost thou bind a Reem in a furrow with his thick band? Doth he harrow valleys after thee?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Dost thou trust in him because great is his power? And dost thou leave unto him thy labour?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Dost thou trust in him That he doth bring back thy seed? And to thy threshing-floor doth gather it?</verse>
  <verse number="13">The wing of the rattling ones exulteth, Whether the pinion of the ostrich or hawk.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For she leaveth on the earth her eggs, And on the dust she doth warm them,</verse>
  <verse number="15">And she forgetteth that a foot may press it, And a beast of the field tread it down.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Her young ones it hath hardened without her, In vain is her labour without fear.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For God hath caused her to forget wisdom, And He hath not given a portion To her in understanding:</verse>
  <verse number="18">At the time on high she lifteth herself up, She laugheth at the horse and at his rider.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Dost thou give to the horse might? Dost thou clothe his neck with a mane?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Dost thou cause him to rush as a locust? The majesty of his snorting is terrible.</verse>
  <verse number="21">They dig in a valley, and he rejoiceth in power, He goeth forth to meet the armour.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He laugheth at fear, and is not affrighted, And he turneth not back from the face of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Against him rattle doth quiver, The flame of a spear, and a halbert.</verse>
  <verse number="24">With trembling and rage he swalloweth the ground, And remaineth not stedfast Because of the sound of a trumpet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Among the trumpets he saith, Aha, And from afar he doth smell battle, Roaring of princes and shouting.</verse>
  <verse number="26">By thine understanding flieth a hawk? Spreadeth he his wings to the south?</verse>
  <verse number="27">At thy command goeth an eagle up high? Or lifteth he up his nest?</verse>
  <verse number="28">A rock he doth inhabit, Yea, he lodgeth on the tooth of a rock, and fortress.</verse>
  <verse number="29">From thence he hath sought food, To a far off place his eyes look attentively,</verse>
  <verse number="30">And his brood gulp up blood, And where the pierced are—there is he!</verse>
</chapter>