<chapter book="Job" number="4" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Eliphaz the Temanite answereth and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hath one tried a word with thee?—Thou art weary! And to keep in words who is able?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Lo, thou hast instructed many, And feeble hands thou makest strong.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The stumbling one do thy words raise up, And bowing knees thou dost strengthen.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But now, it cometh in unto thee, And thou art weary; It striketh unto thee, and thou art troubled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Is not thy reverence thy confidence? Thy hope—the perfection of thy ways?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Remember, I pray thee, Who, being innocent, hath perished? And where have the upright been cut off?</verse>
  <verse number="8">As I have seen—ploughers of iniquity, And sowers of misery, reap it!</verse>
  <verse number="9">From the breath of God they perish, And from the spirit of His anger consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The roaring of a lion, And the voice of a fierce lion, And teeth of young lions have been broken.</verse>
  <verse number="11">An old lion is perishing without prey, And the whelps of the lioness do separate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And unto me a thing is secretly brought, And receive doth mine ear a little of it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In thoughts from visions of the night, In the falling of deep sleep on men,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Fear hath met me, and trembling, And the multitude of my bones caused to fear.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And a spirit before my face doth pass, Stand up doth the hair of my flesh;</verse>
  <verse number="16">It standeth, and I discern not its aspect, A similitude is over-against mine eyes, Silence! and a voice I hear:</verse>
  <verse number="17">‘Is mortal man than God more righteous? Than his Maker is a man cleaner?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Lo, in His servants He putteth no credence, Nor in His messengers setteth praise.’</verse>
  <verse number="19">Also—the inhabitants of houses of clay, (Whose foundation is in the dust, They bruise them before a moth.)</verse>
  <verse number="20">From morning to evening are beaten down, Without any regarding, for ever they perish.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Hath not their excellency been removed with them? They die, and not in wisdom!</verse>
</chapter>