<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jehovah doth answer Job, and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">Is the striver with the Mighty instructed? The reprover of God, let him answer it.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Job answereth Jehovah, and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="4">Lo, I have been vile, What do I return to Thee? My hand I have placed on my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Once I have spoken, and I answer not, And twice, and I add not.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Jehovah answereth Job out of the whirlwind, and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="7">Gird, I pray thee, as a man, thy loins, I ask thee, and cause thou Me to know.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Dost thou also make void My judgment? Dost thou condemn Me, That thou mayest be righteous?</verse>
  <verse number="9">And an arm like God hast thou? And with a voice like Him dost thou thunder?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Put on, I pray thee, excellency and loftiness, Yea, honour and beauty put on.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Scatter abroad the wrath of thine anger, And see every proud one, and make him low.</verse>
  <verse number="12">See every proud one—humble him, And tread down the wicked in their place.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hide them in the dust together, Their faces bind in secret.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And even I—I do praise thee, For thy right hand giveth salvation to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Lo, I pray thee, Behemoth, that I made with thee: Grass as an ox he eateth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo, I pray thee, his power is in his loins, And his strength in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He doth bend his tail as a cedar, The sinews of his thighs are wrapped together,</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are tubes of brass, His bones are as a bar of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is a beginning of the ways of God, His Maker bringeth nigh his sword;</verse>
  <verse number="20">For food do mountains bear for him, And all the beasts of the field play there.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Under shades he lieth down, In a secret place of reed and mire.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Cover him do shades, with their shadow, Cover him do willows of the brook.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Lo, a flood oppresseth—he doth not haste, He is confident though Jordan Doth come forth unto his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Before his eyes doth one take him, With snares doth one pierce the nose?</verse>
</chapter>