<chapter book="Job" number="41" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Dost thou draw leviathan with an angle? And with a rope thou lettest down—his tongue?</verse>
  <verse number="2">Dost thou put a reed in his nose? And with a thorn pierce his jaw?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Doth he multiply unto thee supplications? Doth he speak unto thee tender things?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Doth he make a covenant with thee? Dost thou take him for a servant age-during?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Dost thou play with him as a bird? And dost thou bind him for thy damsels?</verse>
  <verse number="6">(Feast upon him do companions, They divide him among the merchants!)</verse>
  <verse number="7">Dost thou fill with barbed irons his skin? And with fish-spears his head?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Place on him thy hand, Remember the battle—do not add!</verse>
  <verse number="9">Lo, the hope of him is found a liar, Also at his appearance is not one cast down?</verse>
  <verse number="10">None so fierce that he doth awake him, And who is he before Me stationeth himself?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Who hath brought before Me and I repay? Under the whole heavens it is mine.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I do not keep silent concerning his parts, And the matter of might, And the grace of his arrangement.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who hath uncovered the face of his clothing? Within his double bridle who doth enter?</verse>
  <verse number="14">The doors of his face who hath opened? Round about his teeth are terrible.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A pride—strong ones of shields, Shut up—a close seal.</verse>
  <verse number="16">One unto another they draw nigh, And air doth not enter between them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">One unto another they adhere, They stick together and are not separated.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His sneezings cause light to shine, And his eyes are as the eyelids of the dawn.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Out of his mouth do flames go, sparks of fire escape.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Out of his nostrils goeth forth smoke, As a blown pot and reeds.</verse>
  <verse number="21">His breath setteth coals on fire, And a flame from his mouth goeth forth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In his neck lodge doth strength, And before him doth grief exult.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The flakes of his flesh have adhered—Firm upon him—it is not moved.</verse>
  <verse number="24">His heart is firm as a stone, Yea, firm as the lower piece.</verse>
  <verse number="25">From his rising are the mighty afraid, From breakings they keep themselves free.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sword of his overtaker standeth not, Spear—dart—and lance.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He reckoneth iron as straw, brass as rotten wood.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The son of the bow doth not cause him to flee, Turned by him into stubble are stones of the sling.</verse>
  <verse number="29">As stubble have darts been reckoned, And he laugheth at the shaking of a javelin.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Under him are sharp points of clay, He spreadeth gold on the mire.</verse>
  <verse number="31">He causeth to boil as a pot the deep, The sea he maketh as a pot of ointment.</verse>
  <verse number="32">After him he causeth a path to shine, One thinketh the deep to be hoary.</verse>
  <verse number="33">There is not on the earth his like, That is made without terror.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Every high thing he doth see, He is king over all sons of pride.</verse>
</chapter>