<chapter book="Job" number="5" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Pray, call, is there any to answer thee? And unto which of the holy ones dost thou turn?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For provocation slayeth the perverse, And envy putteth to death the simple,</verse>
  <verse number="3">I—I have seen the perverse taking root, And I mark his habitation straightway,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Far are his sons from safety, And they are bruised in the gate, And there is no deliverer.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whose harvest the hungry doth eat, And even from the thorns taketh it, And the designing swallowed their wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For sorrow cometh not forth from the dust, Nor from the ground springeth up misery.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For man to misery is born, And the sparks go high to fly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Yet I—I inquire for God, And for God I give my word,</verse>
  <verse number="9">Doing great things, and there is no searching. Wonderful, till there is no numbering.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Who is giving rain on the face of the land, And is sending waters on the out-places.</verse>
  <verse number="11">To set the low on a high place, And the mourners have been high in safety.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Making void thoughts of the subtile, And their hands do not execute wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Capturing the wise in their subtilty, And the counsel of wrestling ones was hastened,</verse>
  <verse number="14">By day they meet darkness, And as night—they grope at noon.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And He saveth the wasted from their mouth, And from a strong hand the needy,</verse>
  <verse number="16">And there is hope to the poor, And perverseness hath shut her mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Lo, the happiness of mortal man, God doth reprove him: And the chastisement of the Mighty despise not,</verse>
  <verse number="18">For He doth pain, and He bindeth up, He smiteth, and His hands heal.</verse>
  <verse number="19">In six distresses He delivereth thee, And in seven evil striketh not on thee.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In famine He hath redeemed thee from death, And in battle from the hands of the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="21">When the tongue scourgeth thou art hid, And thou art not afraid of destruction, When it cometh.</verse>
  <verse number="22">At destruction and at hunger thou mockest, And of the beast of the earth, Thou art not afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="23">(For with sons of the field is thy covenant, And the beast of the field Hath been at peace with thee.)</verse>
  <verse number="24">And thou hast known that thy tent is peace, And inspected thy habitation, and errest not,</verse>
  <verse number="25">And hast known that numerous is Thy seed, And thine offspring as the herb of the earth;</verse>
  <verse number="26">Thou comest in full age unto the grave, As the going up of a stalk in its season.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Lo, this—we searched it out—it is right, hearken; And thou, know for thyself!</verse>
</chapter>