<chapter book="Job" number="6" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Job answereth and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">O that my provocation were thoroughly weighed, And my calamity in balances They would lift up together!</verse>
  <verse number="3">For now, than the sands of the sea it is heavier, Therefore my words have been rash.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For arrows of the Mighty are with me, Whose poison is drinking up my spirit. Terrors of God array themselves for me!</verse>
  <verse number="5">Brayeth a wild ass over tender grass? Loweth an ox over his provender?</verse>
  <verse number="6">Eaten is an insipid thing without salt? Is there sense in the drivel of dreams?</verse>
  <verse number="7">My soul is refusing to touch! They are as my sickening food.</verse>
  <verse number="8">O that my request may come, That God may grant my hope!</verse>
  <verse number="9">That God would please—and bruise me, Loose His hand and cut me off!</verse>
  <verse number="10">And yet it is my comfort, (And I exult in pain—He doth not spare,) That I have not hidden The sayings of the Holy One.</verse>
  <verse number="11">What is my power that I should hope? And what mine end That I should prolong my life?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is my strength the strength of stones? Is my flesh brazen?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Is not my help with me, And substance driven from me?</verse>
  <verse number="14">To a despiser of his friends is shame, And the fear of the Mighty he forsaketh.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My brethren have deceived as a brook, As a stream of brooks they pass away.</verse>
  <verse number="16">That are black because of ice, By them doth snow hide itself.</verse>
  <verse number="17">By the time they are warm they have been cut off, By its being hot they have been Extinguished from their place.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Turn aside do the paths of their way, They ascend into emptiness, and are lost.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Passengers of Tema looked expectingly, Travellers of Sheba hoped for them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">They were ashamed that one hath trusted, They have come unto it and are confounded.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Surely now ye have become the same! Ye see a downfall, and are afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Is it because I said, Give to me? And, By your power bribe for me?</verse>
  <verse number="23">And, Deliver me from the hand of an adversary? And, From the hand of terrible ones ransom me?</verse>
  <verse number="24">Shew me, and I—I keep silent, And what I have erred, let me understand.</verse>
  <verse number="25">How powerful have been upright sayings, And what doth reproof from you reprove?</verse>
  <verse number="26">For reproof—do you reckon words? And for wind—sayings of the desperate.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Anger on the fatherless ye cause to fall, And are strange to your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And, now, please, look upon me, Even to your face do I lie?</verse>
  <verse number="29">Turn back, I pray you, let it not be perverseness, Yea, turn back again—my righteousness is in it.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Is there in my tongue perverseness? Discerneth not my palate desirable things?</verse>
</chapter>