<chapter book="Job" number="8" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Bildad the Shuhite answereth and saith:—</verse>
  <verse number="2">Till when dost thou speak these things? And a strong wind—sayings of thy mouth?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Doth God pervert judgment? And doth the Mighty One pervert justice?</verse>
  <verse number="4">If thy sons have sinned before Him, And He doth send them away, By the hand of their transgression,</verse>
  <verse number="5">If thou dost seek early unto God, And unto the Mighty makest supplication,</verse>
  <verse number="6">If pure and upright thou art, Surely now He waketh for thee, And hath completed The habitation of thy righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And thy beginning hath been small, And thy latter end is very great.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For, ask I pray thee of a former generation, And prepare to a search of their fathers,</verse>
  <verse number="9">(For of yesterday we are, and we know not, For a shadow are our days on earth.)</verse>
  <verse number="10">Do they not shew thee—speak to thee, And from their heart bring forth words?</verse>
  <verse number="11">‘Doth a rush wise without mire? A reed increase without water?</verse>
  <verse number="12">While it is in its budding—uncropped, Even before any herb it withereth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">So are the paths of all forgetting God, And the hope of the profane doth perish,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Whose confidence is loathsome, And the house of a spider his trust.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He leaneth on his house—and it standeth not: He taketh hold on it—and it abideth not.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Green he is before the sun, And over his garden his branch goeth out.</verse>
  <verse number="17">By a heap his roots are wrapped, A house of stones he looketh for.</verse>
  <verse number="18">If one doth destroy him from his place, Then it hath feigned concerning him, I have not seen thee!</verse>
  <verse number="19">Lo, this is the joy of his way, And from the dust others spring up.’</verse>
  <verse number="20">Lo, God doth not reject the perfect, Nor taketh hold on the hand of evil doers.</verse>
  <verse number="21">While he filleth with laughter thy mouth, And thy lips with shouting,</verse>
  <verse number="22">Those hating thee do put on shame, And the tent of the wicked is not!</verse>
</chapter>