<chapter book="Proverbs" number="21" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The king’s heart in the hand of Jehovah is [as] brooks of water: he turneth it whithersoever he will.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Every way of a man is right in his own eyes; but Jehovah weigheth the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To exercise justice and judgment is more acceptable to Jehovah than sacrifice.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Lofty eyes, and a proud heart, the lamp of the wicked, is sin.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the diligent [tend] only to plenteousness; but of every one that is hasty, only to want.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The getting of treasures by a lying tongue is a fleeting breath of them that seek death.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The devastation of the wicked sweepeth them away, because they refuse to do what is right.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Very crooked is the way of a guilty man; but as for the pure, his work is upright.</verse>
  <verse number="9">It is better to dwell in a corner of the housetop, than with a contentious woman, and a house in common.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The soul of the wicked desireth evil: his neighbour findeth no favour in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">When the scorner is punished, the simple becometh wise; and when the wise is instructed, he receiveth knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">One that is righteous wisely considereth the house of the wicked: he overthroweth the wicked to [their] ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso stoppeth his ears at the cry of the poor, he also himself shall cry, and shall not be heard.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A gift in secret pacifieth anger; and a present in the bosom, vehement fury.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It is joy to a righteous [man] to do what is right; but it is ruin for the workers of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The man that wandereth out of the way of wisdom shall abide in the congregation of the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that loveth mirth shall be a poor man; he that loveth wine and oil shall not be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The wicked is a ransom for the righteous, and a treacherous [man] in the stead of the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="19">It is better to dwell in a desert land. than with a contentious and irritable woman.</verse>
  <verse number="20">There is costly store and oil in the dwelling of a wise [man]; but a foolish man swalloweth it up.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that followeth after righteousness and mercy findeth life, righteousness, and honour.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A wise [man] scaleth the city of the mighty, and casteth down the strength of the confidence thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue keepeth his soul from troubles.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Proud, arrogant, scorner is his name who dealeth in proud wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The desire of the sluggard killeth him; for his hands refuse to work:</verse>
  <verse number="26">He coveteth greedily all the day long; but the righteous giveth and spareth not.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sacrifice of the wicked is abomination: how much more when they bring it with a wicked purpose!</verse>
  <verse number="28">A lying witness shall perish; and a man that heareth shall speak constantly.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A wicked man hardeneth his face; but as for the upright, he establisheth his way.</verse>
  <verse number="30">There is no wisdom, nor understanding, nor counsel against Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The horse is prepared for the day of battle; but safety is of Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>