<chapter book="Proverbs" number="26" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As snow in summer, and as rain in harvest, so honour beseemeth not a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As the sparrow for flitting about, as the swallow for flying, so a curse undeserved shall not come.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A whip for the horse, a bridle for the ass, and a rod for the back of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Answer not a fool according to his folly, lest thou also be like unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Answer a fool according to his folly, lest he be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He that sendeth a message by the hand of a fool cutteth off [his own] feet, [and] drinketh damage.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The legs of the lame hang loose; so is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="8">As a bag of gems in a stoneheap, so is he that giveth honour to a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="9">[As] a thorn goeth up into the hand of a drunkard, so is a proverb in the mouth of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A master roughly worketh every one: he both hireth the fool and hireth passers-by.</verse>
  <verse number="11">As a dog turneth back to its vomit, [so] a fool repeateth his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Hast thou seen a man wise in his own eyes? There is more hope of a fool than of him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The sluggard saith, There is a fierce lion in the way; a lion is in the midst of the streets!</verse>
  <verse number="14">[As] the door turneth upon its hinges, so the sluggard upon his bed.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The sluggard burieth his hand in the dish: it wearieth him to bring it again to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A sluggard is wiser in his own eyes than seven [men] that answer discreetly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that passing by vexeth himself with strife belonging not to him, is [like] one that taketh a dog by the ears.</verse>
  <verse number="18">As a madman who casteth firebrands, arrows, and death,</verse>
  <verse number="19">so is a man that deceiveth his neighbour, and saith, Am I not in sport?</verse>
  <verse number="20">Where no wood is, the fire goeth out; and where there is no talebearer, the contention ceaseth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">[As] coals for hot coals, and wood for fire, so is a contentious man to inflame strife.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The words of a talebearer are as dainty morsels, and they go down into the innermost parts of the belly.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Ardent lips, and a wicked heart, are [as] an earthen vessel overlaid with silver dross.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He that hateth dissembleth with his lips, but he layeth up deceit within him:</verse>
  <verse number="25">when his voice is gracious, believe him not, for there are seven abominations in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Though [his] hatred is covered by dissimulation, his wickedness shall be made manifest in the congregation.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whoso diggeth a pit shall fall therein; and he that rolleth a stone, it shall return upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A lying tongue hateth those that are injured by it, and a flattering mouth worketh ruin.</verse>
</chapter>