<chapter book="Proverbs" number="28" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The wicked flee when no man pursueth; but the righteous are bold as a lion.</verse>
  <verse number="2">By the transgression of a land many are the princes thereof; but by a man of understanding [and] of knowledge, [its] stability is prolonged.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A poor man who oppresseth the helpless is a sweeping rain which leaveth no food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They that forsake the law praise the wicked; but such as keep the law contend with them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Evil men understand not judgment; but they that seek Jehovah understand everything.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Better is the poor that walketh in his integrity, than he that is perverse, double in ways, though he be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Whoso observeth the law is a son that hath understanding; but he that is a companion of profligates bringeth shame to his father.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He that by usury and unjust gain increaseth his substance gathereth it for him that is gracious to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He that turneth away his ear from hearing the law, even his prayer is an abomination.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Whoso causeth the upright to go astray in an evil way, shall himself fall into his own pit; but the perfect shall inherit good.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A rich man is wise in his own eyes; but the poor that hath understanding searcheth him out.</verse>
  <verse number="12">When the righteous triumph, there is great glory; but when the wicked rise, men conceal themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He that covereth his transgressions shall not prosper; but whoso confesseth and forsaketh [them] shall obtain mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Happy is the man that feareth always; but he that hardeneth his heart shall fall into evil.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A roaring lion, and a ranging bear, is a wicked ruler over a poor people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The prince void of intelligence is also a great oppressor: he that hateth covetousness shall prolong [his] days.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A man laden with the blood of [any] person, fleeth to the pit: let no man stay him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Whoso walketh in integrity shall be saved; but he that is perverted in [his] double ways, shall fall in one [of them].</verse>
  <verse number="19">He that tilleth his land shall be satisfied with bread; but he that followeth the worthless shall have poverty enough.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A faithful man aboundeth with blessings; but he that maketh haste to be rich shall not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To have respect of persons is not good; but for a piece of bread will a man transgress.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He that hath an evil eye hasteth after wealth, and knoweth not that poverty shall come upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He that rebuketh a man shall afterwards find more favour than he that flattereth with the tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Whoso robbeth his father and his mother, and saith, It is no transgression, the same is the companion of a destroyer.</verse>
  <verse number="25">He that is puffed up in soul exciteth contention; but he that relieth upon Jehovah shall be made fat.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He that confideth in his own heart is a fool; but whoso walketh wisely, he shall be delivered.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He that giveth unto the poor shall not lack; but he that withdraweth his eyes shall have many a curse.</verse>
  <verse number="28">When the wicked rise, men hide themselves; but when they perish, the righteous increase.</verse>
</chapter>