<chapter book="Proverbs" number="3" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, forget not my teaching, and let thy heart observe my commandments;</verse>
  <verse number="2">for length of days, and years of life, and peace shall they add to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let not loving-kindness and truth forsake thee; bind them about thy neck, write them upon the tablet of thy heart:</verse>
  <verse number="4">and thou shalt find favour and good understanding in the sight of God and man.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Confide in Jehovah with all thy heart, and lean not unto thine own intelligence;</verse>
  <verse number="6">in all thy ways acknowledge him, and he will make plain thy paths.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be not wise in thine own eyes; fear Jehovah, and depart from evil:</verse>
  <verse number="8">it shall be health for thy navel, and moisture for thy bones.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Honour Jehovah with thy substance, and with the first-fruits of all thine increase;</verse>
  <verse number="10">so shall thy barns be filled with plenty, and thy vats shall overflow with new wine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, despise not the instruction of Jehovah, neither be weary of his chastisement;</verse>
  <verse number="12">for whom Jehovah loveth he chasteneth, even as a father the son in whom he delighteth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Blessed is the man that findeth wisdom, and the man that getteth understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the gain thereof is better than the gain of silver, and her revenue than fine gold.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She is more precious than rubies; and all the things thou canst desire are not equal unto her.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Length of days is in her right hand; in her left hand riches and honour.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Her ways are ways of pleasantness, and all her paths are peace.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She is a tree of life to them that lay hold upon her; and happy is he that retaineth her.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Jehovah by wisdom founded the earth; by understanding he established the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By his knowledge the deeps were broken up, and the skies drop down the dew.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, let them not depart from thine eyes; keep sound wisdom and discretion:</verse>
  <verse number="22">so shall they be life unto thy soul, and grace unto thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then shalt thou walk in thy way securely, and thy foot shall not stumble;</verse>
  <verse number="24">when thou liest down, thou shalt not be afraid, but thou shalt lie down and thy sleep shall be sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Be not afraid of sudden fear, neither of the destruction of the wicked, when it cometh;</verse>
  <verse number="26">for Jehovah shall be thy confidence, and he will keep thy foot from being taken.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Withhold not good from them to whom it is due, when it is in the power of thy hand to do it.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Say not unto thy neighbour, Go, and come again, and to-morrow I will give, when thou hast it by thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Devise not evil against thy neighbour, seeing he dwelleth securely by thee.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Strive not with a man without cause, if he have done thee no harm.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Envy not the man of violence, and choose none of his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the perverse is an abomination to Jehovah; but his secret is with the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The curse of Jehovah is in the house of the wicked; but he blesseth the habitation of the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="34">He indeed scorneth the scorners; but he giveth grace unto the lowly.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The wise shall inherit glory; but shame shall be the promotion of the foolish.</verse>
</chapter>