<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if thou hast become surety for thy friend, if thou hast stricken thy hand for a stranger,</verse>
  <verse number="2">thou art snared with the words of thy mouth, thou art taken with the words of thy mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do this now, my son, and deliver thyself, since thou hast come into the hand of thy friend: go, humble thyself, and be urgent with thy friend.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Give not sleep to thine eyes, nor slumber to thine eyelids:</verse>
  <verse number="5">deliver thyself as a gazelle from the hand [of the hunter], and as a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go to the ant, thou sluggard; consider her ways and be wise:</verse>
  <verse number="7">which having no chief, overseer, or ruler,</verse>
  <verse number="8">provideth her bread in the summer, [and] gathereth her food in the harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">How long, sluggard, wilt thou lie down? When wilt thou arise out of thy sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to rest!</verse>
  <verse number="11">So shall thy poverty come as a roving plunderer, and thy penury as an armed man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A man of Belial, a wicked person, is he that goeth about with a perverse mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="13">he winketh with his eyes, he speaketh with his feet, he teacheth with his fingers;</verse>
  <verse number="14">deceits are in his heart; he deviseth mischief at all times, he soweth discords.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore shall his calamity come suddenly: in a moment shall he be broken, and without remedy.</verse>
  <verse number="16">These six [things] doth Jehovah hate, yea, seven are an abomination unto him:</verse>
  <verse number="17">haughty eyes, a lying tongue, and hands that shed innocent blood;</verse>
  <verse number="18">a heart that deviseth wicked imaginations; feet that are swift in running to mischief;</verse>
  <verse number="19">a false witness that uttereth lies, and he that soweth discords among brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, observe thy father’s commandment, and forsake not the teaching of thy mother;</verse>
  <verse number="21">bind them continually upon thy heart, tie them about thy neck:</verse>
  <verse number="22">when thou walkest, it shall lead thee; when thou sleepest, it shall keep thee; and [when] thou awakest, it shall talk with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the commandment is a lamp, and the teaching a light, and reproofs of instruction are the way of life:</verse>
  <verse number="24">to keep thee from the evil woman, from the flattery of the tongue of a strange woman.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Lust not after her beauty in thy heart, neither let her take thee with her eyelids;</verse>
  <verse number="26">for by means of a whorish woman [a man is brought] to a loaf of bread, and another’s wife doth hunt for the precious soul.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Can a man take fire in his bosom, and his garments not be burned?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Can one go upon hot coals, and his feet not be scorched?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So he that goeth in to his neighbour’s wife: whosoever toucheth her shall not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="30">They do not despise a thief, if he steal to satisfy his soul when he is hungry:</verse>
  <verse number="31">and if he be found, he shall restore sevenfold; he shall give all the substance of his house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Whoso committeth adultery with a woman is void of understanding: he that doeth it destroyeth his own soul.</verse>
  <verse number="33">A wound and contempt shall he get; and his reproach shall not be wiped away.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For jealousy is the rage of a man, and he will not spare in the day of vengeance;</verse>
  <verse number="35">he will not regard any ransom, neither will he rest content though thou multipliest [thy] gifts.</verse>
</chapter>