<chapter book="Proverbs" number="8" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Doth not wisdom cry? and understanding give forth her voice?</verse>
  <verse number="2">On the top of high places by the way, at the cross-paths she taketh her stand.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Beside the gates, at the entry of the city, at the coming in at the doors, she crieth aloud.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Unto you, men, I call, and my voice is to the sons of man:</verse>
  <verse number="5">O ye simple, understand prudence; and ye foolish, understand sense.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Hear, for I will speak excellent things, and the opening of my lips shall be right things.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For my palate shall meditate truth, and wickedness is an abomination to my lips.</verse>
  <verse number="8">All the words of my mouth are in righteousness; there is nothing tortuous or perverse in them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They are all plain to him that understandeth, and right to them that find knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Receive my instruction, and not silver; and knowledge rather than choice gold:</verse>
  <verse number="11">for wisdom is better than rubies, and all the things that may be desired are not equal to it.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I wisdom dwell [with] prudence, and find the knowledge [which cometh] of reflection.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fear of Jehovah is to hate evil; pride, and arrogancy, and the evil way, and the froward mouth do I hate.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Counsel is mine, and sound wisdom: I am intelligence; I have strength.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By me kings reign, and rulers make just decrees;</verse>
  <verse number="16">by me princes rule, and nobles, all the judges of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I love those that love me; and they that seek me early shall find me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Riches and honour are with me; durable wealth and righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="19">My fruit is better than fine gold, yea, than pure gold; and my revenue than choice silver.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I walk in the path of righteousness, in the midst of the paths of judgment:</verse>
  <verse number="21">that I may cause those that love me to inherit substance; and I will fill their treasuries.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Jehovah possessed me in the beginning of his way, before his works of old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">I was set up from eternity, from the beginning, before the earth was.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When there were no depths, I was brought forth, when there were no fountains abounding with water.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Before the mountains were settled, before the hills was I brought forth;</verse>
  <verse number="26">while as yet he had not made the earth, nor the fields, nor the beginning of the dust of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When he prepared the heavens I was there; when he ordained the circle upon the face of the deep;</verse>
  <verse number="28">when he established the skies above, when the fountains of the deep became strong;</verse>
  <verse number="29">when he imposed on the sea his decree that the waters should not pass his commandment, when he appointed the foundations of the earth:</verse>
  <verse number="30">then I was by him [his] nursling, and I was daily his delight, rejoicing always before him;</verse>
  <verse number="31">rejoicing in the habitable part of his earth, and my delights [were] with the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And now, sons, hearken unto me, and blessed are they that keep my ways:</verse>
  <verse number="33">hear instruction and be wise, and refuse it not.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Blessed is the man that heareth me, watching daily at my gates, waiting at the posts of my doors.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For whoso findeth me findeth life, and obtaineth favour of Jehovah;</verse>
  <verse number="36">but he that sinneth against me doeth violence to his own soul: all they that hate me love death.</verse>
</chapter>