<chapter book="Luke" number="20" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">On one of those days while He was teaching the people in the Temple and proclaiming the Good News, the High Priests came upon Him, and the Scribes,</verse>
  <verse number="2">together with the Elders, and they asked Him, “Tell us, By what authority are you doing these things? And who is it that gave you this authority?”</verse>
  <verse number="3">“I also will put a question to you, “He said;</verse>
  <verse number="4">“was John’s baptism of Heavenly or of human origin?”</verse>
  <verse number="5">So they debated the matter with one another. “If we say ‘Heavenly,’” they argued, “he will say, ‘Why did you not believe him?’</verse>
  <verse number="6">And if we say, ‘human,’ the people will all stone us; for they are thoroughly convinced that John was a Prophet.”</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they answered that they did not know the origin of it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">“Nor will I tell you,” said Jesus, “by what authority I do these things.”</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then He proceeded to speak a parable to the people. “There was a man,” He said, “who planted a vineyard, let it out to vine-dressers, and went abroad for a considerable time.</verse>
  <verse number="10">At vintage-time he sent a servant to the vine-dressers, for them to give him a share of the crop; but the vine-dressers beat him cruelly and sent him away empty-handed.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Then he sent a second servant; and him too they beat and ill treated and sent away empty-handed.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Then again he sent a third; and this one also they wounded and drove away.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then the owner of the vineyard said, “’What am I to do? I will send my son—my dearly-loved son: they will probably respect him.’</verse>
  <verse number="14">“But when the vine-dressers saw him, they discussed the matter with one another, and said, “’This is the heir: let us kill him, that the inheritance may be ours.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">“So they turned him out of the vineyard and murdered him. What then will the owner of the vineyard do to them?</verse>
  <verse number="16">He will come and put these vine-dressers to death, and give the vineyard to others.” “God forbid!” exclaimed the hearers.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He looked at them and said, “What then does that mean which is written, “’The Stone which the builders rejected has been made the cornerstone’?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Every one who falls on that stone will be severely hurt, but on whomsoever it falls, he will be utterly crushed.”</verse>
  <verse number="19">At this the Scribes and the High Priests wanted to lay hands on Him, then and there; only they were afraid of the people. For they saw that in this parable He had referred to them.</verse>
  <verse number="20">So, after impatiently watching their opportunity, they sent spies who were to act the part of good and honest men, that they might fasten on some expression of His, so as to hand Him over to the ruling power and the Governor’s authority.</verse>
  <verse number="21">So they put a question to Him. “Rabbi,” they said, “we know that you say and teach what is right and that you make no distinctions between one man and another, but teach God’s way truly.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Is it allowable to pay a tax to Caesar, or not?”</verse>
  <verse number="23">But He saw through their knavery and replied,</verse>
  <verse number="24">“Show me a shilling; whose likeness and inscription does it bear?” “Caesar’s,” they said.</verse>
  <verse number="25">“Pay therefore,” He replied, “what is Caesar’s to Caesar—and what is God’s to God.”</verse>
  <verse number="26">There was nothing here that they could lay hold of before the people, and marvelling at His answer they said no more.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Next some of the Sadducees came forward (who deny that there is a Resurrection)</verse>
  <verse number="28">“Rabbi, Moses made it a law for us that if a man’s brother should die, leaving a wife but no children, the man shall marry the widow and raise up a family for his brother.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Now there were seven brothers. The first of them took a wife and died childless.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The second and the third also took her;</verse>
  <verse number="31">and all seven, having done the same, left no children when they died.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Finally the woman also died.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The woman, then—at the Resurrection—whose wife shall she be? for they all seven married her.”</verse>
  <verse number="34">“The men of this age,” replied Jesus, “marry, and the women are given in marriage.</verse>
  <verse number="35">But as for those who shall have been deemed worthy to find a place in that other age and in the Resurrection from among the dead, the men do not marry and the women are not given in marriage.</verse>
  <verse number="36">For indeed they cannot die again; they are like angels, and are sons of God through being sons of the Resurrection.</verse>
  <verse number="37">But that the dead rise to life even Moses clearly implies in the passage about the Bush, where he calls the Lord ‘The God of Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob.’</verse>
  <verse number="38">He is not a God of dead, but of living men, for to Him are all living.”</verse>
  <verse number="39">Then some of the Scribes replied, “Rabbi, you have spoken well.”</verse>
  <verse number="40">From that time, however, no one ventured to challenge Him with a single question.</verse>
  <verse number="41">But He asked them, “How is it they say that the Christ is a son of David?</verse>
  <verse number="42">Why, David himself says in the Book of Psalms, “’The Lord said to my Lord, Sit at My right hand</verse>
  <verse number="43">Until I have made thy foes a footstool under they feet.’</verse>
  <verse number="44">“David himself therefore calls Him Lord, and how can He be his son?”</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then, in the hearing of all the people, He said to the disciples,</verse>
  <verse number="46">“Beware of the Scribes, who like to walk about in long robes, and love to be bowed to in places of public resort and to occupy the best seats in the synagogues or at a dinner party;</verse>
  <verse number="47">who swallow up the property of widows and mask their wickedness by making long prayers. They will be punished far more severely than others.”</verse>
</chapter>