<chapter book="Luke" number="24" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And, on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they came to the tomb bringing the spices they had prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="2">But they found the stone rolled back from the tomb,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and on entering they found that the body of the Lord Jesus was not there.</verse>
  <verse number="4">At this they were in great perplexity, when suddenly there stood by them two men whose raiment flashed like lightning.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The women were terrified; but, as they stood with their faces bowed to the ground, the men said to them, “Why do you search among the dead for Him who is living?</verse>
  <verse number="6">He is not here. He has come back to life. Remember how He spoke to you while He was still in Galilee,</verse>
  <verse number="7">when He told you that the Son of Man must be betrayed into the hands of sinful men, and be crucified, and on the third day rise again.”</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then they remembered His words,</verse>
  <verse number="9">and returning from the tomb they reported all this to the Eleven and to all the rest.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The women were Mary of Magdala, Joanna, and Mary the mother of James; and they and the rest of the women related all this to the Apostles.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But the whole story seemed to them an idle tale; they could not believe the women.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Peter, however, rose and ran to the tomb. Stooping and looking in, he saw nothing but the linen cloths: so he went away to his own home, wondering at what had happened.</verse>
  <verse number="13">On that same day two of the disciples were walking to Emmaus, a village seven or eight miles from Jerusalem,</verse>
  <verse number="14">and were conversing about all these recent events;</verse>
  <verse number="15">and, in the midst of their conversation and discussion, Jesus Himself came and joined them,</verse>
  <verse number="16">though they were prevented from recognizing Him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">“What is the subject,” He asked them, “on which you are talking so earnestly, as you walk?” And they stood still, looking full of sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Then one of them, named Cleopas, answered, “Are you a stranger lodging alone in Jerusalem, that you have known nothing of the things that have lately happened in the city?”</verse>
  <verse number="19">“What things?” He asked. “The things about Jesus the Nazarene,” they said, “who was a Prophet powerful in work and word before God and all the people;</verse>
  <verse number="20">and how our High Priests and Rulers delivered Him up to be sentenced to death, and crucified Him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But we were hoping that it was He who was about to ransom Israel. Yes, and moreover it was the day before yesterday that these things happened.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And, besides, some of the women of our company have amazed us. They went to the tomb at daybreak,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and, finding that His body was not there, they came and declared to us that they had also seen a vision of angels who said that He was alive.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Thereupon some of our party went to the tomb and found things just as the women had said; but Jesus Himself they did not see.”</verse>
  <verse number="25">“O dull-witted men,” He replied, “with minds so slow to believe all that the Prophets have spoken!</verse>
  <verse number="26">Was there not a necessity for the Christ thus to suffer, and then enter into His glory?”</verse>
  <verse number="27">And, beginning with Moses and all the Prophets, He explained to them the passages in Scripture which refer to Himself.</verse>
  <verse number="28">When they had come near the village to which they were going, He appeared to be going further.</verse>
  <verse number="29">But they pressed Him to remain with them. “Because,” said they, “it is getting towards evening, and the day is nearly over.” So He went in to stay with them.</verse>
  <verse number="30">But as soon as He had sat down with them, and had taken the bread and had blessed and broken it, and was handing it to them,</verse>
  <verse number="31">their eyes were opened and they recognized Him. But He vanished from them.</verse>
  <verse number="32">“Were not our hearts,” they said to one another, “burning within us while He talked to us on the way and explained the Scriptures to us?”</verse>
  <verse number="33">So they rose and without an hour’s delay returned to Jerusalem, and found the Eleven and the rest met together, who said to them,</verse>
  <verse number="34">“Yes, it is true: the Master has come back to life. He has been seen by Simon.”</verse>
  <verse number="35">Then they related what had happened on the way, and how He had been recognized by them in the breaking of the bread.</verse>
  <verse number="36">While they were thus talking, He Himself stood in their midst and said, “Peace be to you!”</verse>
  <verse number="37">Startled, and in the utmost alarm, they thought they were looking at a spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="38">but He said to them, “Why such alarm? And why are there such questionings in your minds?</verse>
  <verse number="39">See my hands and my feet—it is my very self. Feel me and see, for a spirit has not flesh and bones as you see I have.”</verse>
  <verse number="40">And then He showed them His hands and His feet.</verse>
  <verse number="41">But, while they still could not believe it for joy and were full of astonishment, He asked them, “Have you any food here?”</verse>
  <verse number="42">And they gave Him a piece of roasted fish,</verse>
  <verse number="43">and He took it and ate it in their presence.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And He said to them, “This is what I told you while I was still with you—that everything must be fulfilled that is written in the Law of Moses and in the Prophets and the Psalms concerning me.”</verse>
  <verse number="45">Then He opened their minds to understand the Scriptures,</verse>
  <verse number="46">and He said, “Thus it is written that the Christ would suffer and on the third day rise again from among the dead;</verse>
  <verse number="47">and that proclamation would be made, in His name, of repentance and forgiveness of sins to all the nations, beginning in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="48">You are witnesses as to these things.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And remember that I am about to send out my Father’s promised gift to rest upon you. But, as for you, wait patiently in the city until you are clothed with power from on high.”</verse>
  <verse number="50">And He brought them out to within view of Bethany, and then lifted up His hands and blessed them.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And while He was blessing them, He parted from them and was carried up into Heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="52">They worshipped Him, and returned to Jerusalem with great joy.</verse>
  <verse number="53">Afterwards they were continually in attendance at the Temple, blessing God.</verse>
</chapter>