<chapter book="Titus" number="1" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, bondman of God, and apostle of Jesus Christ according to [the] faith of God’s elect, and knowledge of [the] truth which [is] according to piety;</verse>
  <verse number="2">in [the] hope of eternal life, which God, who cannot lie, promised before the ages of time,</verse>
  <verse number="3">but has manifested in its own due season his word, in [the] proclamation with which I have been entrusted, according to [the] commandment of our Saviour God;</verse>
  <verse number="4">to Titus, my own child according to [the] faith common [to us]: Grace and peace from God [the] Father, and Christ Jesus our Saviour.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For this cause I left thee in Crete, that thou mightest go on to set right what remained [unordered], and establish elders in each city, as I had ordered thee:</verse>
  <verse number="6">if any one be free from all charge [against him], husband of one wife, having believing children not accused of excess or unruly.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For the overseer must be free from all charge [against him] as God’s steward; not headstrong, not passionate, not disorderly through wine, not a striker, not seeking gain by base means;</verse>
  <verse number="8">but hospitable, a lover of goodness, discreet, just, pious, temperate,</verse>
  <verse number="9">clinging to the faithful word according to the doctrine taught, that he may be able both to encourage with sound teaching and refute gainsayers.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For there are many and disorderly vain speakers and deceivers of people’s minds, specially those of [the] circumcision,</verse>
  <verse number="11">who must have their mouths stopped, who subvert whole houses, teaching things which ought not [to be taught] for the sake of base gain.</verse>
  <verse number="12">One of themselves, a prophet of their own, has said, Cretans are always liars, evil wild beasts, lazy gluttons.</verse>
  <verse number="13">This testimony is true; for which cause rebuke them severely, that they may be sound in the faith,</verse>
  <verse number="14">not turning [their] minds to Jewish fables and commandments of men turning away from the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="15">All things [are] pure to the pure; but to the defiled and unbelieving nothing [is] pure; but both their mind and their conscience are defiled.</verse>
  <verse number="16">They profess to know God, but in works deny [him], being abominable, and disobedient, and found worthless as to every good work.</verse>
</chapter>