<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="24" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now these were the divisions of the sons of Aaron. The sons of Aaron: Nadab, and Abihu, and Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="2">But Nadab and Abihu died before their father, and without children. And so Eleazar and Ithamar exercised the priestly office.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And David distributed them, that is, Zadok of the sons of Eleazar, and Ahimelech of the sons of Ithamar, according to their courses and ministry.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And there were found many more of the sons of Eleazar among the leading men, than of the sons of Ithamar. Therefore, he divided them so that there were, of the sons of Eleazar, sixteen leaders by their families, and of the sons of Ithamar eight by their families and houses.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then he divided among them, in both families, by lot. For there were leaders of the sanctuary and leaders of God, as much from the sons of Eleazar as from the sons of Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the scribe Shemaiah, the son of Nethanel, a Levite, wrote these down before the king and the leaders, with Zadok, the priest, and Ahimelech, the son of Abiathar, and also the leaders of the priestly and Levitical families. And there was one house, which was preeminent over the others, that of Eleazar; and there was another house, which had the others under it, that of Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Now the first lot went forth to Jehoiarib, the second to Jedaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="8">the third to Harim, the fourth to Seorim,</verse>
  <verse number="9">the fifth to Malchijah, the sixth to Mijamin,</verse>
  <verse number="10">the seventh to Hakkoz, the eighth to Abijah,</verse>
  <verse number="11">the ninth to Jeshua, the tenth to Shecaniah,</verse>
  <verse number="12">the eleventh to Eliashib, the twelfth to Jakim,</verse>
  <verse number="13">the thirteenth to Huppah, the fourteenth to Jeshebeab,</verse>
  <verse number="14">the fifteenth to Bilgah, the sixteenth to Immer,</verse>
  <verse number="15">the seventeenth to Hezir, the eighteenth to Happizzez,</verse>
  <verse number="16">the nineteenth to Pethahiah, the twentieth to Jehezkel,</verse>
  <verse number="17">the twenty-first to Jachin, the twenty-second to Gamul,</verse>
  <verse number="18">the twenty-third to Delaiah, the twenty-fourth to Maaziah.</verse>
  <verse number="19">These were their courses according to their ministries, so that they would enter into the house of the Lord in accord with their practice, under the hand of Aaron, their father, just as the Lord, the God of Israel, had instructed.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Now of the sons of Levi who were remaining, there were Shubael, from the sons of Amram, and Jehdeiah, from the sons of Shubael.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Also, there were Isshiah, the leader from the sons of Rehabiah,</verse>
  <verse number="22">and truly Shelomoth, the son of Izhar, and Jahath, the son of Shelomoth,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and his son, Jeriah the first, Amariah the second, Jahaziel the third, Jekameam the fourth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The son of Uzziel was Micah. The son of Micah was Shamir.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The brother of Micah was Isshiah. And the son of Isshiah was Zechariah.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The sons of Merari were Mahli and Mushi. The son of Uzziah was Beno.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Also, the son of Merari: Uzziah, and Shoham, and Zaccur, and Hebri.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In addition, the son of Mahli was Eleazar, who had no children.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Truly, the son of Kish was Jerahmeel.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The sons of Mushi were Mahli, Eder, and Jerimoth. These were the sons of Levi according to the houses of their families.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they also cast lots concerning their brothers, the sons of Aaron, before David the king, and Zadok, and Ahimelech, and the leaders of the priestly and Levitical families, as much concerning the elder as the younger. The lot divided all things equitably.</verse>
</chapter>