<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="8" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now Benjamin conceived Bela as his firstborn, Ashbel the second, Aharah the third,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Nohah the fourth, and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the sons of Bela were: Addar, and Gera, and Abihud,</verse>
  <verse number="4">as well as Abishua, and Naaman, and Ahoah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">then also Gera, and Shephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
  <verse number="6">These are the sons of Ehud, leaders of the kindred living in Geba, who were moved away to Manahath.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Naaman, and Ahijah, and Gera, he also moved them away; and he conceived Uzza and Ahihud.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then Shaharaim conceived, in the region of Moab, after he sent away Hushim and Baara, his wives;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and so, of his wife Hodesh, he conceived Jobab, and Zibia, and Mesha, and Malcam,</verse>
  <verse number="10">and also Jeuz and Sachia, and Mirmah. These were his sons, the leaders of their families.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Truly, of Hushim he conceived Abitub and Elpaal.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the sons of Elpaal were Eber, and Misham, and Shemed, who built Ono and Lod and its daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Now Beriah and Shema were leaders of their families living in Aijalon; these put to flight the inhabitants of Gath.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Ahio, and Shashak, and Jeremoth,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Zebadiah, and Arad, and Eder,</verse>
  <verse number="16">as well as Michael, and Ishpah, and Joha, were the sons of Beriah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Then Zebadiah, and Meshullam, and Hizki, and Heber,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and Ishmerai, and Izliah, and Jobab were the sons of Elpaal.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Then Jakim, and Zichri, and Zabdi,</verse>
  <verse number="20">and Elienai, and Zillethai, and Eliel,</verse>
  <verse number="21">and Adaiah, and Beraiah, and Shimrath were the sons of Shimei.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then Ishpan, and Eber, and Eliel,</verse>
  <verse number="23">and Abdon, and Zichri, and Hanan,</verse>
  <verse number="24">and Hananiah, and Elam, and Anthothijah,</verse>
  <verse number="25">and Iphdeiah, and Penuel were the sons of Shashak.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then Shamsherai, and Shehariah and Athaliah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and Jaareshiah, and Elijah, and Zichri were the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
  <verse number="28">These were the patriarchs and leaders of the families who were living in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Now in Gibeon, there lived Jeiel, the father of Gibeon; and the name of his wife was Maacah,</verse>
  <verse number="30">and his firstborn son was Abdon, and then Zur, and Kish, and Baal, and Nadab,</verse>
  <verse number="31">and Gedor, and Ahio, and Zecher, and Mikloth.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Mikloth conceived Shimeah. And they lived opposite their brothers in Jerusalem, with their brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Now Ner conceived Kish, and Kish conceived Saul. Then Saul conceived Jonathan, and Malchishua, and Abinadab, and Eshbaal.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And the son of Jonathan was Meribbaal; and Meribbaal conceived Micah.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The sons of Micah were Pithon, and Melech, and Tarea, and Ahaz.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Ahaz conceived Jehoaddah. And Jehoaddah conceived Alemeth, and Azmaveth, and Zimri. And Zimri conceived Moza.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Moza conceived Binea, whose son was Raphah, of whom was born Eleasah, who conceived Azel.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Now there were six sons for Azel, whose names were Azrikam, Bocheru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan. All these were the sons of Azel.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Then the sons of Eshek, his brother, were Ulam the firstborn, and Jeush the second, and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the sons of Ulam were very robust men, drawing the bow with great strength. And they had many sons and grandsons, even to one hundred fifty. All these were sons of Benjamin.</verse>
</chapter>