<chapter book="Proverbs" number="11" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Dishonest scales are an abomination to the LORD, but an accurate weight is His delight.</verse>
  <verse number="2">When pride comes, disgrace follows, but with humility comes wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The integrity of the upright guides them, but the perversity of the faithless destroys them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Riches are worthless in the day of wrath, but righteousness brings deliverance from death.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The righteousness of the blameless directs their path, but the wicked fall by their own wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The righteousness of the upright delivers them, but the faithless are trapped by their own desires.</verse>
  <verse number="7">When the wicked man dies, his hope perishes, and the hope of his strength vanishes.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The righteous man is delivered from trouble; in his place the wicked man goes in.</verse>
  <verse number="9">With his mouth the ungodly man destroys his neighbor, but through knowledge the righteous are rescued.</verse>
  <verse number="10">When the righteous thrive, the city rejoices, and when the wicked perish, there are shouts of joy.</verse>
  <verse number="11">By the blessing of the upright a city is built up, but by the mouth of the wicked it is torn down.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Whoever shows contempt for his neighbor lacks judgment, but a man of understanding remains silent.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A gossip reveals a secret, but a trustworthy person keeps a confidence.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For lack of guidance, a nation falls, but with many counselors comes deliverance.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He who puts up security for a stranger will surely suffer, but the one who hates indebtedness is secure.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A gracious woman attains honor, but ruthless men gain only wealth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A kind man benefits himself, but a cruel man brings trouble on himself.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The wicked man earns an empty wage, but he who sows righteousness reaps a true reward.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Genuine righteousness leads to life, but the pursuit of evil brings death.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The perverse in heart are an abomination to the LORD, but the blameless in their walk are His delight.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Be assured that the wicked will not go unpunished, but the offspring of the righteous will escape.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Like a gold ring in a pig’s snout is a beautiful woman who lacks discretion.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The desire of the righteous leads only to good, but the hope of the wicked brings wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="24">One gives freely, yet gains even more; another withholds what is right, only to become poor.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A generous soul will prosper, and he who refreshes others will himself be refreshed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The people will curse the hoarder of grain, but blessing will crown the one who sells it.</verse>
  <verse number="27">He who searches out good finds favor, but evil will come to him who seeks it.</verse>
  <verse number="28">He who trusts in his riches will fall, but the righteous will thrive like foliage.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He who brings trouble on his house will inherit the wind, and the fool will be servant to the wise of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, and he who wins souls is wise.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If the righteous receive their due on earth, how much more the ungodly and the sinner!</verse>
</chapter>