<chapter book="Proverbs" number="14" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Every wise woman builds her house, but a foolish one tears it down with her own hands.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He who walks in uprightness fears the LORD, but the one who is devious in his ways despises Him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The proud speech of a fool brings a rod to his back, but the lips of the wise protect them.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Where there are no oxen, the manger is empty, but an abundant harvest comes through the strength of the ox.</verse>
  <verse number="5">An honest witness does not deceive, but a dishonest witness pours forth lies.</verse>
  <verse number="6">A mocker seeks wisdom and finds none, but knowledge comes easily to the discerning.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Stay away from a foolish man; you will gain no knowledge from his speech.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The wisdom of the prudent is to discern his way, but the folly of fools deceives them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Fools mock the making of amends, but goodwill is found among the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The heart knows its own bitterness, and no stranger shares in its joy.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The house of the wicked will be destroyed, but the tent of the upright will flourish.</verse>
  <verse number="12">There is a way that seems right to a man, but its end is the way of death.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Even in laughter the heart may ache, and joy may end in sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The backslider in heart receives the fill of his own ways, but a good man is rewarded for his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The simple man believes every word, but the prudent man watches his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A wise man fears and turns from evil, but a fool is careless and reckless.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A quick-tempered man acts foolishly, and a devious man is hated.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The simple inherit folly, but the prudent are crowned with knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The evil bow before the good, and the wicked at the gates of the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The poor man is hated even by his neighbor, but many are those who love the rich.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He who despises his neighbor sins, but blessed is he who shows kindness to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Do not those who contrive evil go astray? But those who plan goodness find loving devotion and faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="23">There is profit in all labor, but mere talk leads only to poverty.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The crown of the wise is their wealth, but the effort of fools is folly.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A truthful witness saves lives, but one who utters lies is deceitful.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He who fears the LORD is secure in confidence, and his children shall have a place of refuge.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The fear of the LORD is a fountain of life, turning a man from the snares of death.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A large population is a king’s splendor, but a lack of subjects is a prince’s ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A patient man has great understanding, but a quick-tempered man promotes folly.</verse>
  <verse number="30">A tranquil heart is life to the body, but envy rots the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Whoever oppresses the poor taunts their Maker, but whoever is kind to the needy honors Him.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The wicked man is thrown down by his own sin, but the righteous man has a refuge even in death.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Wisdom rests in the heart of the discerning; even among fools she is known.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Righteousness exalts a nation, but sin is a disgrace to any people.</verse>
  <verse number="35">A king delights in a wise servant, but his anger falls on the shameful.</verse>
</chapter>