<chapter book="Proverbs" number="23" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When you sit down to dine with a ruler, consider carefully what is set before you,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and put a knife to your throat if you possess a great appetite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do not crave his delicacies, for that food is deceptive.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Do not wear yourself out to get rich; be wise enough to restrain yourself.</verse>
  <verse number="5">When you glance at wealth, it disappears, for it makes wings for itself and flies like an eagle to the sky.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Do not eat the bread of a stingy man, and do not crave his delicacies;</verse>
  <verse number="7">for he is keeping track, inwardly counting the cost. “Eat and drink,” he says to you, but his heart is not with you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">You will vomit up what little you have eaten and waste your pleasant words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Do not speak to a fool, for he will despise the wisdom of your words.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Do not move an ancient boundary stone or encroach on the fields of the fatherless,</verse>
  <verse number="11">for their Redeemer is strong; He will take up their case against you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Apply your heart to instruction and your ears to words of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Do not withhold discipline from a child; although you strike him with a rod, he will not die.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Strike him with a rod, and you will deliver his soul from Sheol.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, if your heart is wise, my own heart will indeed rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="16">My inmost being will rejoice when your lips speak what is right.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Do not let your heart envy sinners, but always continue in the fear of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For surely there is a future, and your hope will not be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Listen, my son, and be wise, and guide your heart on the right course.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Do not join those who drink too much wine or gorge themselves on meat.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the drunkard and the glutton will come to poverty, and drowsiness will clothe them in rags.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Listen to your father who gave you life, and do not despise your mother when she is old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Invest in truth and never sell it—in wisdom and instruction and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The father of a righteous man will greatly rejoice, and he who fathers a wise son will delight in him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">May your father and mother be glad, and may she who gave you birth rejoice!</verse>
  <verse number="26">My son, give me your heart, and let your eyes delight in my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For a prostitute is a deep pit, and an adulteress is a narrow well.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Like a robber she lies in wait and multiplies the faithless among men.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Who has woe? Who has sorrow? Who has contentions? Who has complaints? Who has needless wounds? Who has bloodshot eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Those who linger over wine, who go to taste mixed drinks.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Do not gaze at wine while it is red, when it sparkles in the cup and goes down smoothly.</verse>
  <verse number="32">In the end it bites like a snake and stings like a viper.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Your eyes will see strange things, and your mind will utter perversities.</verse>
  <verse number="34">You will be like one sleeping on the high seas or lying on the top of a mast:</verse>
  <verse number="35">“They struck me, but I feel no pain! They beat me, but I did not know it! When can I wake up to search for another drink?”</verse>
</chapter>