<chapter book="Proverbs" number="24" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Do not envy wicked men or desire their company;</verse>
  <verse number="2">for their hearts devise violence, and their lips declare trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="3">By wisdom a house is built and by understanding it is established;</verse>
  <verse number="4">through knowledge its rooms are filled with every precious and beautiful treasure.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A wise man is strong, and a man of knowledge enhances his strength.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Only with sound guidance should you wage war, and victory lies in a multitude of counselors.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Wisdom is too high for a fool; he does not open his mouth in the meeting place.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He who plots evil will be called a schemer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A foolish scheme is sin, and a mocker is detestable to men.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If you faint in the day of distress, how small is your strength!</verse>
  <verse number="11">Rescue those being led away to death, and restrain those stumbling toward the slaughter.</verse>
  <verse number="12">If you say, “Behold, we did not know about this,” does not He who weighs hearts consider it? Does not the One who guards your life know? Will He not repay a man according to his deeds?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Eat honey, my son, for it is good, and the honeycomb is sweet to your taste.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Know therefore that wisdom is sweet to your soul. If you find it, there is a future for you, and your hope will never be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Do not lie in wait, O wicked man, near the dwelling of the righteous; do not destroy his resting place.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For though a righteous man may fall seven times, he still gets up; but the wicked stumble in bad times.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Do not gloat when your enemy falls, and do not let your heart rejoice when he stumbles,</verse>
  <verse number="18">or the LORD will see and disapprove, and turn His wrath away from him.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Do not fret over evildoers, and do not be envious of the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For the evil man has no future; the lamp of the wicked will be extinguished.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, fear the LORD and the king, and do not associate with the rebellious.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For they will bring sudden destruction. Who knows what ruin they can bring?</verse>
  <verse number="23">These also are sayings of the wise: To show partiality in judgment is not good.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Whoever tells the guilty, “You are innocent”—peoples will curse him, and nations will denounce him;</verse>
  <verse number="25">but it will go well with those who convict the guilty, and rich blessing will come upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="26">An honest answer given is like a kiss on the lips.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Complete your outdoor work and prepare your field; after that, you may build your house.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Do not testify against your neighbor without cause, and do not deceive with your lips.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Do not say, “I will do to him as he has done to me; I will repay the man according to his work.”</verse>
  <verse number="30">I went past the field of a slacker and by the vineyard of a man lacking judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Thorns had grown up everywhere, thistles had covered the ground, and the stone wall was broken down.</verse>
  <verse number="32">I observed and took it to heart; I looked and received instruction:</verse>
  <verse number="33">A little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to rest,</verse>
  <verse number="34">and poverty will come upon you like a robber, and need like a bandit.</verse>
</chapter>