<chapter book="Proverbs" number="25" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">These are additional proverbs of Solomon, which were copied by the men of Hezekiah king of Judah:</verse>
  <verse number="2">It is the glory of God to conceal a matter and the glory of kings to search it out.</verse>
  <verse number="3">As the heavens are high and the earth is deep, so the hearts of kings cannot be searched.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Remove the dross from the silver, and a vessel for a silversmith will come forth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Remove the wicked from the king’s presence, and his throne will be established in righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Do not exalt yourself in the presence of the king, and do not stand in the place of great men;</verse>
  <verse number="7">for it is better to be told, “Come up here!” than to be demoted in the presence of the prince. Even what you have seen with your own eyes,</verse>
  <verse number="8">do not bring hastily to court. Otherwise, what will you do in the end when your neighbor puts you to shame?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Argue your case with your neighbor without betraying another’s confidence,</verse>
  <verse number="10">lest he who hears you bring shame upon you, and your infamy never go away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A word fitly spoken is like apples of gold in settings of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Like an earring of gold or an ornament of fine gold is a wise man’s rebuke to a listening ear.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Like the cold of snow in the time of harvest is a trustworthy messenger to those who send him; he refreshes the soul of his masters.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Like clouds and wind without rain is the man who boasts of gifts never given.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Through patience a ruler can be persuaded, and a gentle tongue can break a bone.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If you find honey, eat just what you need, lest you have too much and vomit it up.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Seldom set foot in your neighbor’s house, lest he grow weary and hate you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Like a club or sword or sharp arrow is a man who bears false witness against his neighbor.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Like a broken tooth or a foot out of joint is confidence in a faithless man in time of trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Like one who removes a garment on a cold day or vinegar poured on a wound is one who sings songs to a heavy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If your enemy is hungry, give him food to eat, and if he is thirsty, give him water to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For in so doing, you will heap burning coals on his head, and the LORD will reward you.</verse>
  <verse number="23">As the north wind brings forth rain, so a backbiting tongue brings angry looks.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Better to live on a corner of the roof than to share a house with a quarrelsome wife.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Like cold water to a weary soul is good news from a distant land.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Like a muddied spring or a polluted well is a righteous man who gives way to the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is not good to eat too much honey or to search out one’s own glory.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Like a city whose walls are broken down is a man who does not control his temper.</verse>
</chapter>