<chapter book="Proverbs" number="27" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Do not boast about tomorrow, for you do not know what a day may bring.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Let another praise you, and not your own mouth—a stranger, and not your own lips.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A stone is heavy and sand is a burden, but aggravation from a fool outweighs them both.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Wrath is cruel and anger is like a flood, but who can withstand jealousy?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Better an open rebuke than love that is concealed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The wounds of a friend are faithful, but the kisses of an enemy are deceitful.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The soul that is full loathes honey, but to a hungry soul, any bitter thing is sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Like a bird that strays from its nest is a man who wanders from his home.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Oil and incense bring joy to the heart, and the counsel of a friend is sweetness to the soul.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Do not forsake your friend or your father’s friend, and do not go to your brother’s house in the day of your calamity; better a neighbor nearby than a brother far away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Be wise, my son, and bring joy to my heart, so that I can answer him who taunts me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The prudent see danger and take cover, but the simple keep going and pay the penalty.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Take the garment of him who posts security for a stranger; get collateral if it is for a foreigner.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If one blesses his neighbor with a loud voice early in the morning, it will be counted to him as a curse.</verse>
  <verse number="15">A constant dripping on a rainy day and a contentious woman are alike—</verse>
  <verse number="16">restraining her is like holding back the wind or grasping oil with one’s right hand.</verse>
  <verse number="17">As iron sharpens iron, so one man sharpens another.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Whoever tends a fig tree will eat its fruit, and he who looks after his master will be honored.</verse>
  <verse number="19">As water reflects the face, so the heart reflects the true man.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Sheol and Abaddon are never satisfied; so the eyes of man are never satisfied.</verse>
  <verse number="21">A crucible for silver and a furnace for gold, but a man is tested by the praise accorded him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Though you grind a fool like grain with mortar and a pestle, yet his folly will not depart from him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Be sure to know the state of your flocks, and pay close attention to your herds;</verse>
  <verse number="24">for riches are not forever, nor does a crown endure to every generation.</verse>
  <verse number="25">When hay is removed and new growth appears and the grass from the hills is gathered,</verse>
  <verse number="26">the lambs will provide you with clothing, and the goats with the price of a field.</verse>
  <verse number="27">You will have plenty of goats’ milk to feed you—food for your household and nourishment for your maidservants.</verse>
</chapter>