<chapter book="Proverbs" number="28" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The wicked flee when no one pursues, but the righteous are as bold as a lion.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A land in rebellion has many rulers, but a man of understanding and knowledge maintains order.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A destitute leader who oppresses the poor is like a driving rain that leaves no food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Those who forsake the law praise the wicked, but those who keep the law resist them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Evil men do not understand justice, but those who seek the LORD comprehend fully.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Better a poor man who walks with integrity than a rich man whose ways are perverse.</verse>
  <verse number="7">A discerning son keeps the law, but a companion of gluttons disgraces his father.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He who increases his wealth by interest and usury lays it up for one who is kind to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whoever turns his ear away from hearing the law, even his prayer is detestable.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He who leads the upright along the path of evil will fall into his own pit, but the blameless will inherit what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A rich man is wise in his own eyes, but a poor man with discernment sees through him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">When the righteous triumph, there is great glory, but when the wicked rise, men hide themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He who conceals his sins will not prosper, but whoever confesses and renounces them will find mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Blessed is the man who is always reverent, but he who hardens his heart falls into trouble.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Like a roaring lion or a charging bear is a wicked ruler over a helpless people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">A leader who lacks judgment is also a great oppressor, but he who hates dishonest profit will prolong his days.</verse>
  <verse number="17">A man burdened by bloodguilt will flee into the Pit; let no one support him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He who walks with integrity will be kept safe, but whoever is perverse in his ways will suddenly fall.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The one who works his land will have plenty of food, but whoever chases fantasies will have his fill of poverty.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A faithful man will abound with blessings, but one eager to be rich will not go unpunished.</verse>
  <verse number="21">To show partiality is not good, yet a man will do wrong for a piece of bread.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A stingy man hastens after wealth and does not know that poverty awaits him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He who rebukes a man will later find more favor than one who flatters with his tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He who robs his father or mother, saying, “It is not wrong,” is a companion to the man who destroys.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A greedy man stirs up strife, but he who trusts in the LORD will prosper.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He who trusts in himself is a fool, but one who walks in wisdom will be safe.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whoever gives to the poor will not be in need, but he who hides his eyes will receive many curses.</verse>
  <verse number="28">When the wicked come to power, people hide themselves; but when they perish, the righteous flourish.</verse>
</chapter>