<chapter book="Proverbs" number="7" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, keep my words and treasure my commandments within you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Keep my commandments and live; guard my teachings as the apple of your eye.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Tie them to your fingers; write them on the tablet of your heart.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Say to wisdom, “You are my sister,” and call understanding your kinsman,</verse>
  <verse number="5">that they may keep you from the adulteress, from the stranger with seductive words.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For at the window of my house I looked through the lattice.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I saw among the simple, I noticed among the youths, a young man lacking judgment,</verse>
  <verse number="8">crossing the street near her corner, strolling down the road to her house,</verse>
  <verse number="9">at twilight, as the day was fading into the dark of the night.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then a woman came out to meet him, with the attire of a harlot and cunning of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="11">She is loud and defiant; her feet do not remain at home.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now in the street, now in the squares, she lurks at every corner.</verse>
  <verse number="13">She seizes him and kisses him; she brazenly says to him:</verse>
  <verse number="14">“I have made my peace offerings; today I have paid my vows.</verse>
  <verse number="15">So I came out to meet you; I sought you, and I have found you.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I have decked my bed with coverings, with colored linen from Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I have perfumed my bed with myrrh, with aloes, and with cinnamon.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Come, let us take our fill of love till morning. Let us delight in loving caresses!</verse>
  <verse number="19">For my husband is not at home; he has gone on a long journey.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He took with him a bag of money and will not return till the moon is full.”</verse>
  <verse number="21">With her great persuasion she entices him; with her flattering lips she lures him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He follows her on impulse, like an ox going to the slaughter, like a deer bounding into a trap,</verse>
  <verse number="23">until an arrow pierces his liver, like a bird darting into a snare—not knowing it will cost him his life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Now, my sons, listen to me, and attend to the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Do not let your heart turn aside to her ways; do not stray into her paths.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For she has brought many down to death; her slain are many in number.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Her house is the road to Sheol, descending to the chambers of death.</verse>
</chapter>