<chapter book="Leviticus" number="10" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Nadab and Abihu, the sons of Aaron, took either of them his censer, and put fire therein, and put incense thereon, and offered strange fire before the LORD, which he commanded them not.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And there went out fire from the LORD, and devoured them, and they died before the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Moses said to Aaron, This is it that the LORD spoke, saying, I will be sanctified in them that come near me, and before all the people I will be glorified. And Aaron held his peace.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Moses called Mishael and Elzaphan, the sons of Uzziel the uncle of Aaron, and said to them, Come near, carry your brothers from before the sanctuary out of the camp.</verse>
  <verse number="5">So they went near, and carried them in their coats out of the camp; as Moses had said.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Moses said to Aaron, and to Eleazar and to Ithamar, his sons, Uncover not your heads, neither rend your clothes; lest you die, and lest wrath come on all the people: but let your brothers, the whole house of Israel, mourn the burning which the LORD has kindled.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And you shall not go out from the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, lest you die: for the anointing oil of the LORD is on you. And they did according to the word of Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the LORD spoke to Aaron, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="9">Do not drink wine nor strong drink, you, nor your sons with you, when you go into the tabernacle of the congregation, lest you die: it shall be a statute for ever throughout your generations:</verse>
  <verse number="10">And that you may put difference between holy and unholy, and between unclean and clean;</verse>
  <verse number="11">And that you may teach the children of Israel all the statutes which the LORD has spoken to them by the hand of Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Moses spoke to Aaron, and to Eleazar and to Ithamar, his sons that were left, Take the meat offering that remains of the offerings of the LORD made by fire, and eat it without leaven beside the altar: for it is most holy:</verse>
  <verse number="13">And you shall eat it in the holy place, because it is your due, and your sons’ due, of the sacrifices of the LORD made by fire: for so I am commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the wave breast and heave shoulder shall you eat in a clean place; you, and your sons, and your daughters with you: for they be your due, and your sons’ due, which are given out of the sacrifices of peace offerings of the children of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The heave shoulder and the wave breast shall they bring with the offerings made by fire of the fat, to wave it for a wave offering before the LORD; and it shall be yours, and your sons’ with you, by a statute for ever; as the LORD has commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Moses diligently sought the goat of the sin offering, and, behold, it was burnt: and he was angry with Eleazar and Ithamar, the sons of Aaron which were left alive, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Why have you not eaten the sin offering in the holy place, seeing it is most holy, and God has given it you to bear the iniquity of the congregation, to make atonement for them before the LORD?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Behold, the blood of it was not brought in within the holy place: you should indeed have eaten it in the holy place, as I commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Aaron said to Moses, Behold, this day have they offered their sin offering and their burnt offering before the LORD; and such things have befallen me: and if I had eaten the sin offering to day, should it have been accepted in the sight of the LORD?</verse>
  <verse number="20">And when Moses heard that, he was content.</verse>
</chapter>