<chapter book="Leviticus" number="20" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the LORD spoke to Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Again, you shall say to the children of Israel, Whoever he be of the children of Israel, or of the strangers that sojourn in Israel, that gives any of his seed to Molech; he shall surely be put to death: the people of the land shall stone him with stones.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will set my face against that man, and will cut him off from among his people; because he has given of his seed to Molech, to defile my sanctuary, and to profane my holy name.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And if the people of the land do any ways hide their eyes from the man, when he gives of his seed to Molech, and kill him not:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then I will set my face against that man, and against his family, and will cut him off, and all that go a whoring after him, to commit prostitution with Molech, from among their people.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the soul that turns after such as have familiar spirits, and after wizards, to go a whoring after them, I will even set my face against that soul, and will cut him off from among his people.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Sanctify yourselves therefore, and be you holy: for I am the LORD your God.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And you shall keep my statutes, and do them: I am the LORD which sanctify you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For every one that curses his father or his mother shall be surely put to death: he has cursed his father or his mother; his blood shall be on him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the man that commits adultery with another man’s wife, even he that commits adultery with his neighbor’s wife, the adulterer and the adulteress shall surely be put to death.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the man that lies with his father’s wife has uncovered his father’s nakedness: both of them shall surely be put to death; their blood shall be on them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if a man lie with his daughter in law, both of them shall surely be put to death: they have worked confusion; their blood shall be on them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If a man also lie with mankind, as he lies with a woman, both of them have committed an abomination: they shall surely be put to death; their blood shall be on them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And if a man take a wife and her mother, it is wickedness: they shall be burnt with fire, both he and they; that there be no wickedness among you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And if a man lie with a beast, he shall surely be put to death: and you shall slay the beast.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And if a woman approach to any beast, and lie down thereto, you shall kill the woman, and the beast: they shall surely be put to death; their blood shall be on them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And if a man shall take his sister, his father’s daughter, or his mother’s daughter, and see her nakedness, and she see his nakedness; it is a wicked thing; and they shall be cut off in the sight of their people: he has uncovered his sister’s nakedness; he shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And if a man shall lie with a woman having her sickness, and shall uncover her nakedness; he has discovered her fountain, and she has uncovered the fountain of her blood: and both of them shall be cut off from among their people.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And you shall not uncover the nakedness of your mother’s sister, nor of your father’s sister: for he uncovers his near kin: they shall bear their iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And if a man shall lie with his uncle’s wife, he has uncovered his uncle’s nakedness: they shall bear their sin; they shall die childless.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And if a man shall take his brother’s wife, it is an unclean thing: he has uncovered his brother’s nakedness; they shall be childless.</verse>
  <verse number="22">You shall therefore keep all my statutes, and all my judgments, and do them: that the land, where I bring you to dwell therein, spew you not out.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And you shall not walk in the manners of the nation, which I cast out before you: for they committed all these things, and therefore I abhorred them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But I have said to you, You shall inherit their land, and I will give it to you to possess it, a land that flows with milk and honey: I am the LORD your God, which have separated you from other people.</verse>
  <verse number="25">You shall therefore put difference between clean beasts and unclean, and between unclean fowls and clean: and you shall not make your souls abominable by beast, or by fowl, or by any manner of living thing that creeps on the ground, which I have separated from you as unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And you shall be holy to me: for I the LORD am holy, and have severed you from other people, that you should be mine.</verse>
  <verse number="27">A man also or woman that has a familiar spirit, or that is a wizard, shall surely be put to death: they shall stone them with stones: their blood shall be on them.</verse>
</chapter>