<chapter book="Galatians" number="5" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Stand fast, and be not held again under the yoke of bondage.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Behold, I Paul tell you, that if you be circumcised, Christ shall profit you nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I testify again to every man circumcising himself, that he is a debtor to the whole law.</verse>
  <verse number="4">You are made void of Christ, you who are justified in the law: you are fallen from grace.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For we in spirit, by faith, wait for the hope of justice.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For in Christ Jesus neither circumcision availeth any thing, nor uncircumcision: but faith that worketh by charity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">You did run well, who hath hindered you, that you should not obey the truth?</verse>
  <verse number="8">This persuasion is not from him that calleth you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A little leaven corrupteth the whole lump.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I have confidence in you in the Lord: that you will not be of another mind: but he that troubleth you, shall bear the judgment, whosoever he be.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I, brethren, if I yet preach circumcision, why do I yet suffer persecution? Then is the scandal of the cross made void.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I would they were even cut off, who trouble you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For you, brethren, have been called unto liberty: only make not liberty an occasion to the flesh, but by charity of the spirit serve one another.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For all the law is fulfilled in one word: Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But if you bite and devour one another; take heed you be not consumed one of another.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I say then, walk in the spirit, and you shall not fulfil the lusts of the flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the flesh lusteth against the spirit: and the spirit against the flesh; for these are contrary one to another: so that you do not the things that you would.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But if you are led by the spirit, you are not under the law.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Now the works of the flesh are manifest, which are fornication, uncleanness, immodesty, luxury,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Idolatry, witchcrafts, enmities, contentions, emulations, wraths, quarrels, dissensions, sects,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Envies, murders, drunkenness, revellings, and such like. Of the which I foretell you, as I have foretold to you, that they who do such things shall not obtain the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But the fruit of the Spirit is, charity, joy, peace, patience, benignity, goodness, longanimity,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Mildness, faith, modesty, continency, chastity. Against such there is no law.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they that are Christ’s, have crucified their flesh, with the vices and concupiscences.</verse>
  <verse number="25">If we live in the Spirit, let us also walk in the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Let us not be made desirous of vain glory, provoking one another, envying on another.</verse>
</chapter>