<chapter book="Mark" number="10" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And he arose from there, and comes into the coasts of Judaea by the farther side of Jordan: and the people resort to him again; and, as he was wont, he taught them again.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the Pharisees came to him, and asked him, Is it lawful for a man to put away his wife? tempting him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he answered and said to them, What did Moses command you?</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they said, Moses suffered to write a bill of divorce, and to put her away.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jesus answered and said to them, For the hardness of your heart he wrote you this precept.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But from the beginning of the creation God made them male and female.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and join to his wife;</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they two shall be one flesh: so then they are no more two, but one flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What therefore God has joined together, let not man put asunder.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And in the house his disciples asked him again of the same matter.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he said to them, Whoever shall put away his wife, and marry another, commits adultery against her.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if a woman shall put away her husband, and be married to another, she commits adultery.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they brought young children to him, that he should touch them: and his disciples rebuked those that brought them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But when Jesus saw it, he was much displeased, and said to them, Suffer the little children to come to me, and forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Truly I say to you, Whoever shall not receive the kingdom of God as a little child, he shall not enter therein.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he took them up in his arms, put his hands on them, and blessed them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And when he was gone forth into the way, there came one running, and kneeled to him, and asked him, Good Master, what shall I do that I may inherit eternal life?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Jesus said to him, Why call you me good? there is none good but one, that is, God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">You know the commandments, Do not commit adultery, Do not kill, Do not steal, Do not bear false witness, Defraud not, Honor your father and mother.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he answered and said to him, Master, all these have I observed from my youth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Then Jesus beholding him loved him, and said to him, One thing you lack: go your way, sell whatever you have, and give to the poor, and you shall have treasure in heaven: and come, take up the cross, and follow me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he was sad at that saying, and went away grieved: for he had great possessions.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Jesus looked round about, and said to his disciples, How hardly shall they that have riches enter into the kingdom of God!</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the disciples were astonished at his words. But Jesus answers again, and said to them, Children, how hard is it for them that trust in riches to enter into the kingdom of God!</verse>
  <verse number="25">It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle, than for a rich man to enter into the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they were astonished out of measure, saying among themselves, Who then can be saved?</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Jesus looking on them said, With men it is impossible, but not with God: for with God all things are possible.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then Peter began to say to him, See, we have left all, and have followed you.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Jesus answered and said, Truly I say to you, There is no man that has left house, or brothers, or sisters, or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands, for my sake, and the gospel’s,</verse>
  <verse number="30">But he shall receive an hundred times now in this time, houses, and brothers, and sisters, and mothers, and children, and lands, with persecutions; and in the world to come eternal life.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But many that are first shall be last; and the last first.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they were in the way going up to Jerusalem; and Jesus went before them: and they were amazed; and as they followed, they were afraid. And he took again the twelve, and began to tell them what things should happen to him,</verse>
  <verse number="33">Saying, Behold, we go up to Jerusalem; and the Son of man shall be delivered to the chief priests, and to the scribes; and they shall condemn him to death, and shall deliver him to the Gentiles:</verse>
  <verse number="34">And they shall mock him, and shall whip him, and shall spit on him, and shall kill him: and the third day he shall rise again.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And James and John, the sons of Zebedee, come to him, saying, Master, we would that you should do for us whatever we shall desire.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And he said to them, What would you that I should do for you?</verse>
  <verse number="37">They said to him, Grant to us that we may sit, one on your right hand, and the other on your left hand, in your glory.</verse>
  <verse number="38">But Jesus said to them, You know not what you ask: can you drink of the cup that I drink of? and be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?</verse>
  <verse number="39">And they said to him, We can. And Jesus said to them, You shall indeed drink of the cup that I drink of; and with the baptism that I am baptized with shall you be baptized:</verse>
  <verse number="40">But to sit on my right hand and on my left hand is not my to give; but it shall be given to them for whom it is prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And when the ten heard it, they began to be much displeased with James and John.</verse>
  <verse number="42">But Jesus called them to him, and said to them, You know that they which are accounted to rule over the Gentiles exercise lordship over them; and their great ones exercise authority on them.</verse>
  <verse number="43">But so shall it not be among you: but whoever will be great among you, shall be your minister:</verse>
  <verse number="44">And whoever of you will be the most chief, shall be servant of all.</verse>
  <verse number="45">For even the Son of man came not to be ministered to, but to minister, and to give his life a ransom for many.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And they came to Jericho: and as he went out of Jericho with his disciples and a great number of people, blind Bartimaeus, the son of Timaeus, sat by the highway side begging.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out, and say, Jesus, you son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And many charged him that he should hold his peace: but he cried the more a great deal, You son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Jesus stood still, and commanded him to be called. And they call the blind man, saying to him, Be of good comfort, rise; he calls you.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And he, casting away his garment, rose, and came to Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And Jesus answered and said to him, What will you that I should do to you? The blind man said to him, Lord, that I might receive my sight.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And Jesus said to him, Go your way; your faith has made you whole. And immediately he received his sight, and followed Jesus in the way.</verse>
</chapter>