<chapter book="1 Thessalonians" number="5" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But concerning the times and the seasons, brethren, ye have no need that aught be written unto you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For yourselves know perfectly that the day of the Lord so cometh as a thief in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="3">When they are saying, Peace and safety, then sudden destruction cometh upon them, as travail upon a woman with child; and they shall in no wise escape.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But ye, brethren, are not in darkness, that that day should overtake you as a thief:</verse>
  <verse number="5">for ye are all sons of light, and sons of the day: we are not of the night, nor of darkness;</verse>
  <verse number="6">so then let us not sleep, as do the rest, but let us watch and be sober.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For they that sleep sleep in the night; and they that be drunken are drunken in the night.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But let us, since we are of the day, be sober, putting on the breastplate of faith and love; and for a helmet, the hope of salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For God appointed us not unto wrath, but unto the obtaining of salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="10">who died for us, that, whether we wake or sleep, we should live together with him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wherefore exhort one another, and build each other up, even as also ye do.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But we beseech you, brethren, to know them that labour among you, and are over you in the Lord, and admonish you;</verse>
  <verse number="13">and to esteem them exceeding highly in love for their work’s sake. Be at peace among yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And we exhort you, brethren, admonish the disorderly, encourage the fainthearted, support the weak, be longsuffering toward all.</verse>
  <verse number="15">See that none render unto any one evil for evil; but alway follow after that which is good, one toward another, and toward all.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Rejoice alway;</verse>
  <verse number="17">pray without ceasing;</verse>
  <verse number="18">in everything give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus to you-ward.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Quench not the Spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="20">despise not prophesyings;</verse>
  <verse number="21">prove all things; hold fast that which is good;</verse>
  <verse number="22">abstain from every form of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the God of peace himself sanctify you wholly; and may your spirit and soul and body be preserved entire, without blame at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Faithful is he that calleth you, who will also do it.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Brethren, pray for us.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Salute all the brethren with a holy kiss.</verse>
  <verse number="27">I adjure you by the Lord that this epistle be read unto all the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
</chapter>