<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The proverbs of Solomon the son of David, king of Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="2">To know wisdom and instruction; To comprehend the words of understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">To receive the discipline of wisdom, Justice, and right, and equity;</verse>
  <verse number="4">To give prudence to the simple, To the young man knowledge and discretion;</verse>
  <verse number="5">That the wise man may hear, and increase in learning, And the man of understanding may attain unto wise counsels;</verse>
  <verse number="6">To understand a proverb, and a figure; The words of the wise, and their dark sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The fear of the LORD is the beginning of knowledge; But the foolish despise wisdom and discipline.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Hear, my son, the instruction of thy father, And forsake not the teaching of thy mother;</verse>
  <verse number="9">For they shall be a chaplet of grace unto thy head, And chains about thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if sinners entice thee, Consent thou not.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they say: ‘Come with us, Let us lie in wait for blood, Let us lurk for the innocent without cause;</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let us swallow them up alive as the grave, And whole, as those that go down into the pit;</verse>
  <verse number="13">We shall find all precious substance, We shall fill our houses with spoil;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Cast in thy lot among us; Let us all have one purse’—</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, walk not thou in the way with them, Restrain thy foot from their path;</verse>
  <verse number="16">For their feet run to evil, And they make haste to shed blood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For in vain the net is spread In the eyes of any bird;</verse>
  <verse number="18">And these lie in wait for their own blood, They lurk for their own lives.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So are the ways of every one that is greedy of gain; It taketh away the life of the owners thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom crieth aloud in the streets, She uttereth her voice in the broad places;</verse>
  <verse number="21">She calleth at the head of the noisy streets, At the entrances of the gates, in the city, she uttereth her words:</verse>
  <verse number="22">How long, ye thoughtless, will ye love thoughtlessness? And how long will scorners delight them in scorning, And fools hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn you at my reproof; Behold, I will pour out my spirit unto you, I will make known my words unto you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I have called, and ye refused, I have stretched out my hand, and no man attended,</verse>
  <verse number="25">But ye have set at nought all my counsel, And would none of my reproof;</verse>
  <verse number="26">I also, in your calamity, will laugh, I will mock when your dread cometh;</verse>
  <verse number="27">When your dread cometh as a storm, And your calamity cometh on as a whirlwind; When trouble and distress come upon you.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then will they call me, but I will not answer, They will seek me earnestly, but they shall not find me.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For that they hated knowledge, And did not choose the fear of the LORD;</verse>
  <verse number="30">They would none of my counsel, They despised all my reproof.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Therefore shall they eat of the fruit of their own way, And be filled with their own devices.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the waywardness of the thoughtless shall slay them, And the confidence of fools shall destroy them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But whoso hearkeneth unto me shall dwell securely, And shall be quiet without fear of evil.’</verse>
</chapter>