<chapter book="Proverbs" number="16" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The preparations of the heart are man’s, But the answer of the tongue is from the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="2">All the ways of a man are clean in his own eyes; But the LORD weigheth the spirits.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Commit thy works unto the LORD, And thy thoughts shall be established.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The LORD hath made every things for His own purpose, Yea, even the wicked for the day of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Every one that is proud in heart is an abomination to the LORD; My hand upon it! he shall not be unpunished.</verse>
  <verse number="6">By mercy and truth iniquity is expiated; And by the fear of the LORD men depart from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="7">When a man’s ways please the LORD, He maketh even his enemies to be at peace with him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Better is a little with righteousness Than great revenues with injustice.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A man’s heart deviseth his way; But the LORD directeth his steps.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A divine sentence is in the lips of the king; His mouth trespasseth not in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A just balance and scales are the LORD’S; All the weights of the bag are His work.</verse>
  <verse number="12">It is an abomination to kings to commit wickedness; For the throne is established by righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Righteous lips are the delight of kings; And they love him that speaketh right.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The wrath of a king is as messengers of death; But a wise man will pacify it.</verse>
  <verse number="15">In the light of the king’s countenance is life; And his favour is as a cloud of the latter rain.</verse>
  <verse number="16">How much better is it to get wisdom than gold! Yea, to get understanding is rather to be chosen than silver.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The highway of the upright is to depart from evil; He that keepeth his way preserveth his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Pride goeth before destruction, And a haughty spirit before a fall.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Better it is to be of a lowly spirit with the humble, Than to divide the spoil with the proud.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He that giveth heed unto the word shall find good; And whoso trusteth in the LORD, happy is he.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The wise in heart is called a man of discernment; And the sweetness of the lips increaseth learning.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Understanding is a fountain of life unto him that hath it; But folly is the chastisement of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The heart of the wise teacheth his mouth, And addeth learning to his lips.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Pleasant words are as a honeycomb, Sweet to the soul, and health to the bones.</verse>
  <verse number="25">There is a way which seemeth right unto a man, But the end thereof are the ways of death.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The hunger of the labouring man laboureth for him; For his mouth compelleth him.</verse>
  <verse number="27">An ungodly man diggeth up evil, And in his lips there is as a burning fire.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A froward man soweth strife; And a whisperer separateth familiar friends.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A man of violence enticeth his neighbour, And leadeth him into a way that is not good.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He shutteth his eyes, it is to devise froward things; He that biteth his lips bringeth evil to pass.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The hoary head is a crown of glory, It is found in the way of righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He that is slow to anger is better than the mighty; And he that ruleth his spirit than he that taketh a city.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The lot is cast into the lap; But the whole disposing thereof is of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>