<chapter book="Proverbs" number="20" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wine is a mocker, strong drink is riotous; And whosoever reeleth thereby is not wise.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The terror of a king is as the roaring of a lion: He that provoketh him to anger forfeiteth his life.</verse>
  <verse number="3">It is an honour for a man to keep aloof from strife; But every fool will be snarling.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The sluggard will not plow when winter setteth in; Therefore he shall beg in harvest, and have nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Counsel in the heart of man is like deep water; But a man of understanding will draw it out.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Most men will proclaim every one his own goodness; But a faithful man who can find?</verse>
  <verse number="7">He that walketh in his integrity as a just man, Happy are his children after him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A king that sitteth on the throne of judgment Scattereth away all evil with his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who can say: ‘I have made my heart clean, I am pure from my sin’?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Divers weights, and divers measures, Both of them alike are abomination to the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Even a child is known by his doings, Whether his work be pure, and whether it be right.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The hearing ear, and the seeing eye, The LORD hath made even both of them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Love not sleep, lest thou come to poverty; Open thine eyes, and thou shalt have bread in plenty.</verse>
  <verse number="14">It is bad, it is bad’, saith the buyer; But when he is gone his way, then he boasteth.</verse>
  <verse number="15">There is gold, and a multitude of rubies; But the lips of knowledge are a precious jewel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Take his garment that is surety for a stranger; And hold him in pledge that is surety for an alien woman.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Bread of falsehood is sweet to a man; But afterwards his mouth shall be filled with gravel.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Every purpose is established by counsel; And with good advice carry on war.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He that goeth about as a talebearer revealeth secrets; Therefore meddle not with him that openeth wide his lips.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Whoso curseth his father or his mother, His lamp shall be put out in the blackest darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="21">An estate may be gotten hastily at the beginning; But the end thereof shall not be blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Say not thou: ‘I will requite evil’; Wait for the LORD, and He will save thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Divers weights are an abomination to the LORD; And a false balance is not good.</verse>
  <verse number="24">A man’s goings are of the LORD; How then can man look to his way?</verse>
  <verse number="25">It is a snare to a man rashly to say: ‘Holy’, And after vows to make inquiry.</verse>
  <verse number="26">A wise king sifteth the wicked, And turneth the wheel over them.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The spirit of man is the lamp of the LORD, Searching all the inward parts.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Mercy and truth preserve the king; And his throne is upheld by mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The glory of young men is their strength; And the beauty of old men is the hoary head.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Sharp wounds cleanse away evil; So do stripes that reach the inward parts.</verse>
</chapter>