<chapter book="Proverbs" number="21" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The king’s heart is in the hand of the LORD, as the watercourses: He turneth it whithersoever He will.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Every way of a man is right in his own eyes; But the LORD weigheth the hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">To do righteousness and justice Is more acceptable to the LORD than sacrifice.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A haughty look, and a proud heart—The tillage of the wicked is sin.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the diligent tend only to plenteousness; But every one that is hasty hasteth only to want.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The getting of treasures by a lying tongue Is a vapour driven to and fro; they [that seek them] seek death.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The violence of the wicked shall drag them away; Because they refuse to do justly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The way of man is froward and strange; But as for the pure, his work is right.</verse>
  <verse number="9">It is better to dwell in a corner of the housetop, Than in a house in common with a contentious woman.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The soul of the wicked desireth evil; His neighbour findeth no favour in his eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="11">When the scorner is punished, the thoughtless is made wise; And when the wise is instructed, he receiveth knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The Righteous One considereth the house of the wicked; Overthrowing the wicked to their ruin.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso stoppeth his ears at the cry of the poor, He also shall cry himself, but shall not be answered.</verse>
  <verse number="14">A gift in secret pacifieth anger, And a present in the bosom strong wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="15">To do justly is joy to the righteous, But ruin to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The man that strayeth out of the way of understanding Shall rest in the congregation of the shades.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He that loveth pleasure shall be a poor man; He that loveth wine and oil shall not be rich.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The wicked is a ransom for the righteous; And the faithless cometh in the stead of the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="19">It is better to dwell in a desert land, Than with a contentious and fretful woman.</verse>
  <verse number="20">There is desirable treasure and oil in the dwelling of the wise; But a foolish man swalloweth it up.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He that followeth after righteousness and mercy Findeth life, prosperity, and honour.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A wise man scaleth the city of the mighty, And bringeth down the stronghold wherein it trusteth.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue Keepeth his soul from troubles.</verse>
  <verse number="24">A proud and haughty man, scorner is his name, Even he that dealeth in overbearing pride.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The desire of the slothful killeth him; For his hands refuse to labour.</verse>
  <verse number="26">There is that coveteth greedily all the day long; But the righteous giveth and spareth not.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sacrifice of the wicked is an abomination; How much more, when he bringeth it with the proceeds of wickedness?</verse>
  <verse number="28">A false witness shall perish; But the man that obeyeth shall speak unchallenged.</verse>
  <verse number="29">A wicked man hardeneth his face; But as for the upright, he looketh well to his way.</verse>
  <verse number="30">There is no wisdom nor understanding Nor counsel against the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="31">The horse is prepared against the day of battle; But victory is of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>