<chapter book="Proverbs" number="22" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A good name is rather to be chosen than great riches, And loving favour rather than silver and gold.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The rich and the poor meet together—The LORD is the maker of them all.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A prudent man seeth the evil, and hideth himself; But the thoughtless pass on, and are punished.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The reward of humility is the fear of the LORD, Even riches, and honour, and life.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Thorns and snares are in the way of the froward; He that keepeth his soul holdeth himself far from them.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Train up a child in the way he should go, And even when he is old, he will not depart from it.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The rich ruleth over the poor, And the borrower is servant to the lender.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He that soweth iniquity shall reap vanity; And the rod of his wrath shall fail.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He that hath a bountiful eye shall be blessed; For he giveth of his bread to the poor.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Cast out the scorner, and contention will go out; Yea, strife and shame will cease.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He that loveth pureness of heart, That hath grace in his lips, the king shall be his friend.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The eyes of the LORD preserve him that hath knowledge, But He overthroweth the words of the faithless man.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The sluggard saith: ‘There is a lion without; I shall be slain in the streets.’</verse>
  <verse number="14">The mouth of strange women is a deep pit: He that is abhorred of the LORD shall fall therein.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Foolishness is bound up in the heart of a child; But the rod of correction shall drive it far from him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">One may oppress the poor, yet will their gain increase; One may give to the rich, yet will want come.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Incline thine ear, and hear the words of the wise, And apply thy heart unto my knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For it is a pleasant thing if thou keep them within thee; Let them be established altogether upon thy lips.</verse>
  <verse number="19">That thy trust may be in the LORD, I have made them known to thee this day, even to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Have not I written unto thee excellent things Of counsels and knowledge;</verse>
  <verse number="21">That I might make thee know the certainty of the words of truth, That thou mightest bring back words of truth to them that send thee?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Rob not the weak, because he is weak, Neither crush the poor in the gate;</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the LORD will plead their cause, And despoil of life those that despoil them.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Make no friendship with a man that is given to anger; And with a wrathful man thou shalt not go;</verse>
  <verse number="25">Lest thou learn his ways, And get a snare to thy soul.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Be thou not of them that strike hands, Or of them that are sureties for debts;</verse>
  <verse number="27">If thou hast not wherewith to pay, Why should he take away thy bed from under thee?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Remove not the ancient landmark, Which thy fathers have set.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Seest thou a man diligent in his business? he shall stand before kings; He shall not stand before mean men.</verse>
</chapter>