<chapter book="Proverbs" number="23" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When thou sittest to eat with a ruler, Consider well him that is before thee;</verse>
  <verse number="2">And put a knife to thy throat, If thou be a man given to appetite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Be not desirous of his dainties; Seeing they are deceitful food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Weary not thyself to be rich; Cease from thine own wisdom.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Wilt thou set thine eyes upon it? it is gone; For riches certainly make themselves wings, Like an eagle that flieth toward heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Eat thou not the bread of him that hath an evil eye, Neither desire thou his dainties;</verse>
  <verse number="7">For as one that hath reckoned within himself, so is he: ‘Eat and drink’, saith he to thee; But his heart is not with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The morsel which thou hast eaten shalt thou vomit up, And lose thy sweet words.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Speak not in the ears of a fool; For he will despise the wisdom of thy words.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Remove not the ancient landmark; And enter not into the fields of the fatherless;</verse>
  <verse number="11">For their Redeemer is strong; He will plead their cause with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Apply thy heart unto instruction, And thine ears to the words of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Withhold not correction from the child; For though thou beat him with the rod, he will not die.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thou beatest him with the rod, And wilt deliver his soul from the nether-world.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, if thy heart be wise, My heart will be glad, even mine;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Yea, my reins will rejoice, When thy lips speak right things.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let not thy heart envy sinners, But be in the fear of the LORD all the day;</verse>
  <verse number="18">For surely there is a future; And thy hope shall not be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Hear thou, my son, and be wise, And guide thy heart in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Be not among winebibbers; Among gluttonous eaters of flesh;</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the drunkard and the glutton shall come to poverty; And drowsiness shall clothe a man with rags.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Hearken unto thy father that begot thee, And despise not thy mother when she is old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Buy the truth, and sell it not; Also wisdom, and instruction, and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The father of the righteous will greatly rejoice; And he that begetteth a wise child will have joy of him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let thy father and thy mother be glad, And let her that bore thee rejoice.</verse>
  <verse number="26">My son, give me thy heart, And let thine eyes observe my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For a harlot is a deep ditch; And an alien woman is a narrow pit.</verse>
  <verse number="28">She also lieth in wait as a robber, And increaseth the faithless among men.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Who crieth: ‘Woe’? who: ‘Alas’? Who hath contentions? who hath raving? Who hath wounds without cause? Who hath redness of eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="30">They that tarry long at the wine; They that go to try mixed wine.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Look not thou upon the wine when it is red, When it giveth its colour in the cup, When it glideth down smoothly;</verse>
  <verse number="32">At the last it biteth like a serpent, And stingeth like a basilisk.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Thine eyes shall behold strange things, And thy heart shall utter confused things.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Yea, thou shalt be as he that lieth down in the midst of the sea, Or as he that lieth upon the top of a mast.</verse>
  <verse number="35">They have struck me, and I felt it not, They have beaten me, and I knew it not; When shall I awake? I will seek it yet again.’</verse>
</chapter>