<chapter book="Proverbs" number="25" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">These also are proverbs of Solomon, which the men of Hezekiah king of Judah copied out.</verse>
  <verse number="2">It is the glory of God to conceal a thing; but the glory of kings is to search out a matter.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The heaven for height, and the earth for depth, and the heart of kings is unsearchable.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Take away the dross from the silver, and there cometh forth a vessel for the refiner;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Take away the wicked from before the king, and his throne shall be established in righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Glorify not thyself in the presence of the king, and stand not in the place of great men;</verse>
  <verse number="7">For better is it that it be said unto thee: ‘Come up hither’, than that thou shouldest be put lower in the presence of the prince, whom thine eyes have seen.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Go not forth hastily to strive, lest thou know not what to do in the end thereof, when thy neighbour hath put thee to shame.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Debate thy cause with thy neighbour, but reveal not the secret of another;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Lest he that heareth it revile thee, and thine infamy turn not away.</verse>
  <verse number="11">A word fitly spoken Is like apples of gold in settings of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">As an ear-ring of gold, and an ornament of fine gold, So is a wise reprover upon an obedient ear.</verse>
  <verse number="13">As the cold of snow in the time of harvest, So is a faithful messenger to him that sendeth him; For he refresheth the soul of his master.</verse>
  <verse number="14">As vapours and wind without rain, So is he that boasteth himself of a false gift.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By long forbearing is a ruler persuaded, And a soft tongue breaketh the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Hast thou found honey? eat so much as is sufficient for thee, Lest thou be filled therewith, and vomit it.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let thy foot be seldom in thy neighbour’s house; Lest he be sated with thee, and hate thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">As a maul, and a sword, and a sharp arrow, So is a man that beareth false witness against his neighbour.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Confidence in an unfaithful man in time of trouble Is like a broken tooth, and a foot out of joint.</verse>
  <verse number="20">As one that taketh off a garment in cold weather, and as vinegar upon nitre, So is he that singeth songs to a heavy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="21">If thine enemy be hungry, give him bread to eat, And if he be thirsty, give him water to drink;</verse>
  <verse number="22">For thou wilt heap coals of fire upon his head, And the LORD will reward thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The north wind bringeth forth rain, And a backbiting tongue an angry countenance.</verse>
  <verse number="24">It is better to dwell in a corner of the housetop, Than in a house in common with a contentious woman.</verse>
  <verse number="25">As cold waters to a faint soul, So is good news from a far country.</verse>
  <verse number="26">As a troubled fountain, and a corrupted spring, So is a righteous man that giveth way before the wicked.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is not good to eat much honey; So for men to search out their own glory is not glory.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Like a city broken down and without a wall, So is he whose spirit is without restraint.</verse>
</chapter>