<chapter book="Proverbs" number="3" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, forget not my teaching; But let thy heart keep my commandments;</verse>
  <verse number="2">For length of days, and years of life, And peace, will they add to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let not kindness and truth forsake thee; Bind them about thy neck, write them upon the table of thy heart;</verse>
  <verse number="4">So shalt thou find grace and good favour In the sight of God and man.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Trust in the LORD with all thy heart, And lean not upon thine own understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In all thy ways acknowledge Him, And He will direct thy paths.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be not wise in thine own eyes; Fear the LORD, and depart from evil;</verse>
  <verse number="8">It shall be health to thy navel, And marrow to thy bones.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Honour the LORD with thy substance, And with the first-fruits of all thine increase;</verse>
  <verse number="10">So shall thy barns be filled with plenty, And thy vats shall overflow with new wine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, despise not the chastening of the LORD, Neither spurn thou His correction;</verse>
  <verse number="12">For whom the LORD loveth He correcteth, Even as a father the son in whom he delighteth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Happy is the man that findeth wisdom, And the man that obtaineth understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the merchandise of it is better than the merchandise of silver, And the gain thereof than fine gold.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She is more precious than rubies; And all the things thou canst desire are not to be compared unto her.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Length of days is in her right hand; In her left hand are riches and honour.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Her ways are ways of pleasantness, And all her paths are peace.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She is a tree of life to them that lay hold upon her, And happy is every one that holdest her fast.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The LORD by wisdom founded the earth; By understanding He established the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By His knowledge the depths were broken up, And the skies drop down the dew.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, let not them depart from thine eyes; Keep sound wisdom and discretion;</verse>
  <verse number="22">So shall they be life unto thy soul, And grace to thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then shalt thou walk in thy way securely, And thou shalt not dash thy foot.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When thou liest down, thou shalt not be afraid; Yea, thou shalt lie down, and thy sleep shall be sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Be not afraid of sudden terror, Neither of the destruction of the wicked, when it cometh;</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the LORD will be thy confidence, And will keep thy foot from being caught.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Withhold not good from him to whom it is due, When it is in the power of thy hand to do it.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Say not unto thy neighbour: ‘Go, and come again, And to-morrow I will give’; when thou hast it by thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Devise not evil against thy neighbour, Seeing he dwelleth securely by thee.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Strive not with a man without cause, If he have done thee no harm.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Envy thou not the man of violence, And choose none of his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the perverse is an abomination to the LORD; But His counsel is with the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The curse of the LORD is in the house of the wicked; But He blesseth the habitation of the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="34">If it concerneth the scorners, He scorneth them, But unto the humble He giveth grace.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The wise shall inherit honour; But as for the fools, they carry away shame.</verse>
</chapter>