<chapter book="Proverbs" number="30" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of Agur the son of Jakeh; the burden. The man saith unto Ithiel, unto Ithiel and Ucal:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Surely I am brutish, unlike a man, And have not the understanding of a man;</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I have not learned wisdom, That I should have the knowledge of the Holy One.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who hath ascended up into heaven, and descended? Who hath gathered the wind in his fists? Who hath bound the waters in his garment? Who hath established all the ends of the earth? What is his name, and what is his son’s name, if thou knowest?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Every word of God is tried; He is a shield unto them that take refuge in Him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Add thou not unto His words, Lest He reprove thee, and thou be found a liar.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Two things have I asked of Thee; Deny me them not before I die:</verse>
  <verse number="8">Remove far from me falsehood and lies; Give me neither poverty nor riches; feed me with mine allotted bread;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Lest I be full, and deny, and say: ‘Who is the LORD?’ Or lest I be poor, and steal, And profane the name of my God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Slander not a servant unto his master, Lest he curse thee, and thou be found guilty.</verse>
  <verse number="11">There is a generation that curse their father, And do not bless their mother.</verse>
  <verse number="12">There is a generation that are pure in their own eyes, And yet are not washed from their filthiness.</verse>
  <verse number="13">There is a generation, Oh how lofty are their eyes! And their eyelids are lifted up.</verse>
  <verse number="14">There is a generation whose teeth are as swords, and their great teeth as knives, To devour the poor from off the earth, and the needy from among men.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The horseleech hath two daughters: ‘Give, give.’ There are three things that are never satisfied, Yea, four that say not: ‘Enough’ :</verse>
  <verse number="16">The grave; and the barren womb; The earth that is not satisfied with water; And the fire that saith not: ‘Enough.’</verse>
  <verse number="17">The eye that mocketh at his father, And despiseth to obey his mother, The ravens of the valley shall pick it out, And the young vultures shall eat it.</verse>
  <verse number="18">There are three things which are too wonderful for me, Yea, four which I know not:</verse>
  <verse number="19">The way of an eagle in the air; The way of a serpent upon a rock; The way of a ship in the midst of the sea; And the way of a man with a young woman.</verse>
  <verse number="20">So is the way of an adulterous woman; She eateth, and wipeth her mouth, And saith: ‘I have done no wickedness.’</verse>
  <verse number="21">For three things the earth doth quake, And for four it cannot endure:</verse>
  <verse number="22">For a servant when he reigneth; And a churl when he is filled with food;</verse>
  <verse number="23">For an odious woman when she is married; And a handmaid that is heir to her mistress.</verse>
  <verse number="24">There are four things which are little upon the earth, But they are exceeding wise:</verse>
  <verse number="25">The ants are a people not strong, Yet they provide their food in the summer;</verse>
  <verse number="26">The rock-badgers are but a feeble folk, Yet make they their houses in the crags;</verse>
  <verse number="27">The locusts have no king, Yet go they forth all of them by bands;</verse>
  <verse number="28">The spider thou canst take with the hands, Yet is she in kings’ palaces.</verse>
  <verse number="29">There are three things which are stately in their march, Yea, four which are stately in going:</verse>
  <verse number="30">The lion, which is mightiest among beasts, And turneth not away for any;</verse>
  <verse number="31">The greyhound; the he-goat also; And the king, against whom there is no rising up.</verse>
  <verse number="32">If thou hast done foolishly in lifting up thyself, Or if thou hast planned devices, lay thy hand upon thy mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For the churning of milk bringeth forth curd, And the wringing of the nose bringeth forth blood; So the forcing of wrath bringeth forth strife.</verse>
</chapter>