<chapter book="Proverbs" number="31" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of king Lemuel; the burden wherewith his mother corrected him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">What, my son? and what, O son of my womb? And what, O son of my vows?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Give not thy strength unto women, Nor thy ways to that which destroyeth kings.</verse>
  <verse number="4">It is not for kings, O Lemuel, it is not for kings to drink wine: Nor for princes to say: ‘Where is strong drink?’</verse>
  <verse number="5">Lest they drink, and forget that which is decreed, And pervert the justice due to any that is afflicted.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Give strong drink unto him that is ready to perish, And wine unto the bitter in soul;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Let him drink, and forget his poverty, And remember his misery no more.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Open thy mouth for the dumb, In the cause of all such as are appointed to destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Open thy mouth, judge righteously, And plead the cause of the poor and needy.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A woman of valour who can find? For her price is far above rubies.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The heart of her husband doth safely trust in her, And he hath no lack of gain.</verse>
  <verse number="12">She doeth him good and not evil All the days of her life.</verse>
  <verse number="13">She seeketh wool and flax, And worketh willingly with her hands.</verse>
  <verse number="14">She is like the merchant-ships; She bringeth her food from afar.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She riseth also while it is yet night, And giveth food to her household, And a portion to her maidens.</verse>
  <verse number="16">She considereth a field, and buyeth it; With the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard.</verse>
  <verse number="17">She girdeth her loins with strength, And maketh strong her arms.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She perceiveth that her merchandise is good; Her lamp goeth not out by night.</verse>
  <verse number="19">She layeth her hands to the distaff, And her hands hold the spindle.</verse>
  <verse number="20">She stretcheth out her hand to the poor; Yea, she reacheth forth her hands to the needy.</verse>
  <verse number="21">She is not afraid of the snow for her household; For all her household are clothed with scarlet.</verse>
  <verse number="22">She maketh for herself coverlets; Her clothing is fine linen and purple.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Her husband is known in the gates, When he sitteth among the elders of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="24">She maketh linen garments and selleth them; And delivereth girdles unto the merchant.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Strength and dignity are her clothing; And she laugheth at the time to come.</verse>
  <verse number="26">She openeth her mouth with wisdom; And the law of kindness is on her tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="27">She looketh well to the ways of her household, And eateth not the bread of idleness.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Her children rise up, and call her blessed; Her husband also, and he praiseth her:</verse>
  <verse number="29">Many daughters have done valiantly, But thou excellest them all.’</verse>
  <verse number="30">Grace is deceitful, and beauty is vain; But a woman that feareth the LORD, she shall be praised.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Give her of the fruit of her hands; And let her works praise her in the gates.</verse>
</chapter>