<chapter book="Proverbs" number="4" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hear, ye children, the instruction of a father, And attend to know understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For I give you good doctrine; Forsake ye not my teaching.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For I was a son unto my father, Tender and an only one in the sight of my mother.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he taught me, and said unto me: ‘Let thy heart hold fast my words, Keep my commandments, and live;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Get wisdom, get understanding; Forget not, neither decline from the words of my mouth;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Forsake her not, and she will preserve thee; Love her, and she will keep thee.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The beginning of wisdom is: Get wisdom; Yea, with all thy getting get understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Extol her, and she will exalt thee; She will bring thee to honour, when thou dost embrace her.</verse>
  <verse number="9">She will give to thy head a chaplet of grace; A crown of glory will she bestow on thee.’</verse>
  <verse number="10">Hear, O my son, and receive my sayings; And the years of thy life shall be many.</verse>
  <verse number="11">I have taught thee in the way of wisdom; I have led thee in paths of uprightness.</verse>
  <verse number="12">When thou goest, thy step shall not be straitened; And if thou runnest, thou shalt not stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Take fast hold of instruction, let her not go; Keep her, for she is thy life.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Enter not into the path of the wicked, And walk not in the way of evil men.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Avoid it, pass not by it; Turn from it, and pass on.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For they sleep not, except they have done evil; And their sleep is taken away, unless they cause some to fall.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For they eat the bread of wickedness, And drink the wine of violence.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But the path of the righteous is as the light of dawn, That shineth more and more unto the perfect day.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The way of the wicked is as darkness; They know not at what they stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, attend to my words; Incline thine ear unto my sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Let them not depart from thine eyes; Keep them in the midst of thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For they are life unto those that find them, And health to all their flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Above all that thou guardest keep thy heart; For out of it are the issues of life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Put away from thee a froward mouth, And perverse lips put far from thee.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let thine eyes look right on, And let thine eyelids look straight before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Make plain the path of thy feet, And let all thy ways be established.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Turn not to the right hand nor to the left; Remove thy foot from evil.</verse>
</chapter>