<chapter book="Proverbs" number="5" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, attend unto my wisdom; Incline thine ear to my understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="2">That thou mayest preserve discretion, And that thy lips may keep knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the lips of a strange woman drop honey, And her mouth is smoother than oil;</verse>
  <verse number="4">But her end is bitter as wormwood, Sharp as a two-edged sword.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Her feet go down to death; Her steps take hold on the nether-world;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Lest she should walk the even path of life, Her ways wander, but she knoweth it not.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Now therefore, O ye children, hearken unto me, And depart not from the words of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Remove thy way far from her, And come not nigh the door of her house;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Lest thou give thy vigour unto others, And thy years unto the cruel;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Lest strangers be filled with thy strength, And thy labours be in the house of an alien;</verse>
  <verse number="11">And thou moan, when thine end cometh, When thy flesh and thy body are consumed,</verse>
  <verse number="12">And say: ‘How have I hated instruction, And my heart despised reproof;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Neither have I hearkened to the voice of my teachers, Nor inclined mine ear to them that instructed me!</verse>
  <verse number="14">I was well nigh in all evil In the midst of the congregation and assembly.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">Drink waters out of thine own cistern, And running waters out of thine own well.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Let thy springs be dispersed abroad, And courses of water in the streets.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let them be only thine own, And not strangers’ with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Let thy fountain be blessed; And have joy of the wife of thy youth.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A lovely hind and a graceful doe, Let her breasts satisfy thee at all times; With her love be thou ravished always.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why then wilt thou, my son, be ravished with a strange woman, And embrace the bosom of an alien?</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the ways of man are before the eyes of the LORD, And He maketh even all his paths.</verse>
  <verse number="22">His own iniquities shall ensnare the wicked, And he shall be holden with the cords of his sin.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He shall die for lack of instruction; And in the greatness of his folly he shall reel.</verse>
</chapter>