<chapter book="Proverbs" number="8" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Doth not wisdom call, And understanding put forth her voice?</verse>
  <verse number="2">In the top of high places by the way, Where the paths meet, she standeth;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Beside the gates, at the entry of the city, At the coming in at the doors, she crieth aloud:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Unto you, O men, I call, And my voice is to the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="5">O ye thoughtless, understand prudence, And, ye fools, be ye of an understanding heart.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Hear, for I will speak excellent things, And the opening of my lips shall be right things.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For my mouth shall utter truth, And wickedness is an abomination to my lips.</verse>
  <verse number="8">All the words of my mouth are in righteousness, There is nothing perverse or crooked in them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They are all plain to him that understandeth, And right to them that find knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Receive my instruction, and not silver, And knowledge rather than choice gold.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For wisdom is better than rubies, And all things desirable are not to be compared unto her.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I wisdom dwell with prudence, And find out knowledge of devices.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The fear of the LORD is to hate evil; Pride, and arrogancy, and the evil way, And the froward mouth, do I hate.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Counsel is mine, and sound wisdom; I am understanding, power is mine.</verse>
  <verse number="15">By me kings reign, And princes decree justice.</verse>
  <verse number="16">By me princes rule, And nobles, even all the judges of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I love them that love me, And those that seek me earnestly shall find me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Riches and honour are with me; Yea, enduring riches and righteousness.</verse>
  <verse number="19">My fruit is better than gold, yea, than fine gold; And my produce than choice silver.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I walk in the way of righteousness, In the midst of the paths of justice;</verse>
  <verse number="21">That I may cause those that love me to inherit substance, And that I may fill their treasuries.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The LORD made me as the beginning of His way, The first of His works of old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">I was set up from everlasting, from the beginning, Or ever the earth was.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When there were no depths, I was brought forth; When there were no fountains abounding with water.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Before the mountains were settled, Before the hills was I brought forth;</verse>
  <verse number="26">While as yet He had not made the earth, nor the fields, Nor the beginning of the dust of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="27">When He established the heavens, I was there; When He set a circle upon the face of the deep,</verse>
  <verse number="28">When He made firm the skies above, When the fountains of the deep showed their might,</verse>
  <verse number="29">When He gave to the sea His decree, That the waters should not transgress His commandment, When He appointed the foundations of the earth;</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then I was by Him, as a nursling; And I was daily all delight, Playing always before Him,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Playing in His habitable earth, And my delights are with the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Now therefore, ye children, hearken unto me; For happy are they that keep my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Hear instruction, and be wise, And refuse it not.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Happy is the man that hearkeneth to me, Watching daily at my gates, waiting at the posts of my doors.</verse>
  <verse number="35">For whoso findeth me findeth life, And obtaineth favour of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="36">But he that misseth me wrongeth his own soul; All they that hate me love death.’</verse>
</chapter>