<chapter book="Job" number="10" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My soul is weary of my life; I will give free course to my complaint; I will speak in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will say unto God: Do not condemn me; Make me know wherefore Thou contendest with me.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it good unto Thee that Thou shouldest oppress, That Thou shouldest despise the work of Thy hands, And shine upon the counsel of the wicked?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Hast Thou eyes of flesh? Or seest Thou as man seeth?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Are Thy days as the days of man, Or Thy years as a man’s days,</verse>
  <verse number="6">That Thou inquirest after mine iniquity, And searchest after my sin,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Although Thou knowest that I shall not be condemned; And there is none that can deliver out of Thy hand?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thy hands have framed me and fashioned me Together round about; yet Thou dost destroy me!</verse>
  <verse number="9">Remember, I beseech Thee, that Thou hast fashioned me as clay; And wilt Thou bring me into dust again?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Hast Thou not poured me out as milk, And curdled me like cheese?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thou hast clothed me with skin and flesh, And knit me together with bones and sinews.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Thou hast granted me life and favour, And Thy providence hath preserved my spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Yet these things Thou didst hide in Thy heart; I know that this is with Thee;</verse>
  <verse number="14">If I sin, then Thou markest me, And Thou wilt not acquit me from mine iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If I be wicked, woe unto me; And if I be righteous, yet shall I not lift up my head—Being filled with ignominy And looking upon mine affliction.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And if it exalt itself, Thou huntest me as a lion; And again Thou showest Thyself marvellous upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou renewest Thy witnesses against me, And increasest Thine indignation upon me; Host succeeding host against me.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Wherefore then hast Thou brought me forth out of the womb? Would that I had perished, and no eye had seen me!</verse>
  <verse number="19">I should have been as though I had not been; I should have been carried from the womb to the grave.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Are not my days few? Cease then, And let me alone, that I may take comfort a little,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Before I go whence I shall not return, Even to the land of darkness and of the shadow of death;</verse>
  <verse number="22">A land of thick darkness, as darkness itself; A land of the shadow of death, without any order, And where the light is as darkness.</verse>
</chapter>