<chapter book="Job" number="11" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Zophar the Naamathite, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Should not the multitude of words be answered? And should a man full of talk be accounted right?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Thy boastings have made men hold their peace, And thou hast mocked, with none to make thee ashamed;</verse>
  <verse number="4">And thou hast said: ‘My doctrine is pure, And I am clean in Thine eyes.’</verse>
  <verse number="5">But oh that God would speak, And open His lips against thee;</verse>
  <verse number="6">And that He would tell thee the secrets of wisdom, That sound wisdom is manifold! Know therefore that God exacteth of thee less than thine iniquity deserveth.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Canst thou find out the deep things of God? Canst thou attain unto the purpose of the Almighty?</verse>
  <verse number="8">It is high as heaven; what canst thou do? Deeper than the nether-world; what canst thou know?</verse>
  <verse number="9">The measure thereof is longer than the earth, And broader than the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If He pass by, and shut up, Or gather in, then who can hinder Him?</verse>
  <verse number="11">For He knoweth base men; And when He seeth iniquity, will He not then consider it?</verse>
  <verse number="12">But an empty man will get understanding, When a wild ass’s colt is born a man.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If thou set thy heart aright, And stretch out thy hands toward Him—</verse>
  <verse number="14">If iniquity be in thy hand, put it far away, And let not unrighteousness dwell in thy tents—</verse>
  <verse number="15">Surely then shalt thou lift up thy face without spot; Yea, thou shalt be stedfast, and shalt not fear;</verse>
  <verse number="16">For thou shalt forget thy misery; Thou shalt remember it as waters that are passed away;</verse>
  <verse number="17">And thy life shall be clearer than the noonday; Though there be darkness, it shall be as the morning.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And thou shalt be secure, because there is hope; Yea, thou shalt look about thee, and shalt take thy rest in safety.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Also thou shalt lie down, and none shall make thee afraid; Yea, many shall make suit unto thee.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But the eyes of the wicked shall fail, And they shall have no way to flee, And their hope shall be the drooping of the soul.</verse>
</chapter>