<chapter book="Job" number="12" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">No doubt but ye are the people, And wisdom shall die with you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">But I have understanding as well as you; I am not inferior to you; Yea, who knoweth not such things as these?</verse>
  <verse number="4">I am as one that is a laughing-stock to his neighbour, A man that called upon God, And He answered him; The just, the innocent man is a laughing-stock,</verse>
  <verse number="5">A contemptible brand in the thought of him that is at ease, A thing ready for them whose foot slippeth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The tents of robbers prosper, And they that provoke God are secure, In whatsoever God bringeth into their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But ask now the beasts, and they shall teach thee; And the fowls of the air, and they shall tell thee;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Or speak to the earth, and it shall teach thee; And the fishes of the sea shall declare unto thee;</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who knoweth not among all these, That the hand of the LORD hath wrought this?</verse>
  <verse number="10">In whose hand is the soul of every living thing, And the breath of all mankind.—</verse>
  <verse number="11">Doth not the ear try words, Even as the palate tasteth its food?</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is wisdom with aged men, And understanding in length of days?—</verse>
  <verse number="13">With Him is wisdom and might; He hath counsel and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Behold, He breaketh down, and it cannot be built again; He shutteth up a man, and there can be no opening.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, He withholdeth the waters, and they dry up; Also He sendeth them out, and they overturn the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">With Him is strength and sound wisdom; The deceived and the deceiver are His.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He leadeth counsellors away stripped, And judges maketh He fools.</verse>
  <verse number="18">He looseth the bond of kings, And bindeth their loins with a girdle.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He leadeth priests away stripped, And overthroweth the mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="20">He removeth the speech of men of trust, And taketh away the sense of the elders.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He poureth contempt upon princes, And looseth the belt of the strong.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He uncovereth deep things out of darkness, And bringeth out to light the shadow of death.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He increaseth the nations, and destroyeth them; He enlargeth the nations, and leadeth them away.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He taketh away the heart of the chiefs of the people of the land, And causeth them to wander in a wilderness where there is no way.</verse>
  <verse number="25">They grope in the dark without light, And He maketh them to stagger like a drunken man.</verse>
</chapter>