<chapter book="Job" number="19" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then Job answered and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">How long will ye vex my soul, And crush me with words?</verse>
  <verse number="3">These ten times have ye reproached me; Ye are not ashamed that ye deal harshly with me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And be it indeed that I have erred, Mine error remaineth with myself.</verse>
  <verse number="5">If indeed ye will magnify yourselves against me, And plead against me my reproach;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Know now that God hath subverted my cause, And hath compassed me with His net.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Behold, I cry out: ‘Violence!’ but I am not heard; I cry aloud, but there is no justice.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He hath fenced up my way that I cannot pass, And hath set darkness in my paths.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He hath stripped me of my glory, And taken the crown from my head.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He hath broken me down on every side, and I am gone; And my hope hath He plucked up like a tree.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He hath also kindled His wrath against me, And He counteth me unto Him as one of His adversaries.</verse>
  <verse number="12">His troops come on together, And cast up their way against me, And encamp round about my tent.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He hath put my brethren far from me, And mine acquaintance are wholly estranged from me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My kinsfolk have failed, And my familiar friends have forgotten me.</verse>
  <verse number="15">They that dwell in my house, and my maids, count me for a stranger; I am become an alien in their sight.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I call unto my servant, and he giveth me no answer, Though I entreat him with my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">My breath is abhorred of my wife, And I am loathsome to the children of my tribe.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Even urchins despised me; If I arise, they speak against me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">All my intimate friends abhor me; And they whom I loved are turned against me.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My bone cleaveth to my skin and to my flesh, And I am escaped with the skin of my teeth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Have pity upon me, have pity upon me, O ye my friends; For the hand of God hath touched me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Why do ye persecute me as God, And are not satisfied with my flesh?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Oh that my words were now written! Oh that they were inscribed in a book!</verse>
  <verse number="24">That with an iron pen and lead They were graven in the rock for ever!</verse>
  <verse number="25">But as for me, I know that my Redeemer liveth, And that He will witness at the last upon the dust;</verse>
  <verse number="26">And when after my skin this is destroyed, Then without my flesh shall I see God;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whom I, even I, shall see for myself, And mine eyes shall behold, and not another’s. My reins are consumed within me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">If ye say: ‘How we will persecute him!’ Seeing that the root of the matter is found in me;</verse>
  <verse number="29">Be ye afraid of the sword; For wrath bringeth the punishments of the sword, That ye may know there is a judgment.</verse>
</chapter>