<chapter book="Job" number="22" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can a man be profitable unto God? Or can he that is wise be profitable unto Him?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it any advantage to the Almighty, that thou art righteous? Or is it gain to Him, that thou makest thy ways blameless?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Is it for thy fear of Him that He reproveth thee, That He entereth with thee into judgment?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Is not thy wickedness great? And are not thine iniquities without end?</verse>
  <verse number="6">For thou hast taken pledges of thy brother for nought, And stripped the naked of their clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thou hast not given water to the weary to drink, And thou hast withholden bread from the hungry.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And as a mighty man, who hath the earth, And as a man of rank, who dwelleth in it,</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou hast sent widows away empty, And the arms of the fatherless have been broken.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore snares are round about thee, And sudden dread affrighted thee,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Or darkness, that thou canst not see, And abundance of waters cover thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is not God in the height of heaven? And behold the topmost of the stars, how high they are!</verse>
  <verse number="13">And thou sayest: ‘What doth God know? Can He judge through the dark cloud?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thick clouds are a covering to Him, that He seeth not; And He walketh in the circuit of heaven.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">Wilt thou keep the old way Which wicked men have trodden?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Who were snatched away before their time, Whose foundation was poured out as a stream;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Who said unto God: ‘Depart from us’; And what could the Almighty do unto them?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Yet He filled their houses with good things—But the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The righteous saw it, and were glad, And the innocent laugh them to scorn:</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely their substance is cut off, And their abundance the fire hath consumed.’</verse>
  <verse number="21">Acquaint now thyself with Him, and be at peace; Thereby shall thine increase be good.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Receive, I pray thee, instruction from His mouth, And lay up His words in thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If thou return to the Almighty, thou shalt be built up—If thou put away unrighteousness far from thy tents,</verse>
  <verse number="24">And lay thy treasure in the dust, And the gold of Ophir among the stones of the brooks;</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the Almighty be thy treasure, And precious silver unto thee;</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then surely shalt thou have thy delight in the Almighty, And shalt lift up thy face unto God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thou shalt make thy prayer unto Him, and He will hear thee, And thou shalt pay thy vows;</verse>
  <verse number="28">Thou shalt also decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee, And light shall shine upon thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When they cast thee down, thou shalt say: ‘There is lifting up’; For the humble person He saveth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He delivereth him that is innocent, Yea, thou shalt be delivered through the cleanness of thy hands.</verse>
</chapter>