<chapter book="Job" number="30" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But now they that are younger than I have me in derision, Whose fathers I disdained to set with the dogs of my flock.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Yea, the strength of their hands, whereto should it profit me? Men in whom ripe age is perished.</verse>
  <verse number="3">They are gaunt with want and famine; They gnaw the dry ground, in the gloom of wasteness and desolation.</verse>
  <verse number="4">They pluck salt-wort with wormwood; And the roots of the broom are their food.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They are driven forth from the midst of men; They cry after them as after a thief.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the clefts of the valleys must they dwell, In holes of the earth and of the rocks.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Among the bushes they bray; Under the nettles they are gathered together.</verse>
  <verse number="8">They are children of churls, yea, children of ignoble men; They were scourged out of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And now I am become their song, Yea, I am a byword unto them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They abhor me, they flee far from me, And spare not to spit in my face.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For He hath loosed my cord, and afflicted me, And they have cast off the bridle before me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Upon my right hand rise the brood; They entangle my feet, And they cast up against me their ways of destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They break up my path, They further my calamity, Even men that have no helper.</verse>
  <verse number="14">As through a wide breach they come; In the midst of the ruin they roll themselves upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Terrors are turned upon me, They chase mine honour as the wind; And my welfare is passed away as a cloud.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And now my soul is poured out within me; Days of affliction have taken hold upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In the night my bones are pierced, and fall from me, And my sinews take no rest.</verse>
  <verse number="18">By the great force [of my disease] is my garment disfigured; It bindeth me about as the collar of my coat.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He hath cast me into the mire, And I am become like dust and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I cry unto Thee, and Thou dost not answer me; I stand up, and Thou lookest at me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Thou art turned to be cruel to me; With the might of Thy hand Thou hatest me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Thou liftest me up to the wind, Thou causest me to ride upon it; And Thou dissolvest my substance.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For I know that Thou wilt bring me to death, And to the house appointed for all living.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Surely none shall put forth his hand to a ruinous heap, Neither because of these things shall help come in one’s calamity,</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I have not wept for him that was in trouble, And if my soul grieved not for the needy.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Yet, when I looked for good, there came evil; And when I waited for light, there came darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Mine inwards boil, and rest not; Days of affliction are come upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="28">I go mourning without the sun; I stand up in the assembly, and cry for help.</verse>
  <verse number="29">I am become a brother to jackals, And a companion to ostriches.</verse>
  <verse number="30">My skin is black, and falleth from me, And my bones are burned with heat.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Therefore is my harp turned to mourning, And my pipe into the voice of them that weep.</verse>
</chapter>