<chapter book="Job" number="31" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I made a covenant with mine eyes; How then should I look upon a maid?</verse>
  <verse number="2">For what would be the portion of God from above, And the heritage of the Almighty from on high?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it not calamity to the unrighteous, And disaster to the workers of iniquity?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Doth not He see my ways, And count all my steps?</verse>
  <verse number="5">If I have walked with vanity, And my foot hath hasted to deceit—</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let me be weighed in a just balance, That God may know mine integrity—</verse>
  <verse number="7">If my step hath turned out of the way, And my heart walked after mine eyes, And if any spot hath cleaved to my hands;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then let me sow, and let another eat; Yea, let the produce of my field be rooted out.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If my heart have been enticed unto a woman, And I have lain in wait at my neighbour’s door;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then let my wife grind unto another, And let others bow down upon her.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For that were a heinous crime; Yea, it were an iniquity to be punished by the judges.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is a fire that consumeth unto destruction, And would root out all mine increase.</verse>
  <verse number="13">If I did despise the cause of my man-servant, Or of my maid-servant, when they contended with me—</verse>
  <verse number="14">What then shall I do when God riseth up? And when He remembereth, what shall I answer Him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Did not He that made me in the womb make him? And did not One fashion us in the womb?</verse>
  <verse number="16">If I have withheld aught that the poor desired, Or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Or have eaten my morsel myself alone, And the fatherless hath not eaten thereof—</verse>
  <verse number="18">Nay, from my youth he grew up with me as with a father, And I have been her guide from my mother’s womb.</verse>
  <verse number="19">If I have seen any wanderer in want of clothing, Or that the needy had no covering;</verse>
  <verse number="20">If his loins have not blessed me, And if he were not warmed with the fleece of my sheep;</verse>
  <verse number="21">If I have lifted up my hand against the fatherless, Because I saw my help in the gate;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then let my shoulder fall from the shoulder-blade, And mine arm be broken from the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For calamity from God was a terror to me, And by reason of His majesty I could do nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="24">If I have made gold my hope, And have said to the fine gold: ‘Thou art my confidence’;</verse>
  <verse number="25">If I rejoiced because my wealth was great, And because my hand had gotten much;</verse>
  <verse number="26">If I beheld the sun when it shined, Or the moon walking in brightness;</verse>
  <verse number="27">And my heart hath been secretly enticed, And my mouth hath kissed my hand;</verse>
  <verse number="28">This also were an iniquity to be punished by the judges; For I should have lied to God that is above.</verse>
  <verse number="29">If I rejoiced at the destruction of him that hated me, Or exulted when evil found him—</verse>
  <verse number="30">Yea, I suffered not my mouth to sin By asking his life with a curse.</verse>
  <verse number="31">If the men of my tent said not: ‘Who can find one that hath not been satisfied with his meat?’</verse>
  <verse number="32">The stranger did not lodge in the street; My doors I opened to the roadside.</verse>
  <verse number="33">If after the manner of men I covered my transgressions, By hiding mine iniquity in my bosom—</verse>
  <verse number="34">Because I feared the great multitude, And the most contemptible among families terrified me, So that I kept silence, and went not out of the door.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Oh that I had one to hear me!—Lo, here is my signature, let the Almighty answer me—And that I had the indictment which mine adversary hath written!</verse>
  <verse number="36">Surely I would carry it upon my shoulder; I would bind it unto me as a crown.</verse>
  <verse number="37">I would declare unto him the number of my steps; As a prince would I go near unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="38">If my land cry out against me, And the furrows thereof weep together;</verse>
  <verse number="39">If I have eaten the fruits thereof without money, Or have caused the tillers thereof to be disappointed—</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let thistles grow instead of wheat, And noisome weeds instead of barley. The words of Job are ended.</verse>
</chapter>