<chapter book="Job" number="34" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover Elihu answered and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear my words, ye wise men; And give ear unto me, ye that have knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the ear trieth words, As the palate tasteth food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Let us choose for us that which is right; Let us know among ourselves what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For Job hath said: ‘I am righteous, And God hath taken away my right;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Notwithstanding my right I am accounted a liar; My wound is incurable, though I am without transgression.’</verse>
  <verse number="7">What man is like Job, Who drinketh up scorning like water?</verse>
  <verse number="8">Who goeth in company with the workers of iniquity, And walketh with wicked men.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For he hath said: ‘It profiteth a man nothing That he should be in accord with God.’</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore hearken unto me, ye men of understanding: Far be it from God, that He should do wickedness; And from the Almighty, that He should commit iniquity.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the work of a man will He requite unto him, And cause every man to find according to his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Yea, of a surety, God will not do wickedly, Neither will the Almighty pervert justice.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who gave Him a charge over the earth? Or who hath disposed the whole world?</verse>
  <verse number="14">If He set His heart upon man, If He gather unto Himself his spirit and his breath;</verse>
  <verse number="15">All flesh shall perish together, And man shall return unto dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">If now thou hast understanding, hear this; Hearken to the voice of my words.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Shall even one that hateth right govern? And wilt thou condemn Him that is just and mighty—</verse>
  <verse number="18">Is it fit to say to a king: ‘Thou art base’? Or to nobles: ‘Ye are wicked’?—</verse>
  <verse number="19">That respecteth not the persons of princes, Nor regardeth the rich more than the poor? For they all are the work of His hands.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In a moment they die, even at midnight; The people are shaken and pass away, And the mighty are taken away without hand.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For His eyes are upon the ways of a man, And He seeth all his goings.</verse>
  <verse number="22">There is no darkness, nor shadow of death, Where the workers of iniquity may hide themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For He doth not appoint a time unto any man, When he should go before God in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He breaketh in pieces mighty men without inquisition, And setteth others in their stead.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Therefore He taketh knowledge of their works; And He overturneth them in the night, so that they are crushed.</verse>
  <verse number="26">He striketh them as wicked men In the open sight of others;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Because they turned aside from following Him, And would not have regard to any of His ways;</verse>
  <verse number="28">So that they cause the cry of the poor to come unto Him, And He heareth the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When He giveth quietness, who then can condemn? And when He hideth His face, who then can behold Him? Whether it be done unto a nation, or unto a man, alike;</verse>
  <verse number="30">That the godless man reign not, That there be none to ensnare the people.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For hath any said unto God: ‘I have borne chastisement, though I offend not;</verse>
  <verse number="32">That which I see not teach Thou me; If I have done iniquity, I will do it no more’?</verse>
  <verse number="33">Shall His recompense be as thou wilt? For thou loathest it, So that thou must choose, and not I; Therefore speak what thou knowest.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Men of understanding will say unto me, Yea, every wise man that heareth me:</verse>
  <verse number="35">Job speaketh without knowledge, And his words are without discernment.’</verse>
  <verse number="36">Would that Job were tried unto the end, Because of his answering like wicked men.</verse>
  <verse number="37">For he addeth rebellion unto his sin, He clappeth his hands among us, And multiplieth his words against God.</verse>
</chapter>