<chapter book="Job" number="37" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">At this also my heart trembleth, And is moved out of its place.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hear attentively the noise of His voice, And the sound that goeth out of His mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He sendeth it forth under the whole heaven, And His lightning unto the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">After it a voice roareth; He thundereth with the voice of His majesty; And He stayeth them not when His voice is heard.</verse>
  <verse number="5">God thundereth marvellously with His voice; Great things doeth He, which we cannot comprehend.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For He saith to the snow: ‘Fall thou on the earth’; Likewise to the shower of rain, and to the showers of His mighty rain.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He sealeth up the hand of every man, That all men whom He hath made may know it.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then the beasts go into coverts, And remain in their dens.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Out of the Chamber cometh the storm; And cold out of the north.</verse>
  <verse number="10">By the breath of God ice is given, And the breadth of the waters is straitened.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Yea, He ladeth the thick cloud with moister, He spreadeth abroad the cloud of His lightning;</verse>
  <verse number="12">And they are turned round about by His guidance, That they may do whatsoever He commandeth them Upon the face of the habitable world:</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whether it be for correction, or for His earth, Or for mercy, that He cause it to come.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Hearken unto this, O Job; Stand still, and consider the wondrous works of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Dost thou know how God enjoineth them, And causeth the lightning of His cloud to shine?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Dost thou know the balancings of the clouds, The wondrous works of Him who is perfect in knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou whose garments are warm, When the earth is still by reason of the south wind;</verse>
  <verse number="18">Canst thou with Him spread out the sky, Which is strong as a molten mirror?</verse>
  <verse number="19">Teach us what we shall say unto Him; For we cannot order our speech by reason of darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Shall it be told Him that I would speak? Or should a man wish that he were swallowed up?</verse>
  <verse number="21">And now men see not the light which is bright in the skies; But the wind passeth, and cleanseth them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Out of the north cometh golden splendour, About God is terrible majesty.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The Almighty, whom we cannot find out, is excellent in power, Yet to judgment and plenteous justice He doeth no violence.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Men do therefore fear Him; He regardeth not any that are wise of heart.</verse>
</chapter>