<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover the LORD answered Job, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shall he that reproveth contend with the Almighty? He that argueth with God, let him answer it.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Job answered the LORD, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Behold, I am of small account; what shall I answer Thee? I lay my hand upon my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Once have I spoken, but I will not answer again; Yea, twice, but I will proceed no further.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then the LORD answered Job out of the whirlwind, and said:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Gird up thy loins now like a man; I will demand of thee, and declare thou unto Me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Wilt thou even make void My judgment? Wilt thou condemn Me, that thou mayest be justified?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Or hast thou an arm like God? And canst thou thunder with a voice like Him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Deck thyself now with majesty and excellency, And array thyself with glory and beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Cast abroad the rage of thy wrath; And look upon every one that is proud, and abase him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Look on every one that is proud, and bring him low; And tread down the wicked in their place.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hide them in the dust together; Bind their faces in the hidden place.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then will I also confess unto thee That thine own right hand can save thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold now behemoth, which I made with thee; He eateth grass as an ox.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo now, his strength is in his loins, And his force is in the stays of his body.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He straineth his tail like a cedar; The sinews of his thighs are knit together.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are as pipes of brass; His gristles are like bars of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is the beginning of the ways of God; He only that made him can make His sword to approach unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely the mountains bring him forth food, And all the beasts of the field play there.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He lieth under the lotus-trees, In the covert of the reed, and fens.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The lotus-trees cover him with their shadow; The willows of the brook compass him about.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Behold, if a river overflow, he trembleth not; He is confident, though the Jordan rush forth to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Shall any take him by his eyes, Or pierce through his nose with a snare?</verse>
</chapter>