<chapter book="Job" number="7" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Is there not a time of service to man upon earth? And are not his days like the days of a hireling?</verse>
  <verse number="2">As a servant that eagerly longeth for the shadow, And as a hireling that looketh for his wages;</verse>
  <verse number="3">So am I made to possess—months of vanity, And wearisome nights are appointed to me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">When I lie down, I say: ‘When shall I arise?’ But the night is long, and I am full of tossings to and fro unto the dawning of the day.</verse>
  <verse number="5">My flesh is clothed with worms and clods of dust; My skin closeth up and breaketh out afresh.</verse>
  <verse number="6">My days are swifter than a weaver’s shuttle, And are spent without hope.</verse>
  <verse number="7">O remember that my life is a breath; Mine eye shall no more see good.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The eye of him that seeth me shall behold me no more; While Thine eyes are upon me, I am gone.</verse>
  <verse number="9">As the cloud is consumed and vanisheth away, So he that goeth down to the grave shall come up no more.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He shall return no more to his house, Neither shall his place know him any more.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore I will not refrain my mouth; I will speak in the anguish of my spirit; I will complain in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Am I a sea, or a sea-monster, That Thou settest a watch over me?</verse>
  <verse number="13">When I say: ‘My bed shall comfort me, My couch shall ease my complaint’;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then Thou scarest me with dreams, And terrifiest me through visions;</verse>
  <verse number="15">So that my soul chooseth strangling, And death rather than these my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I loathe it; I shall not live alway; Let me alone; for my days are vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="17">What is man, that Thou shouldest magnify him, And that Thou shouldest set Thy heart upon him,</verse>
  <verse number="18">And that Thou shouldest remember him every morning, And try him every moment?</verse>
  <verse number="19">How long wilt Thou not look away from me, Nor let me alone till I swallow down my spittle?</verse>
  <verse number="20">If I have sinned, what do I unto Thee, O Thou watcher of men? Why hast Thou set me as a mark for Thee, So that I am a burden to myself?</verse>
  <verse number="21">And why dost Thou not pardon my transgression, And take away mine iniquity? For now shall I lie down in the dust; And Thou wilt seek me, but I shall not be.</verse>
</chapter>