<chapter book="Ephesians" number="5" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Be imitators of God, therefore, as beloved children,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and walk in love, just as Christ loved us and gave Himself up for us as a fragrant sacrificial offering to God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">But among you, as is proper among the saints, there must not be even a hint of sexual immorality, or of any kind of impurity, or of greed.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Nor should there be obscenity, foolish talk, or crude joking, which are out of character, but rather thanksgiving.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For of this you can be sure: No immoral, impure, or greedy person (that is, an idolater) has any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let no one deceive you with empty words, for because of such things the wrath of God is coming on the sons of disobedience.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Therefore do not be partakers with them.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For you were once darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light,</verse>
  <verse number="9">for the fruit of the light consists in all goodness, righteousness, and truth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Test and prove what pleases the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Have no fellowship with the fruitless deeds of darkness, but rather expose them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For it is shameful even to mention what the disobedient do in secret.</verse>
  <verse number="13">But everything exposed by the light becomes visible, for everything that is illuminated becomes a light itself.</verse>
  <verse number="14">So it is said: “Wake up, O sleeper, rise up from the dead, and Christ will shine on you.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">Pay careful attention, then, to how you walk, not as unwise but as wise,</verse>
  <verse number="16">redeeming the time, because the days are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the Lord’s will is.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Do not get drunk on wine, which leads to reckless indiscretion. Instead, be filled with the Spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Speak to one another with psalms, hymns, and spiritual songs. Sing and make music in your hearts to the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="20">always giving thanks to God the Father for everything in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Submit to one another out of reverence for Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Wives, submit to your husbands as to the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the husband is the head of the wife as Christ is the head of the church, His body, of which He is the Savior.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Now as the church submits to Christ, so also wives should submit to their husbands in everything.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ loved the church and gave Himself up for her</verse>
  <verse number="26">to sanctify her, cleansing her by the washing with water through the word,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and to present her to Himself as a glorious church, without stain or wrinkle or any such blemish, but holy and blameless.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the same way, husbands ought to love their wives as their own bodies. He who loves his wife loves himself.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Indeed, no one ever hated his own body, but he nourishes and cherishes it, just as Christ does the church.</verse>
  <verse number="30">For we are members of His body.</verse>
  <verse number="31">“For this reason a man will leave his father and mother and be united to his wife, and the two will become one flesh.”</verse>
  <verse number="32">This mystery is profound, but I am speaking about Christ and the church.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Nevertheless, each one of you also must love his wife as he loves himself, and the wife must respect her husband.</verse>
</chapter>