<chapter book="1 Peter" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The elders among you I beseech, a fellow elder, and witness of the sufferings of Christ, and a participator of the glory which is about to be revealed:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Tend the flock of God which among you, inspecting, not by force, but voluntarily; neither occupied in sordid gain, but of a ready will;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Neither as ruling over the portions obtained by lot, but being types of the flock.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the chief Shepherd having been manifested, ye shall be attired with an unfading crown of glory.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Likewise, ye younger, be subjected to the elders. And all being subject to one another, be wrapped up in humility: for God opposes the proud, and gives grace to the humble.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Therefore be humbled under the strong hand of God, that he might lift you up) in due measure:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Having cast all your care upon him; for to him is the care for you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Be abstemious, watch; for your adversary the accuser, as a roaring lion, walks around, seeking whom he might swallow down:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whom resist firm in the faith, knowing that the same of sufferings are completed by your brotherhood in the world.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the God of all grace, having called us to his eternal glory in Christ Jesus, may he put you in proper order, having suffered a little time, may he support you, make firm, lay the foundation.</verse>
  <verse number="11">To him the glory and the strength for the time of times. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="12">By Silvanus, to you the faithful brother, as I reckon, I wrote briefly, beseeching, and bearing testimony this to be the true grace of God in which ye stand.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The chosen together in Babylon, greet you; also Marcus my son.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Greet one another in a kiss of love. Peace to all you which in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>