<chapter book="Amos" number="7" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Thus has the Lord GOD showed to me; and, behold, he formed grasshoppers in the beginning of the shooting up of the latter growth; and, see, it was the latter growth after the king’s mowings.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And it came to pass, that when they had made an end of eating the grass of the land, then I said, O Lord GOD, forgive, I beseech you: by whom shall Jacob arise? for he is small.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The LORD repented for this: It shall not be, said the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thus has the Lord GOD showed to me: and, behold, the Lord GOD called to contend by fire, and it devoured the great deep, and did eat up a part.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then said I, O Lord GOD, cease, I beseech you: by whom shall Jacob arise? for he is small.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The LORD repented for this: This also shall not be, said the Lord GOD.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thus he showed me: and, behold, the LORD stood on a wall made by a plumb line, with a plumb line in his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the LORD said to me, Amos, what see you? And I said, A plumb line. Then said the LORD, Behold, I will set a plumb line in the middle of my people Israel: I will not again pass by them any more:</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the high places of Isaac shall be desolate, and the sanctuaries of Israel shall be laid waste; and I will rise against the house of Jeroboam with the sword.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Then Amaziah the priest of Bethel sent to Jeroboam king of Israel, saying, Amos has conspired against you in the middle of the house of Israel: the land is not able to bear all his words.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For thus Amos said, Jeroboam shall die by the sword, and Israel shall surely be led away captive out of their own land.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Also Amaziah said to Amos, O you seer, go, flee you away into the land of Judah, and there eat bread, and prophesy there:</verse>
  <verse number="13">But prophesy not again any more at Bethel: for it is the king’s chapel, and it is the king’s court.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then answered Amos, and said to Amaziah, I was no prophet, neither was I a prophet’s son; but I was an herdsman, and a gatherer of sycomore fruit:</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the LORD took me as I followed the flock, and the LORD said to me, Go, prophesy to my people Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Now therefore hear you the word of the LORD: You say, Prophesy not against Israel, and drop not your word against the house of Isaac.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Therefore thus said the LORD; Your wife shall be an harlot in the city, and your sons and your daughters shall fall by the sword, and your land shall be divided by line; and you shall die in a polluted land: and Israel shall surely go into captivity forth of his land.</verse>
</chapter>