<chapter book="Jeremiah" number="28" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it will be in this year, in the beginning of the reign of Zedekiah king of Judah, in the fourth year, in the fifth month, Hananiah son of Azur the prophet which was from the hill, said to me in the house of Jehovah, before the eyes of the priests, and all the people, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thus said Jehovah of armies, God of Israel, saving, I broke the yoke of the king of Babel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">In yet two years of days I turn back to this place all the vessels of the house of Jehovah which Nebuchadnezzar king of Babel took from this place, and brought them to Babel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Jeconiah son of Jehoiakim King of Judah, and all the captivity of Judah going to Babel, I turn back to this place, says Jehovah; for I will break the yoke of the king of Babel.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jeremiah the prophet will say to Hansaiah the prophet, before the eyes of the priests and before the eyes of all the people standing in the house of Jehovah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Jeremiah the prophet will say, Verily: so will Jehovah do: will Jehovah raise up thy words which thou didst prophesy, to turn back the vessels of the house of Jehovah, and all the captivity from Babel to this place.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But hear now this word which I speak in thine ears and in the ears of all the people.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The prophets which were before me and before thee from of old, and they will prophesy to many lands and against great kingdoms, for war and for evil and for death.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The prophet which will prophesy for peace in the coming of the word of the prophet, the prophet shall be known: that Jehovah sent him in truth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Hananiah the prophet will take the yoke from off the neck of Jeremiah the prophet, and break it.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Hananiah will say before the eyes of all the people, saying, Thus said Jehovah, Thus will I break the yoke of Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babel in yet two years of days from off the neck of all the nations. And Jeremiah the prophet will go to his way.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the word of Jehovah will be to Jeremiah after Hananiah the prophet broke the yoke from off the neck of Jeremiah the prophet, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Go and say to Hananiah, saying, Thus said Jehovah, Thou didst break the staves of wood; but make instead of them staves of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For thus said Jehovah of armies, God of Israel, I gave an iron yoke upon the neck of all these nations to serve Nebuchadnezzar king of Babel: and they served him: and also the beasts of the field I gave to him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Jeremiah the prophet will say to Hananiah the prophet, Hear now, Hananiah; Jehovah sent thee not; and thou didst cause this people to trust upon falsehood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For this, thus said Jehovah, Behold me sending thee from off the face of the earth: this year thou diest, because thou spakest turning away against Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Hananiah the prophet will die in this year in the seventh month.</verse>
</chapter>