<chapter book="Job" number="22" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Can a man be profitable unto God? Surely he that is wise is profitable unto himself.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Is it any pleasure to the Almighty, that thou art righteous? Or is it gain to him, that thou makest thy ways perfect?</verse>
  <verse number="4">Is it for thy fear of him that he reproveth thee, That he entereth with thee into judgment?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Is not thy wickedness great? Neither is there any end to thine iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For thou hast taken pledges of thy brother for nought, And stripped the naked of their clothing.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thou hast not given water to the weary to drink, And thou hast withholden bread from the hungry.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But as for the mighty man, he had the earth; And the honorable man, he dwelt in it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou hast sent widows away empty, And the arms of the fatherless have been broken.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore snares are round about thee, And sudden fear troubleth thee,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Or darkness, so that thou canst not see, And abundance of waters cover thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Is not God in the height of heaven? And behold the height of the stars, how high they are!</verse>
  <verse number="13">And thou sayest, What doth God know? Can he judge through the thick darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thick clouds are a covering to him, so that he seeth not; And he walketh on the vault of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Wilt thou keep the old way Which wicked men have trodden?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Who were snatched away before their time, Whose foundation was poured out as a stream,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Who said unto God, Depart from us; And, What can the Almighty do for us?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Yet he filled their houses with good things: But the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The righteous see it, and are glad; And the innocent laugh them to scorn,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Saying, Surely they that did rise up against us are cut off, And the remnant of them the fire hath consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Acquaint now thyself with him, and be at peace: Thereby good shall come unto thee.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Receive, I pray thee, the law from his mouth, And lay up his words in thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If thou return to the Almighty, thou shalt be built up, If thou put away unrighteousness far from thy tents.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And lay thou thy treasure in the dust, And the gold of Ophir among the stones of the brooks;</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the Almighty will be thy treasure, And precious silver unto thee.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For then shalt thou delight thyself in the Almighty, And shalt lift up thy face unto God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thou shalt make thy prayer unto him, and he will hear thee; And thou shalt pay thy vows.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Thou shalt also decree a thing, and it shall be established unto thee; And light shall shine upon thy ways.</verse>
  <verse number="29">When they cast thee down, thou shalt say, There is lifting up; And the humble person he will save.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He will deliver even him that is not innocent: Yea, he shall be delivered through the cleanness of thy hands.</verse>
</chapter>