<chapter book="Job" number="4" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">If one assay to commune with thee, wilt thou be grieved? But who can withhold himself from speaking?</verse>
  <verse number="3">Behold, thou hast instructed many, And thou hast strengthened the weak hands.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thy words have upholden him that was falling, And thou hast made firm the feeble knees.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But now it is come unto thee, and thou faintest; It toucheth thee, and thou art troubled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Is not thy fear of God thy confidence, And the integrity of thy ways thy hope?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Remember, I pray thee, who ever perished, being innocent? Or where were the upright cut off?</verse>
  <verse number="8">According as I have seen, they that plow iniquity, And sow trouble, reap the same.</verse>
  <verse number="9">By the breath of God they perish, And by the blast of his anger are they consumed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The roaring of the lion, and the voice of the fierce lion, And the teeth of the young lions, are broken.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The old lion perisheth for lack of prey, And the whelps of the lioness are scattered abroad.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now a thing was secretly brought to me, And mine ear received a whisper thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In thoughts from the visions of the night, When deep sleep falleth on men,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Fear came upon me, and trembling, Which made all my bones to shake.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Then a spirit passed before my face; The hair of my flesh stood up.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It stood still, but I could not discern the appearance thereof; A form was before mine eyes: There was silence, and I heard a voice, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Shall mortal man be more just than God? Shall a man be more pure than his Maker?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Behold, he putteth no trust in his servants; And his angels he chargeth with folly:</verse>
  <verse number="19">How much more them that dwell in houses of clay, Whose foundation is in the dust, Who are crushed before the moth!</verse>
  <verse number="20">Betwixt morning and evening they are destroyed: They perish for ever without any regarding it.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Is not their tent-cord plucked up within them? They die, and that without wisdom.</verse>
</chapter>