<chapter book="Job" number="40" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Moreover Jehovah answered Job, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shall he that cavilleth contend with the Almighty? He that argueth with God, let him answer it.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Then Job answered Jehovah, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Behold, I am of small account; What shall I answer thee? I lay my hand upon my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Once have I spoken, and I will not answer; Yea, twice, but I will proceed no further.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Then Jehovah answered Job out of the whirlwind, and said,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Gird up thy loins now like a man: I will demand of thee, and declare thou unto me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Wilt thou even annul my judgment? Wilt thou condemn me, that thou mayest be justified?</verse>
  <verse number="9">Or hast thou an arm like God? And canst thou thunder with a voice like him?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Deck thyself now with excellency and dignity; And array thyself with honor and majesty.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Pour forth the overflowings of thine anger; And look upon every one that is proud, and abase him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Look on every one that is proud, and bring him low; And tread down the wicked where they stand.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Hide them in the dust together; Bind their faces in the hidden place.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then will I also confess of thee That thine own right hand can save thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold now, behemoth, which I made as well as thee; He eateth grass as an ox.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo now, his strength is in his loins, And his force is in the muscles of his belly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">He moveth his tail like a cedar: The sinews of his thighs are knit together.</verse>
  <verse number="18">His bones are as tubes of brass; His limbs are like bars of iron.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He is the chief of the ways of God: He only that made him giveth him his sword.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Surely the mountains bring him forth food, Where all the beasts of the field do play.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He lieth under the lotus-trees, In the covert of the reed, and the fen.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The lotus-trees cover him with their shade; The willows of the brook compass him about.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Behold, if a river overflow, he trembleth not; He is confident, though a Jordan swell even to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Shall any take him when he is on the watch, Or pierce through his nose with a snare?</verse>
</chapter>