<chapter book="Ephesians" number="6" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Children, obey your parents in the Lord: for this is right.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Honour thy father and mother (which is the first commandment with promise),</verse>
  <verse number="3">that it may be well with thee, and thou mayest live long on the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And, ye fathers, provoke not your children to wrath: but nurture them in the chastening and admonition of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Servants, be obedient unto them that according to the flesh are your masters, with fear and trembling, in singleness of your heart, as unto Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="6">not in the way of eyeservice, as men-pleasers; but as servants of Christ, doing the will of God from the heart;</verse>
  <verse number="7">with good will doing service, as unto the Lord, and not unto men:</verse>
  <verse number="8">knowing that whatsoever good thing each one doeth, the same shall he receive again from the Lord, whether he be bond or free.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And, ye masters, do the same things unto them, and forbear threatening: knowing that both their Master and yours is in heaven, and there is no respect of persons with him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Finally, be strong in the Lord, and in the strength of his might.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Put on the whole armour of God, that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the devil.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For our wrestling is not against flesh and blood, but against the principalities, against the powers, against the world-rulers of this darkness, against the spiritual hosts of wickedness in the heavenly places.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore take up the whole armour of God, that ye may be able to withstand in the evil day, and, having done all, to stand.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Stand therefore, having girded your loins with truth, and having put on the breastplate of righteousness,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and having shod your feet with the preparation of the gospel of peace;</verse>
  <verse number="16">withal taking up the shield of faith, wherewith ye shall be able to quench all the fiery darts of the evil one.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And take the helmet of salvation, and the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God:</verse>
  <verse number="18">with all prayer and supplication praying at all seasons in the Spirit, and watching thereunto in all perseverance and supplication for all the saints,</verse>
  <verse number="19">And on my behalf, that utterance may be given unto me in opening my mouth, to make known with boldness the mystery of the gospel,</verse>
  <verse number="20">for which I am an ambassador in chains; that in it I may speak boldly, as I ought to speak.</verse>
  <verse number="21">But that ye also may know my affairs, how I do, Tychicus, the beloved brother and faithful minister in the Lord, shall make known to you all things:</verse>
  <verse number="22">whom I have sent unto you for this very purpose, that ye may know our state, and that he may comfort your hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Peace be to the brethren, and love with faith, from God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Grace be with all them that love our Lord Jesus Christ in uncorruptness.</verse>
</chapter>