<chapter book="Isaiah" number="54" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Sing, O barren, she hath not borne! Break forth with singing, and cry aloud, She hath not brought forth! For more are the sons of the desolate, Than the sons of the married one, said Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Enlarge the place of thy tent, And the curtains of thy tabernacles they stretch out, Restrain not—lengthen thy cords, And thy pins make strong.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For right and left thou breakest forth, And thy seed doth nations possess,</verse>
  <verse number="4">And desolate cities they cause to be inhabited. Fear not, for thou art not ashamed, Nor blush, for thou art not confounded, For the shame of thy youth thou forgettest, And the reproach of thy widowhood Thou dost not remember any more.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For thy Maker is thy husband, Jehovah of Hosts is His name, And thy Redeemer is the Holy One of Israel, ‘God of all the earth,’ He is called.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For, as a woman forsaken and grieved in spirit, Called thee hath Jehovah, Even a youthful wife when she is refused, said thy God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In a small moment I have forsaken thee, And in great mercies I do gather thee,</verse>
  <verse number="8">In overflowing wrath I hid my face for a moment from thee, And in kindness age-during I have loved thee, Said thy Redeemer—Jehovah!</verse>
  <verse number="9">For, the waters of Noah is this to Me, In that I have sworn—the waters of Noah Do not pass again over the earth—So I have sworn, Wrath is not upon thee, Nor rebuke against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For the mountains depart, and the hills remove, And My kindness from thee departeth not, And the covenant of My peace removeth not, Said hath thy loving one—Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="11">O afflicted, storm-tossed, not comforted, Lo, I am laying with cement thy stones, And have founded thee with sapphires,</verse>
  <verse number="12">And have made of agate thy pinnacles, And thy gates of carbuncle stones, And all thy border of stones of delight,</verse>
  <verse number="13">And all thy sons are taught of Jehovah, And abundant is the peace of thy sons.</verse>
  <verse number="14">In righteousness thou establishest thyself, Be far from oppression, for thou fearest not, And from ruin, for it cometh not near unto thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Lo, he doth diligently assemble without My desire, Who hath assembled near thee? By thee he falleth!</verse>
  <verse number="16">Lo, I—I have prepared an artisan, Blowing on a fire of coals, And bringing out an instrument for his work, And I have prepared a destroyer to destroy.</verse>
  <verse number="17">No weapon formed against thee prospereth, And every tongue rising against thee, In judgment thou condemnest. This is the inheritance of the servants of Jehovah, And their righteousness from me, an affirmation of Jehovah!</verse>
</chapter>