<chapter book="Isaiah" number="7" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it cometh to pass in the days of Ahaz, son of Jotham, son of Uzziah, king of Judah, gone up hath Rezin king of Aram, and Pekah, son of Remaliah, king of Israel, to Jerusalem, to battle against it, and he is not able to fight against it.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And it is declared to the house of David, saying, ‘Aram hath been led towards Ephraim,’ And his heart and the heart of his people is moved, like the moving of trees of a forest by the presence of wind.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Jehovah saith unto Isaiah, ‘Go forth, I pray thee, to meet Ahaz, thou, and Shear-Jashub thy son, unto the end of the conduit of the upper pool, unto the highway of the fuller’s field,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and thou hast said unto him: ‘Take heed, and be quiet, fear not, And let not thy heart be timid, Because of these two tails of smoking brands, For the fierceness of the anger of Rezin and Aram, And the son of Remaliah.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Because that Aram counselled against thee evil, Ephraim and the son of Remaliah, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="6">We go up into Judah, and we vex it, And we rend it unto ourselves, And we cause a king to reign in its midst—The son of Tabeal.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Thus said the Lord Jehovah: It doth not stand, nor shall it be!</verse>
  <verse number="8">For the head of Aram is Damascus, And the head of Damascus is Rezin, And within sixty and five years Is Ephraim broken from being a people.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the head of Ephraim is Samaria, And the head of Samaria is the son of Remaliah. If ye do not give credence, Surely ye are not stedfast.’</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jehovah addeth to speak unto Ahaz, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="11">Ask for thee a sign from Jehovah thy God, Make deep the request, or make it high upwards.’</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Ahaz saith, ‘I do not ask nor try Jehovah.’</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he saith, ‘Hear, I pray you, O house of David, Is it a little thing for you to weary men, That ye weary also my God?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Therefore the Lord Himself giveth to you a sign, Lo, the Virgin is conceiving, And is bringing forth a son, And hath called his name Immanuel,</verse>
  <verse number="15">Butter and honey he doth eat, When he knoweth to refuse evil, and to fix on good.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For before the youth doth know To refuse evil, and to fix on good, Forsaken is the land thou art vexed with, because of her two kings.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Jehovah bringeth on thee, and on thy people, And on the house of thy father, Days that have not come, Even from the day of the turning aside of Ephraim from Judah, By the king of Asshur.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And it hath come to pass, in that day, Jehovah doth hiss for a fly that is in the extremity of the brooks of Egypt, And for a bee that is in the land of Asshur.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And they have come, and rested all of them in the desolate valleys, And in holes of the rocks, and on all the thorns, And on all the commendable things.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In that day doth the Lord shave, By a razor that is hired beyond the river, By the king of Asshur, The head, and the hair of the feet, Yea, also the beard it consumeth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And it hath come to pass, in that day, A man keepeth alive a heifer of the herd, And two of the flock,</verse>
  <verse number="22">And it hath come to pass, From the abundance of the yielding of milk he eateth butter, For butter and honey doth every one eat Who is left in the heart of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And it hath come to pass, in that day, Every place where there are a thousand vines, At a thousand silverlings, Is for briers and for thorns.</verse>
  <verse number="24">With arrows and with bow he cometh thither, Because all the land is brier and thorn.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And all the hills that with a mattock are kept in order, Thither cometh not the fear of brier and thorn, And it hath been for the sending forth of ox, And for the treading of sheep!’</verse>
</chapter>