<chapter book="Song of Solomon" number="1" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The Song of songs, which is Solomon’s.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Let him kiss me with the kisses of his mouth: for thy love is better than wine.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Thine ointments have a goodly fragrance; thy name is as ointment poured forth; therefore do the virgins love thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Draw me; we will run after thee: the king hath brought me into his chambers: we will be glad and rejoice in thee, we will make mention of thy love more than of wine: rightly do they love thee.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I am black, but comely, O ye daughters of Jerusalem, as the tents of Kedar, as the curtains of Solomon.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Look not upon me, because I am swarthy, because the sun hath scorched me. My mother’s sons were incensed against me, they made me keeper of the vineyards; but mine own vineyard have I not kept.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Tell me, O thou whom my soul loveth, where thou feedest thy flock, where thou makest it to rest at noon: for why should I be as one that is veiled beside the flocks of thy companions?</verse>
  <verse number="8">If thou know not, O thou fairest among women, go thy way forth by the footsteps of the flock, and feed thy kids beside the shepherds’ tents.</verse>
  <verse number="9">I have compared thee, O my love, to a steed in Pharaoh’s chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thy cheeks are comely with plaits of hair, thy neck with strings of jewels</verse>
  <verse number="11">We will make thee plaits of gold with studs of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="12">While the king sat at his table, my spikenard sent forth its fragrance.</verse>
  <verse number="13">My beloved is unto me as a bundle of myrrh, that lieth betwixt my breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="14">My beloved is unto me as a cluster of henna-flowers in the vineyards of En-gedi.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, thou art fair, my love; behold, thou art fair; thine eyes are as doves.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, thou art fair, my beloved, yea, pleasant: also our couch is green.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The beams of our house are cedars, and our rafters are firs.</verse>
</chapter>