<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="6" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And working together with him we entreat also that ye receive not the grace of God in vain</verse>
  <verse number="2">(for he saith, At an acceptable time I hearkened unto thee, And in a day of salvation did I succour thee: behold, now is the acceptable time; behold, now is the day of salvation):</verse>
  <verse number="3">giving no occasion of stumbling in anything, that our ministration be not blamed;</verse>
  <verse number="4">but in everything commending ourselves, as ministers of God, in much patience, in afflictions, in necessities, in distresses,</verse>
  <verse number="5">in stripes, in imprisonments, in tumults, in labours, in watchings, in fastings;</verse>
  <verse number="6">in pureness, in knowledge, in longsuffering, in kindness, in the Holy Ghost, in love unfeigned,</verse>
  <verse number="7">in the word of truth, in the power of God; by the armour of righteousness on the right hand and on the left,</verse>
  <verse number="8">by glory and dishonour, by evil report and good report; as deceivers, and yet true;</verse>
  <verse number="9">as unknown, and yet well known; as dying, and behold, we live; as chastened, and not killed;</verse>
  <verse number="10">as sorrowful, yet alway rejoicing; as poor, yet making many rich; as having nothing, and yet possessing all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Our mouth is open unto you, O Corinthians, our heart is enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Ye are not straitened in us, but ye are straitened in your own affections.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Now for a recompense in like kind (I speak as unto my children), be ye also enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Be not unequally yoked with unbelievers: for what fellowship have righteousness and iniquity? or what communion hath light with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And what concord hath Christ with Belial? or what portion hath a believer with an unbeliever?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And what agreement hath a temple of God with idols? for we are a temple of the living God; even as God said, I will dwell in them, and walk in them; and I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Wherefore Come ye out from among them, and be ye separate, saith the Lord, And touch no unclean thing; And I will receive you,</verse>
  <verse number="18">And will be to you a Father, And ye shall be to me sons and daughters, saith the Lord Almighty.</verse>
</chapter>