<chapter book="Revelation" number="16" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then I heard a loud voice from the sanctuary say to the seven angels, “Go and pour on to the earth the seven bowls of the anger of God.”</verse>
  <verse number="2">So the first angel went away and poured his bowl on to the earth; and it brought a bad and painful sore upon the men who had on them the mark of the Wild Beast and worshipped his statue.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The second angel poured his bowl into the sea, and it became blood, like a dead man’s blood, and every living creature in the sea died.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The third angel poured his bowl into the rivers and springs of water, and they became blood.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And I heard the angel of the waters say, “Righteous art Thou, who art and wast, the holy One, because Thou hast thus taken vengeance.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For they poured out the blood of Thy people and of the Prophets, and in return Thou hast given them blood to drink. And this they deserved.”</verse>
  <verse number="7">And I heard a voice from the altar say, “Even so, O Lord God, the Ruler of all, true and righteous are Thy judgments.”</verse>
  <verse number="8">Then the fourth angel poured his bowl on to the sun, and power was given to it to scorch men with fire.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the men were severely burned; and yet they spoke evil of God who had power over the plagues, and they did not repent so as to give Him glory.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The fifth angel poured his bowl on to the throne of the Wild Beast; and his kingdom became darkened. People gnawed their tongues because of the pain,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and they spoke evil of the God in Heaven because of their pains and their sores, and did not repent of their misconduct.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The sixth angel poured his bowl into that great river, the Euphrates; and its stream was dried up in order to clear the way for the kings who are to come from the east.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then I saw three foul spirits, resembling frogs, issue from the mouth of the Dragon, from the mouth of the Wild Beast, and from the mouth of the false Prophet.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For they are the spirits of demons working marvels—spirits that go out to control the kings of the whole earth, to assemble them for the battle which is to take place on the great day of God, the Ruler of all.</verse>
  <verse number="15"></verse>
  <verse number="16">And assemble them they did at the place called in Hebrew ‘Har-Magedon.’</verse>
  <verse number="17">Then the seventh angel poured his bowl into the air; and a loud voice came out of the sanctuary from the throne, saying, “Everything is now ready.”</verse>
  <verse number="18">Flashes of lightning followed, and voices, and peals of thunder, and an earthquake more dreadful than there had ever been since there was a man upon the earth—so terrible was it, and so great!</verse>
  <verse number="19">The great city was split into three parts; the cities of the nations fell; and great Babylon came into remembrance before God, for Him to make her drink from the wine-cup of His fierce anger.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Every island fled away, and there was not a mountain anywhere to be seen.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And heavy hail, that seemed to be a talent in weight, fell from the sky upon the people; and they spoke evil of God on account of the plague of the hail—because the plague of it was exceedingly severe.</verse>
</chapter>