<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="1" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The words of the preacher, son of David, king in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Vanity of vanities, said the preacher; vanity of vanities, all vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="3">What the profit to a man in all the labor he will labor under the sun?</verse>
  <verse number="4">A generation went away, and a generation came: and the earth stood forever.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The sun arose and the sun went down, and panted after its place which it arose there.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Going to the south and turning round about to the north, it turned round about; the wind turned round about, going, and the wind turned back upon its circuits.</verse>
  <verse number="7">All the torrents going into the sea, and the sea not full: to the place the torrents going, there they turn back to go.</verse>
  <verse number="8">All words becoming weary; man shall not be able to speak: the eye shall not be satisfied to see, and the ear shall not be filled from hearing.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What was, that shall be; and what was done, that shall be done: and not anything new under the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Is there a word will be said, See, this is new? This was already to a long time which was before us.</verse>
  <verse number="11">No remembrance to former things; and also to the latter things that shall be; to them shall be no remembrance with them which shall be for the latter state.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I the preacher was king over Israel in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I gave my heart to seek and to search out in wisdom concerning all which was done under the heavens: this evil business God gave to the sons of man to be occupied in it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I saw all the works they did under the sun; and behold, all vanity and striving of the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The crooked thing shall not be able to be made straight: and the deficiency shall not be able to be numbered.</verse>
  <verse number="16">It spake with my heart, saying, Behold, I was magnified, and added wisdom over all that were before me at Jerusalem: and my heart saw much of wisdom and knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I will give my heart to know wisdom, and the knowledge of praise and understanding: I knew this also it is the striving of the spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For in abundance of wisdom, abundance of trouble: and he adding knowledge will increase pain.</verse>
</chapter>