<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">A good name is above good oil, and the day of death above the day of birth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Good to go to the house of mourning rather than to go to the house of drinking, in that it is the end of every man; and he living shall give to his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Good is grief above laughter: for in the illness of the face the heart shall be good.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The heart of the wise is in the house of mourning; and the heart of the foolish in the house of gladness.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Good to hear the reproof of the wise one, above a man hearing the song of the foolish:</verse>
  <verse number="6">For as the voice of thorns under the pot, so the laughter of the foolish one. Also this is vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For oppression will make foolish the wise one; and a gift will destroy the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Good the last of a word above its beginning: good slowness of spirit above pride of spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thou shalt not be hastened in thy spirit to be angry, for anger shall rest in the bosom of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thou shalt not say, Why was it the former days were good above these? for thou didst not ask from wisdom concerning this.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wisdom is good with an inheritance: and a remainder to those seeing the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For in the shadow, wisdom; in the shadow, silver: and the excellence of knowledge is wisdom shall preserve alive those possessing it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">See the work of God: for who shall be able to make straight what he made it crooked?</verse>
  <verse number="14">In the day of good, be in good; and in the day of evil, see thou: also God made this over against this, to the end that man shall not find anything after him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">I saw all in the days of my vanity: there is a just one perishing in his justice, and there is an unjust one, being prolonged in his evil.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Thou shalt not be greatly just; and thou shalt not be exceedingly wise: wherefore wilt thou be made desolate?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou shalt not be greatly wicked, and thou shalt not be foolish: wherefore wilt thou die not in thy time?</verse>
  <verse number="18">Good that thou shalt hold fast upon this; also from this thou shalt not lead away thy hand: for he fearing God shall come forth with all of them.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wisdom shall strengthen to the wise one more than ten having power which were in the city.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For not a just man in the earth, who shall do good and not sin.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Also to all the words that shall be spoken thou shalt not give thy heart, that thou shalt not hear thy servant cursing thee.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For also many times thy heart knew that thou didst also curse others.</verse>
  <verse number="23">All this I proved by wisdom: I said I will be wise, and it was removed far off from me.</verse>
  <verse number="24">What was far off, and the depth, deep, who shall find it?</verse>
  <verse number="25">I went round about, I and my heart, to know, and to examine, and to search out wisdom and understanding, and to know the injustice of folly, and the folly of wickedness:</verse>
  <verse number="26">And I find bitter above death the woman that her heart it is snares and nets, her hands are bonds: the good one before God shall escape from her, and he sinning shall be taken by her.</verse>
  <verse number="27">See, this I found, said the preacher: one to one to find understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Which yet my soul sought, and found not; one man from a thousand I found; and a woman in all these I found not.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Only see, this I found, that God made man upright; and they sought out many purposes.</verse>
</chapter>