<chapter book="Hebrews" number="8" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now of the things which we have spoken this is the sum: We have such an high priest, who is set on the right hand of the throne of the Majesty in the heavens;</verse>
  <verse number="2">A minister of the sanctuary, and of the true tabernacle, which the Lord pitched, and not man.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For every high priest is ordained to offer gifts and sacrifices: why it is of necessity that this man have somewhat also to offer.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For if he were on earth, he should not be a priest, seeing that there are priests that offer gifts according to the law:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who serve to the example and shadow of heavenly things, as Moses was admonished of God when he was about to make the tabernacle: for, See, said he, that you make all things according to the pattern showed to you in the mount.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But now has he obtained a more excellent ministry, by how much also he is the mediator of a better covenant, which was established on better promises.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For if that first covenant had been faultless, then should no place have been sought for the second.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For finding fault with them, he said, Behold, the days come, said the Lord, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel and with the house of Judah:</verse>
  <verse number="9">Not according to the covenant that I made with their fathers in the day when I took them by the hand to lead them out of the land of Egypt; because they continued not in my covenant, and I regarded them not, said the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this is the covenant that I will make with the house of Israel after those days, said the Lord; I will put my laws into their mind, and write them in their hearts: and I will be to them a God, and they shall be to me a people:</verse>
  <verse number="11">And they shall not teach every man his neighbor, and every man his brother, saying, Know the Lord: for all shall know me, from the least to the greatest.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I will be merciful to their unrighteousness, and their sins and their iniquities will I remember no more.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In that he said, A new covenant, he has made the first old. Now that which decays and waxes old is ready to vanish away.</verse>
</chapter>