<chapter book="Amos" number="5" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Hear ye this word which I take up for a lamentation over you, O house of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="2">The virgin of Israel is fallen, She shall no more rise; She is cast down upon her land, There is none to raise her up.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For thus saith the Lord GOD: The city that went forth a thousand shall have a hundred left, and that which went forth a hundred shall have ten left, of the house of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For thus saith the LORD unto the house of Israel: Seek ye Me, and live;</verse>
  <verse number="5">But seek not Beth-el, Nor enter into Gilgal, And pass not to Beer-sheba; For Gilgal shall surely go into captivity, And Beth-el shall come to nought.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Seek the LORD, and live—Lest He break out like fire in the house of Joseph, And it devour, and there be none to quench it in Bethel—</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ye who turn judgment to wormwood, And cast righteousness to the ground;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Him that maketh the Pleiades and Orion, And bringeth on the shadow of death in the morning, And darkeneth the day into night; That calleth for the waters of the sea, And poureth them out upon the face of the earth; The LORD is His name;</verse>
  <verse number="9">That causeth destruction to flash upon the strong, So that destruction cometh upon the fortress.</verse>
  <verse number="10">They hate him that reproveth in the gate, And they abhor him that speaketh uprightly.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore, because ye trample upon the poor, And take from him exactions of wheat; Ye have built houses of hewn stone, But ye shall not dwell in them, Ye have planted pleasant vineyards, But ye shall not drink wine thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For I know how manifold are your transgressions, And how mighty are your sins; Ye that afflict the just, that take a ransom, And that turn aside the needy in the gate.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Therefore the prudent doth keep silence in such a time; For it is an evil time.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Seek good, and not evil, that ye may live; And so the LORD, the God of hosts, will be with you, as ye say.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Hate the evil, and love the good, And establish justice in the gate; It may be that the LORD, the God of hosts, Will be gracious unto the remnant of Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Therefore thus saith the LORD, The God of hosts, the Lord: Lamentation shall be in all the broad places, And they shall say in all the streets: ‘Alas! alas!’ And they shall call the husbandman to mourning, And proclaim lamentation to such as are skilful of wailing.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And in all vineyards shall be lamentation; For I will pass through the midst of thee, Saith the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Woe unto you that desire the day of the LORD! Wherefore would ye have the day of the LORD? It is darkness, and not light.</verse>
  <verse number="19">As if a man did flee from a lion, And a bear met him; And went into the house and leaned his hand on the wall, And a serpent bit him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Shall not the day of the LORD be darkness, and not light? Even very dark, and no brightness in it?</verse>
  <verse number="21">I hate, I despise your feasts, And I will take no delight in your solemn assemblies.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Yea, though ye offer me burnt-offerings and your meal-offerings, I will not accept them; Neither will I regard the peace-offerings of your fat beasts.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Take thou away from Me the noise of thy songs; And let Me not hear the melody of thy psalteries.</verse>
  <verse number="24">But let justice well up as waters, And righteousness as a mighty stream.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Did ye bring unto Me sacrifices and offerings in the wilderness forty years, O house of Israel?</verse>
  <verse number="26">So shall ye take up Siccuth your king and Chiun your images, the star of your god, which ye made to yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Therefore will I cause you to go into captivity beyond Damascus, saith He, whose name is the LORD God of hosts.</verse>
</chapter>