<chapter book="Joshua" number="19" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The second lot came out for the clans of the tribe of Simeon: Their inheritance lay within the territory of Judah</verse>
  <verse number="2">and included Beersheba (or Sheba), Moladah,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Hazar-shual, Balah, Ezem,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Eltolad, Bethul, Hormah,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Ziklag, Beth-marcaboth, Hazar-susah,</verse>
  <verse number="6">Beth-lebaoth, and Sharuhen—thirteen cities, along with their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Ain, Rimmon, Ether, and Ashan—four cities, along with their villages,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and all the villages surrounding these cities as far as Baalath-beer (Ramah of the Negev). This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Simeon.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The inheritance of the Simeonites was taken from the territory of Judah, because the share for Judah’s descendants was too large for them. So the Simeonites received an inheritance within Judah’s portion.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The third lot came up for the clans of the tribe of Zebulun: The border of their inheritance stretched as far as Sarid.</verse>
  <verse number="11">It went up westward to Maralah, reached Dabbesheth, and met the brook east of Jokneam.</verse>
  <verse number="12">From Sarid it turned eastward along the border of Chisloth-tabor and went on to Daberath and up to Japhia.</verse>
  <verse number="13">From there it crossed eastward to Gath-hepher and to Eth-kazin; it extended to Rimmon and curved around toward Neah.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Then the border circled around the north side of Neah to Hannathon and ended at the Valley of Iphtah-el.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It also included Kattath, Nahalal, Shimron, Idalah, and Bethlehem. There were twelve cities, along with their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="16">This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Zebulun, including these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The fourth lot came out for the clans of the tribe of Issachar:</verse>
  <verse number="18">Their territory included Jezreel, Chesulloth, Shunem,</verse>
  <verse number="19">Hapharaim, Shion, Anaharath,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Rabbith, Kishion, Ebez,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Remeth, En-gannim, En-haddah, and Beth-pazzez.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The border reached Tabor, Shahazumah, and Beth-shemesh, and ended at the Jordan. There were sixteen cities, along with their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="23">This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Issachar, including these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The fifth lot came out for the clans of the tribe of Asher:</verse>
  <verse number="25">Their territory included Helkath, Hali, Beten, Achshaph,</verse>
  <verse number="26">Allammelech, Amad, and Mishal. On the west the border touched Carmel and Shihor-libnath,</verse>
  <verse number="27">then turned eastward toward Beth-dagon, touched Zebulun and the Valley of Iphtah-el, and went north to Beth-emek and Neiel, passing Cabul on the left.</verse>
  <verse number="28">It went on to Ebron, Rehob, Hammon, and Kanah, as far as Greater Sidon.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The border then turned back toward Ramah as far as the fortified city of Tyre, turned toward Hosah, and came out at the Sea in the region of Achzib,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Ummah, Aphek, and Rehob. There were twenty-two cities, along with their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="31">This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Asher, including these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The sixth lot came out for the clans of the tribe of Naphtali:</verse>
  <verse number="33">Their border started at Heleph and the great tree of Zaanannim, passing Adami-nekeb and Jabneel as far as Lakkum and ending at the Jordan.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Then the border turned westward to Aznoth-tabor and ran from there to Hukkok, touching Zebulun on the south side, Asher on the west, and Judah at the Jordan on the east.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The fortified cities were Ziddim, Zer, Hammath, Rakkath, Chinnereth,</verse>
  <verse number="36">Adamah, Ramah, Hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Kedesh, Edrei, En-hazor,</verse>
  <verse number="38">Iron, Migdal-el, Horem, Beth-anath, and Beth-shemesh. There were nineteen cities, along with their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="39">This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Naphtali, including these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The seventh lot came out for the clans of the tribe of Dan:</verse>
  <verse number="41">The territory of their inheritance included Zorah, Eshtaol, Ir-shemesh,</verse>
  <verse number="42">Shaalabbin, Aijalon, Ithlah,</verse>
  <verse number="43">Elon, Timnah, Ekron,</verse>
  <verse number="44">Eltekeh, Gibbethon, Baalath,</verse>
  <verse number="45">Jehud, Bene-berak, Gath-rimmon,</verse>
  <verse number="46">Me-jarkon, and Rakkon, including the territory across from Joppa.</verse>
  <verse number="47">(Later, when the territory of the Danites was lost to them, they went up and fought against Leshem, captured it, and put it to the sword. So they took possession of Leshem, settled there, and renamed it after their father Dan.)</verse>
  <verse number="48">This was the inheritance of the clans of the tribe of Dan, including these cities and their villages.</verse>
  <verse number="49">When they had finished distributing the land into its territories, the Israelites gave Joshua son of Nun an inheritance among them,</verse>
  <verse number="50">as the LORD had commanded. They gave him the city of Timnath-serah in the hill country of Ephraim, as he requested. He rebuilt the city and settled in it.</verse>
  <verse number="51">These are the inheritances that Eleazar the priest, Joshua son of Nun, and the heads of the families distributed by lot to the tribes of Israel at Shiloh before the LORD at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. So they finished dividing up the land.</verse>
</chapter>