<chapter book="Titus" number="2" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But speak you the things which become sound doctrine:</verse>
  <verse number="2">That the aged men be sober, grave, temperate, sound in faith, in charity, in patience.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The aged women likewise, that they be in behavior as becomes holiness, not false accusers, not given to much wine, teachers of good things;</verse>
  <verse number="4">That they may teach the young women to be sober, to love their husbands, to love their children,</verse>
  <verse number="5">To be discreet, chaste, keepers at home, good, obedient to their own husbands, that the word of God be not blasphemed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Young men likewise exhort to be sober minded.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In all things showing yourself a pattern of good works: in doctrine showing soundness, gravity, sincerity,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Sound speech, that cannot be condemned; that he that is of the contrary part may be ashamed, having no evil thing to say of you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Exhort servants to be obedient to their own masters, and to please them well in all things; not answering again;</verse>
  <verse number="10">Not purloining, but showing all good fidelity; that they may adorn the doctrine of God our Savior in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the grace of God that brings salvation has appeared to all men,</verse>
  <verse number="12">Teaching us that, denying ungodliness and worldly lusts, we should live soberly, righteously, and godly, in this present world;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Looking for that blessed hope, and the glorious appearing of the great God and our Savior Jesus Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who gave himself for us, that he might redeem us from all iniquity, and purify to himself a peculiar people, zealous of good works.</verse>
  <verse number="15">These things speak, and exhort, and rebuke with all authority. Let no man despise you.</verse>
</chapter>