<chapter book="John" number="7" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Jesus was walking after these things in Galilee, for he did not wish to walk in Judea, because the Jews were seeking to kill him,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and the feast of the Jews was nigh—that of tabernacles—</verse>
  <verse number="3">his brethren, therefore, said unto him, ‘Remove hence, and go away to Judea, that thy disciples also may behold thy works that thou dost;</verse>
  <verse number="4">for no one in secret doth anything, and himself seeketh to be in public; if thou dost these things—manifest thyself to the world;’</verse>
  <verse number="5">for not even were his brethren believing in him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Jesus, therefore, saith to them, ‘My time is not yet present, but your time is always ready;</verse>
  <verse number="7">the world is not able to hate you, but me it doth hate, because I testify concerning it that its works are evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Ye—go ye up to this feast; I do not yet go up to this feast, because my time hath not yet been fulfilled;’</verse>
  <verse number="9">and saying these things to them, he remained in Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And when his brethren went up, then also he himself went up to the feast, not manifestly, but as in secret;</verse>
  <verse number="11">the Jews, therefore, were seeking him, in the feast, and said, ‘Where is that one?’</verse>
  <verse number="12">and there was much murmuring about him among the multitudes, some indeed said—‘He is good;’ and others said, ‘No, but he leadeth astray the multitude;’</verse>
  <verse number="13">no one, however, was speaking freely about him, through fear of the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And it being now the middle of the feast, Jesus went up to the temple, and he was teaching,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and the Jews were wondering, saying, ‘How hath this one known letters—not having learned?’</verse>
  <verse number="16">Jesus answered them and said, ‘My teaching is not mine, but His who sent me;</verse>
  <verse number="17">if any one may will to do His will, he shall know concerning the teaching, whether it is of God, or—I do speak from myself.</verse>
  <verse number="18">‘He who is speaking from himself his own glory doth seek, but he who is seeking the glory of him who sent him, this one is true, and unrighteousness is not in him;</verse>
  <verse number="19">hath not Moses given you the law? and none of you doth the law; why me do ye seek to kill?’</verse>
  <verse number="20">The multitude answered and said, ‘Thou hast a demon, who doth seek to kill thee?’</verse>
  <verse number="21">Jesus answered and said to them, ‘One work I did, and ye all wonder,</verse>
  <verse number="22">because of this, Moses hath given you the circumcision—not that it is of Moses, but of the fathers—and on a sabbath ye circumcise a man;</verse>
  <verse number="23">if a man doth receive circumcision on a sabbath that the law of Moses may not be broken, are ye wroth with me that I made a man all whole on a sabbath?</verse>
  <verse number="24">judge not according to appearance, but the righteous judgment judge.’</verse>
  <verse number="25">Certain, therefore, of the Jerusalemites said, ‘Is not this he whom they are seeking to kill?</verse>
  <verse number="26">and, lo, he doth speak freely, and they say nothing to him; did the rulers at all know truly that this is truly the Christ?</verse>
  <verse number="27">but this one—we have known whence he is; and the Christ, when he doth come, no one doth know whence he is.’</verse>
  <verse number="28">Jesus cried, therefore, in the temple, teaching and saying, ‘Ye have both known me, and ye have known whence I am; and I have not come of myself, but He who sent me is true, whom ye have not known;</verse>
  <verse number="29">and I have known Him, because I am from Him, and He did send me.’</verse>
  <verse number="30">They were seeking, therefore, to seize him, and no one laid the hand on him, because his hour had not yet come,</verse>
  <verse number="31">and many out of the multitude did believe in him, and said—‘The Christ—when he may come—will he do more signs than these that this one did?’</verse>
  <verse number="32">The Pharisees heard the multitude murmuring these things concerning him, and the Pharisees and the chief priests sent officers that they may take him;</verse>
  <verse number="33">Jesus, therefore, said to them, ‘Yet a little time I am with you, and I go away unto Him who sent me;</verse>
  <verse number="34">ye will seek me, and ye shall not find; and where I am, ye are not able to come.’</verse>
  <verse number="35">The Jews, therefore, said among themselves, ‘Whither is this one about to go that we shall not find him?—to the dispersion of the Greeks is he about to go? and to teach the Greeks;</verse>
  <verse number="36">what is this word that he said, Ye will seek me, and ye shall not find? and, Where I am, ye are not able to come?’</verse>
  <verse number="37">And in the last, the great day of the feast, Jesus stood and cried, saying, ‘If any one doth thirst, let him come unto me and drink;</verse>
  <verse number="38">he who is believing in me, according as the Writing said, Rivers out of his belly shall flow of living water;’</verse>
  <verse number="39">and this he said of the Spirit, which those believing in him were about to receive; for not yet was the Holy Spirit, because Jesus was not yet glorified.</verse>
  <verse number="40">Many, therefore out of the multitude, having heard the word, said, ‘This is truly the Prophet;’</verse>
  <verse number="41">others said, ‘This is the Christ;’ and others said, ‘Why, out of Galilee doth the Christ come?</verse>
  <verse number="42">Did not the Writing say, that out of the seed of David, and from Bethlehem—the village where David was—the Christ doth come?’</verse>
  <verse number="43">A division, therefore, arose among the multitude because of him.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And certain of them were willing to seize him, but no one laid hands on him;</verse>
  <verse number="45">the officers came, therefore, unto the chief priests and Pharisees, and they said to them, ‘Wherefore did ye not bring him?’</verse>
  <verse number="46">The officers answered, ‘Never so spake man—as this man.’</verse>
  <verse number="47">The Pharisees, therefore, answered them, ‘Have ye also been led astray?</verse>
  <verse number="48">did any one out of the rulers believe in him? or out of the Pharisees?</verse>
  <verse number="49">but this multitude, that is not knowing the law, is accursed.’</verse>
  <verse number="50">Nicodemus saith unto them—he who came by night unto him—being one of them,</verse>
  <verse number="51">‘Doth our law judge the man, if it may not hear from him first, and know what he doth?’</verse>
  <verse number="52">They answered and said to him, ‘Art thou also out of Galilee? search and see, that a prophet out of Galilee hath not risen;’</verse>
  <verse number="53">and each one went on to his house, but Jesus went on to the mount of the Olives.</verse>
</chapter>