<chapter book="2 Timothy" number="3" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But understand this: In the last days terrible times will come.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For men will be lovers of themselves, lovers of money, boastful, arrogant, abusive, disobedient to their parents, ungrateful, unholy,</verse>
  <verse number="3">unloving, unforgiving, slanderous, without self-control, brutal, without love of good,</verse>
  <verse number="4">traitorous, reckless, conceited, lovers of pleasure rather than lovers of God,</verse>
  <verse number="5">having a form of godliness but denying its power. Turn away from such as these!</verse>
  <verse number="6">They are the kind who worm their way into households and captivate vulnerable women who are weighed down with sins and led astray by various passions,</verse>
  <verse number="7">who are always learning but never able to come to a knowledge of the truth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Just as Jannes and Jambres opposed Moses, so also these men oppose the truth. They are depraved in mind and disqualified from the faith.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But they will not advance much further. For just like Jannes and Jambres, their folly will be plain to everyone.</verse>
  <verse number="10">You, however, have observed my teaching, my conduct, my purpose, my faith, my patience, my love, my perseverance,</verse>
  <verse number="11">my persecutions, and the sufferings that came upon me in Antioch, Iconium, and Lystra. What persecutions I endured! Yet the Lord rescued me from all of them.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Indeed, all who desire to live godly lives in Christ Jesus will be persecuted,</verse>
  <verse number="13">while evil men and imposters go from bad to worse, deceiving and being deceived.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But as for you, continue in the things you have learned and firmly believed, since you know from whom you have learned them.</verse>
  <verse number="15">From infancy you have known the Holy Scriptures, which are able to make you wise for salvation through faith in Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="16">All Scripture is God-breathed and is useful for instruction, for conviction, for correction, and for training in righteousness,</verse>
  <verse number="17">so that the man of God may be complete, fully equipped for every good work.</verse>
</chapter>