<chapter book="Isaiah" number="14" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For Jehovah will pity Jacob, and he yet chose in Israel, and he gave them rest upon their land: and the stranger was joined to them, and they joined themselves to the house of Jacob.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And peoples took them and brought them to their place, and the house of Israel inherited them upon the land of Jehovah for servants and for maids: and they were captives to those having been made captives, and they came down upon those pressing them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And it was in that day Jehovah gave rest to thee from thy toil and from thy trouble, and from the hard service which was served upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And thou tookest up this parable against the king of Babel, and thou saidst, How did he oppressing, cease! oppression ceased.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Jehovah broke in pieces the rod of the unjust, the rod of the rulers.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Striking the peoples in wrath a blow not removed, bringing down the nations in anger; pursuing, not sparing.</verse>
  <verse number="7">All the earth rested, having quiet: they broke forth a rejoicing.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Also the cypresses rejoiced at thee, the cedars of Lebanon: From that time thou wert laid down, he cutting off will not come up against us.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Hades from beneath was moved for thee to meet thy coming: it roused the shades for thee, all the leaders of the earth: it raised up from their thrones all the kings of the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="10">All they will answer and say to thee, Also thou wert weak as we; thou wert made like to us.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thy grandeur was brought down to hades, the sound of thy harps: the worm was spread under thee, and worms covering thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">How thou fallest from the heavens, brilliant star, son of the morning! thou wert cut off to the earth, overthrowing upon the nations!</verse>
  <verse number="13">And thou saidst in thy heart, I will go up to the heavens; from above to the stars of God I will lift up my throne, and I will sit upon the mountain of appointment in the thighs of the north.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I will go up upon the heights of the cloud: I will become like the Most High.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But to hades shalt thou come down, to the thighs of the pit.</verse>
  <verse number="16">They seeing thee shall look upon thee, they shall attend to thee. This the man moving the earth, shaking kingdoms:</verse>
  <verse number="17">Setting the habitable globe as a desert, and destroying its cities: for his bound opening not the house.</verse>
  <verse number="18">All the kings of the nations, all of them, lay down in honor, a man in his house.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And thou wert east out of thy grave as a sprout abhorred, a garment of the slain thrust through with the sword, and going down to the stones of the pit as a corpse trodden down.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Thou shalt not be united with them in the grave, for thou destroyedst thy land, and didst slay thy people: the seed of those doing evil shall not be called forever.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Prepare slaughter for his sons, for the iniquity of their fathers; they shall not rise and possess the land, and fill the face of the habitable globe with cities.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And I rose against them, said Jehovah of armies, and I cut off to Babel the name and remainder, offspring and progeny, says Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And I set it for the possession of the hedge-hog, and pools of water: and I swept her with the broom of desolation, says Jehovah of armies.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Jehovah of armies sware, saying, If not as I purposed thus it was, and as I counseled, this shall stand:</verse>
  <verse number="25">To break Assur in my land, and upon my mountain I will tread him down: and his yoke was removed from off them, and his burden shall remove from off their shoulder.</verse>
  <verse number="26">This the counsel being counseled upon all the land: and this the hand stretched out upon all the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For Jehovah of armies counseled and who shall bring to nought? and his hand was stretched out, and who shall turn it back?</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the year king Ahaz died was this burden.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Thou shalt not rejoice Philistia, all of thee, because the rod of him striking thee was broken: for from the root of the serpent shall come forth a viper, and his fruit burning flying.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the first born of the poor were fed, and the needy shall lie down confidently: and I killed thy root with famine, and thy residue he shall slay.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Wail, thou gate; cry out, thou city; all thou Philistia, melting away, for from the north a smoke coming, and none being alone in his appointments.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And what shall the messengers of the nations answer? for Jehovah founded Zion, and the humble of his people shall trust in her.</verse>
</chapter>