<chapter book="Isaiah" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Behold, Jehovah emptying the earth and making it waste, and subverting its face, and scattering its inhabitants.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And it was as the people, so the priest; as the servant, so his lord; as the maid, so the mistress; as the buyer, so he selling; as he lending, so the borrower; as be lending on interest, so he exacting interest to him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Being emptied, the land shall be emptied: and being plundered, it shall be plundered: for Jehovah spake this word.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The earth mourning, fell away: the habitable globe languishing, fell away: the heights of the people of the land languished,</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the earth was polluted under its inhabitants, for they passed by the instructions, they changed the law, they broke the eternal covenant.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For this, the curse consumed the earth, and they dwelling in it, will transgress: for this, they dwelling upon the earth were burned, and those remaining, men of fewness.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The new wine mourned, the vine languished, all they joyful of heart, sighed.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The exulting of the drums ceased, the noise of those triumphing, left off, the exulting of the harp ceased.</verse>
  <verse number="9">They shall not drink wine with a song; strong drink shall be bitter to those drinking it.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The city of desolation was broken down: every house was shut up from coining in.</verse>
  <verse number="11">An outcry for wine in the streets; all joy grew dark, the exulting of the earth was carried into exile.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Desolation was left in the city, and the gate shall be struck in ruins.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For thus it shall be in the midst of the land in the midst of the peoples, as the beating of the olive, as the gleanings if the vintage was finished.</verse>
  <verse number="14">They shall lift up their voice, they shall shout for joy in the majesty of Jehovah they cried aloud from the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For this, with lights they honored Jehovah in the isles of the sea, the name of Jehovah the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">From the wing of the earth we heard songs, glory to the just one. And saying, Destruction to me, destruction to me, wo to me! they acting deceitfully, acted deceitfully; and spoiling, they acting deceitfully, acted deceitfully.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Fear, and the pit, and the snare, upon thee, thou inhabiters of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And it was he fleeing from the voice of the fear shall fall into the pit; and he coming up out of the midst of the pit, shall be taken in the snare: for the windows from the height were opened, and the foundations of the earth, will tremble.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And being broken, the earth was broken to pieces, and the earth being abolished, it was abolished; the earth being shaken, shook.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The earth moving to and fro, shall move to and fro as the intoxicated, and it was removed as a lodge; and its transgression was heavy upon it and it fell, and it shall not add to rise.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And it was in that day Jehovah shall review upon the army of the height upon the height, and upon the kings of the earth upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And they gathered a collection of the bound into the dungeon, and they were shut up into a shutting up, and after many days they shall be reviewed.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the moon blushed, and the sun was ashamed, for Jehovah of armies reigned in mount Zion, and in Jerusalem, and was honored before his old men.</verse>
</chapter>