<chapter book="Isaiah" number="29" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wo to Ariel, Ariel, the city David encamped in! add ye year upon year; the festivals shall run their circle.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I pressed upon Ariel, and there was sorrow and sighing, and it was to me as Ariel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I encamped as a circle upon thee, and I pressed upon thee with a garrison, and I raised intrenchments against thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And thou being brought down, thou shalt speak from the earth, and thy word shall be depressed out of the dust, and thy voice as a necromancer from the earth, and thy saying Shall peep from the dust.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the multitude of thy strangers was as the thin dust, and Its the chaff passing away, the multitude of the terrible ones: and it was at a moment suddenly.</verse>
  <verse number="6">From Jehovah of armies shalt thou be reviewed, with thunder and with shaking, and a great voice, whirlwind and storm, and the flames of consuming fire.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And it was as a dream of a vision of the night, the multitude of all the nations warring against Ariel and all warring against her and her fastnesses, and those pressing upon her.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And it was as when the hungry shall dream, and behold, he ate; and he awoke and his soul was empty: and as when the thirsty shall dream, and behold, he drank, and he awoke, and behold, he fainted, and his soul desired: thus shall be the multitude of all the nations warring against mount Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Linger ye, and wonder; delight yourselves, and be ye blinded; they were drunken and not with wine; they reeled and not with strong drink.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For Jehovah poured out upon you the spirit of deep sleep, and he will close your eyes: the prophets and your heads, the seeing he covered.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the vision of all will be to you as the words of the book being sealed, which they shall give to him, to him knowing writing, saying, Read now, this: and he said, I shall not be able, for it was sealed.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the book was given to him not knowing writing, saying, Read now, this: and he said, I know not writing.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Jehovah will say, Because that this people drew near with their month, and honored me with their lips, and their heart was far from me, and their fear towards me shall be taught from the command of men.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For this, behold me adding to be wonderful with this people, dealing wonderfully and being a wonder: and the wisdom of their wise perished, and the understanding of their understanding ones shall be hid.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Wo to those making deep to hide counsel from Jehovah, and their work was in darkness, and they will say, Who saw us? and who knew us?</verse>
  <verse number="16">Shall not your perverting be reckoned as the potter’s clay? for shall the work say to him making it, He made me not? and he being formed, say to him forming, He understood not?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Is it not yet a very little and Lebanon turned back to Carmel, and Carmel shall be reckoned for a forest?</verse>
  <verse number="18">In that day the deaf heard the words of the book, and the eyes of the blind shall see out of thick darkness, and darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the humble shall add joy in Jehovah, and the poor of men shall rejoice in the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For the terrible one ceased, the mocker was consumed, and they watching vanity were cut off:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Leading a man into sin by a word, and laying snares for him doing justice in the gate, and they will turn aside the just one by vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For this, thus said Jehovah, to the house of Jacob, who redeemed Abraham, Jacob shall not now be ashamed and his face shall not now become pale.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For in his seeing his children, the work of my hand, in his midst, they shall consecrate my name, and consecrate the Holy One of Jacob, and they shall fear the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they going astray shall know understanding, and they murmuring shall learn knowledge.</verse>
</chapter>