<chapter book="Isaiah" number="32" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Behold, a king shall reign for justice, and for chiefs they shall rule for judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And a man was as a hiding of the spirit, and a covering of the tempest; as brooks of water in Zion, as the shadow of a weighty rock in a weary land.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the eyes of those seeing shall not be blinded, and the ears of those hearing shall attend.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the heart of the hasty shall understand to know, and the tongue of those stammering shall hasten to speak plain.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Liberal shall no more be called to the foolish, and noble shall not be said to the deceiver.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For the foolish will speak folly, and his heart will do vanity to do profaneness and to speak error to Jehovah, to empty the soul of the hungry; and he will cause the drink of the thirsty to fail.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the implements of the deceiver are evil: he will meditate counsels to destroy the humble with words of falsehood, and in the needy’s speaking judgments.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the liberal will counsel liberal things, and upon liberal things shall he stand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Rise up, ye careless women; hear my voice, ye confident daughters; give ear to my word.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Days over a year shall ye being confident, be disturbed; for the vintage being finished, the ingathering shall not come.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Tremble, ye careless be disturbed, ye, confident: strip and be naked, gird upon the loins.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Smiting upon the breasts for the fields of desire, for the fruitful vine.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Upon the land of my people shall come up the thorn of the sharp point; so upon the houses of rejoicing of the exulting city.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the fortress was left, the multitude of the city was forsaken; the hill and the watch-tower for caves even forever; the rejoicing of the wild asses a pasture of the flocks;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Until the spirit shall be poured upon us from on high, and the desert be for Carmel, and Carmel be reckoned for a forest.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And judgment dwelling in the desert, and justice shall sit in Carmel.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the work of justice was peace, and the service of justice, rest and confidence, even to forever.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And my people shall sit in a dwelling of peace, and in habitations of trust and in quiet resting places.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the hail hailing upon the forest; and the city shall be made low in lowness.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Happy ye sowing upon all waters, sending the foot of the ox and the ass.</verse>
</chapter>