<chapter book="Isaiah" number="40" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Comfort ye, comfort ye my people, will your God say.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Speak ye to the heart of Jerusalem, and call to her that her war was filled up, her iniquity was paid off: that she received from the hand of Jehovah double for all her sins.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The voice of him calling in the desert, Prepare ye the way of Jehovah, make straight in the sterile region a highway for our God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Every valley shall be lifted up, and every mountain and hill shall be made low: and the acclivity was for evenness, and the mountain ranges for a valley:</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the glory of Jehovah was uncovered, and all flesh saw it together: for the mouth of Jehovah spake.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The voice said, Call And he said, What shall I call? All flesh grass, and all its goodness as the flower of the field:</verse>
  <verse number="7">The grass was dried up, the flower fell away: for the spirit of Jehovah blew upon it: surely the people grass.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The grass was dried up, the flower fell away: and the word of our God shall stand forever.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Upon the high mountain come up for thee, O Zion: announcing the good news, lift up thy voice with strength, O Jerusalem; announcing the good news, lift up, thou shalt not be afraid; say to the cities, Behold your God!</verse>
  <verse number="10">Behold the Lord Jehovah will come in strength, and his arm ruling for him: behold, his reward with him and his work before him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">As a shepherd he will feed his flock: with his arm he will gather the lambs, and will lift up into his bosom, he will lead those coming up.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Who measured the water in his palm, and measured the heavens with a span, and held the dust of the earth in a third, and weighed the mountains in a balance and the bills in scales?</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who measured the spirit of Jehovah? and will a man of his counsel make him to know?</verse>
  <verse number="14">With whom did he consult, and will he cause him to understand and teach him in the path of judgment, and teach him knowledge, and cause him to know the way of understanding?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, the nations as a drop from a bucket; they were reckoned as the fine dust of the scales: behold, he will cast down the isles as small dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Lebanon not enough to burn, and its beasts not enough for a burnt-offering.</verse>
  <verse number="17">All the nations as nothing before him; they were reckoned to him from nothing, and vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And to whom will ye liken God? what likeness will ye compare to him?</verse>
  <verse number="19">The artificer cast the carved image, and the founder will spread it out with gold, and he smelted chains of silver.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he being poor of oblation will choose wood that will not be rotten; he will seek to him a wise artificer to prepare a carved image that will not shake.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Will ye not know? will ye not hear? was it not announced to you from the beginning? did ye not understand from the foundations of the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="22">He sitting upon the circle of the earth, and its inhabitants as locusts; he stretching out the heavens as fine cloth, and he will extend them as a tent to dwell in:</verse>
  <verse number="23">He gave princes to nothing; he made the judges of the earth as vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Also they were not planted: also they were not sown: also their stock took not root in the earth: and he also blew upon them and they will be dried up, and the storm will lift them up as straw.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And to whom will ye liken me, and shall I be equal? will say the Holy One.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Lift up your eyes on high, and see who created these, bringing forth their army by number: he will call to all of them by name, from the multitude of their strength; and he is strong of power; a man was not wanting.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For what wilt thou say, O Jacob, and wilt thou speak, O Israel, My way was hid from Jehovah, and my judgment will pass over from my God.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Didst thou not know? heardest thou not the eternal God, Jehovah, creating the extremities of the earth, will not faint, and will not be weary? no searching to his understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He gave power to the faint; and to the not strong he will increase strength.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the boys shall be faint and weary, and the young men faltering, shall become feeble.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they waiting for Jehovah shall change power; they shall go up on the wing as eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall go and not faint.</verse>
</chapter>