<chapter book="Isaiah" number="45" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Thus said Jehovah to his Messiah, to Cyrus whom I held by his right hand to bring down nations before him; and I will loosen the loins of kings to open before him the doors; and the gates shall not be shut.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I will go before thee, and I will make straight the circles: I will break in pieces the doors of brass, and I will cut down the bars of iron:</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I gave to thee the treasures of darkness, and the hidden stores of lurking places, so that thou shalt know that I Jehovah calling by, thy name am the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For sake of my servant Jacob, and Israel my chosen, and I will call to thee by thy name: and I will address thee, and thou knewest me not.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I am Jehovah, and none yet, no God besides me: I will gird thee and thou knewest me not:</verse>
  <verse number="6">So that they shall know from the rising of the sun, and from the west, that none besides me. I am Jehovah, and none yet.</verse>
  <verse number="7">I shall form light and create darkness: making peace and creating evil: I Jehovah doing all these.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Drop, ye heavens, from above, and the clouds shall shake out justice: the earth shall open, and they shall bring forth salvation, and justice shall spring up together; I Jehovah created it.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Wo to him striving with him forming him! the potsherd with the potsherds of the earth. Shall the clay say to him forming it, What wilt thou make? and thy work, No hands to it?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Wo to him saying to the father, What wilt thou beget? and to the woman, What wilt thou bring forth?</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thus said Jehovah, the Holy One of Israel, and his potter, Ask me of things coming concerning the sons, and concerning the work of my hands will ye command me?</verse>
  <verse number="12">I made the earth, and man upon it I created: my hand stretched forth the heavens, and all their army I commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="13">I mused him up in justice, and I will make straight all his ways: he shall build my city, and he shall send away my captivity, not by price and not by a gift, said Jehovah of armies.</verse>
  <verse number="14">This said Jehovah, The labor of Egypt and the gain of Cush, and of the Sabeans, men of measure, shall pass over upon thee, and to thee shall they be: after thee shall they come in fetters: they shall pass over and to thee shall they worship and supplicate to thee, Surely God is in thee, and none yet: no God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Surely thou art God hiding thyself, the God of Israel, the Saviour.</verse>
  <verse number="16">They were ashamed and also disgraced, all of them: together they went in shame the workmen of images.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Israel was saved in Jehovah with an everlasting salvation: ye shall not be ashamed and ye shall not be disgraced even to forever, forever.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For thus said Jehovah creating the heavens, He the God forming the earth, and he made it; he prepared it, be created it not in vain, he formed it to be dwelt in: I Jehovah and none besides.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I spake not in secret in a dark place of the earth: I said not to the seed of Jacob, Seek ye me in vain: I Jehovah speak justice, announcing straightnesses.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Assemble ye together and come; draw ye near together, the escaped of the nations: they knew not lifting up the wood of their carved image, and praying to God he will not save.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Announce ye, and bring near; also ye shall take counsel together: who caused this to be heard from of old, from then announcing it? was it not I Jehovah? and no God more beside me; a just God and Saviour; none beside me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Look to me all ye ends of the earth and be saved, for I am God, and none else.</verse>
  <verse number="23">By myself I sware the word, justice went forth out of my mouth, and shall not turn back, That to me every knee shall bend, every tongue shall swear.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Surely saying, In Jehovah to me justice and strength: even to him shall he come; and all being angry against him shall be ashamed.</verse>
  <verse number="25">In Jehovah shall all the seed of Israel be justified, and shall glory.</verse>
</chapter>