<chapter book="Isaiah" number="52" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Awake, awake, put on thy strength, O Zion; put on the garments of thy glory, O Jerusalem, the holy city: for the uncircumcised shall no more add to come into thee, and the unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shake thyself from dust: arise, sit down, O Jerusalem: loose thyself from the bonds of thy neck, thou captive daughter of Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For thus said Jehovah, Ye sold yourselves gratuitously, and ye shall not be redeemed with silver.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thus said the Lord Jehovah, My people at first went down to Egypt to sojourn there, and Assur oppressed them for nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And now what to me here, says Jehovah, that my people were taken gratuitously? ruling, they will cause to give a sharp sound, says Jehovah; and continually all the day my name being despised.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For this, my people shall know my name: for this in that day, for I am he speaking: behold me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">How exalted upon the mountains the feet of him announcing good news, causing peace to be beard: announcing good news of good, causing salvation to be heard; saying to Zion, Thy God reigns!</verse>
  <verse number="8">They watching thee lifted up the voice; the voice together they will shout: for they shall see eye to eye in Jehovah’s turning back Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Break forth into joy, shout together, ye wastes of Jerusalem, for Jehovah comforted his people, he redeemed Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Jehovah uncovered his holy arm to the eyes of all nations, and all the ends of the earth saw the salvation of our God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Turn aside, turn aside, come ye forth from thence; ye shall not touch the unclean thing; come forth from the midst of her; be separated ye lifting up the vessels of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For ye shall not come forth with haste, and in flight ye shall not go; for Jehovah goes before you, and he gathering you the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Behold, my servant shall be wise, he shall be exalted, and lifted up, and be high exceedingly.</verse>
  <verse number="14">As many were astonished at thee, his appearance being so spoiled from man, and his form from the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="15">So shall he cause many nations to rejoice for him; kings shall shut their mouth; for what was not recounted to them they saw; and what they heard not, they considered.</verse>
</chapter>