<chapter book="Isaiah" number="53" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Who believed in our report? and to whom was the arm of Jehovah uncovered?</verse>
  <verse number="2">He shall come up as a sucking child before him, and as a root out of a land of dryness: no form to him and no decoration; and we shall see him, and no appearance and we shall desire him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">He was despised and forsaken of men; a man of griefs and knowing affliction: and as hiding the faces from him; he was despised and we regarded him not.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Surely he lifted up our afflictions, and our griefs he carried them: and we reckoned him to be smitten, struck of God, and afflicted.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And he being wounded for our transgressions, and crushed from our iniquities; the correction of our peace upon him, and in the marks of his stripes it was healed to us.</verse>
  <verse number="6">All we as sheep went astray; we turned a man to his way; and Jehovah caused the iniquity of us all to fall upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He was pressed, and he was afflicted, and he will not open his mouth: he was brought as a sheep for the slaughter, and as a sheep before his shearers being dumb and he will not open his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">From constraint and from judgment was he taken, and his generation who shall comprehend? for he was cut off out of the land of the living: for the transgression of my people was he struck for them.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he will give with the unjust his grave, and with the rich in his deaths, for he did no violence, and no deceit in his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Jehovah inclined to crash him; piercing him when his soul shall be set a sacrifice for sin, he shall see seed, he shall prolong the days, and the delight of Jehovah shall prosper in his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And be shall see of the labor of his soul, he shall be satisfied: by his knowledge my just servant shall justify for many; and he shall bear their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For this I will divide to him with many, and he shall divide the spoil with the strong; for which his soul was poured out to death, and he was numbered with transgressors; and he lifted up the sin of many, and he will supplicate for transgressors.</verse>
</chapter>