<chapter book="Isaiah" number="54" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Shout, thou barren, not bringing forth; break forth in shouting, cry aloud, not being pained; for more the sons of the desolate than the sons of the married, said Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Enlarge the place of thy tent, stretch forth the hangings of thy dwellings; thou shalt not spare; lengthen thy cords and strengthen thy pegs.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For the right and the left thou shalt break forth, and thy seed shall inherit the nations, and they shall cause desolated cities to be inhabited.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou shalt not fear; for thou shalt not be ashamed: and thou shalt not be disgraced, and thou shalt not be put to shame, for thou shalt forget the shame of thy youth, and thou shalt no more remember the reproach of thy widowhood.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For thy Lord making thee; Jehovah of armies his name; and he redeeming thee, the Holy One of Israel; the God of the earth shall he be called.</verse>
  <verse number="6">As a wife forsaken and grieved of spirit Jehovah called thee, and a wife of youth; for thou shalt be rejected, said thy God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">In a little moment I forsook thee; and with great mercies I will gather thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">In the outpouring of anger I hid a moment my face from thee; and in eternal mercy I compassionated thee, said Jehovah redeeming thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For this the water of Noah to me: as I sware to the water of Noah from again passing over the earth; thus I sware from being angry against thee and from rebuking upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For the mountains shall remove and the hills shall waver; and my mercy shall not remove from thee, and the covenant of my peace shall not waver, said Jehovah compassionating thee.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Thou afflicted, tossed about, not comforted behold me laying thy stones with paint, and I founded thee with sapphires.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I set thy battlements the ruby, and thy gates in stones of sparkling, and all thy bound in stones of delight.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And all thy sons taught of Jehovah; and much the peace of thy sons.</verse>
  <verse number="14">In justice shalt thou be prepared: go far off from violence; for thou shalt not be afraid: and from terror, for it shall not draw near to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Behold, gathering, it shall gather together, not from me: who sojourned with thee shall fall for thee.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Behold, I created the workman blowing the coals in the fire, and bringing forth a utensil for his work; and I created the destroyer to overthrow.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Every vessel formed against thee shall not prosper: and every tongue that shall rise against thee in judgment thou shalt condemn. This the inheritance of the servants of Jehovah, and their justice is from me, says Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>