<chapter book="Isaiah" number="57" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The just one perished and none put upon the heart: men of kindness being taken away, for none understanding that the just one was taken away from the face of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He shall come into peace: they shall rest upon their beds, he went in his justice.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And ye, come ye near here, sons of her practicing magic, seed of the adulterer and the harlot.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Against whom will ye deride? against whom will ye make broad the mouth, will ye thrust out the tongue? are ye not children of transgressing and a seed of falsehood?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Being comforted with gods under every green tree, slaughtering the children in the valleys, under the clefts of the rocks?</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the smoothnesses of the torrent they thy portion, they thy lot; also to them thou didst pour out a libation, thou didst bring up a gift Shall I be comforted with these?</verse>
  <verse number="7">Upon a mountain high and lifted up thou didst set thy bed: also there thou wentest up to sacrifice a sacrifice.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Behind the doors and the door-post thou didst set thy memorial: for from me thou didst migrate, and thou wilt go up; thou didst make broad thy bed, and thou wilt cut out to thee from them; thou didst love their bed; thou didst look upon the hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And thou wilt pour out for the king with oil and thou wilt increase thy perfumes, and thou wilt send thy messengers even from far off, and thou wilt be made low, even to hades.</verse>
  <verse number="10">In the abundance of thy way thou wert wearied; thou midst, Not to give over; thou didst find the living of thy hand; for this, thou wert not pained.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And whom didst thou fear? and wilt thou be afraid? for thou wilt lie, and thou didst not remember me; thou didst not put it upon thy heart; was not I being silent and from of old, and thou wilt not be afraid of me?</verse>
  <verse number="12">I will announce thy justice and thy works, and they shall not profit thee.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In thy crying out, shall thy gatherings deliver thee? and the wind shall lift them all up; a breath shall take: and he taking refuge in me shall inherit the land, and he shall inherit my holy mountain;</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he shall say, Lift ye up, lift ye up; clear the way, take up the stumbling block out of the way of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For thus said the high and lifted up inhabiting eternity, and his name Holy; being lifted up, and I will dwell in the holy place, and with the broken and humble of spirit, to preserve alive the spirit of the humble, and to revive the heart of the broken.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For not forever will I contend, and not to everlasting will I be angry: for the spirit will faint from before me, and the lives I made.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the iniquity of his plunder was I angry, and I will smite him: covering myself, and I will be angry, and he went turning away in the way of his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I saw his ways, and I will heal him: and I will lead him and I will restore comforts to him, and to his mourners.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Creating the fruit of the lips; Peace, peace to him being far off, and to him being near, said Jehovah; and I healed him.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the unjust as the tossed sea when it shall not be able to rest, and its waters will toss up mud and mire;</verse>
  <verse number="21">no peace, said God, to the unjust.</verse>
</chapter>