<chapter book="James" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My brethren, do not have the faith of our Lord Jesus Christ, [Lord] of glory, with respect of persons:</verse>
  <verse number="2">for if there come unto your synagogue a man with a gold ring in splendid apparel, and a poor man also come in in vile apparel,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and ye look upon him who wears the splendid apparel, and say, Do thou sit here well, and say to the poor, Do thou stand there, or sit here under my footstool:</verse>
  <verse number="4">have ye not made a difference among yourselves, and become judges having evil thoughts?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Hear, my beloved brethren: Has not God chosen the poor as to the world, rich in faith, and heirs of the kingdom, which he has promised to them that love him?</verse>
  <verse number="6">But ye have despised the poor [man]. Do not the rich oppress you, and [do not] they drag you before [the] tribunals?</verse>
  <verse number="7">And [do not] they blaspheme the excellent name which has been called upon you?</verse>
  <verse number="8">If indeed ye keep [the] royal law according to the scripture, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself, ye do well.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But if ye have respect of persons, ye commit sin, being convicted by the law as transgressors.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For whoever shall keep the whole law and shall offend in one [point], he has come under the guilt of [breaking] all.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For he who said, Thou shalt not commit adultery, said also, Thou shalt not kill. Now if thou dost not commit adultery, but killest, thou art become transgressor of [the] law.</verse>
  <verse number="12">So speak ye, and so act, as those that are to be judged by [the] law of liberty;</verse>
  <verse number="13">for judgment [will be] without mercy to him that has shewn no mercy. Mercy glories over judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="14">What [is] the profit, my brethren, if any one say he have faith, but have not works? can faith save him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">Now if a brother or a sister is naked and destitute of daily food,</verse>
  <verse number="16">and one from amongst you say to them, Go in peace, be warmed and filled; but give not to them the needful things for the body, what [is] the profit?</verse>
  <verse number="17">So also faith, if it have not works, is dead by itself.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But some one will say, Thou hast faith and I have works. Shew me thy faith without works, and I from my works will shew thee my faith.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou believest that God is one. Thou doest well. The demons even believe, and tremble.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But wilt thou know, O vain man, that faith without works is dead?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Was not Abraham our father justified by works when he had offered Isaac his son upon the altar?</verse>
  <verse number="22">Thou seest that faith wrought with his works, and that by works faith was perfected.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And the scripture was fulfilled which says, Abraham believed God, and it was reckoned to him as righteousness, and he was called Friend of God.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Ye see that a man is justified on the principle of works, and not on the principle of faith only.</verse>
  <verse number="25">But was not in like manner also Rahab the harlot justified on the principle of works, when she had received the messengers and put [them] forth by another way?</verse>
  <verse number="26">For as the body without a spirit is dead, so also faith without works is dead.</verse>
</chapter>