<chapter book="Hosea" number="13" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When Ephraim speaketh tremblingly, He hath been lifted up in Israel, When he becometh guilty in Baal he dieth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And now do they add to sin, And make to them a molten image of their silver, By their own understanding—idols, A work of artisans—all of it, Of them they say, who are sacrificers among men, ‘The calves let them kiss.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">Therefore they are as a cloud of the morning, And as dew, rising early, going away, As chaff tossed about out of a floor, And as smoke out of a window.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I am Jehovah thy God from the land of Egypt, And a God besides Me thou dost not know, And a Saviour—there is none save Me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">I—I have known thee in a wilderness, In a land of droughts.</verse>
  <verse number="6">According to their feedings they are satiated, They have been satiated, And their heart is lifted up, Therefore they have forgotten Me,</verse>
  <verse number="7">And I am to them as a lion, As a leopard by the way I look out.</verse>
  <verse number="8">I do meet them as a bereaved bear, And I rend the enclosure of their heart.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And I consume them there as a lioness, A beast of the field doth rend them.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Thou hast destroyed thyself, O Israel, But in Me is thy help, Where is thy king now—And he doth save thee in all thy cities? And thy judges of whom thou didst say, ‘Give to me a king and heads?’</verse>
  <verse number="11">I give to thee a king in Mine anger, And I take away in My wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Bound up is the iniquity of Ephraim, Hidden is his sin,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Pangs of a travailing woman come to him, He is a son not wise, For he remaineth not the time for the breaking forth of sons.</verse>
  <verse number="14">From the hand of Sheol I do ransom them, From death I redeem them, Where is thy plague, O death? Where thy destruction, O Sheol? Repentance is hid from Mine eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Though he among brethren produceth fruit, Come in doth an east wind, a wind of Jehovah, From a wilderness it is coming up, And it drieth up his fountain, And become dry doth his spring, It—it spoileth a treasure—every desirable vessel.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Become desolate doth Samaria, Because she hath rebelled against her God, By sword they do fall, Their sucklings are dashed in pieces, And its pregnant ones are ripped up!</verse>
</chapter>