<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I the man seeing affliction by the rod of his wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He led me and he brought darkness and not light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Surely he will turn back against me; he will turn his hand all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He wasted away my flesh and my skin; he broke my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He built against me, and he will surround with poison and distress.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He caused me to dwell in darknesses as the dead of old.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He walled about me and I shall not go forth: he loaded my brass.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Also when I shall exclaim and cry out, he stopped my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He walled up my ways with hewn stones, he made crooked my beaten paths.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He is to me a bear lying in wait, a lion in secret places.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He turned aside my ways and he will tear me in pieces: he set me a desolation.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He bent his bow, he will set me up as a mark for the arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He brought the sons of his quiver into my reins.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I was a derision to all my people; their song all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He filled me with bitternesses, he gave me wormwood to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He will break my teeth with gravel stones, he covered me with ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Thou wilt cast of my soul from peace: I forgat good.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And saying, My glory perished, and my hope from Jehovah:</verse>
  <verse number="19">Remembering my affliction and my bitterness, the wormwood and the poison.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Remembering, my soul will remember, and will be bowed down upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">I will turn this back to my heart; for this I shall hope.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The mercies of Jehovah are that we were not consumed, for his compassions were not finished.</verse>
  <verse number="23">New for the mornings: great thy faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Jehovah my portion, said my soul; for this I will hope toward him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Good Jehovah to those waiting for him, to the soul that will seek him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Good, and he shall wait and stand still for the salvation of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Good for a man that he shall lift up the yoke in his youth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">He will sit alone and be silent, for he laid upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">He will give his mouth in the dust, if perhaps there is hope.</verse>
  <verse number="30">He will give the cheek to him striking him: he will be filled with reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For Jehovah will not cast of forever:</verse>
  <verse number="32">For if he afflicted, and he compassionated according to the multitude of his mercy.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For he afflicted not from his heart and grieved the sons of men,</verse>
  <verse number="34">To crush under his feet all the bound of the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="35">To turn aside the judgment of a man before the face of the Most High.</verse>
  <verse number="36">To pervert a man in his contention Jehovah saw not.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who this saying, And it shall be Jehovah commanding not?</verse>
  <verse number="38">From the mouth of the Most High shall not come forth evil and good.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Why shall a living man murmur? a man for his sin?</verse>
  <verse number="40">We will search out our ways, and examine and turn back even to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="41">We will lift up our hearts upon the hands to God in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="42">We transgressed and resisted: thou forgavest not.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Thou didst cover with anger, and thou wilt pursue us: thou didst slay, thou didst not pity.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Thou didst cover over thyself with a cloud from a prayer passing through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Thou didst set us the offscouring and despising in the midst of peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All our enemies opened their mouth against us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Fear and a snare were to us, desolation and breaking.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Mine eye will bring down streams of water for the breaking of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">Mine eye flowed and it will not be silent, from no intermission,</verse>
  <verse number="50">Till Jehovah shall look forth and see from the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Mine eye will glean for my soul for all the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Hunting, they hunted me as a bird, mine enemies, gratuitously.</verse>
  <verse number="53">They cut off my life in the pit, and cast a stone upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">Waters were spread over my head; I said I was cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="55">I called thy name, O Jehovah, in the pit underneath.</verse>
  <verse number="56">Thou heardest my voice: thou wilt not hide thine ear at my breathing, at my cry.</verse>
  <verse number="57">Thou drewest near in the day I shall call thee: thou saidst, Thou shalt not fear.</verse>
  <verse number="58">Thou didst contend, O Jehovah, the contentions of my soul; thou didst redeem my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">Thou sawest, O Jehovah, my bowing down: judge thou my judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="60">Thou sawest all their vengeance, all their purposes against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">Thou heardest their reproach, O Jehovah, all their purposes against me.</verse>
  <verse number="62">The lips of those rising up, and their devices against me all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="63">Their sitting and their rising, look thou: I their song.</verse>
  <verse number="64">Thou wilt turn back to them a retribution, O Jehovah, according to the work of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="65">Thou wilt give to them a covering of heart, thy curse to them.</verse>
  <verse number="66">Thou wilt pursue in thine anger, and thou wilt destroy them from under the heavens, O Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>