<chapter book="Acts" number="15" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And certain having come down from Judea taught the brethren, That except ye be circumcised by Moses custom, ye cannot be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Therefore dissension and no small discussion having been to Paul and Barnabas with them, they arranged for Paul and Barnabas to go up, and certain others of them, to the sent and elders in Jerusalem about this question.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Truly therefore the sent by the church passed through Phenice and Samaria, relating the turning back of the nations: and they made great joy to all the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And having arrived at Jerusalem they were received by the church, and the sent and elders, and they announced what God did with them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And certain of them from the sect of the Pharisees having believed, rose up, saying, That they must be circumcised, and to enjoin to keep the law of Moses.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the sent and elders were gathered together to see about this word.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And much discussion having been, Peter having risen up, said to them, Men, brethren, ye know that from ancient days God chose among us, through my month for the nations to hear the word of good news, and believe.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And God the knower of hearts testified to them, having given them the Holy Spirit, as also us;</verse>
  <verse number="9">And separated nothing between us and also them, by faith having purified their hearts.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now therefore why tempt ye God, to put a yoke upon the neck of the disciples, which neither our fathers nor we were able to bear?</verse>
  <verse number="11">But by grace of our Lord Jesus Christ we believe to be saved, as also they.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And all the multitude were silent, and heard Barnabas and Paul, recounting what signs and wonders God did in the nations through them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And after they were silent, James answered, saying, Men, brethren, hear me:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Simeon related how God first reviewed to take from the nations a people for his name.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And with this the words of the prophets agree: as has been written,</verse>
  <verse number="16">After these will I return, and rebuild the tent of David, having fallen; and its things undermined will I rebuild, and set it upright:</verse>
  <verse number="17">So that they remaining of men might seek out the Lord, and all the nations upon whom my name has been called upon them, says the Lord, making all these.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Known to God are all his works from eternity.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wherefore I judge, not to molest them, from the nations turning back to God:</verse>
  <verse number="20">But to send to them, to keep off from pollutions of images, and harlotry, and strangulation, and blood.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For Moses of ancient generations has them proclaiming him in every city, being read in the synagogues in every sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then it seemed fitting to the sent and the elders, with the whole church, to send chosen men of them to Antioch with Paul and Barnabas; Judas surnamed Barsabas, and Silas, leading men among the brethren:</verse>
  <verse number="23">Having written by their hand thus; The sent and elders and brethren to the brethren in Antioch and Syria and Cilicia from the nations, health:</verse>
  <verse number="24">Since we heard that certain of us having come out have troubled you with words, destroying your souls, saying, To be circumcised, and keep the law: to whom we sent no word:</verse>
  <verse number="25">It seemed fitting to us, having been unanimous, to send to you chosen men with our dearly beloved Barnabas and Paul,</verse>
  <verse number="26">Men having delivered up their souls for the name of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Therefore have we sent Judas and Silas, and these by the word announcing these things.</verse>
  <verse number="28">For it seemed fitting to the Holy Spirit, and to us, for no more burden to be put upon you but the necessities of these;</verse>
  <verse number="29">To keep off from things sacrificed to idols, and from blood, and strangulation, and harlotry: from which keeping yourselves, ye shall do well. Fare ye well.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Truly therefore having been loosed, they came to Antioch; and having gathered the multitude together, they gave up the epistle:</verse>
  <verse number="31">And having read, they rejoiced for the encouraging.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Judas and Silas, they also being prophets, through much speech consoled the brethren, and supported.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And having made time, they were loosed with peace from the brethren to the sent.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And it seemed fitting to Silas to wait for him.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And Paul and Barnabas tarried in Antioch, teaching and announcing good news, with many others, the word of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And after certain days said Paul to Barnabas, Now having turned back, let us review our brethren in every city in which we announced the word of the Lord, how they hold.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And Barnabas purposed to take with them John, called Mark.</verse>
  <verse number="38">But Paul deemed worthy, having withdrawn from them from Pamphylia, and not having come with them to the work, not to take him with them.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Therefore there was an incitement, so that they separated from one another: and Barnabas, having taken Mark, sailed to Cyprus;</verse>
  <verse number="40">And Paul, having chosen Silas, went forth, having been delivered to the grace of God by the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And he passed through Syria and Cilicia, supporting the churches.</verse>
</chapter>