<chapter book="Acts" number="16" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And he arrived at Derbe and Lystra: and, behold, a certain disciple was there, by name Timothy, son of a certain woman, a faithful Jewess; and of a Greek father:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Who was testified of by the brethren in Lystra and Iconium.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Him Paul wished to go forth with him; and having taken, he circumcised him, on account of the Jews being in those places: for all knew his father that he was a Greek.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And as they were going through the cities, they delivered them the orders to watch, having been determined by the sent and the elders in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Therefore truly the churches were rendered firm in faith, and abounded in number daily.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And having passed through Phrygia and the Galatian country, hindered by the Holy Spirit from speaking the word in Asia,</verse>
  <verse number="7">Having come to Mysia, they tried to go to Bithynia: and the Spirit suffered them not.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And having passed by Mysia they came down to Troas.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And a vision was seen to Paul by night; A certain man, a Macedonian, was standing, beseeching him, and saying, Having passed to Macedonia, help us.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And when he saw the vision, we quickly sought to come out to Macedonia, concluding that the Lord called us to announce good news to them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore having been conveyed from Troas, we ran straight forward to Samothracia, and the following day to Neapolis;</verse>
  <verse number="12">And thence to Philippi, which is the first city of Macedonia, a colony. And we were in that city passing certain days.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the day of the sabbaths we came out of the city by the river, where prayer was customary to be; and having sat down, we spake to the women come together.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And a certain woman, by name Lydia, a dealer in purple garments, of the city of Thyatira, worshipping God, heard: whose heart the Lord opened to attend to things spoken by Paul.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And when she was immersed, and her house, she besought, saying, If ye have judged me to be faithful to the Lord, having come into my house, remain. And she forced us.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And it was we going for prayer, a certain young girl having the spirit of Python met us, who furnished much gain to her lords, prophesying:</verse>
  <verse number="17">She having followed Paul and us, cried, saying, These men are the servants of the most high God, who announce to us the way of salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And this did she for many days. And Paul, having been exercised, and having turned back to the spirit, said, I command thee in the name of Jesus Christ to come out of her. And it came out the same hour.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And her lords having seen that the hope of their gain went out, taking Paul and Silas, they drew to the assembly to the rulers,</verse>
  <verse number="20">And having brought them to the generals, they said, These the men who cause disturbance to our city, being Jews,</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they announce customs, which it is not lawful for us to receive, nor do, being Romans.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the crowd set together against them: and the generals having rent their garments, commanded to scourge with rods.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And many blows having been put upon them, they cast into prison, having commanded the jailor to keep them safely:</verse>
  <verse number="24">Who, having received such an order, cast them into the inner prison, and placed their feet firmly in wood.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And at midnight Paul and Silas praying, praised God: and the imprisoned heard them.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And suddenly was a great earthquake, so that the foundations of the prison were shaken: and immediately all the doors were opened, and the bonds of all were let loose.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And the jailor being awakened, and having seen the doors of the prison opened, having drawn a sword, was about to kill himself, supposing the imprisoned to have fled.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Paul called with a great voice, saying, Thou shouldest do no injury to thyself; for we are all here.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And having asked for a light, he rushed in, and being trembling, fell before Paul and Silas,</verse>
  <verse number="30">And bringing them out, he said, Lords, what must I do that I might be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they said, Believe in the Lord Jesus Christ, and thou shalt be saved, and thy house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they spake to him the word of the Lord, and to all in his house.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And having taken them in that hour of the night, he washed out the blows; and was immersed, he and all his, immediately.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And having brought them up to his house, he set a table before, and rejoiced with the entire household, having believed God.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And it being day, the generals sent the bearers of the rod, saying, Loose these men.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the jailor announced these words to Paul, That the generals have sent that ye be loosed: now therefore having come out, go in peace.</verse>
  <verse number="37">But Paul said to them, Having stripped us publicly not condemned, being Roman men, they cast into prison and now do they cast us out secretly? not so; but having come themselves, let them bring us out.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And the bearer of the rod announced these words to the generals: and they were afraid, having heard that they are Romans.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And having come they besought them, and having brought out, they entreated to come out of the city.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And having come out of prison, they came to Lydia; and having seen the brethren, they encouraged them, and they came forth.</verse>
</chapter>