<chapter book="Acts" number="26" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Agrippa said to Paul, It is permitted thee to speak for thyself. Then Paul defended himself, having stretched out the hand:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Concerning all of which I am accused by the Jews, king Agrippa, I deem myself happy, being about to defend myself to thee this day:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Especially thee being judge of all the customs among the Jews, and also of the questions: wherefore I beseech thee to hear me patiently.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Therefore truly my manner of life from youth, having been from the beginning in my nation in Jerusalem, all the Jews know:</verse>
  <verse number="5">Knowing me beforehand, from a former period, if they would testify, that according to the most strict sect of our religion, I lived a Pharisee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And now in the hope of the solemn promise having been made to the fathers by God, I stand, being judged,</verse>
  <verse number="7">To which our twelve tribes, serving night and day, hope to arrive. For which hope I am accused, king Agrippa, by the Jews.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Why is it judged incredible by you, if God raise the dead?</verse>
  <verse number="9">I therefore truly thought to myself, I must do many things contrary to the name of Jesus, the Nazarite.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Which I also did in Jerusalem: and many of the holy ones I shut up in prison, having received authority from chief priests; and they taken up, I carried down a vote.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And in all the synagogues, many times punishing them, I compelled to blaspheme; and being exceedingly enraged against them, I drove out even also to cities without.</verse>
  <verse number="12">In which also going to Damascus with authority, and superintendence from the chief priests,</verse>
  <verse number="13">The middle of day, I saw in the way, O king, a light from heaven, above the brilliancy of the sun, having shone around me, and those going with me.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And we having all fallen to the earth, I heard a voice speaking to me, and saying in the Hebrew dialect, Saul, Saul, why drivest thou me out? hard for thee to kick against goads.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And I said, Who art thou, Lord? And he said, I am Jesus whom thou drivest out.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But arise, and stand upon thy feet: for, for this was I sent to thee, to take thee in hand, a servant and witness both of what things thou sawest, and of what I shall be seen to thee;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Taking thee away from people, and nations, to whom I now send thee.</verse>
  <verse number="18">To open their eyes, to turn them back from darkness to light, and from the power of Satan to God, fur them to receive remission of sins, and inheritance with the consecrated by faith in me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Wherefore, O king Agrippa, I was not disobedient to the heavenly vision:</verse>
  <verse number="20">But to them in Damascus first, and Jerusalem, and all the country of Judea, and to the nations, announcing to change the mind, and to turn back to God, doing works worthy of change of mind.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For these things, me the Jews, having seized in the temple, attempted to kill with their own hands.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Therefore having obtained assistance from God, till this day do I stand, testifying both to small and great, saying nothing but what both the prophets and Moses spake being about to be:</verse>
  <verse number="23">That Christ exposed to suffering, that first from the rising of the dead, he is about to announce light to the people, and nations.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he defending himself by these, Festus said with a great voice, Thou art frenzied, Paul; many letters turn thee to madness.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he says, I am not frenzied, most excellent Festus; but I speak the words of truth and soundness of mind.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the king knows of these, to whom speaking freely I speak: for I am persuaded that none of these are unknown to him; for these were not done in a corner.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Believest thou the prophets, king Agrippa? I know that thou believest.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Agrippa said to Paul, In a little thou persuadest me to be a Christian.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Paul said, I would pray to God also in little, and in much, not only thee, but also all hearing me this day to become such, of what kind I also am, besides these bonds.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he having said these, the king arose, and the leader, and Bernice, and they sitting with them:</verse>
  <verse number="31">And having withdrawn, they spake to one another, saying, This man does nothing worthy of death or of bonds.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Agrippa said to Festus, This man could have been loosed, if he had not appealed to Caesar.</verse>
</chapter>