<chapter book="Acts" number="27" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And when it was determined for us to sail to Italy, they delivered Paul and certain others bound to a centurion named Julius, of Augustus’ band.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And having embarked in a ship of Adramyttium, being about to navigate places in Asia, we were conveyed; Aristarchus, a Macedonian of Thessalonica, being with us.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And another day we were brought down to Sidon. And Julius having treated Paul affectionately, gave him up, having gone to his friends to obtain care.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And conveyed from thence, we sailed to Cyprus, for the winds were contrary.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And having sailed over the sea by Cilicia and Pamphylia, we came down to Myra, of Lycia.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And there the centurion having found an Alexandrian ship sailing to Italy, placed us upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And in many days sailing slowly, and with difficulty having come to Cnidus, the wind not permitting us, we sailed under Crete, to Salmone;</verse>
  <verse number="8">And, with difficulty sailing by it, we came to a certain place called The fair havens; to which the city Lasea was near.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And a suitable time having intervened, and sailing being already dangerous, for the fast had already passed by, Paul advised,</verse>
  <verse number="10">Saying to them, Men, I see that with violence and much damage, not only of the cargo and ship, but also of our lives, the voyage is about to be.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But the centurion was rather persuaded by the pilot and the shipmaster, than by the things spoken by Paul.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the harbor being not suitable for passing the winter, the greater part took counsel to be conveyed from thence, if perhaps having arrived at Phenice, they may be able to pass the winter; a harbor of Crete, looking to the south west and to the country.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the south wind having blown softly, having thought to have obtained the purpose, hoisting up near, they sailed by Crete.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And after not much a violent wind struck against it, called Enroclydon.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the ship having been caught, and not able to resist the wind, yielding we were carried away.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And having run under a certain island called Clauda, with difficulty were we able to be commanding the boat:</verse>
  <verse number="17">Which having taken up, they used helps, undergirding the ship: and fearing lest they might fall through into the quicksand, having loosened the vessel, so were they borne away.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And we being exceedingly tempest tossed, the following day they made a casting of the cargo overboard;</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the third, working with our bands, we cast out the rigging of the ship.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And neither sun nor stars appearing for many days, and no small tempest impending, finally all hope for us to be saved was removed.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And there being much abstinence from food, then Paul having stood in the midst of them, said, Truly it was fitting, O men, having obeyed me, not to be conveyed from Crete, and gain this violence and damage.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And now I advise you to be cheerful: for there shall be no throwing away of soul from you, but of the ship.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the messenger of God stood by me in this night, whose I am, and whom I serve,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Saying, Fear not, Paul; Thou must stand before Caesar: and, behold, God has bestowed on thee as a gift all these sailing with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Wherefore, O men, be cheerful: for I believe God, that so it shall be as he has spoken to me.</verse>
  <verse number="26">But we must fall upon a certain island.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And when it was the fourteenth night, we being carried up and down in Adria, at midnight the sailors supposed some country brought near them;</verse>
  <verse number="28">And having sounded, they found twenty fathoms; and having removed a little, and again having sounded, they found fifteen fathoms.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And fearing lest perhaps we might fall through into rough places, having cast four anchors from the stern, prayed for day to come.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And the sailors seeking to flee out of the ship, and having loosened the boat to the sea, for a pretext as about to extend the anchors from the prow,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Paul said to the centurion and to the soldiers, Except these should remain in the ship, ye cannot be saved.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Then the soldiers cut off the ropes of the boat, and suffered it to fall off.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And till it was about to be day, Paul besought all to take food, saying, Awaiting this day the fourteenth day, ye continue fasting, having taken nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Wherefore I beseech you to take food: for this is for your salvation: for not a hair of the head of one of you shall fall.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And having said these, and having taken bread, he returned thanks to God before all: and having broken, he began to eat.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And all being cheerful, these also received food.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And we were, all the souls in the ship, two hundred and seventy-six.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And satisfied with food, they lightened the ship, casting out the wheat into the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And when it was day, they knew not the land: and they observed a certain deep bay having a coast, into which they resolved, if able, to push the ship.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And having in removed the anchors, they let go into the sea, at the same time having let loose the bonds of the rudders, and having lifted up the mizen mast, they held with the blast to the coast.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And having fallen into a place between two seas, they caused the ship to strike; and truly the prow, fixed firmly, remained undisturbed, but the stern was loosed by force of the waves.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And the soldiers’ counsel was that they kill the prisoners, lest any, having swum away, may escape.</verse>
  <verse number="43">But the centurion wishing to save Paul, hindered from the resolution; and he commanded those being able to swim, having cast off first, to come to land:</verse>
  <verse number="44">And the rest, truly some on boards, and some on certain things from the ship. And so it was, all were saved upon the land.</verse>
</chapter>