<chapter book="Acts" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the chief priest said, Hold these things thus?</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he said, Men, brethren, and fathers, hear ye: The God of glory was sent to our father Abraham, being in Mesopotamia, before he dwelt in Charran,</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he said to him, Come out of thy land, and from thy kindred, and come into the land which I shall show thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Then having come out of the land of the Chaldeans, he dwelt in Charran: and thence, after his father died, he transplanted him into this land, in which ye now dwell.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And he gave him none inheritance in it, not a step of the foot: and he promised to give it him for a possession, and to his seed after him, there being no child to him.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And God spake thus, That his seed shall be dwelling in a strange land; and it shall subjugate them, and inflict evil four hundred years.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the nation which they serve will I judge, said God: and after these shall they go out, and shall serve me in this place.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he gave him the covenant of circumcision: and so he begat Isaac, and circumcised him the eighth day; and Isaac Jacob; and Jacob the twelve patriarchs.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the patriarchs having been jealous, sold Joseph into Egypt: but God was with him,</verse>
  <verse number="10">And took him out of all his pressures, and gave him grace and wisdom before Pharaoh king of Egypt; and set him leader over Egypt and his whole house.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And a famine came upon the whole land of Egypt and Chanaan, and great pressure: and our fathers found no food.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Jacob having beard wheat being in Egypt, sent our fathers first.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And in the second time, Joseph was made known to his brethren; and Joseph’s race was manifest to Pharaoh.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And Joseph having sent, called for his father Jacob, and all his kindred, in seventy-five souls.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Jacob went down to Egypt, and died, he, and our fathers,</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they transported him to Sychem and put him in the tomb which Abraham was satisfied with for a price of silver from the sons of Emmor of Sychem.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And as the time of the solemn promise drew near, which God aware to Abraham, the people increased and were multiplied in Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Till another king arose, which knew not Joseph.</verse>
  <verse number="19">He having deceived our race by sophistry, inflicted evil upon our fathers, to make their babes cast out, that they should not breed.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In which time Moses was born, and he was shrewd to God, who was nourished up three months in his father’s house:</verse>
  <verse number="21">And he having been exposed, Pharaoh’s daughter took him up, and nourished him for a son to herself.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Moses was instructed in all the wisdom of the Egyptians, and was powerful in words and in works.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And when the time of forty years was completed to him, it came up upon his heart to take a view of his brethren the sons of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And having seen a certain one injured, he defended, and did vengeance for him harassed, having struck the Egyptian,</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he supposed his brethren to understand that God by his hand gives them salvation: and they understood not.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And the following day he was seen to those contending, and he compelled them to peace, having said, Men, ye are brethren; wherefore injure ye one another?</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he injuring the neighbor repulsed him, having said, Who set thee a ruler and judge over us?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Wilt thou not kill me, as thou didst kill the Egyptian yesterday?</verse>
  <verse number="29">And Moses fled at this word, and he was a sojourner in the land of Madian, where he begat two sons.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And forty years completed, a messenger of the Lord was seen to him in the desert of mount Sina, in a flame of fire in a bramble.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And Moses having seen, wondered at the sight: and he coming near to observe attentively, the voice of the Lord was to him,</verse>
  <verse number="32">I the God of thy fathers, God of Abraham, and God of Isaac, and God of Jacob. And Moses being trembling, dared not observe attentively.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And the Lord said to him, Loose the shoes of thy feet: for the place in which thou standest is holy land.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Having seen, I saw the injury of my people in Egypt, and I heard their groaning, and came down to take them away. And now came, I will send thee into Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="35">This Moses which they denied, having said, Who set thee ruler and judge? this, God sent, a ruler and redeemer by the hand of the messenger having been seen to him in the bramble.</verse>
  <verse number="36">He brought them out, having done wonders and sign in the land of Egypt, and in the Red sea, and in the desert forty years.</verse>
  <verse number="37">This is Moses, having said to the sons of Israel, A prophet shall the Lord your God raise up to you of your brethren, like me; him shall ye hear.</verse>
  <verse number="38">This is he having been in the church in the desert with the messenger speaking to him in Mount Sina, and our fathers: who received the living oracles to give to us:</verse>
  <verse number="39">To whom our fathers would not be obedient, but rejected, and in their hearts they turned back into Egypt,</verse>
  <verse number="40">Having said to Aaron, Make us gods who shall go before us: for this Moses, who brought us out of the land of Egypt, we know not what has been to him.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And they made a calf in those days, and brought up a sacrifice to the image, and rejoiced in the works of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And God turned, and delivered them up to serve the army of heaven; as it has been written in the book of the prophets, Slain victims and sacrifices brought ye not to me forty years in the desert, O house of Israel,</verse>
  <verse number="43">And ye took up the tent of Moloch, and the star of your god Remphan, types which ye made to worship them: and I will transplant you beyond Babylon.</verse>
  <verse number="44">The tent of testimony was with our fathers in the desert, as he speaking set to Moses, to make it according to the type which he had seen.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Which also our fathers having received brought in with Jesus in the possession of nations, which God drove out from our fathers’ face, even to the days of David;</verse>
  <verse number="46">Who found grace before God, and asked to find a tent to the God of Jacob.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And Solomon built for himself a house.</verse>
  <verse number="48">But the Highest dwells not in temples made by hands; as says the prophet,</verse>
  <verse number="49">Heaven a throne to me, and earth the footstool of my feet: what house will ye build to me? says the Lord: or what the place of my rest?</verse>
  <verse number="50">Did not my hand make all these things?</verse>
  <verse number="51">Ye stiffnecked and uncircumcised in heart and ears, ye always resist the Holy Spirit: as your fathers, also you.</verse>
  <verse number="52">Which of the prophets did not your fathers drive out and they slew them announcing beforehand of the coming of the Just; of whom ye have now been traitors and murderers:</verse>
  <verse number="53">Who have received the law by the regulations of messengers, and ye watched not.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And having heard those, they were sawn through their hearts, and they gnashed the teeth upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And being full of the Holy Spirit, having looked intently to heaven, he saw the glory of God, and Jesus standing at the right hand of God,</verse>
  <verse number="56">And he said, Behold, I see the heavens opened, and the Son of man standing at the right hand of God.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And having cried with a great voice, they held fast their ears, and rushed unanimously upon him,</verse>
  <verse number="58">And having cast out of the city, they stoned: and the witnesses laid down their garments at the feet of a young man called Saul.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And they stoned Stephen, calling upon, and saying, Lord Jesus, receive my spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="60">And having set the knees, he cried with a great voice, Lord, wouldest thou not set this sin to them. And having said this he was set to sleep.</verse>
</chapter>