<chapter book="Revelation" number="8" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And when it opened the seventh seal, there was silence in the heaven about half an hour.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I saw the seven angels who stand before God, and seven trumpets were given to them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And another angel came and stood at the altar, having a golden censer; and much incense was given to him, that he might give [efficacy] to the prayers of all saints at the golden altar which [was] before the throne.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the smoke of the incense went up with the prayers of the saints, out of the hand of the angel before God.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the angel took the censer, and filled it from the fire of the altar, and cast [it] on the earth: and there were voices, and thunders and lightnings, and an earthquake.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And the seven angels who had the seven trumpets prepared themselves that they might sound with [their] trumpets.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the first sounded [his] trumpet: and there was hail and fire, mingled with blood, and they were cast upon the earth; and the third part of the earth was burnt up, and the third part of the trees was burnt up, and all green grass was burnt up.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the second angel sounded [his] trumpet: and as a great mountain burning with fire was cast into the sea, and the third part of the sea became blood;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and the third part of the creatures which were in the sea which had life died; and the third part of the ships were destroyed.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the third angel sounded [his] trumpet: and there fell out of the heaven a great star, burning as a torch, and it fell upon the third part of the rivers, and upon the fountains of waters.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And the name of the star is called Wormwood; and the third part of the waters became wormwood, and many of the men died of the waters because they were made bitter.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the fourth angel sounded [his] trumpet: and the third part of the sun was smitten, and the third part of the moon, and the third part of the stars; so that the third part of them should be darkened, and that the day should not appear [for] the third part of it, and the night the same.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I saw, and I heard an eagle flying in mid-heaven, saying with a loud voice, Woe, woe, woe, to them that dwell upon the earth, for the remaining voices of the trumpet of the three angels who are about to sound.</verse>
</chapter>