<chapter book="Genesis" number="24" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Abraham was old and come days: and Jehovah praised Abraham in every thing.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Abraham will say to the old man of his house ruling over all which is to him, Put now thy hand under my thigh.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will cause thee to swear by Jehovah, God of the heavens, and God of the earth, that thou wilt not take a wife to my son, from the daughters of the Canaanites in the midst of whom I shall dwell.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For thou shalt go to my land and to my native country, and take a wife to my son, to Isaak.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the servant will say to him, Perhaps the woman will not be willing to come after me to this land: shall I turning back, turn back your son to the land from whence thou camest?</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Abraham will say to him, Observe to thyself that thou shalt not turn back ray son there.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Jehovah, God of the heavens, who took me from my father’s house, and from the land of my birth, and who spake to me, and who sware to me, saying, To thy seed will I give this land: he will send his messenger before thy face, and thou shalt take a wife to my son from thence.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And if the woman shall not be willing to come after thee, and thou shalt be clear from this thine oath; only thou shalt not turn back my son there.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the servant will put his hand under the thigh of Abraham his lord, and swear to him concerning this word.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the servant shall take ten camels from the camels of his lord, and will go, and all the goods of his lord in his hand; and he will rise and go to Syria of the rivers to the city of Nahor.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he will make his camels to kneel down without the city by the well of waters, at the time of evening, of the going forth to draw water.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And he will say, Jehovah, God of lord Abraham, light upon my face this day, and do kindness with lord Abraham.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Behold, I stand at the fountain of waters, and the daughters of the men of the city come forth to draw water.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And it shall be the girl to whom saying to her, incline now thy bucket, and I will drink; and she said, Drink, and I will also give thy camels to drink; thou didst appoint for thy servant Isaak; and by it I shall know that thou didst kindness with my lord.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And it shall be before he finished speaking, and behold Rebekah came forth, who was born to Bethuel, son of Milcah, the wife of Nahor, Abraham’s brother, and her bucket upon her shoulder.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the girl good of aspect exceedingly; a virgin, and man knew her not: and she will go down to the fountain and fill her bucket, and come up.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the servant will run to meet her, and he will say, Give me to drink now a little water from thy bucket.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And she will say, Drink, lord: and she will hasten, and she will bring down her bucket upon her hand, and will give him to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And she will finish to give him to drink, and will say, I will draw also for thy camels; till they finished drinking.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And she will hasten and empty her bucket into the watering trough, and will run again to the well to draw, and will draw for all his camels.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the man looking with attention at her, being silent to know whether Jehovah prospered his way or not.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And it shall be when the camels finished drinking, and the man will take a gold ring of half a shekel, and two bracelets for her hands of ten shekels of gold.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he will say, Whose daughter thou? announce now to me: is there place in thy father’s house for us to pass the night?</verse>
  <verse number="24">And she will say to him, I the daughter of Bethuel, son of Milcah, who was born to Nahor.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And she will say to him, also straw, and also much fodder to us; also a place to pass the night.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And the man will bow down and prostrate himself to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he will say, Praised be Jehovah, God of lord Abraham, who let not go his kindness and his truth from my lord: I in the way, Jehovah led me to the house of my lord’s brother.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the girl will run and announce to the house of her mother, according to these words.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And to Rebekah a brother, and his name Laban: and Laban will run to the man without at the fountain.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And it will be after seeing the ring and the bracelets upon his sister’s hands, and when hearing the words of Rebekah his sister, saying, Thus the man spake to me; and he will come to the man, and behold, he stood by the camels at the fountain.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And he will say, Come thou blessed of Jehovah, why wilt thou stand without? and I prepared the house, and a place for the camels.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the man will come into the house and will loosen the camels, and give straw and fodder to the camels, and water to wash his feet, and the feet of the men which are with him.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he will set before his face to eat, and he will say, Not to eat till I have spoken my word. And he will say, Speak.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And he will say, I am Abraham’s servant.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And Jehovah blessed my lord greatly, and he will be great; and he will give to him sheep and oxen, and silver and gold, and servants and maids and camels and asses.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And Sarah my lord’s wife will bring forth a son to my lord after she was old, and to him he will give all which is to him.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And my lord will cause me to swear, saying, Thou shalt not take a wife to my son from the daughters of the Canaanites in whose land I dwell.</verse>
  <verse number="38">If not, thou shalt go to my father’s house, and to my family, and take a wife to my son.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And saying to my lord, If the woman will not come after me?</verse>
  <verse number="40">And he will say to me, Jehovah, before whose face I walked, will send his messenger with thee, and prosper thy way, and thou shalt take a wife to my son from my family, and from my father’s house.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Then shalt thou be clean from mine oath, when thou shalt come to my family; if they will not give to thee, and thou shalt be pure from mine oath.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And I will come this day to the fountain, and say, Jehovah, God of lord Abraham, if thou wilt now incline thyself to prosper my way in which I go:</verse>
  <verse number="43">Behold, I stand by the fountain of waters, and the virgin coming forth to draw, and I said to her, Now give me to drink a little water from thy bucket.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And she saying to me, Both drink thou, and I will also draw for thy camels: she the woman which Jehovah appointed for my lord’s son.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Before I shall finish speaking to my heart, and behold, Rebekah went forth, and her bucket upon her shoulder; and she will go down to the fountain and draw; and saying to her, Give me to drink now.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And she will hasten and will bring down her bucket from her, and will say, Drink, and I will water thy camels also: and I shall drink, and she watered the camels also.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And I shall ask her and say, Whose daughter thou? And she will say, The daughter of Bethuel, son of Nahor, whom Milcah brought forth to him: and I shall place the ring upon her face, and the bracelets upon her hands.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And I shall bow down and worship Jehovah, and bless Jehovah, God of lord Abraham, who led me in the way of truth to take the daughter of my lord’s brother to his son.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And now if ye are doing kindness and truth with my lord, announce to me, and if not, announce to me; and I shall turn to the right hand or to the left.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And Laban will answer, and Bethuel, and they will say, This word came from Jehovah; we shall not be able to speak to thee, evil or good.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Behold, Rebekah before thy face, take and go, and she shall be wife to thy lord’s son, according to what Jehovah spake.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And it shall be when Abraham’s servant heard their words, and he will worship Jehovah to the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And the servant will bring forth silver vessels, and gold vessels, and garments, and he will give to Rebekah; and giving precious things to her brother and to her mother.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And they will eat and drink, he and the men which were with him; and they will pass the night; and they will rise up in the morning, and he will say, Send me forth to my lord.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And her brother will say, and her mother, The girl shall remain with us, perhaps ten days; after that she shall go.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And he will say to them, Ye shall not delay me, and Jehovah prospered my way send me forth, and I shall go to my lord.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And they will say, We will, call to the girl, and ask her mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="58">And they will call to Rebekah, and will say to her, Wilt thou go with this man? And she will say, I will go.</verse>
  <verse number="59">And they will send forth Rebekah their sister, and her nurse, and Abraham’s servant, and his men.</verse>
  <verse number="60">And they will bless Rebekah and will say to her, Thou our sister; be thou into thousands of ten thousands, and thy seed shall inherit the gate of his enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And Rebekah will rise up, and her maidens, and ride upon the camels, and will go after the man: and the servant will take Rebekah and will go.</verse>
  <verse number="62">And Isaak came from going to the well to the living vision, and he dwelt in the south land.</verse>
  <verse number="63">And Isaak will go forth to investigate in the field at the face of evening: and will lift up his eyes, and will see, and behold, the camels coming.</verse>
  <verse number="64">And Rebekah will lift up her eyes, and see Isaak; and she will descend from the camel.</verse>
  <verse number="65">And she will say to the servant, Who this man going in the field to meet us? And the servant will say, He is my lord: and she will take a covering and cover herself.</verse>
  <verse number="66">And the servant will recount to Isaak all the words which he did.</verse>
  <verse number="67">And Isaak will come into Sarah’s his mother’s tent, and will take Rebekah and she will be to him for a wife; and he will love her: and Isaak will be comforted after that for his mother.</verse>
</chapter>