<chapter book="Genesis" number="26" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And a famine shall be in the land, besides the first famine which was in the days of Abraham. And Isaak will go to Abimelech king of the Philistines to Gerar.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Jehovah will be seen to him, and will say, Thou shalt not go down to Egypt: dwell in the land which I shall say to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Sojourn in this land, and I will be with thee, and will bless thee, for to thee and to thy seed will I give all these lands; and I established the oath which I sware to Abraham thy father.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I will increase thy seed as the stars of the heavens, and I will give to thy seed all these lands: and in thy seed shall all the nations of the earth be praised.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Because that Abraham listened to my voice, and he will watch my watches, my commands, my statutes, and my precepts.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Isaak dwelt in Gerar.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the men of the place will ask concerning his wife; and he will say, She is my sister: for he will be afraid to say, My wife, lest the men of the place will kill me for Rebekah, because she is good in appearance.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And it was when the days there were long to him, and Abimelech king of the Philistines shall bend forward through the window, and will see, and behold, Isaak playing with Rebekah his wife.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Abimelech will call to Isaak, and will say, Surely, behold, she thy wife; and how saidst thou, She is my sister? And Isaak will say to him, Because I said, Lest I shall die for her.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Abimelech will say, What this thou didst to us? nearly one of the people lay with thy wife, and thou broughtest blame upon us.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Abimelech will command all the people, saying, He touching this man and his wife, dying, shall die.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Isaak will sow in that land, and will find in that year a hundred measures; and Jehovah will praise him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the man will become great, and went going, and he became great, until that he became very great.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And there will be to him possession of flocks, and possession of oxen, and service of many; and the Philistines will envy him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And all the wells which his father’s servants digged in the days of Abraham his father, the Philistines stopped them and filled them with dust.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Abimelech will say to Isaak, Go from us: for thou wert strong above us exceedingly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Isaak will go from thence, and will sit down in the valley of Gerar, and will dwell there.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Isaak will dwell, and he will dig the wells of waters which they digged in the days of Abraham his father; and the Philistines will stop them after Abraham died: and he will call them the names after the names which his father called them.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Isaak’s servants will dig in the valley and will find there a well of waters.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the shepherds of Gerar will contend with Isaak’s shepherds, saying; The waters are to us: and he will call the name of the well Esek; because they strove with him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they will dig another well, and will strive for that also: and he will call its name Sitnah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he will remove from thence, and will dig another well; and they strove not for that: and he will call its name Rehoboth; and he will say, For now Jehovah made wide for us, and made us fruitful in the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he will go up from thence to the well of the oath.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Jehovah will be seen to him in that night, and will say, I am the God of Abraham thy father: thou shalt not be afraid, for I am with thee, and I praised thee, and I increased thy seed, for sake of Abraham my servant.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he will build an altar there, and will call on the name of Jehovah, and will stretch out there his tent: and there Isaak’s servants will dig a well.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Abimelech went to him from Gerar, and Ahuzzath his friend, and Phicol, leader of his army.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Isaak will say to them, Wherefore came ye to me, and ye hated me, and will send me away from you?</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they will say, Seeing we saw that Jehovah was with thee: and we will say, There shall be an oath between us, between us and between thee, and we will make a covenant with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Wilt thou do evil to us as that we touched thee not, as that we did to thee only good, and we sent thee away in peace, thou now art praised of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he will make to them a drinking, and they will eat and drink.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they will rise early in the morning, and they will swear, a man to his brother, and Isaak will send them away and they will go from him in peace.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And it shall be in that day, and Isaak’s servants will come and announce to him concerning the well which they digged, and they will say to him, We found water.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he will call it oath: for this the name of the city the well of the oath till this day.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Esau will be the son of forty years, and he will take a wife, Judith, the daughter of Beeri the Hittite, and Bashemah, daughter of Elon the Hittite.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And they will be bitterness of spirit to Isaak and to Rebekah.</verse>
</chapter>