<chapter book="Genesis" number="34" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Dinah, the daughter of Leah, which she brought forth to Jacob, will go forth to see the daughters of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Shechem will see her, the son of Hamor the Hivite, chief of the land; will take her, and lie with her, and will humble her.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And his soul will cleave to Dinah, the daughter of Jacob, and he will love the maiden, and he will speak to the heart of the maiden.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Shechem will say to Hamor his father, saying, Take to me this maid for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Jacob heard that he defiled Dinah his daughter: and his sons were with his cattle in the field, and Jacob was silent till their coming.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Hamor the father of Shechem will go forth to Jacob to speak to him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sons of Jacob came from the field when they having heard: and the men will be grieved, and it will be kindled to them exceedingly because he did folly in Israel, to lie with Jacob’s daughter; and thus it shall not be done.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And Hamor will speak with them, saying, The soul of Shechem my son, was attached with his soul to your daughter; now give her to him for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And contract ye marriages with us; ye shall give your daughters to us, and ye shall take our daughters to you.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And ye shall dwell with us, and the land shall be before you; dwell ye and traffic in it, and take possession in it.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Shechem will say to her father, and to her brethren, Shall I find favor in your eyes? and what ye shall say to me I will give.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Increase to me greatly the dowry and gift, and I will give according to that ye shall say to me; and ye shall give to me this maiden for a wife.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the sons of Jacob will answer Shechem and Hamor his father with deceit, and will say, Because he defiled Dinah their sister.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they will say to them, We shall not be able to do this word, to give our sister to a man which to him is uncircumcision; for this a reproach to us.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But in this will we consent to you, if ye will be as we to circumcise to you every male;</verse>
  <verse number="16">And we will give our daughters to you, and we will take your daughters to us, and we will dwell with you and be one people.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And if ye will not listen to us to be circumcised, and we will take out daughter and depart.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And their words will be pleasing in the eyes of Hamor, and in the eyes of Shechem, Hamor’s son.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the youth deferred not to do the word, for he delighted in Jacob’s daughter, and he was honorable more than all his father’s house.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Hamor will come, and Shechem his son, to the gate of their city, and they will speak to the men of the city, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="21">These men they are living peacefully with us, and they shall dwell in the land, and traffic in it; and the land, behold, being broad to the hands before them: we will take their daughters to us for wives, and give our daughters to them.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Only in this will the men consent to us to dwell with us to be for one people, in the circumcising to us every male according as they having been circumcised.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Their cattle and their possession and all their quadrupeds, shall they not be to us? only we will consent to them, and they will dwell with us.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And to Hamor and to Shechem his son, will listen all going out of the gate of the city: and they will circumcise every male, all going out of the gate of the city.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And it will be in the third day, in their having pain, and the two sons of Jacob, Simeon and Levi, Dinah’s brethren, will take a man his sword, and will go against the city securely, and will kill every male.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they killed Hamor and Shechem his son, with the mouth of the sword; and they will take Dinah from the house of Shechem, and go forth.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The sons of Jacob came upon the wounded, and they will plunder the city, because they defiled their sister.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Their sheep and their oxen and their asses, and what was in the city, and what in the field, they took.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And all their force and all their little ones, and their wives they led captive, and they will plunder all which is in the house.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Jacob will say to Simeon and to Levi, Ye troubled me to make me evil to him dwelling in the land to the Canaanites, and to the Perizzites and I men of number, and they will gather together and smite me, and I all be destroyed, and my house.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they will say, Shall he do to our sister as an harlot?</verse>
</chapter>