<chapter book="Genesis" number="45" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Joseph will not be able to restrain himself before all standing by him; and he will cry out, Take out every man from me: and a man stood not with him, in Joseph’s making himself known to his brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he will give forth his voice in weeping, and the Egyptians will hear and the house of Pharaoh will hear.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Joseph will say to his brethren, I am Joseph; is my father yet living? and his brethren will not be able to answer him; for they trembled from before him.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Joseph will say to his brethren, Come near now to me: and they will come near, and he will say, I am Joseph, your brother, whom ye sold me into Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And now, ye shall not be grieved, and it shall not burn in your eyes, because ye sold me here: for God sent me before you for the preservation of life.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For this the second year of the famine in the midst of the land: and yet five years in which no ploughing and reaping.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And God will send me before you to put for you a remnant upon the earth, and to preserve life for you by a great deliverance.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And now not you sent me here, but God: and he placed me for a father to Pharaoh, and for lord to all his house, and ruler over all the land of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Hasten and go up to my father, and say to him, Thus said thy son Joseph, God placed me for lord to all Egypt; come down to me, thou wilt not remain.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And thou didst dwell in the land of Goshen, and thou wert near to me, thou, and thy sons, and thy sons’ sons, and thy sheep and thine oxen and all which is to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I nourished thee there (for yet five years of famine), lest thou shalt be poor, thou and thy house, and all which is to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And behold, your eyes seeing, and the eyes of my brother Benjamin, that my mouth is speaking to you.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And ye announced to my father all my glory in Egypt, and all which ye have seen: and haste ye, and bring ye down my father here.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he will fall upon his brother Benjamin’s neck, and will weep; and and Benjamin wept upon his neck.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he will kiss all his brethren, and will weep upon them: and after this his brethren sake with him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the voice was heard in the house of Pharaoh, saying, Joseph’s brethren came; and it will be good in the eyes of Pharaoh and in the eyes of his servants.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Pharaoh will say to Joseph, Say to thy brethren, This do ye: your cattle and come, go to the land of Canaan.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And take your father and your houses, and come to me: and I will give to you the good of the land of Egypt, and ye shall eat the heart of the land.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And thou being commanded, this do ye; take to you from the land of Egypt, wagons for your little ones, and for your wives, and take your father and come.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And your eye shall not spare upon your vessels: for the good of all the land of Egypt is to you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And the sons of Israel will do so: and Joseph will give to them wagons, by the mouth of Pharaoh, and he will give to them provision for the way.</verse>
  <verse number="22">To all of them he gave, to each, changes of garments: and to Benjamin he gave three hundred of silver and five changes of garments.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And to his father he sent according to this: ten asses lifting up from the good of Egypt, and ten she-asses lifting up grain and bread: and food for his father for the way.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he will send his brethren away, and they will go; and he will say to them, Ye shall not be angry in the way.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And they will go up from Egypt, and will come to the land of Canaan to Jacob their father.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they will announce to him, saying, Joseph is yet living, and that he the ruler over all the land of Egypt. And his heart will be cold for he believed them not.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And they will say to him all the words of Joseph which he spake to them: and he will see the wagons which Joseph sent to take him, and the spirit of Jacob their father will live.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Israel will say, It is much: Joseph my son is yet living: I will go and see him before I shall die.</verse>
</chapter>