<chapter book="Ephesians" number="5" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Become, then, followers of God, as children beloved,</verse>
  <verse number="2">and walk in love, as also the Christ did love us, and did give himself for us, an offering and a sacrifice to God for an odour of a sweet smell,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and whoredom, and all uncleanness, or covetousness, let it not even be named among you, as becometh saints;</verse>
  <verse number="4">also filthiness, and foolish talking, or jesting,—the things not fit—but rather thanksgiving;</verse>
  <verse number="5">for this ye know, that every whoremonger, or unclean, or covetous person, who is an idolater, hath no inheritance in the reign of the Christ and God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Let no one deceive you with vain words, for because of these things cometh the anger of God upon the sons of the disobedience,</verse>
  <verse number="7">become not, then, partakers with them,</verse>
  <verse number="8">for ye were once darkness, and now light in the Lord; as children of light walk ye,</verse>
  <verse number="9">for the fruit of the Spirit is in all goodness, and righteousness, and truth,</verse>
  <verse number="10">proving what is well-pleasing to the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="11">and have no fellowship with the unfruitful works of the darkness and rather even convict,</verse>
  <verse number="12">for the things in secret done by them it is a shame even to speak of,</verse>
  <verse number="13">and all the things reproved by the light are manifested, for everything that is manifested is light;</verse>
  <verse number="14">wherefore he saith, ‘Arouse thyself, thou who art sleeping, and arise out of the dead, and the Christ shall shine upon thee.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">See, then, how exactly ye walk, not as unwise, but as wise,</verse>
  <verse number="16">redeeming the time, because the days are evil;</verse>
  <verse number="17">because of this become not fools, but—understanding what is the will of the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and be not drunk with wine, in which is dissoluteness, but be filled in the Spirit,</verse>
  <verse number="19">speaking to yourselves in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody in your heart to the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="20">giving thanks always for all things, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, to the God and Father;</verse>
  <verse number="21">subjecting yourselves to one another in the fear of God.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The wives! to your own husbands subject yourselves, as to the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="23">because the husband is head of the wife, as also the Christ is head of the assembly, and he is saviour of the body,</verse>
  <verse number="24">but even as the assembly is subject to Christ, so also are the wives to their own husbands in everything.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The husbands! love your own wives, as also the Christ did love the assembly, and did give himself for it,</verse>
  <verse number="26">that he might sanctify it, having cleansed it with the bathing of the water in the saying,</verse>
  <verse number="27">that he might present it to himself the assembly in glory, not having spot or wrinkle, or any of such things, but that it may be holy and unblemished;</verse>
  <verse number="28">so ought the husbands to love their own wives as their own bodies: he who is loving his own wife—himself he doth love;</verse>
  <verse number="29">for no one ever his own flesh did hate, but doth nourish and cherish it, as also the Lord—the assembly,</verse>
  <verse number="30">because members we are of his body, of his flesh, and of his bones;</verse>
  <verse number="31">‘for this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and shall be joined to his wife, and they shall be—the two—for one flesh;’</verse>
  <verse number="32">this secret is great, and I speak in regard to Christ and to the assembly;</verse>
  <verse number="33">but ye also, every one in particular—let each his own wife so love as himself, and the wife—that she may reverence the husband.</verse>
</chapter>