<chapter book="Zechariah" number="10" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Ask ye of the LORD rain in the time of the latter rain, Even of the LORD that maketh lightnings; And He will give them showers of rain, To every one grass in the field.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For the teraphim have spoken vanity, And the diviners have seen a lie, And the dreams speak falsely, They comfort in vain; Therefore they go their way like sheep, They are afflicted, because there is no shepherd.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Mine anger is kindled against the shepherds, And I will punish the he-goats; For the LORD of hosts hath remembered His flock the house of Judah, And maketh them as His majestic horse in the battle.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Out of them shall come forth the corner-stone, Out of them the stake, Out of them the battle bow, Out of them every master together.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they shall be as mighty men, Treading down in the mire of the streets in the battle, And they shall fight, because the LORD is with them; And the riders on horses shall be confounded.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And I will strengthen the house of Judah, And I will save the house of Joseph, And I will bring them back, for I have compassion upon them, And they shall be as though I had not cast them off; For I am the LORD their God, and I will hear them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they of Ephraim shall be like a mighty man, And their heart shall rejoice as through wine; Yea, their children shall see it, And rejoice, their heart shall be glad in the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="8">I will hiss for them, and gather them, For I have redeemed them; And they shall increase as they have increased.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And I will sow them among the peoples, And they shall remember Me in far countries; And they shall live with their children, and shall return.</verse>
  <verse number="10">I will bring them back also out of the land of Egypt, And gather them out of Assyria; And I will bring them into the land of Gilead and Lebanon; And place shall not suffice them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And over the sea affliction shall pass, And the waves shall be smitten in the sea, And all the depths of the Nile shall dry up; And the pride of Assyria shall be brought down, And the sceptre of Egypt shall depart away.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I will strengthen them in the LORD; And they shall walk up and down in His name, Saith the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>