<chapter book="Galatians" number="6" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Brethren, if a man also may be overtaken in any trespass, ye who are spiritual restore such a one in a spirit of meekness, considering thyself—lest thou also may be tempted;</verse>
  <verse number="2">of one another the burdens bear ye, and so fill up the law of the Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="3">for if any one doth think himself to be something—being nothing—himself he doth deceive;</verse>
  <verse number="4">and his own work let each one prove, and then in regard to himself alone the glorying he shall have, and not in regard to the other,</verse>
  <verse number="5">for each one his own burden shall bear.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And let him who is instructed in the word share with him who is instructing—in all good things.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be not led astray; God is not mocked; for what a man may sow—that also he shall reap,</verse>
  <verse number="8">because he who is sowing to his own flesh, of the flesh shall reap corruption; and he who is sowing to the Spirit, of the Spirit shall reap life age-during;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and in the doing good we may not be faint-hearted, for at the proper time we shall reap—not desponding;</verse>
  <verse number="10">therefore, then, as we have opportunity, may we work the good to all, and especially unto those of the household of the faith.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Ye see in how large letters I have written to you with my own hand;</verse>
  <verse number="12">as many as are willing to make a good appearance in the flesh, these constrain you to be circumcised—only that for the cross of the Christ they may not be persecuted,</verse>
  <verse number="13">for neither do those circumcised themselves keep the law, but they wish you to be circumcised, that in your flesh they may glory.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And for me, let it not be—to glory, except in the cross of our Lord Jesus Christ, through which to me the world hath been crucified, and I to the world;</verse>
  <verse number="15">for in Christ Jesus neither circumcision availeth anything, nor uncircumcision, but a new creation;</verse>
  <verse number="16">and as many as by this rule do walk—peace upon them, and kindness, and on the Israel of God!</verse>
  <verse number="17">Henceforth, let no one give me trouble, for I the scars of the Lord Jesus in my body do bear.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ is with your spirit, brethren! Amen.</verse>
</chapter>