<chapter book="Titus" number="2" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But say the things which fit sound doctrine,</verse>
  <verse number="2">that older men should be temperate, sensible, sober minded, sound in faith, in love, and in patience:</verse>
  <verse number="3">and that older women likewise be reverent in behavior, not slanderers nor enslaved to much wine, teachers of that which is good;</verse>
  <verse number="4">that they may train the young women to love their husbands, to love their children,</verse>
  <verse number="5">to be sober minded, chaste, workers at home, kind, being in subjection to their own husbands, that God’s word may not be blasphemed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Likewise, exhort the younger men to be sober minded;</verse>
  <verse number="7">in all things showing yourself an example of good works; in your teaching showing integrity, seriousness, incorruptibility,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and soundness of speech that can’t be condemned; that he who opposes you may be ashamed, having no evil thing to say about us.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Exhort servants to be in subjection to their own masters, and to be well-pleasing in all things; not contradicting;</verse>
  <verse number="10">not stealing, but showing all good fidelity; that they may adorn the doctrine of God, our Savior, in all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation to all men,</verse>
  <verse number="12">instructing us to the intent that, denying ungodliness and worldly lusts, we would live soberly, righteously, and godly in this present world;</verse>
  <verse number="13">looking for the blessed hope and appearing of the glory of our great God and Savior, Jesus Christ;</verse>
  <verse number="14">who gave himself for us, that he might redeem us from all iniquity, and purify for himself a people for his own possession, zealous for good works.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Say these things and exhort and reprove with all authority. Let no man despise you.</verse>
</chapter>