<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="23" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And these the last words of David. The declaration of David, son of Jesse, and the declaration of the man raised up for the Messiah of the God of Jacob, and the sweet songs of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The Spirit of Jehovah spake in me, and his word upon my tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The God of Israel said to me, the Rock of Israel spake a parable upon the just man: a parable to fear God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And as the light of the morning the sun will rise: the morning not dense; from the shining of the rain bringing forth herbage from the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For not thus my house with the Strong One, for he set to me an eternal covenant, prepared in all, and watched: for all my salvation and delight will he not bring forth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Belial as the thorn thrusting out are all they, for they will not be taken by the hand.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the man laboring in them shall be filled with iron and the wood of a spear; and in fire burning they shall burn in the dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="8">These the names of the mighty, which were to David: the Tachmonite dwelling in the dwelling, head of the third; he Adino the Eznite: against eight hundred wounded at one time.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And after him Eleazar son of Dodo, son of Ahohi, among the three mighty with David in their upbraiding the rovers; they were gathered together there to war, and the men of Israel will go up.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He arose, and he will strike against the rovers till that his hand will be weary, and his hand will cleave to the sword: and Jehovah will do a great salvation in that day; and they sat down behind him only to strip off.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And after him, Shammah, son of Aga the Hararite. And the rovers will be gathered together to live; and there will be there a portion of the field full of lentiles: and the people fled from the face of the rovers.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And he will stand in the midst of the portion, and he will take it away, and he will strike the rovers: and Jehovah will do a great salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And three of the thirty heads will go down and come to the harvest, to David, to the cave of Adullam: and the wild beasts, the rovers, encamped in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And David then in the fortress, and the station of the rovers then in the House of Bread.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And David will desire and say, Who will give me to drink waters from the well of the House of Bread, which is in the gate?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And the three mighty will break forth through the camp of the rovers, and draw waters from the well of the House of Bread, which is in the gate, and they will lift up and bring to David: and he would not drink them, and he will pour them out to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And he will say, Far be it to me, O Jehovah, my doing this the blood of the men going with their souls: and he would not drink them. These did the three mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Abishai Joab’s brother, son of Zeruiah, he the head of the three. And he raised up his spear against three hundred wounded, and to him a name among the three.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Above the three was he not honored? and he will be to them for chief: and he came not even to the three.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Benaiah son of Jehoida, son of a living man great of works, from Kabzeel, he struck two lions of god of Moab: and he went down and struck a lion in the midst of a well in the day of snow.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And he struck a man, an Egyptian, who was seeing; and in the hand of the Egyptian a spear; and he went down to him with a rod, and he will pluck the spear out of the Egyptian’s hand and kill him with his spear.</verse>
  <verse number="22">These did Benaiah son of Jehoida, and to him a name among the three mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="23">He was honored above the thirty, and to the three he came not. And David will set him to his audience.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Asahel, brother of Joab, among the thirty; Elhanan, son of Dodo of the House of Bread.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Shammah the Harodite, Elika the Harodite,</verse>
  <verse number="26">Helez the Paltite, Ira, son of Ikkesh the Tekoite,</verse>
  <verse number="27">Abiezer the Anethothite, Mebunnai the Hushathite,</verse>
  <verse number="28">Zalmon the Ahohite, Maharai the Netophathite,</verse>
  <verse number="29">Heleb, son of Banah the Netophathite, Ittai, son of Ribai, from the hill of the sons of Benjamin,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Benaiah the Pirathonite, Hiddai of the torrents of Gaash,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Abialbon the Arbathite, Azmaveth the Barhumite,</verse>
  <verse number="32">Eliahba the Shaalbonite; of the sons of Jashen, Jonathan,</verse>
  <verse number="33">Shammah the Hararite, Ahiam son of Sharar the Hararite,</verse>
  <verse number="34">Eliphalet, son of Ahasbai, son of the Maacathite, Eliam son of Ahithophel the Gilonite,</verse>
  <verse number="35">Hezri the Carmelite, Paarai the Arbite,</verse>
  <verse number="36">Igal son of Nathan of Zobah, sons of the Gadite,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Zelek the Ammonite, Naharai the Beerothite, lifting up the arms of Joab, son of Zeruiah,</verse>
  <verse number="38">Ira the Ithrite, Gareb the Ithrite,</verse>
  <verse number="39">Uriah the Hittite: all, thirty and seven.</verse>
</chapter>