<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="4" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And Saul’s son will hear that Abner died in Hebron, and his hands will be relaxed, and all Israel trembled.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And two men, chiefs of troops, were to the son of Saul: the name of the one, Baanah, and the name of the second, Rechab, sons of Rimmon the Beerothite, of the sons of Benjamin, for also Beeroth was reckoned to Benjamin.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the Beerothites will flee to Gittaim, and they will be sojourners there till this day.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And to Jonathan, Saul’s son, a son smitten in the feet: he was the son of five years in the news coming of Saul and Jonathan from Jezreel, and his nurse will lift him up and flee: and it will be in her springing up to flee, and he will fall, and he will be lame: and his name Mephibosheth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the sons of Rimmon the Beerothite, Rechab and Baanah, will go, and they will come about the heat of the day to the house of the man of shame; and he lay down upon the bed at noon.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And behold, they came even to the midst of the house, taking wheat; and they will strike him in the belly; and Rechab and Baanah his brother escaped.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they will come to the house, and he will lie upon his couch in his bed-chamber, and they will strike him and kill him, and take away his head, and they will take his head and go the way of the sterile region all night.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they will bring the head of the man of shame to David to Hebron, and they will say to the king, Behold the head of the man of shame, son of Saul thine enemy, who sought thy soul; and Jehovah will give to my lord the king vengeance this day of Saul and of his seed.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And David will answer Rechab and Baanah his brother, sons of Rimmon the Beerothite, and he will say to them, Jehovah lives who redeemed my soul from all straits,</verse>
  <verse number="10">When he announcing to me, saying, Behold, Saul died; and he was in his eyes as announcing good news; and I shall seize upon him and kill him in Ziklag, which I gave to him for the good news:</verse>
  <verse number="11">Much more when wicked men killed a just man in his house upon his bed; and now shall I not seek out his blood from your hand and take you away from the earth?</verse>
  <verse number="12">And David will command the boys and they will kill them and cut off their hands and their feet, and hang them over the pain Hebron. And the head of Ishbosheth they took and they will bury it in the grave of Abner in Hebron.</verse>
</chapter>