<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="7" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it will be when the king sat in his house, and Jehovah gave rest to him from round about from all his enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the king will say to Nathan the prophet, See now, me dwelling in a house of cedars, and the ark of God dwelling in midst of the curtains.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Nathan will say to the king, All which, is in thy heart, do; for Jehovah is with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And it will be in that night, and the word of Jehovah will be to Nathan, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Go and say to my servant, to David, Thus said Jehovah, Shalt thou build me an house for my resting?</verse>
  <verse number="6">For I dwelt not in a house from the day I brought up the sons of Israel from Egypt even to this day, and I shall be going in a tent and in a dwelling.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And in all where I went among all the sons of Israel spake I a word with one of the judges of Israel whom I commanded to feed my people Israel, saying, Why built ye not to me a house of cedars?</verse>
  <verse number="8">And now thus shalt thou say to my servant, to David, Thus said Jehovah of armies, I took thee from quiet, from after the sheep, to be ruler over my people, over Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="9">And I will be with thee in all where thou wilt go, and I will cut off all thine enemies from thy face, and I made to thee a great name as the name of the great which are upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And I set a place for my people, for Israel, and I planted him and he dwelt in his place, and he shall be no more moved; and the sons of iniquity shall not add to humble him as in the beginning.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And from the day I commanded judges over my people Israel, and I gave rest to thee from all thine enemies. And Jehovah announced to thee that Jehovah will make to thee a house.</verse>
  <verse number="12">When thy days shall be filled up and thou shalt lie down with thy fathers, and I raised up thy seed after thee which shall come forth thy bowels, and I prepared his kingdom.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He shall build a house for my name, and I set the throne of his kingdom even to forever.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I will be to him for father, and he shall be to me for son; who in his sinning I struck him with the rod of men, and with the blows of the sons of men.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And my mercy I will not remove from him as I removed from Saul whom I removed from thy face.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And thy house was firm and thy kingdom even to forever before thee; thy throne shall be prepared even to forever.</verse>
  <verse number="17">According to all these words and according to all this vision so spake Nathan to David.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And king David will come and sit before Jehovah, and say, Who am I Lord Jehovah? and who my house that thou broughtest me even to these?</verse>
  <verse number="19">And this yet will be small in thine eyes, Lord Jehovah; and thou wilt speak also to the house of thy servant for remoteness. And this the law of man, Lord Jehovah?</verse>
  <verse number="20">And what shall David yet add to speak to thee? for thou knewest thy servant, Lord Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For sake of thy word and according to thy heart thou didst all this greatness to make thy servant know.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For this thou wert great, Jehovah God: for none as thee, for no God beside thee according to all we heard in our ears.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And who as thy people, as Israel, one nation in the earth whom God went to redeem to him for a people, and to set up for him a name, and to do for you greatness and wonderful things for thy land from the face of thy people whom thou didst redeem to thee from Egypt, nations and his tents.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And thou wilt prepare to thyself thy people Israel to thee for a people, even to forever. And thou Jehovah wert to them for God.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And now, Jehovah God the word that thou spakest concerning thy servant, and concerning his house, set up even to forever, and do as thou spakest.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And thy name shall be great even to forever, saying, Jehovah of armies the God over Israel: and the house of thy servant David shall be prepared before thee.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For thou, Jehovah of armies, the God of Israel, thou didst open the ear of thy servant, saying, I will build to thee an house: for this thy servant found his heart to pray to thee this prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And now, Lord Jehovah, thou that God, and thy words shall be true, and thou wilt speak to thy servant this goodness.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And now be willing and bless the house of thy servant to be forever before thee: for thou, Lord Jehovah, spakest: and from thy blessing the house of thy servant shall be blessed forever.</verse>
</chapter>