<chapter book="2 Samuel" number="8" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And it will be after this, and David will strike the rovers and subdue them: and David will take the bridle of the metropolis out of the hand of the rovers.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he will smite Moab, and measure them with a cord, laying them down upon the earth; and he will measure with two cords to put to death, and a full cord to save alive. And Moab will be to David for servants, lifting up gifts.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And David will strike Hadadezer, son of Rehob, king of Zobah, in his going to turn back his hand upon the river.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And David will take from him a thousand, and seven hundred horsemen, and twenty thousand footmen; and David will destroy all the chariots, and he will leave from them a hundred chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And Aram of Damascus will come to help Hadadezer, king of Zobah, and David will strike of Aram twenty and two thousand men.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And David will put garrisons in Aram of Damascus: and Aram will be to David for servants, lifting up gifts. And Jehovah saved David in all which he went.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And David will take the shields of gold which were upon the servants of Hadadezer, and he will bring them to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And from Betah and from Berothai, cities of Hadadezer, king David took exceeding much brass.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Toi, king of Hamath will hear that David smote all the strength of Hadadezer;</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Toi will send Joram his son to king David to ask him for peace and to bless him, because he fought with Hadadezer and struck him; (for Hadadezer was a man of war with Toi.) And in his hand were vessels of silver and vessels of gold and vessels of brass:</verse>
  <verse number="11">Also king David consecrated them to Jehovah with the silver and the gold, which he consecrated from all the nations which he subdued:</verse>
  <verse number="12">From Aram, and from Moab, and from the sons of Ammon, and from the rovers, and from Amalek, and from the spoil of Hadadezer, son of Rehob, king of Zobah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And David will make a name in his turning back from his smiting Aram in the valley of salt, eighteen thousand.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he will put garrisons in Edom; in all Edom he put garrisons, and all Edom will be servants to David. And Jehovah will save David in all which he went.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And David will reign over all Israel; and David will be doing judgment and justice to all his people.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Joab, son of Zeruiah, over the army; and Jehoshaphat, son of Ahilud, remembering.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Zadok, son of Ahitub, and Ahimelech, son of Abiathar, the priests; and Seraiah, scribe.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Benaiah, son of Jehoiada, and the Cherethites and the Pelethites: and the sons of David were priests.</verse>
</chapter>