<chapter book="Isaiah" number="52" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Awake, awake; put on your strength, O Zion; put on your beautiful garments, O Jerusalem, the holy city: for from now on there shall no more come into you the uncircumcised and the unclean.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Shake yourself from the dust; arise, and sit down, O Jerusalem: loose yourself from the bands of your neck, O captive daughter of Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For thus said the LORD, You have sold yourselves for nothing; and you shall be redeemed without money.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For thus said the Lord GOD, My people went down aforetime into Egypt to sojourn there; and the Assyrian oppressed them without cause.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Now therefore, what have I here, said the LORD, that my people is taken away for nothing? they that rule over them make them to howl, said the LORD; and my name continually every day is blasphemed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Therefore my people shall know my name: therefore they shall know in that day that I am he that does speak: behold, it is I.</verse>
  <verse number="7">How beautiful on the mountains are the feet of him that brings good tidings, that publishes peace; that brings good tidings of good, that publishes salvation; that said to Zion, Your God reigns!</verse>
  <verse number="8">Your watchmen shall lift up the voice; with the voice together shall they sing: for they shall see eye to eye, when the LORD shall bring again Zion.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Break forth into joy, sing together, you waste places of Jerusalem: for the LORD has comforted his people, he has redeemed Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The LORD has made bore his holy arm in the eyes of all the nations; and all the ends of the earth shall see the salvation of our God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Depart you, depart you, go you out from there, touch no unclean thing; go you out of the middle of her; be you clean, that bear the vessels of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For you shall not go out with haste, nor go by flight: for the LORD will go before you; and the God of Israel will be your rear guard.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Behold, my servant shall deal prudently, he shall be exalted and extolled, and be very high.</verse>
  <verse number="14">As many were astonished at you; his visage was so marred more than any man, and his form more than the sons of men:</verse>
  <verse number="15">So shall he sprinkle many nations; the kings shall shut their mouths at him: for that which had not been told them shall they see; and that which they had not heard shall they consider.</verse>
</chapter>