<chapter book="Nahum" number="1" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">This is the burden against Nineveh, the book of the vision of Nahum the Elkoshite:</verse>
  <verse number="2">The LORD is a jealous and avenging God; the LORD is avenging and full of wrath. The LORD takes vengeance on His foes and reserves wrath for His enemies.</verse>
  <verse number="3">The LORD is slow to anger and great in power; the LORD will by no means leave the guilty unpunished. His path is in the whirlwind and storm, and clouds are the dust beneath His feet.</verse>
  <verse number="4">He rebukes the sea and dries it up; He makes all the rivers run dry. Bashan and Carmel wither, and the flower of Lebanon wilts.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The mountains quake before Him, and the hills melt away; the earth trembles at His presence—the world and all its dwellers.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Who can withstand His indignation? Who can endure His burning anger? His wrath is poured out like fire; even rocks are shattered before Him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The LORD is good, a stronghold in the day of distress; He cares for those who trust in Him.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But with an overwhelming flood He will make an end of Nineveh and pursue His enemies into darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whatever you plot against the LORD, He will bring to an end. Affliction will not rise up a second time.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For they will be entangled as with thorns and consumed like the drink of a drunkard—like stubble that is fully dry.</verse>
  <verse number="11">From you, O Nineveh, comes forth a plotter of evil against the LORD, a counselor of wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="12">This is what the LORD says: “Though they are allied and numerous, yet they will be cut down and pass away. Though I have afflicted you, O Judah, I will afflict you no longer.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For I will now break their yoke from your neck and tear away your shackles.”</verse>
  <verse number="14">The LORD has issued a command concerning you, O Nineveh: “There will be no descendants to carry on your name. I will cut off the carved image and cast idol from the house of your gods; I will prepare your grave, for you are contemptible.”</verse>
  <verse number="15">Look to the mountains—the feet of one who brings good news, who proclaims peace! Celebrate your feasts, O Judah; fulfill your vows. For the wicked will never again march through you; they will be utterly cut off.</verse>
</chapter>