<chapter book="Luke" number="10" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After these things the LORD appointed other seventy also, and sent them two and two before his face into every city and place, where he himself would come.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Therefore said he to them, The harvest truly is great, but the laborers are few: pray you therefore the Lord of the harvest, that he would send forth laborers into his harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Go your ways: behold, I send you forth as lambs among wolves.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Carry neither purse, nor money, nor shoes: and salute no man by the way.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And into whatever house you enter, first say, Peace be to this house.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And if the son of peace be there, your peace shall rest on it: if not, it shall turn to you again.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And in the same house remain, eating and drinking such things as they give: for the laborer is worthy of his hire. Go not from house to house.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And into whatever city you enter, and they receive you, eat such things as are set before you:</verse>
  <verse number="9">And heal the sick that are therein, and say to them, The kingdom of God is come near to you.</verse>
  <verse number="10">But into whatever city you enter, and they receive you not, go your ways out into the streets of the same, and say,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Even the very dust of your city, which sticks on us, we do wipe off against you: notwithstanding be you sure of this, that the kingdom of God is come near to you.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But I say to you, that it shall be more tolerable in that day for Sodom, than for that city.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Woe to you, Chorazin! woe to you, Bethsaida! for if the mighty works had been done in Tyre and Sidon, which have been done in you, they had a great while ago repented, sitting in sackcloth and ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But it shall be more tolerable for Tyre and Sidon at the judgment, than for you.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And you, Capernaum, which are exalted to heaven, shall be thrust down to hell.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He that hears you hears me; and he that despises you despises me; and he that despises me despises him that sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And the seventy returned again with joy, saying, Lord, even the devils are subject to us through your name.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he said to them, I beheld Satan as lightning fall from heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Behold, I give to you power to tread on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy: and nothing shall by any means hurt you.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Notwithstanding in this rejoice not, that the spirits are subject to you; but rather rejoice, because your names are written in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="21">In that hour Jesus rejoiced in spirit, and said, I thank you, O Father, Lord of heaven and earth, that you have hid these things from the wise and prudent, and have revealed them to babes: even so, Father; for so it seemed good in your sight.</verse>
  <verse number="22">All things are delivered to me of my Father: and no man knows who the Son is, but the Father; and who the Father is, but the Son, and he to whom the Son will reveal him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he turned him to his disciples, and said privately, Blessed are the eyes which see the things that you see:</verse>
  <verse number="24">For I tell you, that many prophets and kings have desired to see those things which you see, and have not seen them; and to hear those things which you hear, and have not heard them.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And, behold, a certain lawyer stood up, and tempted him, saying, Master, what shall I do to inherit eternal life?</verse>
  <verse number="26">He said to him, What is written in the law? how read you?</verse>
  <verse number="27">And he answering said, You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart, and with all your soul, and with all your strength, and with all your mind; and your neighbor as yourself.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And he said to him, You have answered right: this do, and you shall live.</verse>
  <verse number="29">But he, willing to justify himself, said to Jesus, And who is my neighbor?</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Jesus answering said, A certain man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho, and fell among thieves, which stripped him of his raiment, and wounded him, and departed, leaving him half dead.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And by chance there came down a certain priest that way: and when he saw him, he passed by on the other side.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And likewise a Levite, when he was at the place, came and looked on him, and passed by on the other side.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But a certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came where he was: and when he saw him, he had compassion on him,</verse>
  <verse number="34">And went to him, and bound up his wounds, pouring in oil and wine, and set him on his own beast, and brought him to an inn, and took care of him.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And on the morrow when he departed, he took out two pence, and gave them to the host, and said to him, Take care of him; and whatever you spend more, when I come again, I will repay you.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Which now of these three, think you, was neighbor to him that fell among the thieves?</verse>
  <verse number="37">And he said, He that showed mercy on him. Then said Jesus to him, Go, and do you likewise.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Now it came to pass, as they went, that he entered into a certain village: and a certain woman named Martha received him into her house.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And she had a sister called Mary, which also sat at Jesus’ feet, and heard his word.</verse>
  <verse number="40">But Martha was encumbered about much serving, and came to him, and said, Lord, do you not care that my sister has left me to serve alone? bid her therefore that she help me.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And Jesus answered and said to her, Martha, Martha, you are careful and troubled about many things:</verse>
  <verse number="42">But one thing is needful: and Mary has chosen that good part, which shall not be taken away from her.</verse>
</chapter>