<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am the man that hath seen affliction By the rod of His wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He hath led me and caused me to walk in darkness and not in light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Surely against me He turneth His hand again and again all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="4">My flesh and my skin hath He worn out; He hath broken my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He hath builded against me, and compassed me With gall and travail.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He hath made me to dwell in dark places, As those that have been long dead.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He hath hedged me about, that I cannot go forth; He hath made my chain heavy.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Yea, when I cry and call for help, He shutteth out my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He hath enclosed my ways with hewn stone, He hath made my paths crooked.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He is unto me as a bear lying in wait, As a lion in secret places.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He hath turned aside my ways, and pulled me in pieces; He hath made me desolate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He hath bent His bow, and set me As a mark for the arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He hath caused the arrows of His quiver To enter into my reins.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I am become a derision to all my people, And their song all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He hath filled me with bitterness, He hath sated me with wormwood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He hath also broken my teeth with gravel stones, He hath made me to wallow in ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And my soul is removed far off from peace, I forgot prosperity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And I said: ‘My strength is perished, And mine expectation from the LORD.’</verse>
  <verse number="19">Remember mine affliction and mine anguish, The wormwood and the gall.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My soul hath them still in remembrance, And is bowed down within me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">This I recall to my mind, Therefore have I hope.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Surely the LORD’S mercies are not consumed, Surely His compassions fail not.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They are new every morning; Great is Thy faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The LORD is my portion’, saith my soul; ‘Therefore will I hope in Him.’</verse>
  <verse number="25">The LORD is good unto them that wait for Him, To the soul that seeketh Him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">It is good that a man should quietly wait For the salvation of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is good for a man that he bear The yoke in his youth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Let him sit alone and keep silence, Because He hath laid it upon him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Let him put his mouth in the dust, If so be there may be hope.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Let him give his cheek to him that smiteth him Let him be filled full with reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For the Lord will not cast off For ever.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For though He cause grief, yet will He have compassion According to the multitude of His mercies.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For He doth not afflict willingly, Nor grieve the children of men.</verse>
  <verse number="34">To crush under foot All the prisoners of the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="35">To turn aside the right of a man Before the face of the Most High,</verse>
  <verse number="36">To subvert a man in his cause, The Lord approveth not.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who is he that saith, and it cometh to pass, When the Lord commandeth it not?</verse>
  <verse number="38">Out of the mouth of the Most High proceedeth not Evil and good?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Wherefore doth a living man complain, A strong man because of his sins?</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let us search and try our ways, And return to the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Let us lift up our heart with our hands Unto God in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="42">We have transgressed and have rebelled; Thou hast not pardoned.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Thou hast covered with anger and pursued us; Thou hast slain unsparingly.</verse>
  <verse number="44">Thou hast covered Thyself with a cloud, So that no prayer can pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">Thou hast made us as the offscouring and refuse In the midst of the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All our enemies have opened their mouth Wide against us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Terror and the pit are come upon us, Desolation and destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="48">Mine eye runneth down with rivers of water, For the breach of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">Mine eye is poured out, and ceaseth not, Without any intermission,</verse>
  <verse number="50">Till the LORD look forth, And behold from heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Mine eye affected my soul, Because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">They have chased me sore like a bird, That are mine enemies without cause.</verse>
  <verse number="53">They have cut off my life in the dungeon, And have cast stones upon me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">Waters flowed over my head; I said: ‘I am cut off.’</verse>
  <verse number="55">I called upon Thy name, O LORD, Out of the lowest dungeon.</verse>
  <verse number="56">Thou heardest my voice; hide not Thine ear at my sighing, at my cry.</verse>
  <verse number="57">Thou drewest near in the day that I called upon Thee; Thou saidst: ‘Fear not.’</verse>
  <verse number="58">O Lord, Thou hast pleaded the causes of my soul; Thou hast redeemed my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">O LORD, Thou hast seen my wrong; Judge Thou my cause.</verse>
  <verse number="60">Thou hast seen all their vengeance And all their devices against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">Thou hast heard their taunt, O LORD, And all their devices against me;</verse>
  <verse number="62">The lips of those that rose up against me, And their muttering against me all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="63">Behold Thou their sitting down, and their rising up; I am their song.</verse>
  <verse number="64">Thou wilt render unto them a recompense, O LORD, According to the work of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="65">Thou wilt give them hardness of heart, Thy curse unto them.</verse>
  <verse number="66">Thou wilt pursue them in anger, and destroy them From under the heavens of the LORD.</verse>
</chapter>