<chapter book="Lamentations" number="5" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Remember, O LORD, what is come upon us; Behold, and see our reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Our inheritance is turned unto strangers, Our houses unto aliens.</verse>
  <verse number="3">We are become orphans and fatherless, Our mothers are as widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">We have drunk our water for money; Our wood cometh to us for price.</verse>
  <verse number="5">To our very necks we are pursued; We labour, and have no rest.</verse>
  <verse number="6">We have given the hand to Egypt, And to Assyria, to have bread enough;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Our fathers have sinned, and are not; And we have borne their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Servants rule over us; There is none to deliver us out of their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">We get our bread with the peril of our lives Because of the sword of the wilderness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Our skin is hot like an oven Because of the burning heat of famine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They have ravished the women in Zion, The maidens in the cities of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Princes are hanged up by their hand; The faces of elders are not honoured.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The young men have borne the mill, And the children have stumbled under the wood.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The elders have ceased from the gate, The young men from their music.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The joy of our heart is ceased; Our dance is turned into mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The crown is fallen from our head; Woe unto us! for we have sinned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For this our heart is faint, For these things our eyes are dim;</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the mountain of Zion, which is desolate, The foxes walk upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou, O LORD, art enthroned for ever, Thy throne is from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wherefore dost Thou forget us for ever, And forsake us so long time?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Turn Thou us unto Thee, O LORD, and we shall be turned; Renew our days as of old.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Thou canst not have utterly rejected us, And be exceeding wroth against us!</verse>
</chapter>