<chapter book="1 Thessalonians" number="5" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But concerning the times and the seasons, brethren, ye have no need that ye should be written to,</verse>
  <verse number="2">for ye know perfectly well yourselves, that the day of [the] Lord so comes as a thief by night.</verse>
  <verse number="3">When they may say, Peace and safety, then sudden destruction comes upon them, as travail upon her that is with child; and they shall in no wise escape.</verse>
  <verse number="4">But ye, brethren, are not in darkness, that the day should overtake you as a thief:</verse>
  <verse number="5">for all ye are sons of light and sons of day; we are not of night nor of darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="6">So then do not let us sleep as the rest do, but let us watch and be sober;</verse>
  <verse number="7">for they that sleep sleep by night, and they that drink drink by night;</verse>
  <verse number="8">but we being of [the] day, let us be sober, putting on [the] breastplate of faith and love, and as helmet [the] hope of salvation;</verse>
  <verse number="9">because God has not set us for wrath, but for obtaining salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="10">who has died for us, that whether we may be watching or sleep, we may live together with him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wherefore encourage one another, and build up each one the other, even as also ye do.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But we beg you, brethren, to know those who labour among you, and take the lead among you in [the] Lord, and admonish you,</verse>
  <verse number="13">and to regard them exceedingly in love on account of their work. Be in peace among yourselves.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But we exhort you, brethren, admonish the disorderly, comfort the faint-hearted, sustain the weak, be patient towards all.</verse>
  <verse number="15">See that no one render to any evil for evil, but pursue always what is good towards one another and towards all;</verse>
  <verse number="16">rejoice always;</verse>
  <verse number="17">pray unceasingly;</verse>
  <verse number="18">in everything give thanks, for this is [the] will of God in Christ Jesus towards you;</verse>
  <verse number="19">quench not the Spirit;</verse>
  <verse number="20">do not lightly esteem prophecies;</verse>
  <verse number="21">but prove all things, hold fast the right;</verse>
  <verse number="22">hold aloof from every form of wickedness.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Now the God of peace himself sanctify you wholly: and your whole spirit, and soul, and body be preserved blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="24">He [is] faithful who calls you, who will also perform [it].</verse>
  <verse number="25">Brethren, pray for us.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Greet all the brethren with a holy kiss.</verse>
  <verse number="27">I adjure you by the Lord that the letter be read to all the [holy] brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="28">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ [be] with you.</verse>
</chapter>