<chapter book="Zechariah" number="10" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Ask ye from Jehovah rain in the time of the latter rain; Jehovah made lightnings, and he will give rain of heavy showers to them, to each the green herb in the field.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For the family gods spake vanity, and the diviners saw falsehood, and they will speak dreams of falsehood they will comfort in vain: for this, they removed as a flock, they were afflicted for there was no shepherd.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Mine anger was kindled against the shepherds, and I will review upon the he goats: for Jehovah of armies reviewed upon his flock the house of Judah, as the house of his strength in the war.</verse>
  <verse number="4">From him the chief, from him the nail, from him the bow of war, from him came forth every tyrant together.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And they were as the strong treading down in the mud of the streets in the battle: and they waged war, for Jehovah was with them, and they riding horses were ashamed.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And I strengthened the house of Judah, and I will save the house of Joseph, and I turned them back for I compassionated them, and they were as if I cast them not off: for I am Jehovah their God, and I will answer them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they were as the strong one of Ephraim, and their heart rejoiced as from wine: and their sons shall see, and rejoice; their heart shall exult in Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="8">I will hiss for them, and gather them; for I redeemed them: and they multiplied as they multiplied.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And I will sow them among the peoples, and in distant places shall they remember me: and they lived with their sons, and turned back.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And I turned them back from the hind of Egypt, and from Assur will I gather them, and to the land of Gilead and Lebanon will I bring them; and it shall not be found for them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he passed through the sea of straits, and he struck the waves in the sea, and all the depths of the river dried up; and the pride of Assur was brought down, and the rod of Egypt shall depart.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I strengthened them in Jehovah; and in his name shall they go about, says Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>