<chapter book="Zechariah" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I shall lift up mine eyes and see, and behold, a man, and in his hand a cord of measure.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And saying, Whither goest thou? And he will say to me, To measure Jerusalem, to see according to what its breadth, and according to what its length.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And behold, the messenger speaking with me went forth, and another messenger went forth to meet him:</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he will say to him, Run, speak to this youth, saying, Jerusalem shall be inhabited an open country from the multitude of men and cattle in the midst of her.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And I will be to her, says Jehovah, a wall of fire round about, and I will be for glory in the midst of her.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Alas! alas! and flee ye from the land of the north, says Jehovah: for as the four winds of the heavens I spread you abroad, says Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Alas, O Zion, deliver thyself inhabiting the daughter of Babel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For thus said Jehovah of armies: After glory he sent me to the nations spoiling you: for he touching upon you touched the gate of his eye.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For behold me waving my hand upon them, and they were a spoil to their servants: and ye knew that Jehovah of armies sent me.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Shout for joy and rejoice, O daughter of Zion: for behold me coming, and I dwelt in the midst of thee, says Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And many nations joined themselves to Jehovah in that day, and they were to me for a people: and I dwelt in the midst of thee, and thou knewest that Jehovah of armies sent me to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Jehovah inherited Judah his portion upon the holy land, and he yet chose Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Be silent, all flesh, from the face of Jehovah: for he was raised from the habitation of his holiness.</verse>
</chapter>