<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="11" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then all Israel gathered themselves to David unto Hebron, saying: ‘Behold, we are thy bone and thy flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="2">In times past, even when Saul was king, it was thou that didst lead out and bring in Israel; and the LORD thy God said unto thee: Thou shalt feed My people Israel, and thou shalt be prince over My people Israel.’</verse>
  <verse number="3">So all the elders of Israel came to the king to Hebron; and David made a covenant with them in Hebron before the LORD; and they anointed David king over Israel, according to the word of the LORD by the hand of Samuel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And David and all Israel went to Jerusalem—the same is Jebus—and the Jebusites, the inhabitants of the land, were there.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the inhabitants of Jebus said to David: ‘Thou shalt not come in hither.’ Nevertheless David took the stronghold of Zion; the same is the city of David.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And David said: ‘Whosoever smiteth the Jebusites first shall be chief and captain.’ And Joab the son of Zeruiah went up first, and was made chief.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And David dwelt in the stronghold; therefore they called it the city of David.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he built the city round about, from Millo even round about; and Joab repaired the rest of the city.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And David waxed greater and greater; for the LORD of hosts was with him.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now these are the chief of the mighty men whom David had, who held strongly with him in his kingdom, together with all Israel, to make him king, according to the word of the LORD concerning Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And this is the number of the mighty men whom David had: Jashobeam, the son of a Hachmonite, the chief of the captains; he lifted up his spear against three hundred and slew them at one time.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And after him was Eleazar the son of Dodo, the Ahohite, who was one of the three mighty men.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He was with David at Pas-dammim, and there the Philistines were gathered together to battle, where was a plot of ground full of barley; and the people fled from before the Philistines.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But they stood in the midst of the plot, and defended it, and slew the Philistines; and the LORD saved them by a great victory.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And three of the thirty chiefs went down to the rock to David, unto the cave of Adullam; and the host of the Philistines were encamped in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And David was then in the stronghold, and the garrison of the Philistines was then in Beth-lehem.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And David longed, and said: ‘Oh that one would give me water to drink of the well of Beth-lehem, which is by the gate!’</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the three broke through the host of the Philistines, and drew water out of the well of Beth-lehem, that was by the gate, and took it, and brought it to David; but David would not drink thereof, but poured it out unto the LORD,</verse>
  <verse number="19">and said: ‘My God forbid it me, that I should do this; shall I drink the blood of these men that have put their lives in jeopardy? for with the jeopardy of their lives they brought it.’ Therefore he would not drink it. These things did the three mighty men.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Abishai, the brother of Joab, he was chief of the three; for he lifted up his spear against three hundred and slew them, and had a name among the three.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Of the three in the second rank he was the most honourable, and was made their captain; howbeit he attained not to the first three.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Beniah the son of Jehoiada, the son of a valiant man of Kabzeel, who had done mighty deeds, he smote the two altar-hearths of Moab; he went down also and slew a lion in the midst of a pit in time of snow.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he slew an Egyptian, a man of great stature, five cubits high; and in the Egyptian’s hand was a spear like a weaver’s beam; and he went down to him with a staff, and plucked the spear out of the Egyptian’s hand, and slew him with his own spear.</verse>
  <verse number="24">These things did Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, and had a name among the three mighty men.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Behold, he was more honourable than the thirty, but he attained not to the first three; and David set him over his guard.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Also the mighty men of valour: Asahel the brother of Joab, Elhanan the son of Dodo of Beth-lehem;</verse>
  <verse number="27">Shammoth the Harorite, Helez the Pelonite;</verse>
  <verse number="28">Ira the son of Ikkesh the Tekoite, Abiezer the Anathothite;</verse>
  <verse number="29">Sibbecai the Hushathite, Ilai the Ahohite;</verse>
  <verse number="30">Mahrai the Netophathite, Heled the son of Baanah the Netophathite;</verse>
  <verse number="31">Ithai the son of Ribai of Gibeah of the children of Benjamin, Benaiah the Pirathonite;</verse>
  <verse number="32">Hurai of Nahale-gaash, Abiel the Arbathite;</verse>
  <verse number="33">Azmaveth the Baharumite, Eliahba the Shaalbonite;</verse>
  <verse number="34">the sons of Hashem the Gizonite, Jonathan the son of Shageh the Hararite;</verse>
  <verse number="35">Ahiam the son of Sacar the Hararite, Eliphal the son of Ur;</verse>
  <verse number="36">Hepher the Mecherathite, Ahijah the Pelonite;</verse>
  <verse number="37">Hezro the Carmelite, Naarai the son of Ezbai;</verse>
  <verse number="38">Joel the brother of Nathan, Mibhar the son of Hagri;</verse>
  <verse number="39">Zelek the Ammonite, Nahrai the Berothite, the armour-bearer of Joab the son of Zeruiah;</verse>
  <verse number="40">Ira the Ithrite, Gareb the Ithrite;</verse>
  <verse number="41">Uriah the Hittite, Zabad the son of Ahlai;</verse>
  <verse number="42">Adina the son of Shiza the Reubenite, a chief of the Reubenites, and thirty with him;</verse>
  <verse number="43">Hanan the son of Maacah, and Joshaphat the Mithnite;</verse>
  <verse number="44">Uzzia the Ashterathite, Shama and Jeiel the sons of Hotham the Aroerite;</verse>
  <verse number="45">Jediael the son of Shimri, and Joha his brother, the Tizite;</verse>
  <verse number="46">Eliel the Mahavite, and Jeribai, and Joshaviah, the sons of Elnaam, and Ithmah the Moabite;</verse>
  <verse number="47">Eliel, and Obed, and Jaasiel the Mezobaite.</verse>
</chapter>