<chapter book="Numbers" number="33" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">These are the stages of the children of Israel, by which they went forth out of the land of Egypt by their hosts under the hand of Moses and Aaron.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And Moses wrote their goings forth, stage by stage, by the commandment of the LORD; and these are their stages at their goings forth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And they journeyed from Rameses in the first month, on the fifteenth day of the first month; on the morrow after the passover the children of Israel went out with a high hand in the sight of all the Egyptians,</verse>
  <verse number="4">while the Egyptians were burying them that the LORD had smitten among them, even all their first-born; upon their gods also the LORD executed judgments.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the children of Israel journeyed from Rameses, and pitched in Succoth.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And they journeyed from Succoth, and pitched in Etham, which is in the edge of the wilderness.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they journeyed from Etham, and turned back unto Pihahiroth, which is before Baal-zephon; and they pitched before Migdol.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And they journeyed from Penehahiroth, and passed through the midst of the sea into the wilderness; and they went three days’ journey in the wilderness of Etham, and pitched in Marah.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And they journeyed from Marah, and came unto Elim; and in Elim were twelve springs of water, and threescore and ten palm-trees; and they pitched there.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they journeyed from Elim, and pitched by the Red Sea.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And they journeyed from the Red Sea, and pitched in the wilderness of Sin.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And they journeyed from the wilderness of Sin, and pitched in Dophkah.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they journeyed from Dophkah, and pitched in Alush.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And they journeyed from Alush, and pitched in Rephidim, where was no water for the people to drink.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And they journeyed from Rephidim, and pitched in the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they journeyed from the wilderness of Sinai, and pitched in Kibroth-hattaavah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And they journeyed from Kibroth-hattaavah, and pitched in Hazeroth.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they journeyed from Hazeroth, and pitched in Rithmah.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And they journeyed from Rithmah, and pitched in Rimmon-perez.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And they journeyed from Rimmon-perez, and pitched in Libnah.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they journeyed from Libnah, and pitched in Rissah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And they journeyed from Rissah, and pitched in Kehelah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And they journeyed from Kehelah, and pitched in mount Shepher.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they journeyed from mount Shepher, and pitched in Haradah.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And they journeyed from Haradah, and pitched in Makheloth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they journeyed from Makheloth, and pitched in Tahath.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And they journeyed from Tahath, and pitched in Terah.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they journeyed from Terah, and pitched in Mithkah.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And they journeyed from Mithkah, and pitched in Hashmonah.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And they journeyed from Hashmonah, and pitched in Moseroth.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they journeyed from Moseroth, and pitched in Bene-jaakan.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they journeyed from Bene-jaakan, and pitched in Hor-haggidgad.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And they journeyed from Hor-haggidgad, and pitched in Jotbah.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And they journeyed from Jotbah, and pitched in Abronah.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And they journeyed from Abronah, and pitched in Ezion-geber.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And they journeyed from Ezion-geber, and pitched in the wilderness of Zin—the same is Kadesh.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And they journeyed from Kadesh, and pitched in mount Hor, in the edge of the land of Edom.—</verse>
  <verse number="38">And Aaron the priest went up into mount Hor at the commandment of the LORD, and died there, in the fortieth year after the children of Israel were come out of the land of Egypt, in the fifth month, on the first day of the month.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And Aaron was a hundred and twenty and three years old when he died in mount Hor.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And the Canaanite, the king of Arad, who dwelt in the South in the land of Canaan, heard of the coming of the children of Israel.—</verse>
  <verse number="41">And they journeyed from mount Hor, and pitched in Zalmonah.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And they journeyed from Zalmonah, and pitched in Punon.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And they journeyed from Punon, and pitched in Oboth.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And they journeyed from Oboth, and pitched in Ije-abarim, in the border of Moab.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And they journeyed from Ijim, and pitched in Dibon-gad.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And they journeyed from Dibon-gad, and pitched in Almon-diblathaim.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And they journeyed from Almon-diblathaim, and pitched in the mountains of Abarim, in front of Nebo.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And they journeyed from the mountains of Abarim, and pitched in the plains of Moab by the Jordan at Jericho.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And they pitched by the Jordan, from Beth-jeshimoth even unto Abel-shittim in the plains of Moab.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And the LORD spoke unto Moses in the plains of Moab by the Jordan at Jericho, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="51">Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them: When ye pass over the Jordan into the land of Canaan,</verse>
  <verse number="52">then ye shall drive out all the inhabitants of the land from before you, and destroy all their figured stones, and destroy all their molten images, and demolish all their high places.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And ye shall drive out the inhabitants of the land, and dwell therein; for unto you have I given the land to possess it.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And ye shall inherit the land by lot according to your families—to the more ye shall give the more inheritance, and to the fewer thou shalt give the less inheritance; wheresoever the lot falleth to any man, that shall be his; according to the tribes of your fathers shall ye inherit.</verse>
  <verse number="55">But if ye will not drive out the inhabitants of the land from before you, then shall those that ye let remain of them be as thorns in your eyes, and as pricks in your sides, and they shall harass you in the land wherein ye dwell.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And it shall come to pass, that as I thought to do unto them, so will I do unto you.</verse>
</chapter>