<chapter book="Micah" number="5" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now thou shalt crowd thyself together, O daughter of a troop: besieging there against us; with a rod they will strike the judge of Israel upon the cheek.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And thou, house of bread, of Ephratah, for being small among the thousands of Judah, out of thee shall come forth to me he being ruler in Israel; and his goings forth from of old from the days of eternity.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For this he will give them up even till the time she bearing will bring forth: and the remainder of his brethren shall turn back to the sons of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he stood and fed in the strength of Jehovah, in the majesty of the name of Jehovah his God; and they shall dwell: for now shall he be magnified to the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And this was peace, for Assur shall come up into our land: and when he shall tread in our palaces and we raised against him seven shepherds, and eight anointed men.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And they ruled the land of Assur with the sword, and the land of Nimrod in its openings: and he delivered from Assur when he shall come in to our land, and when he shall tread in our bound.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the remnant of Jacob was in the midst of many peoples as the dew from Jehovah, as showers upon the green herb, which will not wait for man and will not delay for the sons of man.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the remnant of Jacob was among the nations in the midst of many peoples as a lion among the beasts of the forest, as a young lion among the flocks of sheep: who, if he passed through, and he trod down and pulled in pieces, and none delivering.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thy hand shall be raised up against thine adversaries, and all thine enemies shall be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And it was in that day, says Jehovah, and I cut off thy horses from the midst of thee, and I destroyed thy chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I cut off the cities of thy land, and I battled down all thy fortresses:</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I cut off sorceries from thy hand, and they practicing magic shall not be to thee.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I cut off thy carved images and thy statues from the midst of thee; and thou shalt no more worship the work of thy hands.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And I tore up thine images from the midst of thee, and I destroyed thy cities.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And I did vengeance in anger and in wrath with the nations, which they heard not.</verse>
</chapter>