<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Proverbs of Solomon, son of David, king of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="2">For knowing wisdom and instruction, For understanding sayings of intelligence,</verse>
  <verse number="3">For receiving the instruction of wisdom, Righteousness, judgment, and uprightness,</verse>
  <verse number="4">For giving to simple ones—prudence, To a youth—knowledge and discretion.</verse>
  <verse number="5">(The wise doth hear and increaseth learning, And the intelligent doth obtain counsels.)</verse>
  <verse number="6">For understanding a proverb and its sweetness, Words of the wise and their acute sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Fear of Jehovah is a beginning of knowledge, Wisdom and instruction fools have despised!</verse>
  <verse number="8">Hear, my son, the instruction of thy father, And leave not the law of thy mother,</verse>
  <verse number="9">For a graceful wreath are they to thy head, And chains to thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if sinners entice thee be not willing.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they say, ‘Come with us, we lay wait for blood, We watch secretly for the innocent without cause,</verse>
  <verse number="12">We swallow them as Sheol—alive, And whole—as those going down to the pit,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Every precious substance we find, We fill our houses with spoil,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thy lot thou dost cast among us, One purse is—to all of us.’</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son! go not in the way with them, Withhold thy foot from their path,</verse>
  <verse number="16">For their feet to evil do run, And they haste to shed blood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Surely in vain is the net spread out before the eyes of any bird.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they for their own blood lay wait, They watch secretly for their own lives.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So are the paths of every gainer of dishonest gain, The life of its owners it taketh.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom in an out-place crieth aloud, In broad places she giveth forth her voice,</verse>
  <verse number="21">At the head of the multitudes she calleth, In the openings of the gates, In the city her sayings she saith:</verse>
  <verse number="22">‘Till when, ye simple, do ye love simplicity? And have scorners their scorning desired? And do fools hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn back at my reproof, lo, I pour forth to you my spirit, I make known my words with you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I have called, and ye refuse, I stretched out my hand, and none is attending,</verse>
  <verse number="25">And ye slight all my counsel, And my reproof ye have not desired.</verse>
  <verse number="26">I also in your calamity do laugh, I deride when your fear cometh,</verse>
  <verse number="27">When your fear cometh as destruction, And your calamity as a hurricane doth come, When on you come adversity and distress.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then they call me, and I do not answer, They seek me earnestly, and find me not.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Because that they have hated knowledge, And the fear of Jehovah have not chosen.</verse>
  <verse number="30">They have not consented to my counsel, They have despised all my reproof,</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they eat of the fruit of their way, And from their own counsels they are filled.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the turning of the simple slayeth them, And the security of the foolish destroyeth them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And whoso is hearkening to me dwelleth confidently, And is quiet from fear of evil!’</verse>
</chapter>