<chapter book="Proverbs" number="12" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Whoso is loving instruction, is loving knowledge, And whoso is hating reproof is brutish.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The good bringeth forth favour from Jehovah, And the man of wicked devices He condemneth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A man is not established by wickedness, And the root of the righteous is not moved.</verse>
  <verse number="4">A virtuous woman is a crown to her husband, And as rottenness in his bones is one causing shame.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The thoughts of the righteous are justice, The counsels of the wicked—deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The words of the wicked are: ‘Lay wait for blood,’ And the mouth of the upright delivereth them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Overthrow the wicked, and they are not, And the house of the righteous standeth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">According to his wisdom is a man praised, And the perverted of heart becometh despised.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Better is the lightly esteemed who hath a servant, Than the self-honoured who lacketh bread.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The righteous knoweth the life of his beast, And the mercies of the wicked are cruel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Whoso is tilling the ground is satisfied with bread, And whoso is pursuing vanities is lacking heart,</verse>
  <verse number="12">The wicked hath desired the net of evil doers, And the root of the righteous giveth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">In transgression of the lips is the snare of the wicked, And the righteous goeth out from distress.</verse>
  <verse number="14">From the fruit of the mouth is one satisfied with good, And the deed of man’s hands returneth to him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The way of a fool is right in his own eyes, And whoso is hearkening to counsel is wise.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The fool—in a day is his anger known, And the prudent is covering shame.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Whoso uttereth faithfulness declareth righteousness, And a false witness—deceit.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A rash speaker is like piercings of a sword, And the tongue of the wise is healing.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The lip of truth is established for ever, And for a moment—a tongue of falsehood.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Deceit is in the heart of those devising evil, And to those counselling peace is joy.</verse>
  <verse number="21">No iniquity is desired by the righteous, And the wicked have been full of evil.</verse>
  <verse number="22">An abomination to Jehovah are lying lips, And stedfast doers are his delight.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A prudent man is concealing knowledge, And the heart of fools proclaimeth folly.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The hand of the diligent ruleth, And slothfulness becometh tributary.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Sorrow in the heart of a man boweth down, And a good word maketh him glad.</verse>
  <verse number="26">The righteous searcheth his companion, And the way of the wicked causeth them to err.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The slothful roasteth not his hunting, And the wealth of a diligent man is precious.</verse>
  <verse number="28">In the path of righteousness is life, And in the way of that path is no death!</verse>
</chapter>