<chapter book="Proverbs" number="17" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Better is a dry morsel, and rest with it, Than a house full of the sacrifices of strife.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A wise servant ruleth over a son causing shame, And in the midst of brethren He apportioneth an inheritance.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A refining pot is for silver, and a furnace for gold, And the trier of hearts is Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">An evil doer is attentive to lips of vanity, Falsehood is giving ear to a mischievous tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Whoso is mocking at the poor Hath reproached his Maker, Whoso is rejoicing at calamity is not acquitted.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Sons’ sons are the crown of old men, And the glory of sons are their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Not comely for a fool is a lip of excellency, Much less for a noble a lip of falsehood.</verse>
  <verse number="8">A stone of grace is the bribe in the eyes of its possessors, Whithersoever it turneth, it prospereth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Whoso is covering transgression is seeking love, And whoso is repeating a matter Is separating a familiar friend.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Rebuke cometh down on the intelligent More than a hundred stripes on a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="11">An evil man seeketh only rebellion, And a fierce messenger is sent against him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The meeting of a bereaved bear by a man, And—not a fool in his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso is returning evil for good, Evil moveth not from his house.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The beginning of contention is a letting out of waters, And before it is meddled with leave the strife.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Whoso is justifying the wicked, And condemning the righteous, Even both of these are an abomination to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Why is this—a price in the hand of a fool to buy wisdom, And a heart there is none?</verse>
  <verse number="17">At all times is the friend loving, And a brother for adversity is born.</verse>
  <verse number="18">A man lacking heart is striking hands, A surety he becometh before his friend.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Whoso is loving transgression is loving debate, Whoso is making high his entrance is seeking destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="20">The perverse of heart findeth not good, And the turned in his tongue falleth into evil.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Whoso is begetting a fool hath affliction for it, Yea, the father of a fool rejoiceth not.</verse>
  <verse number="22">A rejoicing heart doth good to the body, And a smitten spirit drieth the bone.</verse>
  <verse number="23">A bribe from the bosom the wicked taketh, To turn aside the paths of judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The face of the intelligent is to wisdom, And the eyes of a fool—at the end of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">A provocation to his father is a foolish son, And bitterness to her that bare him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Also, to fine the righteous is not good, To smite nobles for uprightness.</verse>
  <verse number="27">One acquainted with knowledge is sparing his words, And the cool of temper is a man of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Even a fool keeping silence is reckoned wise, He who is shutting his lips intelligent!</verse>
</chapter>