<chapter book="Proverbs" number="18" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For an object of desire he who is separated doth seek, With all wisdom he intermeddleth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">A fool delighteth not in understanding, But—in uncovering his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="3">With the coming of the wicked come also hath contempt, And with shame—reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Deep waters are the words of a man’s mouth, The fountain of wisdom is a flowing brook.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Acceptance of the face of the wicked is not good, To turn aside the righteous in judgment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The lips of a fool enter into strife, And his mouth for stripes calleth.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The mouth of a fool is ruin to him, And his lips are the snare of his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The words of a tale-bearer are as self-inflicted wounds, And they have gone down to the inner parts of the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He also that is remiss in his work, A brother he is to a destroyer.</verse>
  <verse number="10">A tower of strength is the name of Jehovah, Into it the righteous runneth, and is set on high.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The wealth of the rich is the city of his strength, And as a wall set on high in his own imagination.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Before destruction the heart of man is high, And before honour is humility.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Whoso is answering a matter before he heareth, Folly it is to him and shame.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The spirit of a man sustaineth his sickness, And a smitten spirit who doth bear?</verse>
  <verse number="15">The heart of the intelligent getteth knowledge, And the ear of the wise seeketh knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The gift of a man maketh room for him, And before the great it leadeth him.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Righteous is the first in his own cause, His neighbour cometh and hath searched him.</verse>
  <verse number="18">The lot causeth contentions to cease, And between the mighty it separateth.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A brother transgressed against is as a strong city, And contentions as the bar of a palace.</verse>
  <verse number="20">From the fruit of a man’s mouth is his belly satisfied, From the increase of his lips he is satisfied.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Death and life are in the power of the tongue, And those loving it eat its fruit.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Whoso hath found a wife hath found good, And bringeth out good-will from Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="23">With supplications doth the poor speak, And the rich answereth fierce things.</verse>
  <verse number="24">A man with friends is to show himself friendly, And there is a lover adhering more than a brother!</verse>
</chapter>