<chapter book="Proverbs" number="20" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wine is a scorner—strong drink is noisy, And any going astray in it is not wise.</verse>
  <verse number="2">The fear of a king is a growl as of a young lion, He who is causing him to be wroth is wronging his soul.</verse>
  <verse number="3">An honour to a man is cessation from strife, And every fool intermeddleth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Because of winter the slothful plougheth not, He asketh in harvest, and there is nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Counsel in the heart of a man is deep water, And a man of understanding draweth it up.</verse>
  <verse number="6">A multitude of men proclaim each his kindness, And a man of stedfastness who doth find?</verse>
  <verse number="7">The righteous is walking habitually in his integrity, O the happiness of his sons after him!</verse>
  <verse number="8">A king sitting on a throne of judgment, Is scattering with his eyes all evil,</verse>
  <verse number="9">Who saith, ‘I have purified my heart, I have been cleansed from my sin?’</verse>
  <verse number="10">A stone and a stone, an ephah and an ephah, Even both of them are an abomination to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Even by his actions a youth maketh himself known, Whether his work be pure or upright.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A hearing ear, and a seeing eye, Jehovah hath made even both of them.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Love not sleep, lest thou become poor, Open thine eyes—be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="14">‘Bad, bad,’ saith the buyer, And going his way then he boasteth himself.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Substance, gold, and a multitude of rubies, Yea, a precious vessel, are lips of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Take his garment when a stranger hath been surety, And for strangers pledge it.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Sweet to a man is the bread of falsehood, And afterwards is his mouth filled with gravel.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Purposes by counsel thou dost establish, And with plans make thou war.</verse>
  <verse number="19">A revealer of secret counsels is the busybody, And for a deceiver with his lips make not thyself surety.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Whoso is vilifying his father and his mother, Extinguished is his lamp in blackness of darkness.</verse>
  <verse number="21">An inheritance gotten wrongly at first, Even its latter end is not blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Do not say, ‘I recompense evil,’ Wait for Jehovah, and He delivereth thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">An abomination to Jehovah are a stone and a stone, And balances of deceit are not good.</verse>
  <verse number="24">From Jehovah are the steps of a man, And man—how understandeth he his way?</verse>
  <verse number="25">A snare to a man is he hath swallowed a holy thing, And after vows to make inquiry.</verse>
  <verse number="26">A wise king is scattering the wicked, And turneth back on them the wheel.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The breath of man is a lamp of Jehovah, Searching all the inner parts of the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Kindness and truth keep a king, And he hath supported by kindness his throne.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The beauty of young men is their strength, And the honour of old men is grey hairs.</verse>
  <verse number="30">The bandages of a wound thou removest with the evil, Also the plagues of the inner parts of the heart!</verse>
</chapter>