<chapter book="Proverbs" number="23" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">When thou sittest to eat with a ruler, Thou considerest diligently that which is before thee,</verse>
  <verse number="2">And thou hast put a knife to thy throat, If thou art a man of appetite.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Have no desire to his dainties, seeing it is lying food.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Labour not to make wealth, From thine own understanding cease, Dost thou cause thine eyes to fly upon it? Then it is not.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For wealth maketh to itself wings, As an eagle it flieth to the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Eat not the bread of an evil eye, And have no desire to his dainties,</verse>
  <verse number="7">For as he hath thought in his soul, so is he, ‘Eat and drink,’ saith he to thee, And his heart is not with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Thy morsel thou hast eaten thou dost vomit up, And hast marred thy words that are sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="9">In the ears of a fool speak not, For he treadeth on the wisdom of thy words.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Remove not a border of olden times, And into fields of the fatherless enter not,</verse>
  <verse number="11">For their Redeemer is strong, He doth plead their cause with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Bring in to instruction thy heart, And thine ear to sayings of knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Withhold not from a youth chastisement, When thou smitest him with a rod he dieth not.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Thou with a rod smitest him, And his soul from Sheol thou deliverest.</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, if thy heart hath been wise, My heart rejoiceth, even mine,</verse>
  <verse number="16">And my reins exult when thy lips speak uprightly.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Let not thy heart be envious at sinners, But—in the fear of Jehovah all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For, is there a posterity? Then thy hope is not cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Hear thou, my son, and be wise, And make happy in the way thy heart,</verse>
  <verse number="20">Be not thou among quaffers of wine, Among gluttonous ones of flesh,</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the quaffer and glutton become poor, And drowsiness clotheth with rags.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Hearken to thy father, who begat thee, And despise not thy mother when she hath become old.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Truth buy, and sell not, Wisdom, and instruction, and understanding,</verse>
  <verse number="24">The father of the righteous rejoiceth greatly, The begetter of the wise rejoiceth in him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Rejoice doth thy father and thy mother, Yea, she that bare thee is joyful.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Give, my son, thy heart to me, And let thine eyes watch my ways.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For a harlot is a deep ditch, And a strange woman is a strait pit.</verse>
  <verse number="28">She also, as catching prey, lieth in wait, And the treacherous among men she increaseth.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Who hath woe? who hath sorrow? Who hath contentions? who hath plaint? Who hath wounds without cause? Who hath redness of eyes?</verse>
  <verse number="30">Those tarrying by the wine, Those going in to search out mixed wine.</verse>
  <verse number="31">See not wine when it showeth itself red, When it giveth in the cup its colour, It goeth up and down through the upright.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Its latter end—as a serpent it biteth, And as a basilisk it stingeth.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Thine eyes see strange women, And thy heart speaketh perverse things.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And thou hast been as one lying down in the heart of the sea, And as one lying down on the top of a mast.</verse>
  <verse number="35">‘They smote me, I have not been sick, They beat me, I have not known. When I awake—I seek it yet again!’</verse>
</chapter>