<chapter book="Proverbs" number="26" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As snow in summer, and as rain in harvest, So honour is not comely for a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="2">As a bird by wandering, as a swallow by flying, So reviling without cause doth not come.</verse>
  <verse number="3">A whip is for a horse, a bridle for an ass, And a rod for the back of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Answer not a fool according to his folly, Lest thou be like to him—even thou.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Answer a fool according to his folly, Lest he be wise in his own eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He is cutting off feet, he is drinking injury, Who is sending things by the hand of a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Weak have been the two legs of the lame, And a parable in the mouth of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="8">As one who is binding a stone in a sling, So is he who is giving honour to a fool.</verse>
  <verse number="9">A thorn hath gone up into the hand of a drunkard, And a parable in the mouth of fools.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Great is the Former of all, And He is rewarding a fool, And is rewarding transgressors.</verse>
  <verse number="11">As a dog hath returned to its vomit, A fool is repeating his folly.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Thou hast seen a man wise in his own eyes, More hope of a fool than of him!</verse>
  <verse number="13">The slothful hath said, ‘A lion is in the way, A lion is in the broad places.’</verse>
  <verse number="14">The door turneth round on its hinge, And the slothful on his bed.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The slothful hath hid his hand in a dish, He is weary of bringing it back to his mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Wiser is the slothful in his own eyes, Than seven men returning a reason.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Laying hold on the ears of a dog, Is a passer-by making himself wrath for strife not his own.</verse>
  <verse number="18">As one pretending to be feeble, Who is casting sparks, arrows, and death,</verse>
  <verse number="19">So hath a man deceived his neighbour, And hath said, ‘Am not I playing?’</verse>
  <verse number="20">Without wood is fire going out, And without a tale-bearer, contention ceaseth,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Coal to burning coals, and wood to fire, And a man of contentions to kindle strife.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The words of a tale-bearer are as self-inflicted wounds, And they have gone down to the inner parts of the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Silver of dross spread over potsherd, Are burning lips and an evil heart.</verse>
  <verse number="24">By his lips doth a hater dissemble, And in his heart he placeth deceit,</verse>
  <verse number="25">When his voice is gracious trust not in him, For seven abominations are in his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Hatred is covered by deceit, Revealed is its wickedness in an assembly.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whoso is digging a pit falleth into it, And the roller of a stone, to him it turneth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">A lying tongue hateth its bruised ones, And a flattering mouth worketh an overthrow!</verse>
</chapter>