<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son! if thou hast been surety for thy friend, Hast stricken for a stranger thy hand,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Hast been snared with sayings of thy mouth, Hast been captured with sayings of thy mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do this now, my son, and be delivered, For thou hast come into the hand of thy friend. Go, trample on thyself, and strengthen thy friend,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Give not sleep to thine eyes, And slumber to thine eyelids,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Be delivered as a roe from the hand, And as a bird from the hand of a fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go unto the ant, O slothful one, See her ways and be wise;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Which hath not captain, overseer, and ruler,</verse>
  <verse number="8">She doth prepare in summer her bread, She hath gathered in harvest her food.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Till when, O slothful one, dost thou lie? When dost thou arise from thy sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">A little sleep, a little slumber, A little clasping of the hands to rest,</verse>
  <verse number="11">And thy poverty hath come as a traveller, And thy want as an armed man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A man of worthlessness, a man of iniquity, Walking with perverseness of mouth,</verse>
  <verse number="13">Winking with his eyes, speaking with his feet, Directing with his fingers,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Frowardness is in his heart, devising evil at all times, Contentions he sendeth forth.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore suddenly cometh his calamity, Instantly he is broken—and no healing.</verse>
  <verse number="16">These six hath Jehovah hated, Yea, seven are abominations to His soul.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Eyes high—tongues false—And hands shedding innocent blood—</verse>
  <verse number="18">A heart devising thoughts of vanity—Feet hasting to run to evil—</verse>
  <verse number="19">A false witness who doth breathe out lies—And one sending forth contentions between brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Keep, my son, the command of thy father, And leave not the law of thy mother.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Bind them on thy heart continually, Tie them on thy neck.</verse>
  <verse number="22">In thy going up and down, it leadeth thee, In thy lying down, it watcheth over thee, And thou hast awaked—it talketh with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For a lamp is the command, And the law a light, And a way of life are reproofs of instruction,</verse>
  <verse number="24">To preserve thee from an evil woman, From the flattery of the tongue of a strange woman.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Desire not her beauty in thy heart, And let her not take thee with her eyelids.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For a harlot consumeth unto a cake of bread, And an adulteress the precious soul hunteth.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Doth a man take fire into his bosom, And are his garments not burnt?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Doth a man walk on the hot coals, And are his feet not scorched?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So is he who hath gone in unto the wife of his neighbour, None who doth touch her is innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="30">They do not despise the thief, When he stealeth to fill his soul when he is hungry,</verse>
  <verse number="31">And being found he repayeth sevenfold, All the substance of his house he giveth.</verse>
  <verse number="32">He who committeth adultery with a woman lacketh heart, He is destroying his soul who doth it.</verse>
  <verse number="33">A stroke and shame he doth find, And his reproach is not wiped away,</verse>
  <verse number="34">For jealousy is the fury of a man, And he doth not spare in a day of vengeance.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He accepteth not the appearance of any atonement, Yea, he doth not consent, Though thou dost multiply bribes!</verse>
</chapter>