<chapter book="Proverbs" number="7" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son! keep my sayings, And my commands lay up with thee.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Keep my commands, and live, And my law as the pupil of thine eye.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Bind them on thy fingers, Write them on the tablet of thy heart.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Say to wisdom, ‘My sister Thou art.’ And cry to understanding, ‘Kinswoman!’</verse>
  <verse number="5">To preserve thee from a strange woman, From a stranger who hath made smooth her sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For, at a window of my house, Through my casement I have looked out,</verse>
  <verse number="7">And I do see among the simple ones, I discern among the sons, A young man lacking understanding,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Passing on in the street, near her corner, And the way to her house he doth step,</verse>
  <verse number="9">In the twilight—in the evening of day, In the darkness of night and blackness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And, lo, a woman to meet him—(A harlot’s dress, and watchful of heart,</verse>
  <verse number="11">Noisy she is, and stubborn, In her house her feet rest not.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now in an out-place, now in broad places, And near every corner she lieth in wait)—</verse>
  <verse number="13">And she laid hold on him, and kissed him, She hath hardened her face, and saith to him,</verse>
  <verse number="14">Sacrifices of peace-offerings are by me, To-day I have completed my vows.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore I have come forth to meet thee, To seek earnestly thy face, and I find thee.</verse>
  <verse number="16">With ornamental coverings I decked my couch, Carved works—cotton of Egypt.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I sprinkled my bed—myrrh, aloes, and cinnamon.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Come, we are filled with loves till the morning, We delight ourselves in loves.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For the man is not in his house, He hath gone on a long journey.</verse>
  <verse number="20">A bag of money he hath taken in his hand, At the day of the new moon he cometh to his house.’</verse>
  <verse number="21">She turneth him aside with the abundance of her speech, With the flattery of her lips she forceth him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He is going after her straightway, As an ox unto the slaughter he cometh, And as a fetter unto the chastisement of a fool,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Till an arrow doth split his liver, As a bird hath hastened unto a snare, And hath not known that it is for its life.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And now, ye sons, hearken to me, And give attention to sayings of my mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Let not thy heart turn unto her ways, Do not wander in her paths,</verse>
  <verse number="26">For many are the wounded she caused to fall, And mighty are all her slain ones.</verse>
  <verse number="27">The ways of Sheol—her house, Going down unto inner chambers of death!</verse>
</chapter>