<chapter book="Proverbs" number="9" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wisdom hath builded her house, She hath hewn out her pillars—seven.</verse>
  <verse number="2">She hath slaughtered her slaughter, She hath mingled her wine, Yea, she hath arranged her table.</verse>
  <verse number="3">She hath sent forth her damsels, She crieth on the tops of the high places of the city:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Who is simple? let him turn aside hither.’ Whoso lacketh heart: she hath said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="5">‘Come, eat of my bread, And drink of the wine I have mingled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Forsake ye, the simple, and live, And be happy in the way of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The instructor of a scorner Is receiving for it—shame, And a reprover of the wicked—his blemish.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Reprove not a scorner, lest he hate thee, Give reproof to the wise, and he loveth thee.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Give to the wise, and he is wiser still, Make known to the righteous, And he increaseth learning.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The commencement of wisdom is the fear of Jehovah, And a knowledge of the Holy Ones is understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For by me do thy days multiply, And added to thee are years of life.</verse>
  <verse number="12">If thou hast been wise, thou hast been wise for thyself, And thou hast scorned—thyself bearest it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A foolish woman is noisy, Simple, and hath not known what.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And she hath sat at the opening of her house, On a throne—the high places of the city,</verse>
  <verse number="15">To call to those passing by the way, Who are going straight on their paths.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Who is simple? let him turn aside hither.’ And whoso lacketh heart—she said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="17">‘Stolen waters are sweet, And hidden bread is pleasant.’</verse>
  <verse number="18">And he hath not known that Rephaim are there, In deep places of Sheol her invited ones!</verse>
</chapter>