<chapter book="Isaiah" number="3" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">For behold, the Lord, Jehovah of hosts, will take away from Jerusalem and from Judah stay and staff, the whole stay of bread, and the whole stay of water,</verse>
  <verse number="2">the mighty man and the man of war, the judge and the prophet, and the diviner and the elder,</verse>
  <verse number="3">the captain of fifty, and the honourable man, and the counsellor, and the clever among artificers, and the one versed in enchantments.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I will appoint youths as their princes, and children shall rule over them.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the people shall be oppressed one by the other, and each by his neighbour; the child will be insolent against the elder, and the base against the honourable.</verse>
  <verse number="6">When a man shall take hold of his brother, in his father’s house, [and shall say:] Thou hast clothing; be our chief, and let this ruin be under thy hand;</verse>
  <verse number="7">he will lift up [his hand] in that day, saying, I cannot be a healer, and in my house there is neither bread nor clothing; ye shall not make me a chief of the people.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For Jerusalem stumbleth and Judah falleth, because their tongue and their doings are against Jehovah, to provoke the eyes of his glory.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The look of their face doth witness against them, and they declare their sin as Sodom: they hide it not. Woe unto their soul! for they have brought evil upon themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Say ye of the righteous that it shall be well [with him], for they shall eat the fruit of their doings.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Woe unto the wicked! it shall be ill [with him], because the desert of his hands shall be rendered unto him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">[As for] my people, children are their oppressors, and women rule over them. My people! they that guide thee mislead [thee], and destroy the way of thy paths.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Jehovah setteth himself to plead, and standeth to judge the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Jehovah will enter into judgment with the elders of his people and their princes, [saying:] It is ye that have eaten up the vineyard: the spoil of the poor is in your houses.</verse>
  <verse number="15">What mean ye that ye crush my people, and grind the faces of the afflicted? saith the Lord, Jehovah of hosts.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Jehovah said, Because the daughters of Zion are haughty, and walk with stretched-out neck and wanton eyes, and go along mincing, and making a tinkling with their feet;</verse>
  <verse number="17">therefore the Lord will make bald the crown of the head of the daughters of Zion, and Jehovah will lay bare their secret parts.</verse>
  <verse number="18">In that day the Lord will take away the ornament of anklets, and the little suns and crescents,</verse>
  <verse number="19">the pearl-drops, and the bracelets, and the veils,</verse>
  <verse number="20">the head-dresses, and the stepping chains, and the girdles, and the scent-boxes, and the amulets;</verse>
  <verse number="21">the finger-rings, and the nose-rings;</verse>
  <verse number="22">the festival-robes, and the tunics, and the mantles, and the wallets;</verse>
  <verse number="23">the mirrors, and the fine linen bodices, and the turbans, and the flowing veils.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And it shall come to pass, instead of perfume there shall be rottenness; and instead of a girdle, a rope; and instead of well-set hair, baldness; and instead of a robe of display, a girding of sackcloth; brand instead of beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Thy men shall fall by the sword, and thy mighty in the fight;</verse>
  <verse number="26">and her gates shall lament and mourn; and, stripped, she shall sit upon the ground.</verse>
</chapter>