<chapter book="Luke" number="23" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the whole company of them rose up, and brought him before Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And they began to accuse him, saying, We found this man perverting our nation, and forbidding to give tribute to Caesar, and saying that he himself is Christ a king.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Pilate asked him, saying, Art thou the King of the Jews? And he answered him and said, Thou sayest.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And Pilate said unto the chief priests and the multitudes, I find no fault in this man.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But they were the more urgent, saying, He stirreth up the people, teaching throughout all Judaea, and beginning from Galilee even unto this place.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But when Pilate heard it, he asked whether the man were a Galilaean.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And when he knew that he was of Herod’s jurisdiction, he sent him unto Herod, who himself also was at Jerusalem in these days.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Now when Herod saw Jesus, he was exceeding glad: for he was of a long time desirous to see him, because he had heard concerning him; and he hoped to see some miracle done by him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And he questioned him in many words; but he answered him nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the chief priests and the scribes stood, vehemently accusing him.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Herod with his soldiers set him at nought, and mocked him, and arraying him in gorgeous apparel sent him back to Pilate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Herod and Pilate became friends with each other that very day: for before they were at enmity between themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Pilate called together the chief priests and the rulers and the people,</verse>
  <verse number="14">and said unto them, Ye brought unto me this man, as one that perverteth the people: and behold, I, having examined him before you, found no fault in this man touching those things whereof ye accuse him:</verse>
  <verse number="15">no, nor yet Herod: for he sent him back unto us; and behold, nothing worthy of death hath been done by him.</verse>
  <verse number="16">I will therefore chastise him, and release him.</verse>
  <verse number="17"></verse>
  <verse number="18">But they cried out all together, saying, Away with this man, and release unto us Barabbas:</verse>
  <verse number="19">one who for a certain insurrection made in the city, and for murder, was cast into prison.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Pilate spake unto them again, desiring to release Jesus;</verse>
  <verse number="21">but they shouted, saying, Crucify, crucify him.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he said unto them the third time, Why, what evil hath this man done? I have found no cause of death in him: I will therefore chastise him and release him.</verse>
  <verse number="23">But they were instant with loud voices, asking that he might be crucified. And their voices prevailed.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Pilate gave sentence that what they asked for should be done.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he released him that for insurrection and murder had been cast into prison, whom they asked for; but Jesus he delivered up to their will.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And when they led him away, they laid hold upon one Simon of Cyrene, coming from the country, and laid on him the cross, to bear it after Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And there followed him a great multitude of the people, and of women who bewailed and lamented him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But Jesus turning unto them said, Daughters of Jerusalem, weep not for me, but weep for yourselves, and for your children.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For behold, the days are coming, in which they shall say, Blessed are the barren, and the wombs that never bare, and the breasts that never gave suck.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Then shall they begin to say to the mountains, Fall on us; and to the hills, Cover us.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For if they do these things in the green tree, what shall be done in the dry?</verse>
  <verse number="32">And there were also two others, malefactors, led with him to be put to death.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And when they came unto the place which is called The skull, there they crucified him, and the malefactors, one on the right hand and the other on the left.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Jesus said, Father, forgive them; for they know not what they do. And parting his garments among them, they cast lots.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And the people stood beholding. And the rulers also scoffed at him, saying, He saved others; let him save himself, if this is the Christ of God, his chosen.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And the soldiers also mocked him, coming to him, offering him vinegar,</verse>
  <verse number="37">and saying, If thou art the King of the Jews, save thyself.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And there was also a superscription over him, THIS IS THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And one of the malefactors which were hanged railed on him, saying, Art not thou the Christ? save thyself and us.</verse>
  <verse number="40">But the other answered, and rebuking him said, Dost thou not even fear God, seeing thou art in the same condemnation?</verse>
  <verse number="41">And we indeed justly; for we receive the due reward of our deeds: but this man hath done nothing amiss.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And he said, Jesus, remember me when thou comest in thy kingdom.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And he said unto him, Verily I say unto thee, Today shalt thou be with me in Paradise.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And it was now about the sixth hour, and a darkness came over the whole land until the ninth hour,</verse>
  <verse number="45">the sun’s light failing: and the veil of the temple was rent in the midst.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And when Jesus had cried with a loud voice, he said, Father, into thy hands I commend my spirit: and having said this, he gave up the ghost.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And when the centurion saw what was done, he glorified God, saying, Certainly this was a righteous man.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And all the multitudes that came together to this sight, when they beheld the things that were done, returned smiting their breasts.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And all his acquaintance, and the women that followed with him from Galilee, stood afar off, seeing these things.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And behold, a man named Joseph, who was a councillor, a good man and a righteous</verse>
  <verse number="51">(he had not consented to their counsel and deed), a man of Arimathaea, a city of the Jews, who was looking for the kingdom of God:</verse>
  <verse number="52">this man went to Pilate, and asked for the body of Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And he took it down, and wrapped it in a linen cloth, and laid him in a tomb that was hewn in stone, where never man had yet lain.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And it was the day of the Preparation, and the sabbath drew on.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And the women, which had come with him out of Galilee, followed after, and beheld the tomb, and how his body was laid.</verse>
  <verse number="56">And they returned, and prepared spices and ointments. And on the sabbath they rested according to the commandment.</verse>
</chapter>