<chapter book="Genesis" number="26" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And there was a famine in the land, beside the first famine that was in the days of Abraham. And Isaac went to Abimelech king of the Philistines to Gerar.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the LORD appeared to him, and said, Go not down into Egypt; dwell in the land which I shall tell you of:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Sojourn in this land, and I will be with you, and will bless you; for to you, and to your seed, I will give all these countries, and I will perform the oath which I swore to Abraham your father;</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I will make your seed to multiply as the stars of heaven, and will give to your seed all these countries; and in your seed shall all the nations of the earth be blessed;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Because that Abraham obeyed my voice, and kept my charge, my commandments, my statutes, and my laws.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Isaac dwelled in Gerar:</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the men of the place asked him of his wife; and he said, She is my sister: for he feared to say, She is my wife; lest, said he, the men of the place should kill me for Rebekah; because she was fair to look on.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And it came to pass, when he had been there a long time, that Abimelech king of the Philistines looked out at a window, and saw, and, behold, Isaac was sporting with Rebekah his wife.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Abimelech called Isaac, and said, Behold, of a surety she is your wife; and how said you, She is my sister? And Isaac said to him, Because I said, Lest I die for her.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Abimelech said, What is this you have done to us? one of the people might lightly have lien with your wife, and you should have brought guiltiness on us.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And Abimelech charged all his people, saying, He that touches this man or his wife shall surely be put to death.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Then Isaac sowed in that land, and received in the same year an hundred times: and the LORD blessed him.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the man waxed great, and went forward, and grew until he became very great:</verse>
  <verse number="14">For he had possession of flocks, and possession of herds, and great store of servants: and the Philistines envied him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For all the wells which his father’s servants had dig in the days of Abraham his father, the Philistines had stopped them, and filled them with earth.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Abimelech said to Isaac, Go from us; for you are much mightier than we.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And Isaac departed there, and pitched his tent in the valley of Gerar, and dwelled there.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Isaac dig again the wells of water, which they had dig in the days of Abraham his father; for the Philistines had stopped them after the death of Abraham: and he called their names after the names by which his father had called them.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Isaac’s servants dig in the valley, and found there a well of springing water.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And the herdsmen of Gerar did strive with Isaac’s herdsmen, saying, The water is ours: and he called the name of the well Esek; because they strove with him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And they dig another well, and strove for that also: and he called the name of it Sitnah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And he removed from there, and dig another well; and for that they strove not: and he called the name of it Rehoboth; and he said, For now the LORD has made room for us, and we shall be fruitful in the land.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he went up from there to Beersheba.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the LORD appeared to him the same night, and said, I am the God of Abraham your father: fear not, for I am with you, and will bless you, and multiply your seed for my servant Abraham’s sake.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And he built an altar there, and called on the name of the LORD, and pitched his tent there: and there Isaac’s servants dig a well.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then Abimelech went to him from Gerar, and Ahuzzath one of his friends, and Phichol the chief captain of his army.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Isaac said to them, Why come you to me, seeing you hate me, and have sent me away from you?</verse>
  <verse number="28">And they said, We saw certainly that the LORD was with you: and we said, Let there be now an oath between us, even between us and you, and let us make a covenant with you;</verse>
  <verse number="29">That you will do us no hurt, as we have not touched you, and as we have done to you nothing but good, and have sent you away in peace: you are now the blessed of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And he made them a feast, and they did eat and drink.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they rose up betimes in the morning, and swore one to another: and Isaac sent them away, and they departed from him in peace.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And it came to pass the same day, that Isaac’s servants came, and told him concerning the well which they had dig, and said to him, We have found water.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he called it Shebah: therefore the name of the city is Beersheba to this day.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And Esau was forty years old when he took to wife Judith the daughter of Beeri the Hittite, and Bashemath the daughter of Elon the Hittite:</verse>
  <verse number="35">Which were a grief of mind to Isaac and to Rebekah.</verse>
</chapter>