<chapter book="Genesis" number="5" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">This is the book of Adam’s generations. In the day that God created man, in the likeness of God made he him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Male and female created he them; and blessed them, and called their name Adam, in the day when they were created.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And Adam lived a hundred and thirty years, and begot [a son] in his likeness, after his image, and called his name Seth.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the days of Adam after he had begotten Seth were eight hundred years; and he begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And all the days of Adam that he lived were nine hundred and thirty years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Seth lived a hundred and five years, and begot Enosh.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And Seth lived after he had begotten Enosh eight hundred and seven years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And all the days of Seth were nine hundred and twelve years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And Enosh lived ninety years, and begot Cainan.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Enosh lived after he had begotten Cainan eight hundred and fifteen years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And all the days of Enosh were nine hundred and five years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And Cainan lived seventy years, and begot Mahalaleel.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Cainan lived after he had begotten Mahalaleel eight hundred and forty years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And all the days of Cainan were nine hundred and ten years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And Mahalaleel lived sixty-five years, and begot Jared.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And Mahalaleel lived after he had begotten Jared eight hundred and thirty years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And all the days of Mahalaleel were eight hundred and ninety-five years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Jared lived a hundred and sixty-two years, and begot Enoch.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Jared lived after he had begotten Enoch eight hundred years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And all the days of Jared were nine hundred and sixty-two years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Enoch lived sixty-five years, and begot Methushelah.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Enoch walked with God after he had begotten Methushelah three hundred years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And all the days of Enoch were three hundred and sixty-five years.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And Enoch walked with God; and he was not, for God took him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And Methushelah lived a hundred and eighty-seven years, and begot Lemech.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And Methushelah lived after he had begotten Lemech seven hundred and eighty-two years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And all the days of Methushelah were nine hundred and sixty-nine years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Lemech lived a hundred and eighty-two years, and begot a son.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And he called his name Noah, saying, This [one] shall comfort us concerning our work and concerning the toil of our hands, because of the ground which Jehovah has cursed.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Lemech lived after he had begotten Noah five hundred and ninety-five years, and begot sons and daughters.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And all the days of Lemech were seven hundred and seventy-seven years; and he died.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And Noah was five hundred years old, and Noah begot Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
</chapter>