<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="2" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">So I made up my mind not to make another painful visit to you.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For if I grieve you, who is left to cheer me but those whom I have grieved?</verse>
  <verse number="3">I wrote as I did so that on my arrival I would not be grieved by those who ought to make me rejoice. I had confidence in all of you, that you would share my joy.</verse>
  <verse number="4">For through many tears I wrote you out of great distress and anguish of heart, not to grieve you but to let you know how much I love you.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Now if anyone has caused grief, he has not grieved me but all of you—to some degree, not to overstate it.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The punishment imposed on him by the majority is sufficient for him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So instead, you ought to forgive and comfort him, so that he will not be overwhelmed by excessive sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Therefore I urge you to reaffirm your love for him.</verse>
  <verse number="9">My purpose in writing you was to see if you would stand the test and be obedient in everything.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If you forgive anyone, I also forgive him. And if I have forgiven anything, I have forgiven it in the presence of Christ for your sake,</verse>
  <verse number="11">in order that Satan should not outwit us. For we are not unaware of his schemes.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now when I went to Troas to preach the gospel of Christ and a door stood open for me in the Lord,</verse>
  <verse number="13">I had no peace in my spirit, because I did not find my brother Titus there. So I said goodbye to them and went on to Macedonia.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But thanks be to God, who always leads us triumphantly as captives in Christ and through us spreads everywhere the fragrance of the knowledge of Him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">For we are to God the sweet aroma of Christ among those who are being saved and those who are perishing.</verse>
  <verse number="16">To the one we are an odor that brings death, to the other a fragrance that brings life. And who is qualified for such a task?</verse>
  <verse number="17">For we are not like so many others, who peddle the word of God for profit. On the contrary, in Christ we speak before God with sincerity, as men sent from God.</verse>
</chapter>