<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="6" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">As God’s fellow workers, then, we urge you not to receive God’s grace in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For He says: “In the time of favor I heard you, and in the day of salvation I helped you.” Behold, now is the time of favor; now is the day of salvation!</verse>
  <verse number="3">We put no obstacle in anyone’s way, so that no one can discredit our ministry.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Rather, as servants of God we commend ourselves in every way: in great endurance; in troubles, hardships, and calamities;</verse>
  <verse number="5">in beatings, imprisonments, and riots; in labor, sleepless nights, and hunger;</verse>
  <verse number="6">in purity, knowledge, patience, and kindness; in the Holy Spirit and in sincere love;</verse>
  <verse number="7">in truthful speech and in the power of God; with the weapons of righteousness in the right hand and in the left;</verse>
  <verse number="8">through glory and dishonor, slander and praise; viewed as imposters, yet genuine;</verse>
  <verse number="9">unknown, yet well-known; dying, and yet we live on; punished, yet not killed;</verse>
  <verse number="10">sorrowful, yet always rejoicing; poor, yet making many rich; having nothing, and yet possessing everything.</verse>
  <verse number="11">We have spoken freely to you, Corinthians. Our hearts are open wide.</verse>
  <verse number="12">It is not our affection, but yours, that is restrained.</verse>
  <verse number="13">As a fair exchange—I speak as to my children—open wide your hearts also.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Do not be unequally yoked with unbelievers. For what partnership can righteousness have with wickedness? Or what fellowship does light have with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="15">What harmony is there between Christ and Belial? Or what does a believer have in common with an unbeliever?</verse>
  <verse number="16">What agreement can exist between the temple of God and idols? For we are the temple of the living God. As God has said: “I will dwell with them and walk among them, and I will be their God, and they will be My people.”</verse>
  <verse number="17">“Therefore come out from among them and be separate, says the Lord. Touch no unclean thing, and I will receive you.”</verse>
  <verse number="18">And: “I will be a Father to you, and you will be My sons and daughters, says the Lord Almighty.”</verse>
</chapter>