<chapter book="Romans" number="16" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But I commend to you Phoebe, our sister, who is minister of the assembly which is in Cenchrea;</verse>
  <verse number="2">that ye may receive her in [the] Lord worthily of saints, and that ye may assist her in whatever matter she has need of you; for she also has been a helper of many, and of myself.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Salute Prisca and Aquila, my fellow-workmen in Christ Jesus,</verse>
  <verse number="4">(who for my life staked their own neck; to whom not I only am thankful, but also all the assemblies of the nations,)</verse>
  <verse number="5">and the assembly at their house. Salute Epaenetus, my beloved, who is [the] first-fruits of Asia for Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Salute Maria, who laboured much for you.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Salute Andronicus and Junias, my kinsmen and fellow-captives, who are of note among the apostles; who were also in Christ before me.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Salute Amplias, my beloved in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Salute Urbanus, our fellow-workman in Christ, and Stachys, my beloved.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Salute Apelles, approved in Christ. Salute those who belong to Aristobulus.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Salute Herodion, my kinsman. Salute those who belong to Narcissus, who are in [the] Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Salute Tryphaena and Tryphosa, who labour in [the] Lord. Salute Persis, the beloved, who has laboured much in [the] Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Salute Rufus, chosen in [the] Lord; and his mother and mine.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Salute Asyncritus, Phlegon, Hermes, Patrobas, Hermas, and the brethren with them.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Salute Philologus, and Julia, Nereus, and his sister, and Olympas, and all the saints with them.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Salute one another with a holy kiss. All the assemblies of Christ salute you.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But I beseech you, brethren, to consider those who create divisions and occasions of falling, contrary to the doctrine which ye have learnt, and turn away from them.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For such serve not our Lord Christ, but their own belly, and by good words and fair speeches deceive the hearts of the unsuspecting.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For your obedience has reached to all. I rejoice therefore as it regards you; but I wish you to be wise [as] to that which is good, and simple [as] to evil.</verse>
  <verse number="20">But the God of peace shall bruise Satan under your feet shortly. The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ [be] with you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Timotheus, my fellow-workman, and Lucius, and Jason, and Sosipater, my kinsmen, salute you.</verse>
  <verse number="22">I Tertius, who have written this epistle, salute you in [the] Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Gaius, my host and of the whole assembly, salutes you. Erastus, the steward of the city, salutes you, and the brother Quartus.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ [be] with you all. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Now to him that is able to establish you, according to my glad tidings and the preaching of Jesus Christ, according to [the] revelation of [the] mystery, as to which silence has been kept in [the] times of the ages,</verse>
  <verse number="26">but [which] has now been made manifest, and by prophetic scriptures, according to commandment of the eternal God, made known for obedience of faith to all the nations—</verse>
  <verse number="27">[the] only wise God, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory for ever. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>