<chapter book="Romans" number="2" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Therefore thou art inexcusable, O man, every one who judgest, for in that in which thou judgest another, thou condemnest thyself; for thou that judgest doest the same things.</verse>
  <verse number="2">But we know that the judgment of God is according to truth upon those who do such things.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And thinkest thou this, O man, who judgest those that do such things, and practisest them [thyself], that thou shalt escape the judgment of God?</verse>
  <verse number="4">or despisest thou the riches of his goodness, and forbearance, and long-suffering, not knowing that the goodness of God leads thee to repentance?</verse>
  <verse number="5">but, according to thy hardness and impenitent heart, treasurest up to thyself wrath, in [the] day of wrath and revelation of [the] righteous judgment of God,</verse>
  <verse number="6">who shall render to each according to his works:</verse>
  <verse number="7">to them who, in patient continuance of good works, seek for glory and honour and incorruptibility, life eternal.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But to those that are contentious, and are disobedient to the truth, but obey unrighteousness, [there shall be] wrath and indignation,</verse>
  <verse number="9">tribulation and distress, on every soul of man that works evil, both of Jew first, and of Greek;</verse>
  <verse number="10">but glory and honour and peace to every one that works good, both to Jew first and to Greek:</verse>
  <verse number="11">for there is no acceptance of persons with God.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For as many as have sinned without law shall perish also without law; and as many as have sinned under law shall be judged by law,</verse>
  <verse number="13">(for not the hearers of the law [are] just before God, but the doers of the law shall be justified.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For when [those of the] nations, which have no law, practise by nature the things of the law, these, having no law, are a law to themselves;</verse>
  <verse number="15">who shew the work of the law written in their hearts, their conscience also bearing witness, and their thoughts accusing or else excusing themselves between themselves;)</verse>
  <verse number="16">in [the] day when God shall judge the secrets of men, according to my glad tidings, by Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But if thou art named a Jew, and restest in the law, and makest thy boast in God,</verse>
  <verse number="18">and knowest the will, and discerningly approvest the things that are more excellent, being instructed out of the law;</verse>
  <verse number="19">and hast confidence that thou thyself art a leader of the blind, a light of those who [are] in darkness,</verse>
  <verse number="20">an instructor of the foolish, a teacher of babes, having the form of knowledge and of truth in the law:</verse>
  <verse number="21">thou then that teachest another, dost thou not teach thyself? thou that preachest not to steal, dost thou steal?</verse>
  <verse number="22">thou that sayest [man should] not commit adultery, dost thou commit adultery? thou that abhorrest idols, dost thou commit sacrilege?</verse>
  <verse number="23">thou who boastest in law, dost thou by transgression of the law dishonour God?</verse>
  <verse number="24">For the name of God is blasphemed on your account among the nations, according as it is written.</verse>
  <verse number="25">For circumcision indeed profits if thou keep [the] law; but if thou be a law-transgressor, thy circumcision is become uncircumcision.</verse>
  <verse number="26">If therefore the uncircumcision keep the requirements of the law, shall not his uncircumcision be reckoned for circumcision,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and uncircumcision by nature, fulfilling the law, judge thee, who, with letter and circumcision, [art] a law-transgressor?</verse>
  <verse number="28">For he is not a Jew who [is] one outwardly, neither that circumcision which is outward in flesh;</verse>
  <verse number="29">but he [is] a Jew [who is so] inwardly; and circumcision, of the heart, in spirit, not in letter; whose praise [is] not of men, but of God.</verse>
</chapter>