<chapter book="Philippians" number="2" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">If therefore any consolation in Christ, if any encouragement of love, if any mutual participation of the Spirit, if any compassions and mercies,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Fill ye up my joy, that ye may have the same in mind, having the same love, unanimous, being one in mind.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Nothing by hired labor, or vainglory; but in lowliness the leaders hold each other above themselves.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Look ye each not on the things of themselves, but also each the things of others.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For let this be in mind among you, which also in Christ Jesus;</verse>
  <verse number="6">Who, being in the form of God, thought not robbery to be equal to God.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But emptied himself, taking the form of a servant, born in the likeness of men:</verse>
  <verse number="8">And found in fashion as man, he humbled himself, being obedient until death, and the death of the cross.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Wherefore God has also exceedingly exalted him, and favored him as a gift with a name above every name:</verse>
  <verse number="10">That in the name of Jesus every knee should bend, of the heavenlies, and of terrestrial things, and things under earth</verse>
  <verse number="11">And every tongue should avow that the Lord is Jesus Christ, to the glory of the Father.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Therefore, my beloved, as ye have always listened, not as in my presence only, but now much more in my absence, with fear and tremor effect your own salvation.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For God is working in you also to will and to work by benevolence.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Do ye all things without murmurings and discussions:</verse>
  <verse number="15">That ye be complete and pure, children of God, blameless in the midst of a crooked and perverted generation, among whom ye appear as luminaries in the world;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Holding on to the word of life; for boasting to me in the day of Christ, for I ran not in vain, nor was I wearied in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="17">But if also I am poured out upon the sacrifice and service of your faith, I rejoice, and rejoice together with you all.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And do ye also rejoice at the same, and rejoice together with me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And I hope in the Lord Jesus to send Timothy quickly to you, that I also be courageous, having known the things concerning you.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For I have none having a like soul, who naturally will have care for the things concerning you.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For they all seek the things of themselves, and not the things of Christ Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And ye know his proof, that, as a child to a father, he served with me in the good news.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Him therefore I truly hope to send, whenever I shall see from it the things concerning me.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And I have trusted in the Lord that I myself also shall come quickly.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And I thought necessary Epaphroditus, my brother, and cooperator, and fellow-soldier, and your sent, and workman of my necessity, be sent to you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Since he was longing for you all, and harassed because ye heard that he was sick.</verse>
  <verse number="27">For also he was sick near to death: but God compassionated him; and not him only, but also me, lest I should have grief upon grief.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Therefore I sent him the more earnestly, that, seeing him, ye might again rejoice, and I be more free from sorrow.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Therefore receive him in the Lord with all joy; and hold such esteemed.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Because for the work of Christ he drew near to death, having exposed the soul to danger, that he might fill up your want of service to me.</verse>
</chapter>