<chapter book="Micah" number="5" translation="Douay-Rheims Bible" translationID="drb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now shalt thou be laid waste, O daughter of the robber: they have laid siege against us, with a rod shall they strike the cheek of the judge of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="2">AND THOU, BETHLEHEM Ephrata, art a little one among the thousands of Juda: out of thee shall he come forth unto me that is to be the ruler in Israel: and his going forth is from the beginning, from the days of eternity.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Therefore will he give them up even till the time wherein she that travaileth shall bring forth: and the remnant of his brethren shall be converted to the children of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he shall stand, and feed in the strength of the Lord, in the height of the name of the Lord his God: and they shall be converted, for now shall he be magnified even to the ends of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And this man shall be our peace, when the Assyrian shall come into our land, and when he shall set his foot in our houses: and we shall raise against him seven shepherds, and eight principal men.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And they shall feed the land of Assyria with the sword, and the land of Nemrod with the spears thereof: and he shall deliver us from the Assyrian, when he shall come into our land, and when he shall tread in our borders.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the remnant of Jacob shall be in the midst of many peoples as a dew from the Lord, and as drops upon the grass, which waiteth not for man, nor tarrieth for the children of men.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And the remnant of Jacob shall be among the Gentiles in the midst of many peoples as a lion among the beasts of the forests, and as a young lion among the docks of sheep: who when he shall go through and tread down, and take, there is none to deliver.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Thy hand shall be lifted up over thy enemies, and all thy enemies shall be cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And it shall come to pass in that day, saith the Lord, that I will take away thy horses out of the midst of thee, and will destroy thy chariots.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I will destroy the cities of thy land, and will throw down all thy strong holds,</verse>
  <verse number="12">and I will take away sorceries out of thy hand, and there shall be no divinations in thee.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And I will destroy thy graven things, and thy statues out of the midst of thee: and thou shalt no more adore the works of thy hands.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And I will pluck up thy groves out of the midst of thee: and will crush thy cities.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And I will execute vengeance in wrath and in indignation among all the nations that have not given ear.</verse>
</chapter>