<chapter book="Revelation" number="13" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I stood upon the sand of the sea, and I saw coming up from the sea a wild beast, having seven heads and ten horns, and upon his horns ten diadems, and upon his heads the name of blasphemy.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the wild beast which I saw was like a panther, and his feet as of a bear, and his mouth as the mouth of a lion: and the dragon gave him his power, and his throne, and great authority.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I saw one of his heads as slaughtered to death; and his deathblow was healed: and the whole earth wondered after the beast.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they worshipped the dragon which gave power to the wild beast: and they worshipped the wild beast, saying, Who like the beast? who shall be able to war with him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And a mouth was given him speaking great things and blasphemies; and power was given him to make war forty-two months.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And he opened his mouth in blasphemy against God, to blaspheme his name, and his tent, and them dwelling in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And it was given him to make war with the holy, and to conquer them: and power was given him over every tribe, and tongue, and nation.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And all they dwelling upon earth shall worship him, whose names have not been written in the book of life of the slain Lamb from the foundation of the world.</verse>
  <verse number="9">If any have an ear, let him hear.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If any bring together to captivity he shall proceed into captivity: if any shall kill with sword, he shall be killed with the sword. Here is the patience and faith of the holy.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And I saw another wild beast coming up out of the earth; and he had two horns like a lamb, and he spake as a dragon.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And all the powers of the first beast he does before him, and he makes the earth and all dwelling in it that they should worship the first wild beast, whose death-blow was healed.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he does great signs, that also he might make fire come down from heaven to the earth before men,</verse>
  <verse number="14">And he deceives them dwelling upon earth by the signs which were given him to do before the wild beast; saying to them dwelling upon earth, to make an image to the wild beast, who has the blow of the sword, and he lived.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And it was given him to give spirit to the image of the wild beast, that the image of the wild beast might speak, and might make as many as should not worship the image of the wild beast that they be killed.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he makes all, small and great, and rich and poor, and free and servants, that he should give them a stamp upon their right hand, or upon their foreheads:</verse>
  <verse number="17">And that no one could buy or sell, except he having the stamp, or the name of the wild beast, or the number of his name.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Here is wisdom. Let him having intelligence calculate the number of the wild beast: for it is the number of a man; and his number Six hundred and sixty-six.</verse>
</chapter>