<chapter book="Revelation" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And to the messenger of the church in Sardis write: Thus says he having the seven spirits of God, and the seven stars; I know thy works, that thou hast a name that thou livest, and art dead:</verse>
  <verse number="2">Be watching, and make firm the remaining things, which are about to die: For I have not found thy works perfected before God.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Remember therefore how thou hast received, and heard, and do thou, and repent. If therefore thou watch not, I will come upon thee as a thief, and thou shalt not know what hour I shall come upon thee.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Thou hast a few names also in Sardis which stained not their garments; and they shall walk about with me in white things: for they are worthy.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He conquering, the same shall be surrounded in white garments; and I will not wipe out his name from the book of life, but I will acknowledge his name before my Father, and before his messengers.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He having ears, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And to the messenger of the church in Philadelphia write; Thus says the holy, the true, he having the key of David, he opening, and no one shuts; and he shuts, and no one opens;</verse>
  <verse number="8">I know thy works: behold, I have given before thee an open door, and none can shut it, for thou hast a little power, and hast kept my word, and hast not denied my name.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Behold, I give of the synagogue of Satan, of them saying themselves to be Jews, and are not, but they lie; behold, I will make them that they come and worship before thy feet, and they should know that I have loved thee.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For thou didst keep the word of my patience, and I will keep thee from the hour of temptation, about to come upon the whole habitable globe, to try them dwelling upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Behold, I come swiftly: hold what thou hast, that none take thy crown.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He conquering, I will make him a pillar in the temple of my God, and without shall he no more come forth: and I will write upon him the name of my God, and the name of the city of my God, the new Jerusalem, which comes down from heaven from my God: and my new name.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He having ears, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And to the angel of the church of the Laodiceans write; Thus says the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of the creation of God;</verse>
  <verse number="15">I know thy works, that thou art neither cold nor boiling: I would thou shouldest be cold or boiling.</verse>
  <verse number="16">For so thou art tepid, and neither cold nor boiling, I am about to vomit thee out of my month.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For thou sayest, That I am rich, and have abounded, and have need of nothing; and thou knowest not that thou art wretched, and pitiable, and poor, and blind, and naked;</verse>
  <verse number="18">I counsel thee to buy gold of me refined by fire, that thou mightest be rich; and white garments, that thou mightest be surrounded, and that the shame of thy nakedness might not be made manifest; and anoint thine eyes with eyesalve that thou mightest see.</verse>
  <verse number="19">I, if as many as I love, I rebuke and correct: be emulous therefore, and repent.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Behold, I stand before the door, and knock: and if any hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">He conquering, will I give to him to sit with me on my throne, as I also conquered, and sat down with my Father on his throne.</verse>
  <verse number="22">He having ears, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches.</verse>
</chapter>