<chapter book="Revelation" number="6" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I saw when the Lamb opened one of the seals, and I heard one of the four living creatures saying, as the voice of thunder, Come and see.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I saw and behold a white horse: and he sitting upon him having a bow; and a crown was given to him: and he went forth conquering, and that he might conquer.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And when he opened the second seal, I heard the second living creature saying, Come and see.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And another horse came forth fiery red: and it was given to him sitting upon him to take peace from the earth, and that they should slaughter one another: and a great sword was given to him.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And when he opened the third seal, I heard the third living creature saying, Come and see. And I saw, and behold a black horse, and he sitting upon him having a balance in his hand.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And I heard a voice in the midst of the four living creatures saying, A measure of wheat for a drachma, and three measures of barley for a drachma; and thou shouldest not injure the oil and the wine.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And when he opened the fourth seal, I heard a voice of the fourth living creature saying, Come and see.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And I saw, and behold a pale horse: and he sitting above him the name to him Death, and Hades follows with him. And power was given to them to kill upon the fourth of the earth, with sword, and by famine, and by death, and by wild beasts of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And when he opened the fifth seal, I saw under the altar the souls of the slain for the word of God, and for the testimony which they had:</verse>
  <verse number="10">And they cried with a great voice, saying, Till when, Lord, holy and true, dost thou not judge and avenge our blood of them dwelling upon earth</verse>
  <verse number="11">And to each were given white robes; and it was said to them, that they should rest for a little time, till also their fellowservants be filled up, about to be killed, as also they.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I saw when he opened the sixth seal, and, behold, there was a great shaking; and the sun was black as sackcloth of hair, and the moon was as blood;</verse>
  <verse number="13">And the stars of heaven fell to the earth, as a fig tree casts her untimely figs, shaken by a great wind.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the heaven was separated as a book turned round; and every mount and isle were moved from their places.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the kings of the earth, and the great, and the rich, and the captains of thousands, and the powerful, and every servant, and every one free, hid themselves in caves and in rocks of the mountains;</verse>
  <verse number="16">And they say to the mountains and rocks, Fall upon us, and hide us from the face of him sitting upon the throne, and from the wrath of the Lamb:</verse>
  <verse number="17">For the great day of his wrath has come; and who can stand?</verse>
</chapter>