<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="16" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now concerning the collection for the saints, as I commanded the assemblies of Galatia, you do likewise.</verse>
  <verse number="2">On the first day of the week, let each one of you save, as he may prosper, that no collections be made when I come.</verse>
  <verse number="3">When I arrive, I will send whoever you approve with letters to carry your gracious gift to Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="4">If it is appropriate for me to go also, they will go with me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But I will come to you when I have passed through Macedonia, for I am passing through Macedonia.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But with you it may be that I will stay, or even winter, that you may send me on my journey wherever I go.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For I do not wish to see you now in passing, but I hope to stay a while with you, if the Lord permits.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But I will stay at Ephesus until Pentecost,</verse>
  <verse number="9">for a great and effective door has opened to me, and there are many adversaries.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now if Timothy comes, see that he is with you without fear, for he does the work of the Lord, as I also do.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Therefore let no one despise him. But set him forward on his journey in peace, that he may come to me; for I expect him with the brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now concerning Apollos, the brother, I strongly urged him to come to you with the brothers; and it was not at all his desire to come now; but he will come when he has an opportunity.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Watch! Stand firm in the faith! Be courageous! Be strong!</verse>
  <verse number="14">Let all that you do be done in love.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Now I beg you, brothers (you know the house of Stephanas, that it is the first fruits of Achaia, and that they have set themselves to serve the saints),</verse>
  <verse number="16">that you also be in subjection to such, and to everyone who helps in the work and labors.</verse>
  <verse number="17">I rejoice at the coming of Stephanas, Fortunatus, and Achaicus; for that which was lacking on your part, they supplied.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For they refreshed my spirit and yours. Therefore acknowledge those who are like that.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The assemblies of Asia greet you. Aquila and Priscilla greet you much in the Lord, together with the assembly that is in their house.</verse>
  <verse number="20">All the brothers greet you. Greet one another with a holy kiss.</verse>
  <verse number="21">This greeting is by me, Paul, with my own hand.</verse>
  <verse number="22">If any man doesn’t love the Lord Jesus Christ, let him be accursed. Come, Lord!</verse>
  <verse number="23">The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">My love to all of you in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>