<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="6" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The sons of Levi: Gershom, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And the sons of Kohath: Amram, Jizhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the children of Amram: Aaron, and Moses, and Miriam. And the sons of Aaron: Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Eleazar begot Phinehas; Phinehas begot Abishua,</verse>
  <verse number="5">and Abishua begot Bukki, and Bukki begot Uzzi,</verse>
  <verse number="6">and Uzzi begot Zerahiah, and Zerahiah begot Meraioth;</verse>
  <verse number="7">Meraioth begot Amariah, and Amariah begot Ahitub,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and Ahitub begot Zadok, and Zadok begot Ahimaaz,</verse>
  <verse number="9">and Ahimaaz begot Azariah, and Azariah begot Johanan,</verse>
  <verse number="10">and Johanan begot Azariah (he is it that exercised the priesthood in the house that Solomon built in Jerusalem);</verse>
  <verse number="11">and Azariah begot Amariah, and Amariah begot Ahitub,</verse>
  <verse number="12">and Ahitub begot Zadok, and Zadok begot Shallum,</verse>
  <verse number="13">and Shallum begot Hilkijah, and Hilkijah begot Azariah,</verse>
  <verse number="14">and Azariah begot Seraiah, and Seraiah begot Jehozadak,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and Jehozadak went away, when Jehovah carried away Judah and Jerusalem by the hand of Nebuchadnezzar.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The sons of Levi: Gershom, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And these are the names of the sons of Gershom: Libni and Shimei.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the sons of Kohath: Amram, and Jizhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The sons of Merari: Mahli and Mushi. And these are the families of Levi according to their fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Of Gershom: Libni his son, Jahath his son, Zimmah his son,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Joah his son, Iddo his son, Zerah his son, Jeathrai his son.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The sons of Kohath: Amminadab his son, Korah his son, Assir his son,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Elkanah his son, and Ebiasaph his son, and Assir his son,</verse>
  <verse number="24">Tahath his son, Uriel his son, Uzziah his son, and Saul his son.</verse>
  <verse number="25">And the sons of Elkanah: Amasai and Ahimoth.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Elkanah,—the sons of Elkanah: Zophai his son, and Nahath his son,</verse>
  <verse number="27">Eliab his son, Jeroham his son, Elkanah his son.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And the sons of Samuel: the firstborn Vashni and Abijah.</verse>
  <verse number="29">The sons of Merari: Mahli; Libni his son, Shimei his son, Uzza his son,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Shimea his son, Haggijah his son, Asaiah his son.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And these are they whom David set over the service of song in the house of Jehovah after that the ark was in rest.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they ministered before the tabernacle of the tent of meeting with singing, until Solomon had built the house of Jehovah in Jerusalem; and they attended to their office according to their order.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And these are they that attended, and their sons: Of the sons of the Kohathites: Heman the singer, the son of Joel, the son of Samuel,</verse>
  <verse number="34">the son of Elkanah, the son of Jeroham, the son of Eliel, the son of Toah,</verse>
  <verse number="35">the son of Zuph, the son of Elkanah, the son of Mahath, the son of Amasai,</verse>
  <verse number="36">the son of Elkanah, the son of Joel, the son of Azariah, the son of Zephaniah,</verse>
  <verse number="37">the son of Tahath, the son of Assir, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah,</verse>
  <verse number="38">the son of Jizhar, the son of Kohath, the son of Levi, the son of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And his brother Asaph, who stood on his right hand: Asaph, the son of Berechiah, the son of Shimea,</verse>
  <verse number="40">the son of Michael, the son of Baaseiah, the son of Malchijah,</verse>
  <verse number="41">the son of Ethni, the son of Zerah, the son of Adaiah,</verse>
  <verse number="42">the son of Ethan, the son of Zimmah, the son of Shimei,</verse>
  <verse number="43">the son of Jahath, the son of Gershom, the son of Levi.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And their brethren the sons of Merari were on the left hand: Ethan the son of Kishi, the son of Abdi, the son of Malluch,</verse>
  <verse number="45">the son of Hashabiah, the son of Amaziah, the son of Hilkijah,</verse>
  <verse number="46">the son of Amzi, the son of Bani, the son of Shemer,</verse>
  <verse number="47">the son of Mahli, the son of Mushi, the son of Merari, the son of Levi.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And their brethren the Levites were given for all the service of the tabernacle of the house of God.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Aaron and his sons offered upon the altar of the burnt-offering, and on the altar of incense, for all the work of the most holy place, and to make atonement for Israel, according to all that Moses the servant of God had commanded.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And these are the sons of Aaron: Eleazar his son, Phinehas his son, Abishua his son,</verse>
  <verse number="51">Bukki his son, Uzzi his son, Zerahiah his son,</verse>
  <verse number="52">Meraioth his son, Amariah his son, Ahitub his son,</verse>
  <verse number="53">Zadok his son, Ahimaaz his son.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And these are their dwelling-places according to their encampments, within their borders. For the sons of Aaron, of the family of the Kohathites, for theirs was the lot;</verse>
  <verse number="55">and they gave them Hebron in the land of Judah, and its suburbs round about it;</verse>
  <verse number="56">but the fields of the city, and the hamlets thereof gave they to Caleb the son of Jephunneh.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And to the children of Aaron they gave the city of refuge, Hebron; and Libnah and its suburbs, and Jattir, and Eshtemoa and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="58">and Hilen and its suburbs, Debir and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="59">and Ashan and its suburbs, and Beth-shemesh and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="60">and, out of the tribe of Benjamin, Geba and its suburbs, and Allemeth and its suburbs, and Anathoth and its suburbs: all their cities, thirteen cities, according to their families.</verse>
  <verse number="61">And to the children of Kohath that remained [were given] by lot out of the families of the tribe [of Ephraim and of the tribe of Dan and] of the half tribe, half Manasseh, ten cities.</verse>
  <verse number="62">And to the children of Gershom according to their families out of the tribe of Issachar, and out of the tribe of Asher, and out of the tribe of Naphtali, and out of the tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities.</verse>
  <verse number="63">To the children of Merari [were given] by lot, according to their families, out of the tribe of Reuben, and out of the tribe of Gad, and out of the tribe of Zebulun, twelve cities.</verse>
  <verse number="64">And the children of Israel gave to the Levites the cities and their suburbs.</verse>
  <verse number="65">And they gave by lot out of the tribe of the children of Judah, and out of the tribe of the children of Simeon, and out of the tribe of the children of Benjamin, these cities which were mentioned by name.</verse>
  <verse number="66">And to the families of the children of Kohath who had the cities of their territory out of the tribe of Ephraim,</verse>
  <verse number="67">they gave the city of refuge, Shechem and its suburbs in mount Ephraim; and Gezer and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="68">and Jokmeam and its suburbs, and Beth-horon and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="69">and Ajalon and its suburbs, and Gath-Rimmon and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="70">and out of the half tribe of Manasseh: Aner and its suburbs, and Bileam and its suburbs,—for the families of the children of Kohath that remained.</verse>
  <verse number="71">To the children of Gershom [were given] out of the family of the half tribe of Manasseh: Golan in Bashan and its suburbs, and Ashtaroth and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="72">and out of the tribe of Issachar: Kedesh and its suburbs, Dobrath and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="73">and Ramoth and its suburbs, and Anem and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="74">and out of the tribe of Asher: Mashal and its suburbs, and Abdon and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="75">and Hukok and its suburbs, and Rehob and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="76">and out of the tribe of Naphtali: Kedesh in Galilee and its suburbs, and Hammon and its suburbs, and Kirjathaim and its suburbs.</verse>
  <verse number="77">To the children of Merari that remained [were given] out of the tribe of Zebulun, Rimmono and its suburbs, [and] Tabor and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="78">and on the other side of the Jordan by Jericho, on the east side of the Jordan, out of the tribe of Reuben: Bezer in the wilderness and its suburbs, and Jahzah and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="79">and Kedemoth and its suburbs, and Mephaath and its suburbs;</verse>
  <verse number="80">and out of the tribe of Gad: Ramoth in Gilead and its suburbs, and Mahanaim and its suburbs,</verse>
  <verse number="81">and Heshbon and its suburbs, and Jaazer and its suburbs.</verse>
</chapter>