<chapter book="Leviticus" number="2" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">‘And when a person bringeth near an offering, a present to Jehovah, of flour is his offering, and he hath poured on it oil, and hath put on it frankincense;</verse>
  <verse number="2">and he hath brought it in unto the sons of Aaron, the priests, and he hath taken from thence the fulness of his hand of its flour and of its oil, besides all its frankincense, and the priest hath made perfume with its memorial on the altar, a fire-offering of sweet fragrance to Jehovah;</verse>
  <verse number="3">and the remnant of the present is for Aaron and for his sons, most holy, of the fire-offerings of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And when thou bringest near an offering, a present baked in an oven, it is of unleavened cakes of flour mixed with oil, or thin unleavened cakes anointed with oil.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And if thine offering is a present made on the girdel, it is of flour, mixed with oil, unleavened;</verse>
  <verse number="6">divide thou it into parts, and thou hast poured on it oil; it is a present.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And if thine offering is a present made on the frying-pan, of flour with oil it is made,</verse>
  <verse number="8">and thou hast brought in the present which is made of these to Jehovah, and one hath brought it near unto the priest, and he hath brought it nigh unto the altar,</verse>
  <verse number="9">and the priest hath lifted up from the present its memorial, and hath made perfume on the altar, a fire-offering of sweet fragrance to Jehovah;</verse>
  <verse number="10">and the remnant of the present is for Aaron and for his sons, most holy, of the fire-offerings of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="11">No present which ye bring near to Jehovah is made fermented, for with any leaven or any honey ye perfume no fire-offering to Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">An offering of first -fruits—ye bring them near to Jehovah, but on the altar they go not up, for sweet fragrance.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And every offering—thy present—with salt thou dost season, and thou dost not let the salt of the covenant of thy God cease from thy present; with all thine offerings thou dost bring near salt.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And if thou bring near a present of first-ripe fruits to Jehovah,—of green ears, roasted with fire, beaten out corn of a fruitful field thou dost bring near the present of thy first-ripe fruits,</verse>
  <verse number="15">and thou hast put on it oil, and laid on it frankincense, it is a present;</verse>
  <verse number="16">and the priest hath made perfume with its memorial from its beaten out corn, and from its oil, besides all its frankincense—a fire-offering to Jehovah.</verse>
</chapter>