<chapter book="Leviticus" number="7" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And this is a law of the guilt-offering: it is most holy;</verse>
  <verse number="2">in the place where they slaughter the burnt-offering they do slaughter the guilt-offering, and its blood one doth sprinkle on the altar round about,</verse>
  <verse number="3">and all its fat he bringeth near out of it, the fat tail, and the fat which is covering the inwards,</verse>
  <verse number="4">and the two kidneys, and the fat which is on them, which is on the flanks, and the redundance above the liver (beside the kidneys he doth turn it aside);</verse>
  <verse number="5">and the priest hath made them a perfume on the altar, a fire-offering to Jehovah; it is a guilt-offering.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Every male among the priests doth eat it; in the holy place it is eaten—it is most holy;</verse>
  <verse number="7">as is a sin-offering, so is a guilt-offering; one law is for them; the priest who maketh atonement by it—it is his.</verse>
  <verse number="8">‘And the priest who is bringing near any man’s burnt-offering, the skin of the burnt-offering which he hath brought near, it is the priest’s, his own;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and every present which is baked in an oven, and every one done in a frying-pan, and on a girdel, is the priest’s who is bringing it near; it is his;</verse>
  <verse number="10">and every present, mixed with oil or dry, is for all the sons of Aaron—one as another.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And this is a law of the sacrifice of the peace-offerings which one bringeth near to Jehovah:</verse>
  <verse number="12">if for a thank-offering he bring it near, then he hath brought near with the sacrifice of thank-offering unleavened cakes mixed with oil, and thin unleavened cakes anointed with oil, and of fried flour cakes mixed with oil;</verse>
  <verse number="13">besides the cakes, fermented bread he doth bring near with his offering, besides the sacrifice of thank-offering of his peace-offerings;</verse>
  <verse number="14">and he hath brought near out of it one of the whole offering—a heave-offering to Jehovah; to the priest who is sprinkling the blood of the peace-offerings—it is his;</verse>
  <verse number="15">as to the flesh of the sacrifice of the thank-offering of his peace-offerings, in the day of his offering it is eaten; he doth not leave of it till morning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And if the sacrifice of his offering is a vow or free-will offering, in the day of his bringing near his sacrifice it is eaten; and on the morrow also the remnant of it is eaten;</verse>
  <verse number="17">and the remnant of the flesh of the sacrifice on the third day with fire is burnt;</verse>
  <verse number="18">and if any of the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace-offerings be really eaten on the third day, it is not pleasing; for him who is bringing it near it is not reckoned; it is an abominable thing, and the person who is eating of it his iniquity doth bear.</verse>
  <verse number="19">‘And the flesh which cometh against any unclean thing is not eaten; with fire it is burnt; as to the flesh, every clean one doth eat of the flesh;</verse>
  <verse number="20">and the person who eateth of the flesh of the sacrifice of the peace-offerings which are Jehovah’s, and his uncleanness upon him, even that person hath been cut off from his people.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And when a person cometh against any thing unclean, of the uncleanness of man, or of the uncleanness of beasts, or of any unclean teeming creature, and hath eaten of the flesh of the sacrifice of the peace-offerings which are Jehovah’s, even that person hath been cut off from his people.’</verse>
  <verse number="22">And Jehovah speaketh unto Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="23">‘Speak unto the sons of Israel, saying, Any fat of ox and sheep and goat ye do not eat;</verse>
  <verse number="24">and the fat of a carcase, and the fat of a torn thing is prepared for any work, but ye do certainly not eat it;</verse>
  <verse number="25">for whoever eateth the fat of the beast, of which one bringeth near a fire-offering to Jehovah, even the person who eateth hath been cut off from his people.</verse>
  <verse number="26">‘And any blood ye do not eat in all your dwellings, of fowl, or of beast;</verse>
  <verse number="27">any person who eateth any blood, even that person hath been cut off from his people.’</verse>
  <verse number="28">And Jehovah speaketh unto Moses, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="29">‘Speak unto the sons of Israel, saying, He who is bringing near the sacrifice of his peace-offerings to Jehovah doth bring in his offering to Jehovah from the sacrifice of his peace-offerings;</verse>
  <verse number="30">his own hands do bring in the fire-offerings of Jehovah, the fat beside the breast, it he doth bring in with the breast, to wave it—a wave-offering before Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="31">‘And the priest hath made perfume with the fat on the altar, and the breast hath been Aaron’s and his sons;</verse>
  <verse number="32">and the right leg ye do make a heave-offering to the priest of the sacrifices of your peace-offerings;</verse>
  <verse number="33">he of the sons of Aaron who is bringing near the blood of the peace-offerings, and the fat, his is the right leg for a portion.</verse>
  <verse number="34">‘For the breast of the wave-offering, and the leg of the heave-offering, I have taken from the sons of Israel, from the sacrifices of their peace-offerings, and I give them to Aaron the priest, and to his sons, by a statute age-during, from the sons of Israel.’</verse>
  <verse number="35">This is the anointing of Aaron, and the anointing of his sons out of the fire-offerings of Jehovah, in the day he hath brought them near to act as priest to Jehovah,</verse>
  <verse number="36">which Jehovah hath commanded to give to them in the day of His anointing them, from the sons of Israel—a statute age-during to their generations.</verse>
  <verse number="37">This is the law for burnt-offering, for present, and for sin-offering, and for guilt-offering, and for consecrations, and for a sacrifice of the peace-offerings,</verse>
  <verse number="38">which Jehovah hath commanded Moses in Mount Sinai, in the day of his commanding the sons of Israel to bring near their offerings to Jehovah, in the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
</chapter>