<chapter book="Proverbs" number="1" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">The proverbs of Solomon the son of David, king of Israel;</verse>
  <verse number="2">To know wisdom and instruction; to perceive the words of understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">To receive the instruction of wisdom, justice, and judgment, and equity;</verse>
  <verse number="4">To give subtlety to the simple, to the young man knowledge and discretion.</verse>
  <verse number="5">A wise man will hear, and will increase learning; and a man of understanding shall attain to wise counsels:</verse>
  <verse number="6">To understand a proverb, and the interpretation; the words of the wise, and their dark sayings.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The fear of the LORD is the beginning of knowledge: but fools despise wisdom and instruction.</verse>
  <verse number="8">My son, hear the instruction of your father, and forsake not the law of your mother:</verse>
  <verse number="9">For they shall be an ornament of grace to your head, and chains about your neck.</verse>
  <verse number="10">My son, if sinners entice you, consent you not.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If they say, Come with us, let us lay wait for blood, let us lurk privately for the innocent without cause:</verse>
  <verse number="12">Let us swallow them up alive as the grave; and whole, as those that go down into the pit:</verse>
  <verse number="13">We shall find all precious substance, we shall fill our houses with spoil:</verse>
  <verse number="14">Cast in your lot among us; let us all have one purse:</verse>
  <verse number="15">My son, walk not you in the way with them; refrain your foot from their path:</verse>
  <verse number="16">For their feet run to evil, and make haste to shed blood.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Surely in vain the net is spread in the sight of any bird.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And they lay wait for their own blood; they lurk privately for their own lives.</verse>
  <verse number="19">So are the ways of every one that is greedy of gain; which takes away the life of the owners thereof.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Wisdom cries without; she utters her voice in the streets:</verse>
  <verse number="21">She cries in the chief place of concourse, in the openings of the gates: in the city she utters her words, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="22">How long, you simple ones, will you love simplicity? and the scorners delight in their scorning, and fools hate knowledge?</verse>
  <verse number="23">Turn you at my reproof: behold, I will pour out my spirit to you, I will make known my words to you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Because I have called, and you refused; I have stretched out my hand, and no man regarded;</verse>
  <verse number="25">But you have set at nothing all my counsel, and would none of my reproof:</verse>
  <verse number="26">I also will laugh at your calamity; I will mock when your fear comes;</verse>
  <verse number="27">When your fear comes as desolation, and your destruction comes as a whirlwind; when distress and anguish comes on you.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Then shall they call on me, but I will not answer; they shall seek me early, but they shall not find me:</verse>
  <verse number="29">For that they hated knowledge, and did not choose the fear of the LORD:</verse>
  <verse number="30">They would none of my counsel: they despised all my reproof.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Therefore shall they eat of the fruit of their own way, and be filled with their own devices.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the turning away of the simple shall slay them, and the prosperity of fools shall destroy them.</verse>
  <verse number="33">But whoever listens to me shall dwell safely, and shall be quiet from fear of evil.</verse>
</chapter>