<chapter book="Proverbs" number="2" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if you will receive my words, and hide my commandments with you;</verse>
  <verse number="2">So that you incline your ear to wisdom, and apply your heart to understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="3">Yes, if you cry after knowledge, and lift up your voice for understanding;</verse>
  <verse number="4">If you seek her as silver, and search for her as for hid treasures;</verse>
  <verse number="5">Then shall you understand the fear of the LORD, and find the knowledge of God.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For the LORD gives wisdom: out of his mouth comes knowledge and understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He lays up sound wisdom for the righteous: he is a buckler to them that walk uprightly.</verse>
  <verse number="8">He keeps the paths of judgment, and preserves the way of his saints.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Then shall you understand righteousness, and judgment, and equity; yes, every good path.</verse>
  <verse number="10">When wisdom enters into your heart, and knowledge is pleasant to your soul;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Discretion shall preserve you, understanding shall keep you:</verse>
  <verse number="12">To deliver you from the way of the evil man, from the man that speaks fraudulent things;</verse>
  <verse number="13">Who leave the paths of uprightness, to walk in the ways of darkness;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Who rejoice to do evil, and delight in the frowardness of the wicked;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Whose ways are crooked, and they fraudulent in their paths:</verse>
  <verse number="16">To deliver you from the strange woman, even from the stranger which flatters with her words;</verse>
  <verse number="17">Which forsakes the guide of her youth, and forgets the covenant of her God.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For her house inclines to death, and her paths to the dead.</verse>
  <verse number="19">None that go to her return again, neither take they hold of the paths of life.</verse>
  <verse number="20">That you may walk in the way of good men, and keep the paths of the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For the upright shall dwell in the land, and the perfect shall remain in it.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But the wicked shall be cut off from the earth, and the transgressors shall be rooted out of it.</verse>
</chapter>