<chapter book="Proverbs" number="3" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, forget not my law; but let your heart keep my commandments:</verse>
  <verse number="2">For length of days, and long life, and peace, shall they add to you.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Let not mercy and truth forsake you: bind them about your neck; write them on the table of your heart:</verse>
  <verse number="4">So shall you find favor and good understanding in the sight of God and man.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Trust in the LORD with all your heart; and lean not to your own understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In all your ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct your paths.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Be not wise in your own eyes: fear the LORD, and depart from evil.</verse>
  <verse number="8">It shall be health to your navel, and marrow to your bones.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Honor the LORD with your substance, and with the first fruits of all your increase:</verse>
  <verse number="10">So shall your barns be filled with plenty, and your presses shall burst out with new wine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">My son, despise not the chastening of the LORD; neither be weary of his correction:</verse>
  <verse number="12">For whom the LORD loves he corrects; even as a father the son in whom he delights.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Happy is the man that finds wisdom, and the man that gets understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For the merchandise of it is better than the merchandise of silver, and the gain thereof than fine gold.</verse>
  <verse number="15">She is more precious than rubies: and all the things you can desire are not to be compared to her.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Length of days is in her right hand; and in her left hand riches and honor.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Her ways are ways of pleasantness, and all her paths are peace.</verse>
  <verse number="18">She is a tree of life to them that lay hold on her: and happy is every one that retains her.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The LORD by wisdom has founded the earth; by understanding has he established the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="20">By his knowledge the depths are broken up, and the clouds drop down the dew.</verse>
  <verse number="21">My son, let not them depart from your eyes: keep sound wisdom and discretion:</verse>
  <verse number="22">So shall they be life to your soul, and grace to your neck.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Then shall you walk in your way safely, and your foot shall not stumble.</verse>
  <verse number="24">When you lie down, you shall not be afraid: yes, you shall lie down, and your sleep shall be sweet.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Be not afraid of sudden fear, neither of the desolation of the wicked, when it comes.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For the LORD shall be your confidence, and shall keep your foot from being taken.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Withhold not good from them to whom it is due, when it is in the power of your hand to do it.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Say not to your neighbor, Go, and come again, and to morrow I will give; when you have it by you.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Devise not evil against your neighbor, seeing he dwells securely by you.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Strive not with a man without cause, if he have done you no harm.</verse>
  <verse number="31">Envy you not the oppressor, and choose none of his ways.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For the fraudulent is abomination to the LORD: but his secret is with the righteous.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The curse of the LORD is in the house of the wicked: but he blesses the habitation of the just.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Surely he scorns the scorners: but he gives grace to the lowly.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The wise shall inherit glory: but shame shall be the promotion of fools.</verse>
</chapter>