<chapter book="Proverbs" number="6" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">My son, if you be surety for your friend, if you have stricken your hand with a stranger,</verse>
  <verse number="2">You are snared with the words of your mouth, you are taken with the words of your mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Do this now, my son, and deliver yourself, when you are come into the hand of your friend; go, humble yourself, and make sure your friend.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Give not sleep to your eyes, nor slumber to your eyelids.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Deliver yourself as a roe from the hand of the hunter, and as a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Go to the ant, you sluggard; consider her ways, and be wise:</verse>
  <verse number="7">Which having no guide, overseer, or ruler,</verse>
  <verse number="8">Provides her meat in the summer, and gathers her food in the harvest.</verse>
  <verse number="9">How long will you sleep, O sluggard? when will you arise out of your sleep?</verse>
  <verse number="10">Yet a little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to sleep:</verse>
  <verse number="11">So shall your poverty come as one that travels, and your want as an armed man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">A naughty person, a wicked man, walks with a fraudulent mouth.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He winks with his eyes, he speaks with his feet, he teaches with his fingers;</verse>
  <verse number="14">Frowardness is in his heart, he devises mischief continually; he sows discord.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Therefore shall his calamity come suddenly; suddenly shall he be broken without remedy.</verse>
  <verse number="16">These six things does the LORD hate: yes, seven are an abomination to him:</verse>
  <verse number="17">A proud look, a lying tongue, and hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
  <verse number="18">An heart that devises wicked imaginations, feet that be swift in running to mischief,</verse>
  <verse number="19">A false witness that speaks lies, and he that sows discord among brothers.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My son, keep your father’s commandment, and forsake not the law of your mother:</verse>
  <verse number="21">Bind them continually on your heart, and tie them about your neck.</verse>
  <verse number="22">When you go, it shall lead you; when you sleep, it shall keep you; and when you wake, it shall talk with you.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For the commandment is a lamp; and the law is light; and reproofs of instruction are the way of life:</verse>
  <verse number="24">To keep you from the evil woman, from the flattery of the tongue of a strange woman.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Lust not after her beauty in your heart; neither let her take you with her eyelids.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For by means of a whorish woman a man is brought to a piece of bread: and the adulteress will hunt for the precious life.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Can a man take fire in his bosom, and his clothes not be burned?</verse>
  <verse number="28">Can one go on hot coals, and his feet not be burned?</verse>
  <verse number="29">So he that goes in to his neighbor’s wife; whoever touches her shall not be innocent.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Men do not despise a thief, if he steal to satisfy his soul when he is hungry;</verse>
  <verse number="31">But if he be found, he shall restore sevenfold; he shall give all the substance of his house.</verse>
  <verse number="32">But whoever commits adultery with a woman lacks understanding: he that does it destroys his own soul.</verse>
  <verse number="33">A wound and dishonor shall he get; and his reproach shall not be wiped away.</verse>
  <verse number="34">For jealousy is the rage of a man: therefore he will not spare in the day of vengeance.</verse>
  <verse number="35">He will not regard any ransom; neither will he rest content, though you give many gifts.</verse>
</chapter>