<chapter book="Proverbs" number="9" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Wisdom has built her house, she has hewn out her seven pillars:</verse>
  <verse number="2">She has killed her beasts; she has mingled her wine; she has also furnished her table.</verse>
  <verse number="3">She has sent forth her maidens: she cries on the highest places of the city,</verse>
  <verse number="4">Whoever is simple, let him turn in here: as for him that wants understanding, she said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="5">Come, eat of my bread, and drink of the wine which I have mingled.</verse>
  <verse number="6">Forsake the foolish, and live; and go in the way of understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He that reproves a scorner gets to himself shame: and he that rebukes a wicked man gets himself a blot.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Reprove not a scorner, lest he hate you: rebuke a wise man, and he will love you.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Give instruction to a wise man, and he will be yet wiser: teach a just man, and he will increase in learning.</verse>
  <verse number="10">The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom: and the knowledge of the holy is understanding.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For by me your days shall be multiplied, and the years of your life shall be increased.</verse>
  <verse number="12">If you be wise, you shall be wise for yourself: but if you scorn, you alone shall bear it.</verse>
  <verse number="13">A foolish woman is clamorous: she is simple, and knows nothing.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For she sits at the door of her house, on a seat in the high places of the city,</verse>
  <verse number="15">To call passengers who go right on their ways:</verse>
  <verse number="16">Whoever is simple, let him turn in here: and as for him that wants understanding, she said to him,</verse>
  <verse number="17">Stolen waters are sweet, and bread eaten in secret is pleasant.</verse>
  <verse number="18">But he knows not that the dead are there; and that her guests are in the depths of hell.</verse>
</chapter>