<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="11" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Be ye imitators of me, as I also of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And I approve you, brethren, that ye remember me in all things, and as I have delivered to you, do ye hold the traditions.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And I will you to know, that the head of every man is Christ; and the head of the woman the man; and the head of Christ God.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Every man praying or prophesying, having on the head, shames his head.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And every woman praying or prophesying with head uncovered shames her head: for it is one and the same to her having been shaved.</verse>
  <verse number="6">For if the woman is not covered, let her also be shorn: and if shameful to the woman to be shorn or shaven, let her be covered.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For truly the man ought not to have the head covered, being the image and glory of God: and the woman is the glory of the man.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For the man is not of the woman; but the woman of the man.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For also the man was not created through the woman; but the woman through the man.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Therefore the woman ought to have power upon the head for the angels.</verse>
  <verse number="11">But neither the man without the woman, nor the woman without the man, in the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For as the woman by the man, so also the man by the woman; and all things of God.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Judge in yourselves: is it suitable for a woman to pray to God uncovered?</verse>
  <verse number="14">Does not nature itself teach you, that, if a man truly have long hair, it is a dishonour to him?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And if a woman have long hair, it is a glory to her: for the hair has been given her for a cloak.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And if any one seem to be loving strife, we have no such custom, neither the churches of God.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And this announcing I approve not, that not for the better come ye together, but for the worse.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For truly first, ye coming together in the church, I hear divisions to be among you; and some part I believe.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For there must be also sects among you, that the tried might be made manifest among you.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Therefore ye coming together upon the same, it is not to eat the Lord’s supper.</verse>
  <verse number="21">For each takes his own supper in eating: and one is truly hungry, and one is intoxicated.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For, have ye not houses for eating and drinking? or despise ye the church of God, and shame them not having? What should I say to you? shall I praise you in this? I praise not.</verse>
  <verse number="23">For I received from the Lord what I also delivered to you, That the Lord Jesus, in the night which he was delivered up, took bread:</verse>
  <verse number="24">And having given thanks, he brake, and said, Take ye, eat; this is my body, broken for you: this do ye for my remembrance.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Likewise the cup also, after supping, This cup is the new covenant in my blood: this do ye, as often as ye drink, for my remembrance.</verse>
  <verse number="26">For as often as ye eat this bread, and drink this cup, ye announce the Lord’s death till he come.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Therefore whoever should eat this bread, and drink the cup of the Lord, unworthily, shall be liable to the penalty of the body and blood of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And let a man try himself, and so eat of the bread, and drink of the cup.</verse>
  <verse number="29">For he eating and drinking unworthily, eats and drinks judgment to himself, not discerning the Lord’s body.</verse>
  <verse number="30">For this many among you weak and sick, and enough are asleep.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For if we examined ourselves, we should not be judged.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And being judged, we are corrected of the Lord, lest we be condemned with the world.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Therefore, my brethren, coming together to eat, succeed one another.</verse>
  <verse number="34">And if any hunger, let him eat in the house; lest ye come together for judgment. And the rest when I come I will regulate.</verse>
</chapter>