<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="14" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Pursue love, and be emulous of spiritual things, and rather that ye might prophesy.</verse>
  <verse number="2">For he speaking in a tongue speaks not to men, but to God: (for none hears; and in the spirit he speaks mysteries.)</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he prophesying speaks to men for building the house, and entreaty, and encouragement.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And he speaking in a tongue builds himself; and he prophesying builds the church.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And I will ye all to speak with tongues, and rather that ye prophesy; for greater he prophesying, than he speaking with tongues, unless he interpret accurately, that the church receive building up.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And now, brethren, if I come to you speaking with tongues, what shall I profit you, except I speak to you either in revelation, or in knowledge, or in prophecy, or in teaching?</verse>
  <verse number="7">As inanimate things giving a voice, whether pipe or harp, if it give not a distinction to sounds, how shall the piping or harping be known?</verse>
  <verse number="8">For also if the trumpet give an uncertain voice, who shall prepare himself for war?</verse>
  <verse number="9">So also ye, except by the tongue ye give an evident word, how shall the speaking be known? for ye shall be speaking into the air.</verse>
  <verse number="10">If perchance, such kind of voices be in the world, and none of them speechless.</verse>
  <verse number="11">If therefore I know not the power of the voice, I shall be to him speaking a foreigner, and he speaking a foreigner to me.</verse>
  <verse number="12">So also ye, since ye are zealous of spirits, for the building up of the church seek that ye may abound.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore he speaking in a tongue, let, him pray that he might interpret.</verse>
  <verse number="14">For if I pray in a tongue, my spirit prays, and my mind is unfruitful.</verse>
  <verse number="15">What therefore is it? I will pray with the spirit, and I will pray also with the mind: I will play on the harp in the spirit, and I will play also on the harp in the mind.</verse>
  <verse number="16">When if thou praise in the spirit, how shall he filling the place of the private individual say Amen at thy thanksgiving) since he knows not what thou sayest.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For thou truly givest thanks well, but the other is not built up.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I thank my God, speaking in tongues more than you all:</verse>
  <verse number="19">But in the church, I will to speak five words by my mind, that I might also sound in the ears of others, than ten thousand words in a tongue.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Brethren, be not children in reflection: but in wickedness act like children, and in reflection be ye perfected.</verse>
  <verse number="21">It has been written in the law, That in other tongues and in other lips will I speak to this people; and not so will they hear me, says the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="22">So that tongues are for a sign, not to the believing, but to the unbelieving: and the gift of prophecy, not to the unbelieving, but to the believing.</verse>
  <verse number="23">If therefore the whole church come together upon the same, and all speak with tongues, and the private individual, or unbelieving, come in, will they not say that ye are enraged?</verse>
  <verse number="24">And If all prophesy, and any unbelieving, or ignorant private individual come in, he is refuted by all, he is examined by all:</verse>
  <verse number="25">And so the hidden things of his heart are made manifest; and so having fallen upon the face, he will worship God, proclaiming that God is truly with you.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Therefore, what is it brethren when ye come together, every one of you has a Psalms, has teaching, has a tongue, has a revelation, has an interpretatior. Let all things be for the building of the house.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Whether any speak in a tongue, by two, or the most by three, and in part; and let one interpret.</verse>
  <verse number="28">And if there be no interpreter, let him be silent in the church; and let him speak to himself, and to God.</verse>
  <verse number="29">And let the prophets speak two or three, and let others decide.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And if to another sitting by it be revealed, let the first be silent.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For ye are all able to prophesy one by one, that all might learn, and all might be encouraged.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And the spirits of the prophets are subjected to the prophets.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For God is not of unsteadiness, but of peace, as in all the churches of the holy ones.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Let your women be silent in the churches: for it has not been committed to them to speak; but to be subjected, as also says the law.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And if they will learn anything, let them ask their own husbands in the house; for it is shameful for women to speak in the church.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Or came out the word of God from you or did it arrive to you only?</verse>
  <verse number="37">If any think to be a prophet, or spiritual, let him observe what I write to you, that they are the commands of the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="38">And if any is ignorant, let him be ignorant.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Therefore, brethren, be zealous to prophesy, and hinder not to speak in tongues.</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let all things be becomingly and according to order.</verse>
</chapter>