<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="3" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I, brethren, was not able to speak to you as spiritual, but as carnal, as babes in Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="2">I have given you milk to drink, and not food; for ye were not able, but neither now are ye yet able.</verse>
  <verse number="3">For yet are ye carnal: for wherefore envy in you, and strife, and divisions, are ye not carnal, and walk according to man?</verse>
  <verse number="4">For when a certain one should say, I truly am of Paul; and another, I of Apollos; are ye not carnal?</verse>
  <verse number="5">Who then is Paul, and who Apollos, but servants by whom ye believed, and to each as the Lord gave?</verse>
  <verse number="6">I have planted, Apollos watered; but God increased.</verse>
  <verse number="7">So that neither he planting is anything, neither he watering; but God increasing.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And he planting and he watering are one: and each shall receive his own reward according to his own labor.</verse>
  <verse number="9">For we are workers together with God: the agriculture of God, ye are the building of God.</verse>
  <verse number="10">According to the grace of God given to me, as a wise chief-architect, I have laid the foundation, and another builds upon. And let each see how he builds upon.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For none is able to lay another foundation above that laid, which is Jesus the Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And if any one build upon this foundation gold, silver, precious stones, wood, grass, stalks;</verse>
  <verse number="13">The work of each shall be manifested: for the day shall manifest, for in fire it is revealed; and the work of each, what sort it is, the fire shall prove.</verse>
  <verse number="14">If the work of any shall remain which he built upon, he shall receive a reward.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If the work of any one shall be burned, he shall be caused damage: and he shall be saved; and so as by fire.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and the spirit of God dwells in you?</verse>
  <verse number="17">If any one destroy the temple of God, him will God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which ye are.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Let none completely deceive himself. If any think to be wise in this life, let him be foolish, that he may he wise.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For the wisdom of this world is foolishness with God. For it has been written, He seizing the wise in their deceptions.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And again, The Lord knows the reasonings of the wise, that they are vain.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Therefore let none boast in men. For all things are yours;</verse>
  <verse number="22">Whether Paul, or Apollos, or Cephas, or the world, or life, or death, or things present, or about to be; all are yours;</verse>
  <verse number="23">And ye of Christ; and Christ of God.</verse>
</chapter>