<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">I am the man that has seen affliction by the rod of his wrath.</verse>
  <verse number="2">He has led me and caused me to walk in darkness, and not in light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Surely against me he turns his hand again and again all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="4">My flesh and my skin has he made old; he has broken my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">He has built against me, and surrounded me with gall and travail.</verse>
  <verse number="6">He has made me to dwell in dark places, as those that have been long dead.</verse>
  <verse number="7">He has walled me about, that I can’t go forth; he has made my chain heavy.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Yes, when I cry, and call for help, he shuts out my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">He has walled up my ways with cut stone; he has made my paths crooked.</verse>
  <verse number="10">He is to me as a bear lying in wait, as a lion in secret places.</verse>
  <verse number="11">He has turned aside my ways, and pulled me in pieces; he has made me desolate.</verse>
  <verse number="12">He has bent his bow, and set me as a mark for the arrow.</verse>
  <verse number="13">He has caused the shafts of his quiver to enter into my kidneys.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I am become a derision to all my people, and their song all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="15">He has filled me with bitterness, he has sated me with wormwood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">He has also broken my teeth with gravel stones; he has covered me with ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">You have removed my soul far off from peace; I forgot prosperity.</verse>
  <verse number="18">I said, My strength is perished, and my expectation from Yahweh.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Remember my affliction and my misery, the wormwood and the gall.</verse>
  <verse number="20">My soul still remembers them, and is bowed down within me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">This I recall to my mind; therefore have I hope.</verse>
  <verse number="22">It is because of Yahweh’s loving kindnesses that we are not consumed, because his compassion doesn’t fail.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Yahweh is my portion, says my soul; therefore will I hope in him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Yahweh is good to those who wait for him, to the soul that seeks him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">It is good that a man should hope and quietly wait for the salvation of Yahweh.</verse>
  <verse number="27">It is good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Let him sit alone and keep silence, because he has laid it on him.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Let him put his mouth in the dust, if so be there may be hope.</verse>
  <verse number="30">Let him give his cheek to him who strikes him; let him be filled full with reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="31">For the Lord will not cast off forever.</verse>
  <verse number="32">For though he cause grief, yet he will have compassion according to the multitude of his loving kindnesses.</verse>
  <verse number="33">For he does not afflict willingly, nor grieve the children of men.</verse>
  <verse number="34">To crush under foot all the prisoners of the earth,</verse>
  <verse number="35">To turn aside the right of a man before the face of the Most High,</verse>
  <verse number="36">To subvert a man in his cause, the Lord doesn’t approve.</verse>
  <verse number="37">Who is he who says, and it comes to pass, when the Lord doesn’t command it?</verse>
  <verse number="38">Doesn’t evil and good come out of the mouth of the Most High?</verse>
  <verse number="39">Why does a living man complain, a man for the punishment of his sins?</verse>
  <verse number="40">Let us search and try our ways, and turn again to Yahweh.</verse>
  <verse number="41">Let us lift up our heart with our hands to God in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="42">We have transgressed and have rebelled; you have not pardoned.</verse>
  <verse number="43">You have covered with anger and pursued us; you have killed, you have not pitied.</verse>
  <verse number="44">You have covered yourself with a cloud, so that no prayer can pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">You have made us an off-scouring and refuse in the midst of the peoples.</verse>
  <verse number="46">All our enemies have opened their mouth wide against us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">Fear and the pit have come on us, devastation and destruction.</verse>
  <verse number="48">My eye runs down with streams of water, for the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">My eye pours down, and doesn’t cease, without any intermission,</verse>
  <verse number="50">Until Yahweh look down, and see from heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="51">My eye affects my soul, because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">They have chased me relentlessly like a bird, those who are my enemies without cause.</verse>
  <verse number="53">They have cut off my life in the dungeon, and have cast a stone on me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">Waters flowed over my head; I said, I am cut off.</verse>
  <verse number="55">I called on your name, Yahweh, out of the lowest dungeon.</verse>
  <verse number="56">You heard my voice; don’t hide your ear at my breathing, at my cry.</verse>
  <verse number="57">You drew near in the day that I called on you; you said, Don’t be afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="58">Lord, you have pleaded the causes of my soul; you have redeemed my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">Yahweh, you have seen my wrong. Judge my cause.</verse>
  <verse number="60">You have seen all their vengeance and all their devices against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">You have heard their reproach, Yahweh, and all their devices against me,</verse>
  <verse number="62">The lips of those that rose up against me, and their device against me all the day.</verse>
  <verse number="63">You see their sitting down, and their rising up; I am their song.</verse>
  <verse number="64">You will render to them a recompense, Yahweh, according to the work of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="65">You will give them hardness of heart, your curse to them.</verse>
  <verse number="66">You will pursue them in anger, and destroy them from under the heavens of Yahweh.</verse>
</chapter>