<chapter book="Lamentations" number="5" translation="World English Bible" translationID="web" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Remember, Yahweh, what has come on us: Look, and see our reproach.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Our inheritance is turned to strangers, Our houses to aliens.</verse>
  <verse number="3">We are orphans and fatherless; Our mothers are as widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">We have drunken our water for money; Our wood is sold to us.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Our pursuers are on our necks: We are weary, and have no rest.</verse>
  <verse number="6">We have given the hand to the Egyptians, To the Assyrians, to be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Our fathers sinned, and are no more; We have borne their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Servants rule over us: There is none to deliver us out of their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">We get our bread at the peril of our lives, Because of the sword of the wilderness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Our skin is black like an oven, Because of the burning heat of famine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They ravished the women in Zion, The virgins in the cities of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Princes were hanged up by their hand: The faces of elders were not honored.</verse>
  <verse number="13">The young men bare the mill; The children stumbled under the wood.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The elders have ceased from the gate, The young men from their music.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The joy of our heart is ceased; Our dance is turned into mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The crown is fallen from our head: Woe to us! for we have sinned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">For this our heart is faint; For these things our eyes are dim;</verse>
  <verse number="18">For the mountain of Zion, which is desolate: The foxes walk on it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">You, Yahweh, remain forever; Your throne is from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why do you forget us forever, And forsake us so long time?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Turn us to yourself, Yahweh, and we shall be turned. Renew our days as of old.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But you have utterly rejected us; You are very angry against us.</verse>
</chapter>