<chapter book="Mark" number="10" translation="English Revised Version" translationID="erv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And he arose from thence, and cometh into the borders of Judaea and beyond Jordan: and multitudes come together unto him again; and, as he was wont, he taught them again.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And there came unto him Pharisees, and asked him, Is it lawful for a man to put away his wife? tempting him.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And he answered and said unto them, What did Moses command you?</verse>
  <verse number="4">And they said, Moses suffered to write a bill of divorcement, and to put her away.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But Jesus said unto them, For your hardness of heart he wrote you this commandment.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But from the beginning of the creation, Male and female made he them.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and shall cleave to his wife;</verse>
  <verse number="8">and the twain shall become one flesh: so that they are no more twain, but one flesh.</verse>
  <verse number="9">What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And in the house the disciples asked him again of this matter.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And he saith unto them, Whosoever shall put away his wife, and marry another, committeth adultery against her:</verse>
  <verse number="12">and if she herself shall put away her husband, and marry another, she committeth adultery.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they brought unto him little children, that he should touch them: and the disciples rebuked them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">But when Jesus saw it, he was moved with indignation, and said unto them, Suffer the little children to come unto me; forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Verily I say unto you, Whosoever shall not receive the kingdom of God as a little child, he shall in no wise enter therein.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he took them in his arms, and blessed them, laying his hands upon them.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And as he was going forth into the way, there ran one to him, and kneeled to him, and asked him, Good Master, what shall I do that I may inherit eternal life?</verse>
  <verse number="18">And Jesus said unto him, Why callest thou me good? none is good save one, even God.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Thou knowest the commandments, Do not kill, Do not commit adultery, Do not steal, Do not bear false witness, Do not defraud, Honour thy father and mother.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he said unto him, Master, all these things have I observed from my youth.</verse>
  <verse number="21">And Jesus looking upon him loved him, and said unto him, One thing thou lackest: go, sell whatsoever thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come, follow me.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But his countenance fell at the saying, and he went away sorrowful: for he was one that had great possessions.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And Jesus looked round about, and saith unto his disciples, How hardly shall they that have riches enter into the kingdom of God!</verse>
  <verse number="24">And the disciples were amazed at his words. But Jesus answereth again, and saith unto them, Children, how hard is it for them that trust in riches to enter into the kingdom of God!</verse>
  <verse number="25">It is easier for a camel to go through a needle’s eye, than for a rich man to enter into the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And they were astonished exceedingly, saying unto him, Then who can be saved?</verse>
  <verse number="27">Jesus looking upon them saith, With men it is impossible, but not with God: for all things are possible with God.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Peter began to say unto him, Lo, we have left all, and have followed thee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Jesus said, Verily I say unto you, There is no man that hath left house, or brethren, or sisters, or mother, or father, or children, or lands, for my sake, and for the gospel’s sake,</verse>
  <verse number="30">but he shall receive a hundredfold now in this time, houses, and brethren, and sisters, and mothers, and children, and lands, with persecutions; and in the world to come eternal life.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But many that are first shall be last; and the last first.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they were in the way, going up to Jerusalem; and Jesus was going before them: and they were amazed; and they that followed were afraid. And he took again the twelve, and began to tell them the things that were to happen unto him,</verse>
  <verse number="33">saying, Behold, we go up to Jerusalem; and the Son of man shall be delivered unto the chief priests and the scribes; and they shall condemn him to death, and shall deliver him unto the Gentiles:</verse>
  <verse number="34">and they shall mock him, and shall spit upon him, and shall scourge him, and shall kill him; and after three days he shall rise again.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And there come near unto him James and John, the sons of Zebedee, saying unto him, Master, we would that thou shouldest do for us whatsoever we shall ask of thee.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And he said unto them, What would ye that I should do for you?</verse>
  <verse number="37">And they said unto him, Grant unto us that we may sit, one on thy right hand, and one on thy left hand, in thy glory.</verse>
  <verse number="38">But Jesus said unto them, Ye know not what ye ask. Are ye able to drink the cup that I drink? or to be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?</verse>
  <verse number="39">And they said unto him, We are able. And Jesus said unto them, The cup that I drink ye shall drink; and with the baptism that I am baptized withal shall ye be baptized:</verse>
  <verse number="40">but to sit on my right hand or on my left hand is not mine to give: but it is for them for whom it hath been prepared.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And when the ten heard it, they began to be moved with indignation concerning James and John.</verse>
  <verse number="42">And Jesus called them to him, and saith unto them, Ye know that they which are accounted to rule over the Gentiles lord it over them; and their great ones exercise authority over them.</verse>
  <verse number="43">But it is not so among you: but whosoever would become great among you, shall be your minister:</verse>
  <verse number="44">and whosoever would be first among you, shall be servant of all.</verse>
  <verse number="45">For verily the Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister, and to give his life a ransom for many.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And they come to Jericho: and as he went out from Jericho, with his disciples and a great multitude, the son of Timaeus, Bartimaeus, a blind beggar, was sitting by the way side.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out, and say, Jesus, thou son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And many rebuked him, that he should hold his peace: but he cried out the more a great deal, Thou son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
  <verse number="49">And Jesus stood still, and said, Call ye him. And they call the blind man, saying unto him, Be of good cheer: rise, he calleth thee.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And he, casting away his garment, sprang up, and came to Jesus.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And Jesus answered him, and said, What wilt thou that I should do unto thee? And the blind man said unto him, Rabboni, that I may receive my sight.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And Jesus said unto him, Go thy way; thy faith hath made thee whole. And straightway he received his sight, and followed him in the way.</verse>
</chapter>