<chapter book="2 Corinthians" number="6" translation="American King James Version" translationID="akjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">We then, as workers together with him, beseech you also that you receive not the grace of God in vain.</verse>
  <verse number="2">(For he said, I have heard you in a time accepted, and in the day of salvation have I succored you: behold, now is the accepted time; behold, now is the day of salvation.)</verse>
  <verse number="3">Giving no offense in any thing, that the ministry be not blamed:</verse>
  <verse number="4">But in all things approving ourselves as the ministers of God, in much patience, in afflictions, in necessities, in distresses,</verse>
  <verse number="5">In stripes, in imprisonments, in tumults, in labors, in watchings, in fastings;</verse>
  <verse number="6">By pureness, by knowledge, by long-suffering, by kindness, by the Holy Ghost, by love unfeigned,</verse>
  <verse number="7">By the word of truth, by the power of God, by the armor of righteousness on the right hand and on the left,</verse>
  <verse number="8">By honor and dishonor, by evil report and good report: as deceivers, and yet true;</verse>
  <verse number="9">As unknown, and yet well known; as dying, and, behold, we live; as chastened, and not killed;</verse>
  <verse number="10">As sorrowful, yet always rejoicing; as poor, yet making many rich; as having nothing, and yet possessing all things.</verse>
  <verse number="11">O you Corinthians, our mouth is open to you, our heart is enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="12">You are not straitened in us, but you are straitened in your own bowels.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Now for a recompense in the same, (I speak as to my children,) be you also enlarged.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Be you not unequally yoked together with unbelievers: for what fellowship has righteousness with unrighteousness? and what communion has light with darkness?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And what concord has Christ with Belial? or what part has he that believes with an infidel?</verse>
  <verse number="16">And what agreement has the temple of God with idols? for you are the temple of the living God; as God has said, I will dwell in them, and walk in them; and I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Why come out from among them, and be you separate, said the Lord, and touch not the unclean thing; and I will receive you.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And will be a Father to you, and you shall be my sons and daughters, said the Lord Almighty.</verse>
</chapter>