<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="8" translation="Darby Bible Translation" translationID="dbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">But concerning things sacrificed to idols, we know, (for we all have knowledge: knowledge puffs up, but love edifies.</verse>
  <verse number="2">If any one think he knows anything, he knows nothing yet as he ought to know [it].</verse>
  <verse number="3">But if any one love God, he is known of him):</verse>
  <verse number="4">—concerning then the eating of things sacrificed to idols, we know that an idol [is] nothing in [the] world, and that there [is] no other God save one.</verse>
  <verse number="5">For and if indeed there are [those] called gods, whether in heaven or on earth, (as there are gods many, and lords many,)</verse>
  <verse number="6">yet to us [there is] one God, the Father, of whom all things, and we for him; and one Lord, Jesus Christ, by whom [are] all things, and we by him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But knowledge [is] not in all: but some, with conscience of the idol, until now eat as of a thing sacrificed to idols; and their conscience, being weak, is defiled.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But meat does not commend us to God; neither if we should not eat do we come short; nor if we should eat have we an advantage.</verse>
  <verse number="9">But see lest anywise this your right [to eat] itself be a stumbling-block to the weak.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For if any one see thee, who hast knowledge, sitting at table in an idol-house, shall not his conscience, he being weak, be emboldened to eat the things sacrificed to the idol?</verse>
  <verse number="11">and the weak [one], the brother for whose sake Christ died, will perish through thy knowledge.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Now, thus sinning against the brethren, and wounding their weak conscience, ye sin against Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Wherefore if meat be a fall-trap to my brother, I will eat no flesh for ever, that I may not be a fall-trap to my brother.</verse>
</chapter>