<chapter book="Mark" number="14" translation="Webster Bible Translation" translationID="wbt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">After two days was the feast of the passover, and of unleavened bread: and the chief priests, and the scribes, sought how they might take him by craft, and put him to death.</verse>
  <verse number="2">But they said, Not on the feast-day, lest there should be an uproar of the people.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And being in Bethany, in the house of Simon the leper, as he sat at table, there came a woman having an alabaster box of ointment of spikenard, very precious; and she broke the box, and poured it on his head.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And there were some that had indignation within themselves, and said, Why was this waste of the ointment made?</verse>
  <verse number="5">For it might have been sold for more than three hundred pence, and have been given to the poor. And they murmured against her.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And Jesus said, Let her alone; why trouble ye her? she hath wrought a good work on me.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For ye have the poor with you always, and whenever ye will ye may do them good: but me ye have not always.</verse>
  <verse number="8">She hath done what she could: she is come beforehand to anoint my body to the burying.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Verily I say to you, Wherever this gospel shall be preached throughout the whole world, this also that she hath done shall be spoken of, for a memorial of her.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And Judas Iscariot, one of the twelve, went to the chief priests, to betray him to them.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And when they heard it, they were glad, and promised to give him money. And he sought how he might conveniently betray him.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And the first day of unleavened bread, when they killed the passover, his disciples said to him, Where wilt thou that we go and prepare, that thou mayest eat the passover?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And he sendeth two of his disciples, and saith to them, Go ye into the city, and there shall meet you a man bearing a pitcher of water: follow him.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And wherever he shall go in, say ye to the master of the house, The Master saith, Where is the guest-chamber, where I may eat the passover with my disciples?</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he will show you a large upper room furnished and prepared: there make ready for us.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And his disciples went, and came into the city, and found as he had said to them: and they made ready the passover.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And in the evening he cometh with the twelve.</verse>
  <verse number="18">And as they sat, and were eating, Jesus said, Verily I say to you, One of you who eateth with me, will betray me.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And they began to be sorrowful, and to say to him one by one, Is it I? and another said, Is it I?</verse>
  <verse number="20">And he answered and said to them, It is one of the twelve that dippeth with me in the dish.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The Son of man indeed goeth, as it is written concerning him: but woe to that man by whom the Son of man is betrayed! good were it for that man if he had never been born.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And as they were eating, Jesus took bread, and blessed, and broke it, and gave to them, and said, Take, eat: this is my body.</verse>
  <verse number="23">And he took the cup, and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them: and they all drank of it.</verse>
  <verse number="24">And he said to them, This is my blood of the new testament, which is shed for many.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Verily I say to you, I will drink no more of the fruit of the vine, until that day that I drink it new in the kingdom of God.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And when they had sung a hymn, they went out to the mount of Olives.</verse>
  <verse number="27">And Jesus saith to them, All ye will be offended because of me this night: for it is written, I will smite the shepherd, and the sheep shall be scattered.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But after that I am risen, I will go before you into Galilee.</verse>
  <verse number="29">But Peter said to him, Although all shall be offended, yet will not I.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And Jesus saith to him, Verily I say to thee, that this day, even in this night, before the cock shall crow twice, thou wilt deny me thrice.</verse>
  <verse number="31">But he spoke the more vehemently, If I should die with thee, I will not deny thee in any wise. Likewise also said they all.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And they came to a place which was named Gethsemane: and he saith to his disciples, Sit ye here, while I shall pray.</verse>
  <verse number="33">And he taketh with him Peter, and James, and John, and began to be greatly amazed, and to be very heavy;</verse>
  <verse number="34">And saith to them, My soul is exceeding sorrowful to death: tarry ye here, and watch.</verse>
  <verse number="35">And he went forward a little, and fell on the ground, and prayed that, If it were possible, the hour might pass from him.</verse>
  <verse number="36">And he said, Abba, Father, all things are possible to thee; take away this cup from me: nevertheless, not what I will, but what thou wilt.</verse>
  <verse number="37">And he cometh, and findeth them sleeping, and saith to Peter, Simon, sleepest thou? couldst not thou watch one hour?</verse>
  <verse number="38">Watch ye and pray, lest ye enter into temptation. The spirit truly is ready, but the flesh is weak.</verse>
  <verse number="39">And again he went away, and prayed, and spoke the same words.</verse>
  <verse number="40">And when he returned, he found them asleep again (for their eyes were heavy:) neither knew they what to answer him.</verse>
  <verse number="41">And he cometh the third time, and saith to them, Sleep on now, and take your rest: it is enough, the hour is come; behold, the Son of man is betrayed into the hands of sinners.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Rise, let us go; lo, he that betrayeth me is at hand.</verse>
  <verse number="43">And immediately while he was yet speaking, cometh Judas, one of the twelve, and with him a great multitude with swords and staffs, from the chief priests, and the scribes, and the elders.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And he that betrayed him, had given them a token, saying, Whomsoever I shall kiss, that same is he; take him, and lead him away safely.</verse>
  <verse number="45">And as soon as he was come, he goeth immediately to him, and saith, Master, master; and kissed him.</verse>
  <verse number="46">And they laid their hands on him, and took him.</verse>
  <verse number="47">And one of them that stood by drew a sword, and smote a servant of the high priest, and cut off his ear.</verse>
  <verse number="48">And Jesus answered and said to them, Have ye come out, as against a thief, with swords and with staffs to take me?</verse>
  <verse number="49">I was daily with you in the temple, teaching, and ye took me not: but the scriptures must be fulfilled.</verse>
  <verse number="50">And they all forsook him, and fled.</verse>
  <verse number="51">And there followed him a certain young man, having a linen cloth cast about his naked body; and the young men laid hold on him.</verse>
  <verse number="52">And he left the linen cloth, and fled from them naked.</verse>
  <verse number="53">And they led Jesus away to the high priest: and with him were assembled all the chief priests, and the elders and the scribes.</verse>
  <verse number="54">And Peter followed him at a distance, even into the palace of the high priest: and he sat with the servants, and warmed himself at the fire.</verse>
  <verse number="55">And the chief priests, and all the council sought for testimony against Jesus to put him to death; and found none.</verse>
  <verse number="56">For many bore false testimony against him, but their testimony agreed not together.</verse>
  <verse number="57">And there arose certain, and bore false testimony against him, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="58">We heard him say, I will destroy this temple that is made with hands, and within three days I will build another made without hands.</verse>
  <verse number="59">But neither so did their testimony agree together.</verse>
  <verse number="60">And the high priest stood up in the midst, and asked Jesus, saying, Answerest thou nothing? what is it which these testify against thee?</verse>
  <verse number="61">But he held his peace, and answered nothing. Again the high priest asked him, and said to him, Art thou the Christ, the Son of the Blessed?</verse>
  <verse number="62">And Jesus said, I am: and ye shall see the Son of man sitting on the right hand of power, and coming in the clouds of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="63">Then the high priest rent his clothes, and saith, What need we any further witnesses?</verse>
  <verse number="64">Ye have heard the blasphemy: what think ye? And they all condemned him to be guilty of death.</verse>
  <verse number="65">And some began to spit on him, and to cover his face, and to buffet him, and to say to him, Prophesy: and the servants struck him with the palms of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="66">And as Peter was below in the palace, there cometh one of the maids of the high priest:</verse>
  <verse number="67">And when she saw Peter warming himself, she looked upon him, and said, And thou also wast with Jesus of Nazareth.</verse>
  <verse number="68">But he denied, saying, I know not, neither do I understand what thou sayest. And he went out into the porch; and the cock crowed.</verse>
  <verse number="69">And a maid saw him again, and began to say to them that stood by, This is one of them.</verse>
  <verse number="70">And he denied it again. And a little after, they that stood by said again to Peter, Surely thou art one of them: for thou art a Galilean, and thy speech agreeth thereto.</verse>
  <verse number="71">But he began to curse and to swear, saying, I know not this man of whom ye speak.</verse>
  <verse number="72">And the second time the cock crowed. And Peter called to mind the word that Jesus said to him, Before the cock shall crow twice, thou wilt deny me thrice. And when he thought thereon, he wept.</verse>
</chapter>