<chapter book="Galatians" number="1" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Paul, an apostle—sent not from men nor by man, but by Jesus Christ and God the Father, who raised Him from the dead—</verse>
  <verse number="2">and all the brothers with me, To the churches of Galatia:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Grace and peace to you from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
  <verse number="4">who gave Himself for our sins to rescue us from the present evil age, according to the will of our God and Father,</verse>
  <verse number="5">to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen.</verse>
  <verse number="6">I am amazed how quickly you are deserting the One who called you by the grace of Christ and are turning to a different gospel—</verse>
  <verse number="7">which is not even a gospel. Evidently some people are troubling you and trying to distort the gospel of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But even if we or an angel from heaven should preach a gospel contrary to the one we preached to you, let him be under a curse!</verse>
  <verse number="9">As we have said before, so now I say again: If anyone is preaching to you a gospel contrary to the one you received, let him be under a curse!</verse>
  <verse number="10">Am I now seeking the approval of men, or of God? Or am I striving to please men? If I were still trying to please men, I would not be a servant of Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="11">For I want you to know, brothers, that the gospel I preached was not devised by man.</verse>
  <verse number="12">I did not receive it from any man, nor was I taught it; rather, I received it by revelation from Jesus Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For you have heard of my former way of life in Judaism, how severely I persecuted the church of God and tried to destroy it.</verse>
  <verse number="14">I was advancing in Judaism beyond many of my contemporaries and was extremely zealous for the traditions of my fathers.</verse>
  <verse number="15">But when God, who set me apart from my mother’s womb and called me by His grace, was pleased</verse>
  <verse number="16">to reveal His Son in me so that I might preach Him among the Gentiles, I did not rush to consult with flesh and blood,</verse>
  <verse number="17">nor did I go up to Jerusalem to the apostles who came before me, but I went into Arabia and later returned to Damascus.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Only after three years did I go up to Jerusalem to confer with Cephas, and I stayed with him fifteen days.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But I saw none of the other apostles except James, the Lord’s brother.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I assure you before God that what I am writing to you is no lie.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Later I went to the regions of Syria and Cilicia.</verse>
  <verse number="22">I was personally unknown, however, to the churches of Judea that are in Christ.</verse>
  <verse number="23">They only heard the account: “The man who formerly persecuted us is now preaching the faith he once tried to destroy.”</verse>
  <verse number="24">And they glorified God because of me.</verse>
</chapter>