<chapter book="Ezekiel" number="10" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And I shall see, and behold, to the which is over the head of the cherubs, as a stone of sapphire, as the vision of the likeness of a throne was seen over them.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And he will say to the man clothed with linen, and he will say, Go in between the wheel, underneath to the cherub, and fill thy fists with coals of fire from between the cherubs, and scatter over the city. And he will go in before mine eyes.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And the cherubs standing from the right to the house, in his going in, the man; and the cloud filled in the inner enclosure.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And the glory of Jehovah will rise from off the cherub over the threshold of the house, and the house will be filled with the cloud, and the enclosure was filled with the shining of the glory of Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And the voice of the wings of the cherubs was heard, even to the enclosure without, as the voice to the Almighty in his speaking.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And it will be in his commanding the man clothed with linen, saying, Take the fire from between the wheel from between the cherubs; and he will go in and stand by the wheel.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the cherub will stretch forth his hand from between the cherubs to the fire which is between the cherubs, and he will lift up and will give into the fists of him clothed with linen: and he will take and he went forth.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And there will be seen to the cherubs the form of a man’s hand under their wings.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And I shall see, and behold, the four wheels by the cherubs, one wheel by the one cherub, and one wheel by the one cherub: and the vision of the wheels as the eye of a stone of topaz.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And their appearances one likeness to them four, as the wheel will be in the midst of the wheel.</verse>
  <verse number="11">In their going, upon their four sides they will go; they will not turn in their going, for to the place where the head will turn after it will they go; they will not turn in their going.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And all their flesh, and their back, and their hands, and their wings, and the wheels being filled with eyes round about, the wheels to them four.</verse>
  <verse number="13">To the wheels to them was called, Gilgal! in mine ears.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And four faces to the one: the one face the face of the cherub, and the second face the face of a man, and the third, the face of a lion, and the fourth, the face of an eagle.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the cherubs will be lifted up. This the living creature which I saw by the river Chebar.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And in the going of the cherubs, the wheels by them will go: and in the lifting up of the cherubs their wings to rise up from the earth, the wheels they also from beside them will not turn.</verse>
  <verse number="17">In their standing, they will stand: and in their rising, they will rise with them: for the spirit of life was in them:</verse>
  <verse number="18">And the glory of Jehovah went forth from off the threshold of the house, and it will stand over the cherubs.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And the cherubs will lift up their wings, and will rise from the earth before mine eyes: in their going forth and the wheels with them, and they will stand at the door of the eastern gate of the house of Jehovah; and the glory of the God of Israel over them from above.</verse>
  <verse number="20">This the living creature I saw under the God of Israel by the river Chebar; and I shall know that they are the cherubs.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Four, four faces to the one, and four wings to the one; and the likeness of the hands of a man under their wings.</verse>
  <verse number="22">And the likeness of their faces these faces which I saw upon the river Chebar, their appearance and themselves: they will go each over against his face.</verse>
</chapter>