<chapter book="Ezekiel" number="27" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the word of Jehovah will be to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Thou son of man, lift up a lamentation for Tyre;</verse>
  <verse number="3">And say to Tyre, Thou dwelling at the entrance of the sea, a traffic of the peoples for many islands, thus said the Lord Jehovah: O Tyre, thou saidst, I am perfect of beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="4">In the heart of the see thy bound; they building thee completed thy beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="5">They built all thy bounds cypress from Shenir: they took cedars from Lebanon to make a mast for thee.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The oaks of Bashan they made thine oars; the house of the Ashurites made thy desk of ivory from the isles of Chittim.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Fine linen with variegation from Egypt was thy spreading forth to be to thee for a signal; cerulean purple, and reddish purple, from the isles of Elisha was thy covering.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The inhabitants of Zidon and Arvad were rowers to thee: thy wise, O Tyre, were in thee, they thy sailors.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The old men of Gebal and her wise were in thee making strong thy breach: all the ships of the sea and thy seamen were in thee to traffic from thy traffic.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Persia and Lud and Phut were in thy strength, thy men of war: hung the shield and helmet in thee; they gave thy decoration.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The sons of Arvad and thine army upon thy walls round about, and the Gammadims were in thy towers: they hung their shields upon thy walls round about; they completed thy beauty.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Tarshish thy merchant from the multitude of all riches: in silver, iron, alloy, and lead, they gave thy markets.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Javan, Tubal and Meshech, they thy merchants: they gave from thy traffic in the soul of man, and vessels of brass.</verse>
  <verse number="14">From the house of Togarmah, horses and horsemen and mules they gave thy markets.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The sons of Dedan thy merchants; many isles the traffic of thy hand: and they brought back horns of ivory and ebony.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Aram thy merchant from the multitude of thy works: they gave in thy markets with the gem, reddish purple, and variegation, and byssus, and red corals, and ruby.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Judah and the land of Israel, they thy merchants: in wheat of Minnith and Pannag, and honey, and oil, and balsam, they gave thy traffic.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Damascus thy merchant in the multitude of thy works from the multitude of all riches, with wine of Helbon and wool of whiteness.</verse>
  <verse number="19">And Dan and Javan going away gave in thy markets: making iron, cassia and sweet cane was in thy traffic.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Dedan thy merchant, garments of spreading out for the chariot.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Arabia and all the princes of Kedar, they the merchants of thy hand with lambs and rams and he goats: in them thy merchants.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The merchants of Sheba and Raamah, they thy merchants with the head of all spicery, and with every precious stone and gold they gave thy markets.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Haran and Canneh, and Eden, the merchants of Sheba, Assur, and Chilmad, thy merchants.</verse>
  <verse number="24">They thy merchants in perfections in coverings of cerulean purple, and variegation and in treasures of variegated stuffs bound with cords and made fast in thy markets.</verse>
  <verse number="25">The ships of Tarshish celebrating thee in thy traffic; and thou wilt be filled and honored greatly in the heart of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Thy rower brought thee into many waters: the wind of the east broke thee in the heart of the seas.</verse>
  <verse number="27">Thy riches and thy markets, thy traffic, thy seamen, and thy shipmen, they making strong thy breach, and they trafficking thy traffic, and all the men of thy war that are in thee, and in all thy convocation which is in the midst of thee, they shall fall into the heart of the sea, in the day of thy fall.</verse>
  <verse number="28">At the voice of the cry of thy shipmen, the areas shall shake.</verse>
  <verse number="29">All holding the oars, the seamen and the shipmen of the sea, shall come down from their ships, they shall stand upon the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And with their voice they shall cause to be heard against thee, and they shall cry with bitterness, and they shall bring up dust upon their heads, and they shall roll themselves in ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="31">And they made themselves bald with baldness for thee, and they girded themselves with sackcloth, and they wept for thee with bitterness of soul and bitter wailing.</verse>
  <verse number="32">And their sons lifted up a lamentation for thee, and they lamented over thee: Who as Tyre, as she desolated in the midst of the sea?</verse>
  <verse number="33">In the going forth of thy markets from the seas thou didst satisfy many peoples; with the multitude of thy riches and thy traffics thou didst enrich the kings of the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="34">The time thou wert broken from the seas in the depths of the waters, thy traffic and all thy convocation fell in the midst of thee.</verse>
  <verse number="35">All the inhabitants of the isles were astonished at thee, and their kings shuddering, shuddered; the faces were moved.</verse>
  <verse number="36">The merchants among the peoples hissed at thee; thou wert terrors; and thou not, even forever.</verse>
</chapter>