<chapter book="Ezekiel" number="29" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">In the tenth year, in the tenth, in the twelfth to the month, was the word of Jehovah to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Son of man set thy face against Pharaoh king of Egypt, and prophesy against him and against all Egypt:</verse>
  <verse number="3">Speak and say, Thus said the Lord Jehovah: Behold me against thee Pharaoh, king of Egypt, the great sea monster lying in the midst of his rivers, who said, The, river is to me, and I made me.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And I gave hooks in thy jaw bones, and I glued the fishes of thy rivers upon thy scales, and I brought thee up from the midst of thy rivers, and all the Ashes of thy rivers shall be glued to thy scales.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And I cast thee to the desert, thee and all the fish of thy rivers: thou shalt fall upon the face of the field; thou shalt not be gathered, and thou shalt not be collected: I gave thee for food to the beast of the earth and to the birds of the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And all the inhabitants of Egypt shall know that I am Jehovah, because they were a support of reed to the house of Israel:</verse>
  <verse number="7">In their taking hold upon thee by the hand, thou wilt run and rend for them all the shoulder: and in their leaning upon thee, thou: wilt break, and because to them the loins to stand.</verse>
  <verse number="8">For this, thus said the Lord Jehovah: Behold me bringing the sword upon thee, and I cut off from thee man and cattle.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And the land of Egypt was for desolation and waste; and they shall know that I am Jehovah, because he said, The river is to me; I made.</verse>
  <verse number="10">For this, behold me against thee, and against thy rivers, and I gave the land of Egypt for wastes of waste, a desolation from the tower Seveneh and even to the bound of Cush.</verse>
  <verse number="11">The foot of man shall not pass through it, and the foot of cattle shall not pass through it, and it shall not be inhabited forty years.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And I gave the land of Egypt a desolation in the midst of the lands being desolate, and her, cities in the midst of the cities laid waste shall be a desolation forty years: and I scattered Egypt among the nations and I dispersed them in the lands.</verse>
  <verse number="13">For thus said the Lord Jehovah: From the end of forty years I will gather Egypt from the peoples where they were scattered there:</verse>
  <verse number="14">And I turned back the captivity of Egypt; and I caused them to turn back to the land of Paths upon the land of their nativity; and they were there a low kingdom.</verse>
  <verse number="15">It shall be lower than the kingdoms, and it shall no more be lifted up over the nations: and I made them few not to rule over the nations.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And it shall be no more to the house of Israel for trust, bringing iniquity to remembrance in their turning after them: and they shall know that am the Lord Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And it will be in the twenty and seventh year, in the first, in the one to the month, the word, of Jehovah was to me, saying,</verse>
  <verse number="18">Son of man, Nebuchadnezzar king of Babel caused his army to serve a great service against Tyre: every head being made bald, and every shoulder made smooth: and wages were not to him and to his army from Tyre for the service that he served against her.</verse>
  <verse number="19">For this, thus said the Lord Jehovah: Behold me giving to Nebuchadnezzar king of Babel, the land of Egypt; and he lifted up her multitude, and he spoiled her spoil and plundered her plunder, and it was the wages to his army.</verse>
  <verse number="20">I gave to him the land of Egypt the wages which he served against her, because they worked for me, says the Lord Jehovah.</verse>
  <verse number="21">In that day I will cause the born to the house of Israel to spring up, and to thee will I give the opening of the mouth in the midst of them; and they shall know that I am Jehovah,</verse>
</chapter>