<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="13" translation="King James Bible" translationID="kjv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And David consulted with the captains of thousands and hundreds, [and] with every leader.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And David said unto all the congregation of Israel, If [it seem] good unto you, and [that it be] of the LORD our God, let us send abroad unto our brethren every where, [that are] left in all the land of Israel, and with them [also] to the priests and Levites [which are] in their cities [and] suburbs, that they may gather themselves unto us:</verse>
  <verse number="3">And let us bring again the ark of our God to us: for we inquired not at it in the days of Saul.</verse>
  <verse number="4">And all the congregation said that they would do so: for the thing was right in the eyes of all the people.</verse>
  <verse number="5">So David gathered all Israel together, from Shihor of Egypt even unto the entering of Hemath, to bring the ark of God from Kirjathjearim.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And David went up, and all Israel, to Baalah, [that is], to Kirjathjearim, which [belonged] to Judah, to bring up thence the ark of God the LORD, that dwelleth [between] the cherubims, whose name is called [on it].</verse>
  <verse number="7">And they carried the ark of God in a new cart out of the house of Abinadab: and Uzza and Ahio drave the cart.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And David and all Israel played before God with all [their] might, and with singing, and with harps, and with psalteries, and with timbrels, and with cymbals, and with trumpets.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And when they came unto the threshingfloor of Chidon, Uzza put forth his hand to hold the ark; for the oxen stumbled.</verse>
  <verse number="10">And the anger of the LORD was kindled against Uzza, and he smote him, because he put his hand to the ark: and there he died before God.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And David was displeased, because the LORD had made a breach upon Uzza: wherefore that place is called Perezuzza to this day.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And David was afraid of God that day, saying, How shall I bring the ark of God [home] to me?</verse>
  <verse number="13">So David brought not the ark [home] to himself to the city of David, but carried it aside into the house of Obededom the Gittite.</verse>
  <verse number="14">And the ark of God remained with the family of Obededom in his house three months. And the LORD blessed the house of Obededom, and all that he had.</verse>
</chapter>