<chapter book="Ecclesiastes" number="7" translation="Young's Literal Translation" translationID="ylt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Better is a name than good perfume, And the day of death than the day of birth.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Better to go unto a house of mourning, Than to go unto a house of banqueting, For that is the end of all men, And the living layeth it unto his heart.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Better is sorrow than laughter, For by the sadness of the face the heart becometh better.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The heart of the wise is in a house of mourning, And the heart of fools in a house of mirth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">Better to hear a rebuke of a wise man, Than for a man to hear a song of fools,</verse>
  <verse number="6">For as the noise of thorns under the pot, So is the laughter of a fool, even this is vanity.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Surely oppression maketh the wise mad, And a gift destroyeth the heart.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Better is the latter end of a thing than its beginning, Better is the patient of spirit, than the haughty of spirit.</verse>
  <verse number="9">Be not hasty in thy spirit to be angry, For anger in the bosom of fools resteth.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Say not thou, ‘What was it, That the former days were better than these?’ For thou hast not asked wisely of this.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Wisdom is good with an inheritance, And an advantage it is to those beholding the sun.</verse>
  <verse number="12">For wisdom is a defense, money is a defence, And the advantage of the knowledge of wisdom is, She reviveth her possessors.</verse>
  <verse number="13">See the work of God, For who is able to make straight that which He made crooked?</verse>
  <verse number="14">In a day of prosperity be in gladness, And in a day of evil consider. Also this over-against that hath God made, To the intent that man doth not find anything after him.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The whole I have considered in the days of my vanity. There is a righteous one perishing in his righteousness, and there is a wrong-doer prolonging himself in his wrong.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Be not over-righteous, nor show thyself too wise, why art thou desolate?</verse>
  <verse number="17">Do not much wrong, neither be thou a fool, why dost thou die within thy time?</verse>
  <verse number="18">It is good that thou dost lay hold on this, and also, from that withdrawest not thy hand, for whoso is fearing God goeth out with them all.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The wisdom giveth strength to a wise man, more than wealth the rulers who have been in a city.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Because there is not a righteous man on earth that doth good and sinneth not.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Also to all the words that they speak give not thy heart, that thou hear not thy servant reviling thee.</verse>
  <verse number="22">For many times also hath thy heart known that thou thyself also hast reviled others.</verse>
  <verse number="23">All this I have tried by wisdom; I have said, ‘I am wise,’ and it is far from me.</verse>
  <verse number="24">Far off is that which hath been, and deep, deep, who doth find it?</verse>
  <verse number="25">I have turned round, also my heart, to know and to search, and to seek out wisdom, and reason, and to know the wrong of folly, and of foolishness the madness.</verse>
  <verse number="26">And I am finding more bitter than death, the woman whose heart is nets and snares, her hands are bands; the good before God escapeth from her, but the sinner is captured by her.</verse>
  <verse number="27">See, this I have found, said the Preacher, one to one, to find out the reason</verse>
  <verse number="28">(that still my soul had sought, and I had not found), One man, a teacher, I have found, and a woman among all these I have not found.</verse>
  <verse number="29">See, this alone I have found, that God made man upright, and they—they have sought out many devices.</verse>
</chapter>