<chapter book="Matthew" number="18" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">At that time the disciples came to Jesus and asked, “Who then is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?”</verse>
  <verse number="2">Jesus invited a little child to stand among them.</verse>
  <verse number="3">“Truly I tell you,” He said, “unless you change and become like little children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="4">Therefore, whoever humbles himself like this little child is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And whoever welcomes a little child like this in My name welcomes Me.</verse>
  <verse number="6">But if anyone causes one of these little ones who believe in Me to stumble, it would be better for him to have a large millstone hung around his neck and to be drowned in the depths of the sea.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Woe to the world for the causes of sin. These stumbling blocks must come, but woe to the man through whom they come!</verse>
  <verse number="8">If your hand or your foot causes you to sin, cut it off and throw it away. It is better for you to enter life crippled or lame than to have two hands and two feet and be thrown into the eternal fire.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And if your eye causes you to sin, gouge it out and throw it away. It is better for you to enter life with one eye than to have two eyes and be thrown into the fire of hell.</verse>
  <verse number="10">See that you do not look down on any of these little ones. For I tell you that their angels in heaven always see the face of My Father in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="11"></verse>
  <verse number="12">What do you think? If a man has a hundred sheep and one of them goes astray, will he not leave the ninety-nine on the hills and go out to search for the one that is lost?</verse>
  <verse number="13">And if he finds it, truly I tell you, he rejoices more over that one sheep than over the ninety-nine that did not go astray.</verse>
  <verse number="14">In the same way, your Father in heaven is not willing that any of these little ones should perish.</verse>
  <verse number="15">If your brother sins against you, go and confront him privately. If he listens to you, you have won your brother over.</verse>
  <verse number="16">But if he will not listen, take one or two others along, so that ‘every matter may be established by the testimony of two or three witnesses.’</verse>
  <verse number="17">If he refuses to listen to them, tell it to the church. And if he refuses to listen even to the church, regard him as you would a pagan or a tax collector.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Truly I tell you, whatever you bind on earth will be bound in heaven, and whatever you loose on earth will be loosed in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Again, I tell you truly that if two of you on the earth agree about anything you ask for, it will be done for you by My Father in heaven.</verse>
  <verse number="20">For where two or three gather together in My name, there am I with them.”</verse>
  <verse number="21">Then Peter came to Jesus and asked, “Lord, how many times shall I forgive my brother who sins against me? Up to seven times?”</verse>
  <verse number="22">Jesus answered, “I tell you, not just seven times, but seventy-seven times!</verse>
  <verse number="23">Because of this, the kingdom of heaven is like a king who wanted to settle accounts with his servants.</verse>
  <verse number="24">As he began the settlements, a debtor owing ten thousand talents was brought to him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Since the man was unable to pay, the master ordered that he be sold to pay his debt, along with his wife and children and everything he owned.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Then the servant fell on his knees before him. ‘Have patience with me,’ he begged, ‘and I will pay back everything.’</verse>
  <verse number="27">His master had compassion on him, forgave his debt, and released him.</verse>
  <verse number="28">But when that servant went out, he found one of his fellow servants who owed him a hundred denarii. He grabbed him and began to choke him, saying, ‘Pay back what you owe me!’</verse>
  <verse number="29">So his fellow servant fell down and begged him, ‘Have patience with me, and I will pay you back.’</verse>
  <verse number="30">But he refused. Instead, he went and had the man thrown into prison until he could pay his debt.</verse>
  <verse number="31">When his fellow servants saw what had happened, they were greatly distressed, and they went and recounted all of this to their master.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Then the master summoned him and said, ‘You wicked servant! I forgave all your debt because you begged me.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Shouldn’t you have had mercy on your fellow servant, just as I had on you?’</verse>
  <verse number="34">In anger his master turned him over to the jailers to be tortured, until he should repay all that he owed.</verse>
  <verse number="35">That is how My heavenly Father will treat each of you unless you forgive your brother from your heart.”</verse>
</chapter>