<chapter book="Mark" number="16" translation="Smith's Literal Translation" translationID="slt" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">And the sabbath having intervened, Mary Magdalene, and Mary of James, and Salome, bought spices, that having come, they might anoint him.</verse>
  <verse number="2">And very early in the morning of one of the sabbaths, they came to the tomb, the sun having risen.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And they said to themselves, Who shall roll away for us the stone from the door of the tomb?</verse>
  <verse number="4">And having looked up, they saw that the stone was rolled away: for it was very great.</verse>
  <verse number="5">And having come to the tomb, they saw a young man sitting on the right, being encompassed with a white robe; and they were terrified.</verse>
  <verse number="6">And he says to them, Be not terrified: Ye seek Jesus the Nazarene, being crucified: he was raised; he is not here: see the place where they laid him.</verse>
  <verse number="7">But retire ye; say to his disciples and to Peter that he goes before you into Galilee: there shall ye see him, as he said to you.</verse>
  <verse number="8">And having come forth quickly, they fled from the tomb; and terror and amazement held them: and they said nothing to any; for they were afraid.</verse>
  <verse number="9">And having risen early the first of the sabbath, he was manifested first to Mary Magdalene, from whom he had cast seven demons.</verse>
  <verse number="10">She having gone announced to them having been with him, grieving and weeping.</verse>
  <verse number="11">And they having heard that he lives, and was seen by her, believed not.</verse>
  <verse number="12">And after these things, to two of them, walking about, was he manifested in another form, they going into the field.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And they having come announced to the rest: neither did they believe them.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Afterwards to those reclining at table was he manifested, and he reproached their unbelief and hard heart, because they believed not them having seen him raised.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And he said to them, Having gone into all the world proclaim the good news to all creation.</verse>
  <verse number="16">And he having believed and having been immersed shall be saved; but he not having believed shall be condemned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And these signs shall follow those having believed; In my name they shall cast out demons; they shall speak with new tongues;</verse>
  <verse number="18">They shall take up serpents; and should they drink any deadly thing, it shall not hurt them; they shall put hands upon the sick, and they shall be well.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Truly therefore the Lord, after he had spoken to them, was taken up into the heavens, and sat on the right hand of God.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And they, having gone forth, proclaimed every where, the Lord performing together, and confirming the word by signs following. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>