<chapter book="Lamentations" number="3" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">ALEPH. I am a man watching my own poverty by the rod of his indignation.</verse>
  <verse number="2">ALEPH. He has driven me and led me into darkness, and not into light.</verse>
  <verse number="3">ALEPH. Against me only, he has turned and turned again his hand, all day long.</verse>
  <verse number="4">BETH. My skin and my flesh, he has made old; he has crushed my bones.</verse>
  <verse number="5">BETH. He has built all around me, and he has encircled me with gall and hardship.</verse>
  <verse number="6">BETH. He has gathered me into darkness, like those who are forever dead.</verse>
  <verse number="7">GHIMEL. He has built against me all around, so that I may not depart. He has increased the burden of my confinement.</verse>
  <verse number="8">GHIMEL. Yet even when I cry out and beg, he excludes my prayer.</verse>
  <verse number="9">GHIMEL. He has enclosed my ways with square stones; he has subverted my paths.</verse>
  <verse number="10">DALETH. He has become to me like a bear lying in ambush, like a lion in hiding.</verse>
  <verse number="11">DALETH. He has subverted my paths, and he has broken me. He has placed me in desolation.</verse>
  <verse number="12">DALETH. He has bent his bow, and he has positioned me like a target for his arrows.</verse>
  <verse number="13">HE. He has shot into my kidneys the daughters of his quiver.</verse>
  <verse number="14">HE. I have become a derision to all my people, their song throughout the day.</verse>
  <verse number="15">HE. He has filled me with bitterness; he has inebriated me with wormwood.</verse>
  <verse number="16">VAU. And he has broken each one of my teeth; he has fed me with ashes.</verse>
  <verse number="17">VAU. And my soul has been driven away from peace; I have forgotten what is good.</verse>
  <verse number="18">VAU. And I said, “My end and my hope from the Lord has perished.”</verse>
  <verse number="19">ZAIN. Remember my poverty and my transgression, the wormwood and the gall.</verse>
  <verse number="20">ZAIN. I will call to mind the past, and my soul shall languish within me.</verse>
  <verse number="21">ZAIN. These recollections are in my heart; therefore, I shall hope.</verse>
  <verse number="22">HETH. By the mercies of the Lord, we are not consumed. For his compassion has not passed away.</verse>
  <verse number="23">HETH. I know it at first light; great is your faithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="24">HETH. “The Lord is my portion,” said my soul. Because of this, I will wait for him.</verse>
  <verse number="25">TETH. The Lord is good to those who hope in him, to the soul that seeks him.</verse>
  <verse number="26">TETH. It is good to stand ready in silence for the salvation of God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">TETH. It is good for a man, when he has carried the yoke from his youth.</verse>
  <verse number="28">JOD. He shall sit solitary and silent. For he has lifted it upon himself.</verse>
  <verse number="29">JOD. He shall place his mouth in the dirt, if perhaps there may be hope.</verse>
  <verse number="30">JOD. He shall give his cheek to those who strike him; he shall be saturated with reproaches.</verse>
  <verse number="31">CAPH. For the Lord will not rebuke forever.</verse>
  <verse number="32">CAPH. For, if he has cast down, he will also have compassion, according to the multitude of his mercies.</verse>
  <verse number="33">CAPH. For he has not humiliated from his heart, nor has he thrown aside the sons of men,</verse>
  <verse number="34">LAMED. as if to crush under his feet all the prisoners of the land,</verse>
  <verse number="35">LAMED. as if to turn aside the judgment of a man in the sight of the presence of the Most High,</verse>
  <verse number="36">LAMED. as if to pervert a man in his judgment: the Lord does not do this.</verse>
  <verse number="37">MEM. Who is this, who said to do what the Lord did not command?</verse>
  <verse number="38">MEM. Does not both misfortune and good proceed from the mouth of the Most High?</verse>
  <verse number="39">MEM. Why has a living man murmured, a man suffering for his sins?</verse>
  <verse number="40">NUN. Let us examine our ways, and seek out, and return to the Lord.</verse>
  <verse number="41">NUN. Let us lift up our hearts, with our hands, toward the Lord in the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="42">NUN. We have acted sinfully, and we have provoked to wrath. About this, you are relentless.</verse>
  <verse number="43">SAMECH. You have covered us in your fury, and you have struck us. You have killed, and have not spared.</verse>
  <verse number="44">SAMECH. You have set a cloud opposite you, lest our prayer pass through.</verse>
  <verse number="45">SAMECH. In the midst of the peoples, you have uprooted me and cast me out.</verse>
  <verse number="46">PHE. All our enemies have opened their mouths over us.</verse>
  <verse number="47">PHE. Prediction has become for us a dread, and a snare, and a grief.</verse>
  <verse number="48">PHE. My eye has brought forth streams of water at the contrition of the daughter of my people.</verse>
  <verse number="49">AIN. My eye has been afflicted, and it has not been quieted, because there would be no rest</verse>
  <verse number="50">AIN. until the Lord looked down and saw from the heavens.</verse>
  <verse number="51">AIN. My eye has exhausted my soul over every one of the daughters of my city.</verse>
  <verse number="52">SADE. My enemies have chased me, and they have caught me like a bird, without reason.</verse>
  <verse number="53">SADE. My life has fallen into a pit, and they have placed a stone over me.</verse>
  <verse number="54">SADE. The waters have flooded over my head. I said, “I am lost.”</verse>
  <verse number="55">COPH. I called upon your name, O Lord, from the furthest pit.</verse>
  <verse number="56">COPH. You have heard my voice. Do not turn away your ear from my sobbing and my cries.</verse>
  <verse number="57">COPH. You drew near in the daytime, when I called upon you. You said, “Fear not.”</verse>
  <verse number="58">RES. You have judged, O Lord, the case of my soul. You are the Redeemer of my life.</verse>
  <verse number="59">RES. You have seen, O Lord, their iniquity against me. Judge my case.</verse>
  <verse number="60">RES. You have seen all their fury, every one of their thoughts is against me.</verse>
  <verse number="61">SIN. You have heard their reproach, O Lord, all their thoughts are against me.</verse>
  <verse number="62">SIN. The lips of those who rise up against me, and their meditations, are against me all day long.</verse>
  <verse number="63">SIN. Watch their sitting down and their rising up: I am their psalm.</verse>
  <verse number="64">THAU. You shall pay a recompense to them, O Lord, according to the works of their hands.</verse>
  <verse number="65">THAU. You shall give them a heavy shield of the heart: your hardship.</verse>
  <verse number="66">THAU. You shall pursue them in fury, and you shall destroy them under the heavens, O Lord.</verse>
</chapter>