<chapter book="Lamentations" number="5" translation="Catholic Public Domain Version" translationID="cpdv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Remember, O Lord, what has befallen us. Consider and look kindly upon our disgrace.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Our inheritance has been turned over to foreigners; our houses to outsiders.</verse>
  <verse number="3">We have become orphans without a father; our mothers are like widows.</verse>
  <verse number="4">We paid for our drinking water. We acquired our wood for a price.</verse>
  <verse number="5">We were dragged by our necks. Being weary, no rest was given to us.</verse>
  <verse number="6">We have given our hand to Egypt and to the Assyrians, so that we may be satisfied with bread.</verse>
  <verse number="7">Our fathers have sinned, and are not. And we have carried their iniquities.</verse>
  <verse number="8">Servants have become rulers over us. There was no one to redeem us from their hand.</verse>
  <verse number="9">We obtained our bread at the risk of our lives, before the face of the sword, in the wilderness.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Our skin was burned, as if by an oven, before the face of the tempest of the famine.</verse>
  <verse number="11">They humiliated the women in Zion and the virgins in the cities of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="12">The leaders were suspended by their hand. They were not ashamed before the faces of the elders.</verse>
  <verse number="13">They have sexually abused the adolescents, and the children were corrupted in the wood.</verse>
  <verse number="14">The elders have ceased from the gates, the youths from the choir of the psalms.</verse>
  <verse number="15">The gladness of our heart has failed, our singing has been turned into mourning.</verse>
  <verse number="16">The crown has fallen from our head. Woe to us, for we have sinned.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Because of this, our heart became gloomy; for this reason, our eyes have been darkened:</verse>
  <verse number="18">because of mount Zion, because it was ruined. Foxes have wandered upon it.</verse>
  <verse number="19">But you, O Lord, shall remain for eternity, your throne from generation to generation.</verse>
  <verse number="20">Why would you forget us forever? Why would you forsake us for a long time?</verse>
  <verse number="21">Convert us, O Lord, to you, and we shall be converted. Renew our days, as from the beginning.</verse>
  <verse number="22">But you have utterly rejected us; you are vehemently angry against us.</verse>
</chapter>