<chapter book="Judges" number="5" translation="JPS Tanakh 1917 OT" translationID="jps" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Then sang Deborah and Barak the son of Abinoam on that day, saying:</verse>
  <verse number="2">When men let grow their hair in Israel, When the people offer themselves willingly, Bless ye the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Hear, O ye kings; give ear, O ye princes; I, unto the LORD will I sing; I will sing praise to the LORD, the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="4">LORD, when Thou didst go forth out of Seir, When Thou didst march out of the field of Edom, The earth trembled, the heavens also dropped, Yea, the clouds dropped water.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The mountains quaked at the presence of the LORD, Even yon Sinai at the presence of the LORD, the God of Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="6">In the days of Shamgar the son of Anath, In the days of Jael, the highways ceased, And the travellers walked through byways.</verse>
  <verse number="7">The rulers ceased in Israel, they ceased, Until that thou didst arise, Deborah, That thou didst arise a mother in Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="8">They chose new gods; Then was war in the gates; Was there a shield or spear seen Among forty thousand in Israel?</verse>
  <verse number="9">My heart is toward the governors of Israel, That offered themselves willingly among the people. Bless ye the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Ye that ride on white asses, Ye that sit on rich cloths, And ye that walk by the way, tell of it;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Louder than the voice of archers, by the watering-troughs! There shall they rehearse the righteous acts of the LORD, Even the righteous acts of His rulers in Israel. Then the people of the LORD went down to the gates.</verse>
  <verse number="12">Awake, awake, Deborah; Awake, awake, utter a song; Arise, Barak, and lead thy captivity captive, thou son of Abinoam.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Then made He a remnant to have dominion over the nobles and the people; The LORD made me have dominion over the mighty.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Out of Ephraim came they whose root is in Amalek; After thee, Benjamin, among thy peoples; Out of Machir came down governors, And out of Zebulun they that handle the marshal’s staff.</verse>
  <verse number="15">And the princes of Issachar were with Deborah; As was Issachar, so was Barak; Into the valley they rushed forth at his feet. Among the divisions of Reuben There were great resolves of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="16">Why sattest thou among the sheep-folds, To hear the pipings for the flocks? At the divisions of Reuben There were great searchings of heart.</verse>
  <verse number="17">Gilead abode beyond the Jordan; And Dan, why doth he sojourn by the ships? Asher dwelt at the shore of the sea, And abideth by its bays.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Zebulun is a people that jeoparded their lives unto the death, And Naphtali, upon the high places of the field.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The kings came, they fought; Then fought the kings of Canaan, In Taanach by the waters of Megiddo; They took no gain of money.</verse>
  <verse number="20">They fought from heaven, The stars in their courses fought against Sisera.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The brook Kishon swept them away, That ancient brook, the brook Kishon. O my soul, tread them down with strength.</verse>
  <verse number="22">Then did the horsehoofs stamp By reason of the prancings, the prancings of their mighty ones.</verse>
  <verse number="23">Curse ye Meroz’, said the angel of the LORD, ‘Curse ye bitterly the inhabitants thereof, Because they came not to the help of the LORD, To the help of the LORD against the mighty.’</verse>
  <verse number="24">Blessed above women shall Jael be, The wife of Heber the Kenite, Above women in the tent shall she be blessed.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Water he asked, milk she gave him; In a lordly bowl she brought him curd.</verse>
  <verse number="26">Her hand she put to the tent-pin, And her right hand to the workmen’s hammer; And with the hammer she smote Sisera, she smote through his head, Yea, she pierced and struck through his temples.</verse>
  <verse number="27">At her feet he sunk, he fell, he lay; At her feet he sunk, he fell; Where he sunk, there he fell down dead.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Through the window she looked forth, and peered, The mother of Sisera, through the lattice: ‘Why is his chariot so long in coming? Why tarry the wheels of his chariots?</verse>
  <verse number="29">The wisest of her princesses answer her, Yea, she returneth answer to herself:</verse>
  <verse number="30">Are they not finding, are they not dividing the spoil? A damsel, two damsels to every man; To Sisera a spoil of dyed garments, A spoil of dyed garments of embroidery, Two dyed garments of broidery for the neck of every spoiler?’</verse>
  <verse number="31">So perish all Thine enemies, O LORD; But they that love Him be as the sun when he goeth forth in his might. And the land had rest forty years.</verse>
</chapter>