<chapter book="1 Corinthians" number="16" translation="American Standard Version" translationID="asv" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Now concerning the collection for the saints, as I gave order to the churches of Galatia, so also do ye.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Upon the first day of the week let each one of you lay by him in store, as he may prosper, that no collections be made when I come.</verse>
  <verse number="3">And when I arrive, whomsoever ye shall approve, them will I send with letters to carry your bounty unto Jerusalem:</verse>
  <verse number="4">and if it be meet for me to go also, they shall go with me.</verse>
  <verse number="5">But I will come unto you, when I shall have passed through Macedonia; for I pass through Macedonia;</verse>
  <verse number="6">but with you it may be that I shall abide, or even winter, that ye may set me forward on my journey whithersoever I go.</verse>
  <verse number="7">For I do not wish to see you now by the way; for I hope to tarry a while with you, if the Lord permit.</verse>
  <verse number="8">But I will tarry at Ephesus until Pentecost;</verse>
  <verse number="9">for a great door and effectual is opened unto me, and there are many adversaries.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Now if Timothy come, see that he be with you without fear; for he worketh the work of the Lord, as I also do:</verse>
  <verse number="11">let no man therefore despise him. But set him forward on his journey in peace, that he may come unto me: for I expect him with the brethren.</verse>
  <verse number="12">But as touching Apollos the brother, I besought him much to come unto you with the brethren: and it was not at all his will to come now; but he will come when he shall have opportunity.</verse>
  <verse number="13">Watch ye, stand fast in the faith, quit you like men, be strong.</verse>
  <verse number="14">Let all that ye do be done in love.</verse>
  <verse number="15">Now I beseech you, brethren (ye know the house of Stephanas, that it is the firstfruits of Achaia, and that they have set themselves to minister unto the saints),</verse>
  <verse number="16">that ye also be in subjection unto such, and to every one that helpeth in the work and laboreth.</verse>
  <verse number="17">And I rejoice at the coming of Stephanas and Fortunatus and Achaicus: for that which was lacking on your part they supplied.</verse>
  <verse number="18">For they refreshed my spirit and yours: acknowledge ye therefore them that are such.</verse>
  <verse number="19">The churches of Asia salute you. Aquila and Prisca salute you much in the Lord, with the church that is in their house.</verse>
  <verse number="20">All the brethren salute you. Salute one another with a holy kiss.</verse>
  <verse number="21">The salutation of me Paul with mine own hand.</verse>
  <verse number="22">If any man loveth not the Lord, let him be anathema. Maranatha.</verse>
  <verse number="23">The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ be with you.</verse>
  <verse number="24">My love be with you all in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
</chapter>