<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="1" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">Adam, Seth, Enosh,</verse>
  <verse number="2">Kenan, Mahalalel, Jared,</verse>
  <verse number="3">Enoch, Methuselah, Lamech, Noah.</verse>
  <verse number="4">The sons of Noah: Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
  <verse number="5">The sons of Japheth: Gomer, Magog, Madai, Javan, Tubal, Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
  <verse number="6">The sons of Gomer: Ashkenaz, Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
  <verse number="7">And the sons of Javan: Elishah, Tarshish, the Kittites, and the Rodanites.</verse>
  <verse number="8">The sons of Ham: Cush, Mizraim, Put, and Canaan.</verse>
  <verse number="9">The sons of Cush: Seba, Havilah, Sabta, Raamah, and Sabteca. The sons of Raamah: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
  <verse number="10">Cush was the father of Nimrod, who began to be a mighty one on the earth.</verse>
  <verse number="11">Mizraim was the father of the Ludites, the Anamites, the Lehabites, the Naphtuhites,</verse>
  <verse number="12">the Pathrusites, the Casluhites (from whom the Philistines came), and the Caphtorites.</verse>
  <verse number="13">And Canaan was the father of Sidon his firstborn, and of the Hittites,</verse>
  <verse number="14">the Jebusites, the Amorites, the Girgashites,</verse>
  <verse number="15">the Hivites, the Arkites, the Sinites,</verse>
  <verse number="16">the Arvadites, the Zemarites, and the Hamathites.</verse>
  <verse number="17">The sons of Shem: Elam, Asshur, Arphaxad, Lud, and Aram. The sons of Aram: Uz, Hul, Gether, and Meshech.</verse>
  <verse number="18">Arphaxad was the father of Shelah, and Shelah was the father of Eber.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Two sons were born to Eber: One was named Peleg, because in his days the earth was divided, and his brother was named Joktan.</verse>
  <verse number="20">And Joktan was the father of Almodad, Sheleph, Hazarmaveth, Jerah,</verse>
  <verse number="21">Hadoram, Uzal, Diklah,</verse>
  <verse number="22">Obal, Abimael, Sheba,</verse>
  <verse number="23">Ophir, Havilah, and Jobab. All these were sons of Joktan.</verse>
  <verse number="24">So from Shem came Arphaxad, Shelah,</verse>
  <verse number="25">Eber, Peleg, Reu,</verse>
  <verse number="26">Serug, Nahor, Terah,</verse>
  <verse number="27">and Abram (that is, Abraham).</verse>
  <verse number="28">The sons of Abraham were Isaac and Ishmael.</verse>
  <verse number="29">These are their genealogies: Nebaioth the firstborn of Ishmael, then Kedar, Adbeel, Mibsam,</verse>
  <verse number="30">Mishma, Dumah, Massa, Hadad, Tema,</verse>
  <verse number="31">Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah. These were the sons of Ishmael.</verse>
  <verse number="32">The sons born to Keturah, Abraham’s concubine: Zimran, Jokshan, Medan, Midian, Ishbak, and Shuah. The sons of Jokshan: Sheba and Dedan.</verse>
  <verse number="33">The sons of Midian: Ephah, Epher, Hanoch, Abida, and Eldaah. All of these were Keturah’s sons.</verse>
  <verse number="34">Abraham was the father of Isaac. The sons of Isaac: Esau and Israel.</verse>
  <verse number="35">The sons of Esau: Eliphaz, Reuel, Jeush, Jalam, and Korah.</verse>
  <verse number="36">The sons of Eliphaz: Teman, Omar, Zepho, Gatam, and Kenaz; and by Timna, Amalek.</verse>
  <verse number="37">The sons of Reuel: Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah.</verse>
  <verse number="38">The sons of Seir: Lotan, Shobal, Zibeon, Anah, Dishon, Ezer, and Dishan.</verse>
  <verse number="39">The sons of Lotan: Hori and Homam. Timna was Lotan’s sister.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The sons of Shobal: Alvan, Manahath, Ebal, Shepho, and Onam. The sons of Zibeon: Aiah and Anah.</verse>
  <verse number="41">The son of Anah: Dishon. The sons of Dishon: Hemdan, Eshban, Ithran, and Cheran.</verse>
  <verse number="42">The sons of Ezer: Bilhan, Zaavan, and Akan. The sons of Dishan: Uz and Aran.</verse>
  <verse number="43">These are the kings who reigned in the land of Edom before any king reigned over the Israelites: Bela son of Beor. His city was named Dinhabah.</verse>
  <verse number="44">When Bela died, Jobab son of Zerah from Bozrah reigned in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="45">When Jobab died, Husham from the land of the Temanites reigned in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="46">When Husham died, Hadad son of Bedad, who defeated Midian in the country of Moab, reigned in his place. And the name of his city was Avith.</verse>
  <verse number="47">When Hadad died, Samlah from Masrekah reigned in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="48">When Samlah died, Shaul from Rehoboth on the Euphrates reigned in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="49">When Shaul died, Baal-hanan son of Achbor reigned in his place.</verse>
  <verse number="50">When Baal-hanan died, Hadad reigned in his place. His city was named Pau, and his wife’s name was Mehetabel daughter of Matred, the daughter of Me-zahab.</verse>
  <verse number="51">Then Hadad died. Now the chiefs of Edom were Timna, Alvah, Jetheth,</verse>
  <verse number="52">Oholibamah, Elah, Pinon,</verse>
  <verse number="53">Kenaz, Teman, Mibzar,</verse>
  <verse number="54">Magdiel, and Iram. These were the chiefs of Edom.</verse>
</chapter>