<chapter book="1 Chronicles" number="9" translation="Berean Standard Bible" translationID="bsb" language="English" languageID="en">
  <verse number="1">So all Israel was recorded in the genealogies written in the Book of the Kings of Israel. But Judah was exiled to Babylon because of their unfaithfulness.</verse>
  <verse number="2">Now the first to resettle their own property in their cities were Israelites, priests, Levites, and temple servants.</verse>
  <verse number="3">Some of the descendants of Judah, Benjamin, Ephraim, and Manasseh lived in Jerusalem:</verse>
  <verse number="4">Uthai son of Ammihud, the son of Omri, the son of Imri, the son of Bani, a descendant of Perez son of Judah.</verse>
  <verse number="5">From the Shilonites: Asaiah the firstborn and his sons.</verse>
  <verse number="6">From the Zerahites: Jeuel and 690 relatives.</verse>
  <verse number="7">From the Benjamites: Sallu son of Meshullam, the son of Hodaviah, the son of Hassenuah;</verse>
  <verse number="8">Ibneiah son of Jeroham; Elah son of Uzzi, the son of Michri; Meshullam son of Shephatiah, the son of Reuel, the son of Ibnijah;</verse>
  <verse number="9">and 956 of their relatives according to their genealogy. All these men were heads of their families.</verse>
  <verse number="10">From the priests: Jedaiah, Jehoiarib, and Jachin;</verse>
  <verse number="11">Azariah son of Hilkiah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Zadok, the son of Meraioth, the son of Ahitub, the chief official of God’s temple;</verse>
  <verse number="12">Adaiah son of Jeroham, the son of Pashhur, the son of Malchijah; Maasai son of Adiel, the son of Jahzerah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Meshillemith, the son of Immer;</verse>
  <verse number="13">and 1,760 of their relatives, the heads of their families, able men for the work of the service of the house of God.</verse>
  <verse number="14">From the Levites: Shemaiah son of Hasshub, the son of Azrikam, the son of Hashabiah, a descendant of Merari;</verse>
  <verse number="15">Bakbakkar, Heresh, Galal, and Mattaniah son of Mica, the son of Zichri, the son of Asaph;</verse>
  <verse number="16">Obadiah son of Shemaiah, the son of Galal, the son of Jeduthun; and Berechiah son of Asa, the son of Elkanah, who lived in the villages of the Netophathites.</verse>
  <verse number="17">These were the gatekeepers: Shallum, Akkub, Talmon, Ahiman, and their relatives. Shallum was their chief;</verse>
  <verse number="18">he was previously stationed at the King’s Gate on the east side. These were the gatekeepers from the camp of the Levites.</verse>
  <verse number="19">Shallum son of Kore, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah, and his relatives from the Korahites were assigned to guard the thresholds of the Tent, just as their fathers had been assigned to guard the entrance to the dwelling of the LORD.</verse>
  <verse number="20">In earlier times Phinehas son of Eleazar had been in charge of the gatekeepers, and the LORD was with him.</verse>
  <verse number="21">Zechariah son of Meshelemiah was the gatekeeper at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.</verse>
  <verse number="22">The number of those chosen to be gatekeepers at the thresholds was 212. They were registered by genealogy in their villages. David and Samuel the seer had appointed them to their positions of trust.</verse>
  <verse number="23">So they and their descendants were assigned to guard the gates of the house of the LORD—the house called the Tent.</verse>
  <verse number="24">The gatekeepers were stationed on the four sides: east, west, north, and south.</verse>
  <verse number="25">Their relatives came from their villages at fixed times to serve with them for seven-day periods.</verse>
  <verse number="26">But the four chief gatekeepers, who were Levites, were entrusted with the rooms and the treasuries of the house of God.</verse>
  <verse number="27">They would spend the night stationed around the house of God, because they were responsible for guarding it and opening it every morning.</verse>
  <verse number="28">Some of them were in charge of the articles used in worship, to count them whenever they were brought in or taken out.</verse>
  <verse number="29">Others were put in charge of the furnishings and other articles of the sanctuary, as well as the fine flour, wine, oil, frankincense, and spices.</verse>
  <verse number="30">And some of the sons of the priests mixed the spices.</verse>
  <verse number="31">A Levite named Mattithiah, the firstborn son of Shallum the Korahite, was entrusted with baking the bread.</verse>
  <verse number="32">Some of their Kohathite relatives were responsible for preparing the rows of the showbread every Sabbath.</verse>
  <verse number="33">Those who were musicians, the heads of Levite families, stayed in the temple chambers and were exempt from other duties because they were on duty day and night.</verse>
  <verse number="34">All these were heads of Levite families, chiefs according to their genealogies, and they lived in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="35">Jeiel the father of Gibeon lived in Gibeon. His wife’s name was Maacah.</verse>
  <verse number="36">Abdon was his firstborn son, then Zur, Kish, Baal, Ner, Nadab,</verse>
  <verse number="37">Gedor, Ahio, Zechariah, and Mikloth.</verse>
  <verse number="38">Mikloth was the father of Shimeam. They too lived alongside their relatives in Jerusalem.</verse>
  <verse number="39">Ner was the father of Kish, Kish was the father of Saul, and Saul was the father of Jonathan, Malchishua, Abinadab, and Esh-baal.</verse>
  <verse number="40">The son of Jonathan: Merib-baal, who was the father of Micah.</verse>
  <verse number="41">The sons of Micah: Pithon, Melech, Tahrea, and Ahaz.</verse>
  <verse number="42">Ahaz was the father of Jarah; Jarah was the father of Alemeth, Azmaveth, and Zimri; and Zimri was the father of Moza.</verse>
  <verse number="43">Moza was the father of Binea. Rephaiah was his son, Elasah his son, and Azel his son.</verse>
  <verse number="44">And Azel had six sons, and these were their names: Azrikam, Bocheru, Ishmael, Sheariah, Obadiah, and Hanan. These were the sons of Azel.</verse>
</chapter>